<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2067-11-24

                     HUNTINGTON EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

THOMAS-YOSEF,JULIA   840-91-51-9            VISIT DATE: 11/24/67

This patient was seen with Dr. Earley.  The patient was interviewed 

and examined by me.  Resident's note reviewed and confirmed.  The 

plan of care was discussed with the patient.   Please see chart for 

details. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this is a 47-year-old 

woman with a history of asthma and non-insulin-dependent diabetes 

mellitus who has had three weeks of progressive substernal chest 

pain radiating to the back with associated nausea, vomiting, 

shortness of breath, and diaphoresis.  The episodes of pain last 

10-15 minutes with exertion and at rest.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Asthma, hypothyroidism, and recently 

diagnosed diabetes mellitus.

MEDICATIONS:  Levoxyl, Albuterol, Protonix, Tums, Flovent.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Remote history of smoking.  

Family history:  Coronary artery disease in father.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL APPEARANCE:  No acute distress, 

pain-free.  VITAL SIGNS:  Afebrile.  Pulse 105.  Respirations 15. 

Blood pressure 143/96.  Pulse oximetry is 95% on room air.  

CARDIAC:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Normal S1 and S2.  No murmurs, 

gallops, or rubs.  NECK:  JVP 5 cm.  LUNGS:  Clear.  Breathing is 

unlabored.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender, and nondistended with active 

bowel sounds.  EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The EKG shows a normal sinus rhythm with 

lateral T-wave inversions and question of old septal myocardial 

infarction.  Chest x-ray shows no acute cardiopulmonary disease.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain, multiple cardiac risk factors, 

abnormal electrocardiogram, currently pain-free without evidence of 

congestive heart failure.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The plan is 

aspirin, Lopressor, and admission to telemetry.  The patient was 

admitted to the hospital in stable condition.

___________________________________                    VA271/37942 

MARVIN UTECHT, M.D.   MU830                          D:11/24/67 

                                                       T:11/24/67 

Dictated by:  MARVIN UTECHT, M.D.   MU830 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2068-01-25

                     HUNTINGTON EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

THOMAS-YOSEF,JULIA   840-91-51-9

This patient was seen by the resident.  I confirm that I have 

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's 

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the evaluation, 

plan of care, and disposition with the patient. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 52-year-old 

female status post LAD stent placement in November of 2067.  She 

presents to the emergency room with chest pain since last night.  

It has been midsternal going to her back.  She denies any knife or 

crushing pain going down her back.  However, the chest pain has 

been consistent since 9:00 to about 4:00 this morning.  No 

shortness of breath, diaphoresis, light-headedness, or dizziness.  

She did not take any nitroglycerin.  She presented to the emergency 

room today after she talked to her cardiologist, who wanted her to 

come to the emergency room for evaluation.  The patient denies 

taking any nitroglycerin and denies any chest pain episodes since 

her stent was placed back in November 2067.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  The patient had some midsternal chest pain.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for oral hypoglycemic requiring 

diabetes, hypertension, high cholesterol, coronary artery disease, 

and hypothyroidism.  Past surgeries and procedures include stent 

placement for an LAD lesion back in November 2067.

MEDICATIONS:  Glucophage, Ativan, Metoprolol, Zocor, and Plavix, 

including aspirin.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  The patient has a past history 

of tobacco use.  She denies any alcohol or IV drug use.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Afebrile.  Normal vital signs. 

Bilaterally equal blood pressures.  GENERAL APPEARANCE:  

Well-appearing female otherwise in no acute distress.  LUNGS:  

Clear to auscultation bilaterally.  CARDIAC:  S1, S2, regular rate 

and rhythm without murmurs, gallops or rubs.  ABDOMEN:  Positive 

bowel sounds.  Soft, nontender.  RECTAL:  Guaiac-negative.  

EXTREMITIES:  No lower extremity swelling or edema. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Glucose is 204.  Labs are other wise 

negative.  Troponin is 0.04.  Normal CBC and coagulation studies.  

Chest x-ray shows mild cardiomegaly, mild congestion, otherwise 

normal mediastinum, no pleural infiltrates or effusion.  EKG shows 

pseudonormalization in aVL and V2 compared to an EKG in November 

2067.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Impression is a 52-year-old female 

with a history of coronary artery disease presenting with chest 

pain since her stent placement in November.  We will treat her for 

an occluded stent.  We will start IV heparin, nitroglycerin for 

pain, given aspirin, call cardiology as to further intervention and 

management.  At this time the patient is clinically hemodynamically 

stable, awaiting transfer to the cardiac floor.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Condition is 

stable.

___________________________________                    NJ688/96614 

TONYA YOO, M.D.   TY822                             D:01/25/68 

                                                       T:01/25/68 

Dictated by:  TONYA YOO, M.D.   TY822 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2068-09-21

EDVISIT^84091519^Thomas-yosef, Julia^09/21/68^KEMPER, SYLVAN

The patient seen on 09/21/2068 with Dr. Jewell-Wilson. 

Resident's history was reviewed.  Patient was interviewed and

examined by me.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 40-year-old woman

with history of coronary disease and has had intermittent chest

pain over the past 4 days, unrelieved by 2 sublingual

nitroglycerin yesterday, today relieved after 20 minutes with 1

sublingual.  See resident's note for further details.  The

patient is pain free now.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Coronary disease, cardiac stent,

hypercholesterolemia, and diabetes.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Atenolol, Zocor, Plavix, aspirin, and

metformin.  See resident's note for further details.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Past cigarette smoker.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  No shortness of breath, no nausea or

vomiting, no headache.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature 97.5, blood pressure 124/55,

pulse 79, respirations 18, O2 saturation 99% on room air.  HEENT:

 Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils are equal, round, and

reactive to light.  Extraocular muscles intact.  Neck:  Supple,

no meningeal sign.  CV:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Lungs:  Clear.

 Abdomen:  Positive bowel sounds, soft, nontender.  Extremities: 

No cyanosis, clubbing, or edema.  Neurologic:  Alert and oriented

x3.  Cranial nerves are intact.  Motor and sensory are intact.

LABORATORY DATA:  EKG was normal sinus rhythm, with no ST

changes.

The patient was seen by Dr. Donnelly in the Emergency

Department.  The patient will be admitted to the Cardiology

Service for further evaluation for unstable angina.  Started on

heparin in the Emergency Department and likely cardiac

catheterization tomorrow.

See resident's note for details.

______________________________

KEMPER, SYLVAN M.D.

D: 09/21/68

T: 09/21/68

Dictated By: KEMPER, SYLVAN

eScription document:6-7180439 BFFocus

******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-01-01

EDVISIT^84091519^THOMAS-YOSEF, JULIA^01/01/72^HOFFMAN, VICTOR

Seen by me along with Dr. Ickes on 01/01/2072.  History as

documented by Dr. Ickes was reviewed by me with the patient and

found to be accurate and complete.  The physical exam was

confirmed by my examination.  Evaluation and management was also

concurred with.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  In brief, this is a 51-year-old

woman with history of coronary artery disease status post MI

stenting in 2068, presents with 3-day history of substernal chest

pain radiating to her back, and also complaining of mild pain of

inner medial aspect of her right arm, feels like her anginal

symptoms that she had in 2068 with some very mild shortness of

breath and even though she is quite sedentary and she noted that

there is an increase in pain with exertion, position, as well as

eating.  She took many Tums with no relief and says takes Zantac

chronically, but ran out of it.  She says that the pain is

burning epigastric at times, and the thing that is concerning was

her back pain that was reminiscent of the pain that she had when

she had her MI.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  She has a history of hypertension,

diabetes, MI, and breast cancer status post lumpectomy and

radiation.  Last stress test was may be in October, which was

normal.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Positive for breast cancer and diabetes

mellitus.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She does not drink.  She smoked in the past,

quit 15 years ago.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As documented in the chart.  Please see notes

for details.

ALLERGIES:  As documented in the chart.  Please see notes for

details.

MEDICATIONS:  As documented in the chart.  Please see notes for

details.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Awake, alert, well-developed,

well-nourished woman, and in no apparent distress.  Afebrile,

slightly 96.7, pulse 72, respirations 16, blood pressure 124/72,

and O2 saturation 98%.  Anicteric sclerae.  Mucous membranes are

moist.  Neck is supple.  Lungs are clear of rales, wheezes, or

rhonchi.  Cardiovascular:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Abdomen is

obese.  Bowel sounds normoactive, nontender, and no guarding,

rebound, or rigidity.  The skin is intact, warm, and dry.  She

has point tenderness over the upper thoracic cage and trace pedal

edema.

LABORATORY DATA:  The patient has a normal CBC and normal

electrolytes.  D-dimer was less than 200.  Troponin and CK were

normal.

IMAGING STUDIES:  EKG sinus rhythm with unchanged from previous. 

Chest CT was negative PE.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  As such, she was admitted to the

Observation Unit for a second set of enzymes which if normal will

be discharged home, after walking to see if she has any

exertional component, as such, she was subsequently discharged to

home in stable and satisfactory condition.  She was admitted to

the Observation Unit 01/01/2072 with diagnosis of chest pain.

______________________________

HOFFMAN, VICTOR M.D.

D: 01/01/72

T: 01/02/72

Dictated By: HOFFMAN, VICTOR

eScription document:0-5469816 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>