<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2145-08-13

August 12, 2145 

 

 

Dr. Mabel Duvall 

Medicine Department 

Bellflower Doctors Hospital 

 

 

RE:  TUTTLE, Sandy 

MR#:  2793372 

DOB:  January 16, 2082 

 

 

Dear Dr. Duvall:  

 

Thank you for referring Mr. Sandy Tuttle to our Neurology Department.  I understand that he is referred here for evaluation of polyneuropathy.  

 

Mr. Tuttle is a 63-year-old right-handed diabetic man who has developed numbness of his lower extremities since 2125.  The numbness started in his toes and gradually spread proximally up to the level of the knees.  In 2135, the numbness started to affect his hands.  In 2139, the patient noted atrophy of the first dorsal interosseous muscles of both hands, left worse than right.  

 

The patient denies any pain in his legs or feet.  He has a five year history of localized low back pain and neck pain radiating to his left upper extremity all the way down to his hands.  In 2125, the patient fell down a ladder from a height of about 30 feet.  According to the patient, he herniated a cervical disk, but surgery was not indicated.  He remembers having pain in his left elbow and neck after the fall.  

 

The patient developed impotence and constipation in 2130.  In 2139, he started to have symptoms of orthostatic hypotension which he described as feeling light-headed, darkening of vision upon standing.  The patient also noted gait imbalance in 2139 prior to his retirement in 2141.  

 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Insulin dependent diabetes since 2123, hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, constipation, impotence, macular degeneration of the eyes, retinopathy, s/p laser treatments, history of neck pain and low back pain as mentioned above, history of gastroesophageal reflux disease, skin problems using a number of steroid creams, penile implant in 2130.  

 

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Atenolol, Diltiazem, Zestril, Mevacor, steroid creams, Colace, metoclopramide, Naprosyn, insulin.   



ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.  

 

SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient is married he has two daughters, 30 and 40 years of age.  He used to work as a Legal Secretary until he retired in December of 2141.  The patient quit smoking in 2107.  He denies any history of alcohol or drug abuse.  

 

FAMILY HISTORY:  Father died of unclear cause at the age of 45.  His father was diabetic and had heart problems.  Mother died in her 30's.  The patient does not know the cause of death.  The patient had one brother who died in his 50's from diabetic complications.  He had two sister who died of diabetic complications.  Of his two living sisters, one of them is also a diabetic.  The patient's daughters are not diabetic.  There is no known family history of neuromuscular disorders.  

 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Range of motion of the neck is limited.  Head turning 45 degrees to either side.  Limited neck extension.  Negative straight-leg raising.  Negative spine tenderness.  Regular cardiac rhythm, no heart murmur.  Negative carotid bruits.  In the supine position, blood pressure 105/50, heart rate 60 and regular.  Upon standing, blood pressure dropped to 60/40, heart rate remained 60.  The patient was asymptomatic.   



NEUROLOGICAL EXAMINATION:  Mental status:  Alert, coherent and appropriate.  The patient knows the name of his physician, Dr. Duvall, Dr. Villagomez, and Dr. Goldberg at Pioneer Home.  

 

Cranial nerves:  Visual fields full.  Visual acuity with reading glasses 20/30 on the right, 20/20 -1 on the left.  Extraocular movements full.  No nystagmus.  Pupils sluggishly reactive to light.  Optic discs flat bilaterally.  No facial asymmetry.  The tongue and soft palate move symmetrically.  

 

Motor examination:  Atrophy of the first dorsal interosseous and ADM, worse on the left hand.  No atrophy of the abductor pollicis brevis.  Negative arm drift.  Motor strength testing 5/5 in all muscles of both upper extremities except for 4/5 weakness of the first dorsal interosseous and abductor digiti minimi bilaterally.  No weakness of the abductor pollicis brevis on either hand.  Motor strength testing of the lower extremities 5/5 except for mild weakness of toe extensors 4+/5 bilaterally.  The patient was able to walk on his toes and heels while holding onto the examiner.  Deep tendon reflexes 2+ bilaterally at the biceps, triceps, and knees.  Absent ankle jerks bilaterally.  Toes downgoing.  No spasticity of the lower extremities.

   

Sensory examination:  Significant for absent pin prick sensation in both feet up to the level of the knees.  Pin prick sensation is diminished in the dorsal aspect of all fingers and the palmar aspect of both hands.  Vibratory sensation absent in the toes, intact at the ankles and knees bilaterally.  Intact vibratory sensation in the upper extremities.  Romberg test significant for body swaying, but the patient did not fall.  Tandem gait was poor, but improved when holding the examiner.  No limb ataxia.   



LABORATORY DATA:  Review of previous laboratory tests of May, 2145, BUN 36, creatinine 1.7, glucose 310.  December, 2144, TSH normal.  October, 2143, B12 normal.  Negative RPR.  The patient said he was tested negative for HIV in 2142, and 2143.  MRI of the brain in 2142 and 2143 revealed bilateral white matter changes in the cerebral hemisphere without any intracranial mass lesion.   



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  In summary, we have a 63-year-old diabetic man who appears to have significant sensorimotor polyneuropathy with autonomic involvement.  He does have constipation and impotence as well as orthostatic hypotension.  



As we discussed on the phone, his antihypertensive medications need to be adjusted and the patient will be following up with you regarding this.  He may benefit from Jobst stockings to reduce his symptoms of orthostatic hypotension.  I will be ordering an EMG to assess his polyneuropathy and look for any evidence of superimposed ulnar neuropathy or cervical radiculopathy on the left.  The EMG should also include RR interval variations and sympathetic skin responses.  

 

MRI of the cervical spine was also ordered to rule out any cord compression which may also contribute to loss of sensation in the legs.  The patient does have a history of traumatic cervical herniated disk in 2125.  He may also have had a left elbow injury at this time which can make him prone to develop tardy ulnar palsy.  

 

The patient will return for a follow-up visit after the above tests.  

 

Thank you again for referring Mr. Sandy Tuttle to our Neurology Department.  

 

Sincerely, 

 

 

 

Stanly Lang, M.D.  

 

 

cc: Dr. T. Villagomez,Internal Medicine 502F, Bellflower Doctors Hospital 

 

 

 

DD:08/13/45 

DT:08/17/45 

QY:40282   :214 

 





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2147-03-11

Reason for consult:  65 year old man with progressive LBP, found to have heterogeneous marrow on MRI, we have been consulted to help evaluate, possibly perform a bone marrow biopsy.



HPI:

65 yo male with PMH significant for DM, autonomic dysfunction, CRI, depression and arthritis who was admitted for progressive lower back pain.  He has had LBP for at least three years which is located in his mid lumbar region, non radiating, worse with standing.  The pain had progressed such that he has a very poor performance status. He cannot stand but for a few minutes at a time.  He denies focal wekness.   He had an MRI of the LS spine 2/02/47 which revealed heterogeneous marrow concernig for an infiltrating process in his marrow.   He has had an SPEP which was normal, he has had a bone scan which was negatvie. He does not have an elevated protein or globulin fraction. His CRI is longstanding  and attributed to his DM.  He was set up for a outpt BM bx to evaluate the marrow process, but the pain has been so severe, he was admitted for an inpatient work up.  Of note he has longstanding anemia related to his CRI, perhaps anemia of chronic disease.  He denies any weight loss, fevers, chills, night sweats, decreased appetite. He does report fatigue which has become progressive.



PMH:

1. DM

2. autonomic dysfunction with orthostatic hypotension

3. diabetic retinopathy

4. depression

5. CRI

6. OA

7.  H/o TB 2132 

8.  C7 radiculopthy with bil hand weakness and neck pain

9. HL

10 Seborrheic dermatitis



Meds:

lovastatin, fludrocortisone, celexa, reglan, proamatine, ultram, insulin, colace, ecasa



All: NKDA



FH: Father had Diabetes, mother died of breast cancer.



SH: Worked in Foxworthy Industrials 2100-4 during which time he had multple exposures to chemicals. Retired from working in the city of Victorville 2141. He reports a 30 pyr hx of tobacco, former hx of heavy ETOH use, stopped since 12/46. Denies IV DU.



PE:

General: thin gentleman, in no actute distress

HEENT: PERRLA< EOMI, Op without thrush, no thyromegaly, No JVD

Chest: CTA bil

CV: RRR nml s1, s2, no m/g/r

Abd: + bs, soft, non-tender, non-distended, no hepatosplenomegaly

Ext: no c/c/e

neuro: strenth 5/5 throughout; absent patellar reflexes, 2+ biceps, triceps, brachioradialis, downgoing toes bilaterally



Labs:

Cr 1.4  Bun 25  HCT 28.6  WBC 5.5  Plt 201  MCV 87  80seg; 15l

ESR 35

Pt/Ptt nml

SPEP 2/47: nml  T prot 6  Alb 3.4

MRI 1/47: heterogenous bonemarrow uptake in vertebrae and pelvis, concerning for infiltrative process



Imp/Plan:

Mr. Tuttle is a 65 year old male with a three year hisotry of porgressive lower back pain, non-radicualr in nature. The pain has progressed to a significant level such that he spends most of his day in bed.  He did have an MRI of the L/S spine which was negative except it did reveal heterogeous uptake in the vertebral and pelvic bone marrow. They raised the question of multiple myeloma or another infiltrative process. He does have renal insufficiency, but no other abnormalities to suggest MM. We still need a few key pieces of data to rule this out. Other infiltrative processes such as malignancy from elsewhere should be excluded.  In addition, he has a hx of a positive PPD, unclear if he actually had active TB or was treated prophylactically. Is any of this TB?  Recommend:

-- skeletal survey

-- quantitative urine bence jones proteins as there are  non-secretory myelomas

-- beta-2 microglobulin

-- reticulocyte count

-- consider chest CT to r/o lung cancer given his history of tobacco

-- guaiac all stools

-- Will review the MRI with radiologist to get a better differential

-- Consider BM biopsy next week, unfortunately will not be able to perform today. 

-- Will review smear and staff with Dr. Landry in the afternoon.

Thank you for this consult.



______________________________________________



Ivy Whitaker, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2148-02-10

REASON FOR VISIT:  Followup for diabetic cheiropathy.  Rule out other diabetes-related musculoskeletal syndrome.  Monitoring of Ultracet therapy and left shoulder injection.  

 

INTERVAL HISTORY:  Left shoulder injection was helpful but only last short time.  Just  a week or so.  Ultracet was relieving pains but was not able to afford it.  Feels stable and not worse since last seen.  Telling me he is cutting down his medications and he is letting his doctors know about this. No acute swelling or further different joint complaints other than what was described in my previous notes.  Rest of review of systems again unchanged.   



MEDICATIONS:  The medication file is same as last time, except for addition of Tylenols now.  

 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: BP 100/70.  Other VS WNL. Wt. 170lb.  Gait:  Slow.  Cooperative.  VSS.  HEENT:  Halitosis.  Poor teeth hygiene.  Lungs:  Clear.  Heart:  Unremarkable.  Abdomen exam:  Slight sensitiveness in epigastrium.  A little low-frequency tremor in extremities.  Musculoskeletal examination:  Both shoulders with limited ROM.  Left shoulder active ROM is improved compared to the last description.  Hands with prayer's sign present.  Elbows again show lesser degree of flexion contracture.  Range of motion in both shoulders diminished, 

more in the left side.  Hardening of skin on the palm side of hands.  Has atrophy of intrinsic muscles of hands.  The rest of joint examination, free of inflammation.  Unchanged from last description.  

 

IMPRESSION:  Diabetic cheiropathy.  Rule out other diabetes-related musculoskeletal syndrome esp in shoulders.  Helped by Ultracet.  Osteoarthritis changes of early stage.  Status post olecranon bursitis.  Elevated creatinine.  

 

PLANS:  

1.  Continue Ultracet up 2 tablets prn once     twice a day; Samples given.

2.  May consider low-dose narcotics, given his multiple comorbidity and sensitive renal function to nonsteroidal therapy.  3.  Close followup for diabetes care with other physicians.   

DISPOSITION:  Followup in 4 months or so.  

 

 

_______________________________ 

Virgil Gregory, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2148-07-28

Internal Medicine Intern Admit Note

Pt: Samuel Tuttle

MR: 2793372



Cc: EKG changes 



HPI: 66 y.o. male with pmhx of DM, incr.cholestoral, and autonomic insufficeny admitted for EKG changes. The patient has significant risk factors for CAD of DM, incr. Cholesterol, and h/o htn.  He had a adenosine stress test done in 11/47 which was negative for ischemia (lasting 5min and PDP of 13746). His last echo was done in 4/48 showed an EF of 59% presented to the health clinic with a 3 day hx of worsening L shoulder pain and episodes of diaphoresis. The shoulder pain is chronic and thought to be due to oa, and dm chor.He came to the clinic today for a BP check ( he is often hypotensive and orthostatic) and was noted to have TWI inferiorly and laterally on routine EKG.   He denied any chest pain, nausea, vomiting when he went to the e.r. 

In the e.r., his first set of cardiac enzymes was negative, he was also started on heparin IV, and given IV lopressor, and an aspirin. Of note, the patient had a bp up to 182/88. When the patient arrived on the floor he denied any chest pain, nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis. His BP was noted to be 228/105. 2.5 IV lopressor, 12.5 PO lopressor, and nitropaste were given initially to lower bp to 170/75.







PMHx

DM (hx of diabetic retinopathy, nephropathy, autonomic instability, neuropathy)

Hypercholesterolemia

Autonomic insufficiency

Polyneuropathy

TB

Asbestos

CRI (baseline 2.1)

Depression

Arthritis (chronic left shoulder pain)



Medications:

Lovastatin 40mg QD

ASA 81mg QD

Insulin 75/25 22qam 24qpm

Prilosec 20 mg qd

Proamatine 10mg TID

Florinef 0.2mg qd

Ultram 37.5mg TID

Celexa 60mg QD

Buspar 10mg QD



Allergies:NKDA



SOCIAL HISTORY:  Lives with his wife.  He used to work at foxworthy industrials in

     2100-2104, after which he had industrial exposure to various chemicals such

     as trichloroethylene, asbestos and incinerator smoke.  He retired in 2141.

:  Smoking: 30 pack year smoking history, quit in 2107.  Alcohol:

     heavy drinking for 40 years, cut down in 2146 and has stopped drinking

     since December, 2146.  Denies any drug use.



P/E: BP226/109 T96.6 P74 R20 O2 98% on 2L

GEN: WDWN male in n.a.d.

HEENT: EOMI, PERRL, no o-p erythema, no carotid bruits, JVP not visible with patient sitting upright

Chest: crackles Left lung base,  good air movement bilaterally

C-V: regular, s1 s2 no m/g/r PMI in 5th intercostals space midclavicular line

Abd: soft nt normoactive bs

Ext: skin changes on anterior legs bilaterally in LE. No edema

Neuro: A&O x3. CN II-XII intact. No focal motor or sensory deficits







Labs:

7.2>33.1<214 PT 12.8 PTT22.8

Na -146. K 3.8, Cl 113, CO2 24.4, BUN 32, Cr 2.2, Gluc 148

Mg 1.7 PO4 3.2 Ca 9.7

Alb 4, direct bili .6, Alk phos 82, AST 32, ALT 37

CK IE negative, Troponin negative



Chest x-ray - 

1.  NO EVIDENCE OF PNEUMONIA OR PULMONARY EDEMA.

	2.  CALCIFIED PLEURAL PLAQUES, AS BEFORE.

	3.  A NODULAR OPACITY IN THE RIGHT UPPER LUNG ZONE IS NOW BETTER

	DEFINED THAN IN THE PREVIOUS EXAMINATION.  IN LIGHT OF THE CHANGE

	IN APPEARANCE, CHEST C. T. MAY BE WARRANTED TO EXCLUDE A GROWING

	NEOPLASM.



EKG- from e.r. TWI in II, III, avF, v3-v6. borderline LVH, left atrial enlargement

On admission - flattened TW in II, II,avF, TWI v4, v5



Imp: 66 y.o. male with hx of DM, autonomic instability, incr. Cholesterol presents with new EKG changes.



Plan:

1.C-V

a)	ischemia - r/o MI, first set of cardiac enzymes negative, will get two more sets to r/o. Will monitor for EKG changes. New TWI in inferior and lateral chest leads worrisome in a patient with multiple risk factors. Last stress negative 6 months ago. Will talk with PCP and team in a.m. to discuss the need for stress in asymptomatic patient with recent stress. EKG changes may be secondary to htn strain. Will d/c IV heparin. Cont. po lopressor as long as patient's bp tolerates it. ASA qd. Appreciate input of Dr. Bodnari and will discuss future management.

b)	Pump - last ef 59% pt. Appears euvolemic

c)	Rhythm - no hx of arrythmia, on cardiac monitor/telemetry overnight



2. HTN - pt. Htn when he arrived on floor. Hx of hypotension. Will give low dose lopressor 12.5mg BID as well as nitropaste. Need to be careful of lowering BP too fast. Pt.'s bp unstable in past.  Will hold florinef and proamatine for now



3. DM - hx of retinopathy, nephropathy, and neuropathy. Will maintain on home regiman of nph, and cover with iss.



4. Shoulder pain - ultram, PT 



5. Resp - opacity in RUL, may be secondary to old TB. According to radiologist reading it has changed since past x-rays. Asymptomatic. Can be worked up as an outpatient.



6. Prophylaxis - pneumoboots, nexium







_____________________________________________

Bobby U. Spears, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2149-03-19





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

BELLFLOWER DOCTORS HOSPITAL



Reason for visit   67 yo man with DM, supine HTN, orthostatic hypotension, hyperlipidemia, +FH presents with NSTEMI. Patient was in his USOH (extremely limited physical activity 2/2 severe orthostatic hypotension and osteoarthritis) until AM of admission. He had c/o some increased night sweats x 2 weeks s cough and increased constipation. He also c/o worsening "lockjaw" p eating which he attributes to poor denture fitting. He awoke 3/18 AM with sl fatigue, FS 190. He went to his preop cataract appt at FCH and c/o diaphoresis. His FS was 43, BP 122/50, HR 90. EKG revealed STD V2-V3 + pseudonorm T V4-V6-> left with baseline TWI V3-V6. His CK and troponin were positive. He was treated with ASA, BB, ACE, and heparin. He has been sx free since FCH.



Problem List (reviewed)



Tuberculosis MAJOR 

Diabetes mellitus MAJOR 

Radiculopathy MAJOR 

Hypercholesterolemia MAJOR 

Coronary artery disease MAJOR 

Orthostatic hypotension MAJOR 

Shoulder pain MAJOR 

Diabetic retinopathy MAJOR 

Arthritis MAJOR 

Depression MAJOR 

Renal insufficiency MAJOR 

Fatigue MAJOR 

Low back pain MAJOR 

Shortness of breath MAJOR 

Seborrheic dermatitis 

Tinea pedis 

Gastroesophageal reflux disease 

Smoking status: former smoker 

Constipation 

Health maintenance 



Major Problems

Coronary artery disease

History of CAD w/ positive ETT 3/37 (nothing on PCIS); since then had neg adeno-MIBI in 2145, 2147, 8/48 (but only 9680 PDP). Pt on asa, mevacor with hi chol (last fasting 7/48 chol 214, LDL 128). TTE 4/48: EF 59%, LVH, mild MR, no SWMA. Cards = Mildred Gustafson. 

A/P: Cath pending. Cont ASA. Would recheck fasting cholesterol and change to lipitor 80 qd for maximal risk factor management. Limited in use of BB, ACE with orthostatic hypotension. 

Orthostatic hypotension

Fairly severe orthostasis, likely secondary to autonomic dysfunction from diabetes.  Continues to c/o dizziness + nausea with prolonged standing. On fludrocortisone 1x/d, midodrine 10 TID, occ wearing TED stockings. 

A/P: Encourage H2O intake. Needs TED stockings. Continue fludrocortisone 0.1 mg/d, may need to decrease midodrine.

Renal insufficiency

Patient has a h/o DM and CRI. Baseline Cr ranges from 2-3, but went as low as 1.4 in the hospital with hydration. Est CrCl around 28. Ulytes c/w renal disease. Nephrologist Dr. Nesmith. He tries he drinks 6 8 oz glasses of water qd but sometimes doesn't drink as much as that. 

A/P: Encourage hydration, IVF + mucomyst o/n pre cath.



Active Medications



lovastatin 40 mg po qd

Ecotrin 1 qd

omeprazole 20mg po qd

Colace 100mg PO BID

free text medications insulin 75/25 SC 22 u qam, 26 u qsupper

Proamatine 5 po qd

Ultram 37.5 mg po bid prn

fludrocortisone 0.1 mg po qd 2 tabs po qd

Celexa 40mg po qd

Atrovent nasal spray 1-2 spray NAS QD

Buspar 10 mg po qd

vitamin d 800 iu po qd

calcium carbonate 1250mg po tid

Fosamax 70mg po q Week on empty stomach with 6-8 oz. water, remain upright >30min

Miralax 17g po qd 17gm (1tbsp qd prn) as directed

aspirin 325 mg po qd

One touch strips As directed<br />#100<br />RF 6

Syringes B-D ultra fine pen ndl 29gX1/2 use as directed #100   ref:5

Nonmedical therapy One touch test stips (qty 100, RF 5) - 01/02/42



Advance directives   Full code



Review of systems   Negative unless noted above.



Physical examination

Temperature 98.7  

Pulse 80  

Blood pressure 160/80  lying

Respiratory rate 12  

Foot exam   decreased sensation B feet.

General appearance   Tall, thin male, NAD.

Skin   Chronic venous stasis change B shins, skin discoloration, psoriasis.

Heent   NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, O/P clear without erythema or exudates. No evidence of jaw click or pain with jaw motion on exam.

Neck   JVP 7cm; carotids brisk, 2+ bilaterally without bruits, no goiter.

Chest   CTA B w/o c/w/r.

Abdomen   NT/ND, no HSM. Normal bowel sounds.

Rectal exam   Guiac neg in the EW.

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, edema. Not wearing TEDS.

Musc skel   Glenoid cyst L shoulder. B hands c interosseus muscle wasting. C/o joint pain B wrists and PIPs, L shoulder and L MCPs. Sens grossly intact B hand. Decreased stength 2/2 pain B hands, R =L. Nl strength B UE, slightly limited by pain.

Neuro   A&O x3, CN 2-12 grossly intact. Reflexes 2+ and symmetric x 4 extremities. Toes B downgoing. Gait WNL, but requires cane 2/2 lh. Neuropathy B feet.



Assessment and plan   1. CAD: NSTEMI, on ASA, heparin, statin. 2b3a to start, cath pending in AM. Would recheck fasting cholesterol and change to lipitor 80 qd for maximal risk factor management. Be VERY CAUTIOUS in use of BB, ACE with orthostatic hypotension (he has supine HTN but is extremely orthostatic when he stands up).

- cards consult appreciated

- bedrest x 24h

- increase BB; hold ACE with pending cath.

- pls repeat TTE as per cards

- fasting chol pending; inc lipitor to 80 qd.



2. BP: orthostatic hypotension/supine hypertension

- d/c midodrine, florinef

- BP control with BB (he will NOT be able to go home on this), IV TNG + nitropaste as needed.



3. CRI: DM + chronic prerenal. Continue hydration with IVF o/n.

- mucomyst, hold ACE.



4. DM: on  Insulin 75/25, 28 qA, 26qP. Continue QID FS, adjust as needed. Pls resend HbA1c and get a nutrition consult. I am concerned that he is on too much regular insulin causing his nightsweats and his low glc at FCH yesterday. He may need to change back to NPH and regular (was difficult in the past 2/2 poor vision and arthritis).



5. constipation: pls increase bowel regimen (currently on miralax + colace).



6. PT consult please. He will likely need rehab.



Thanks for the excellent care! I will continue to follow with you.



Lauren Lopes

93756



Selected recent labs   chem 7: 140/4.0/107/25.7/32/1.9/101 -> cr 1.6. 

c/m/p: 9.9/3.6/1.8

CBC: 9.1> 33.4< 187; PTT 75 on heparin

CK peak 1172 -> 917

Trop T 2.11

7/48 chol: 214/65/128



EKG 3/19: NSR. HR 73. TWI V3-V6, TWI 2, 3, F.

CXR: neg



Signed electronically by   Lauren  Lopes MD  on  Mar 19, 2149     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>