<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2083-11-17

NORTHWEST IOWA HEALTH CENTER		        Date:	November 17, 2083

RACINE, MAINE				Name:	Quiana Justus

                                                NIHC #:	981-40-48

PROGRESS NOTE					DOB:		







Quiana is a 72-year-old woman who comes in for follow-up of her hypertension.  Please see her current medication list.  She also has a history of diabetes.  



Over the past few weeks to one month she has been having intermittent right shoulder pain.  It is worse with lifting.  The pain is in her deltoid muscle and radiates a little bit across her upper back.  It is worse if she actually lies on her shoulder at night.  There is no history of trauma, no neck pain, no upper extremity numbness or weakness except for occasional left thumb numbness.  The thumb numbness resolves if she shakes her hand.



She is also having bilateral knee pain when she walks.  There is no swelling or effusion or heat in her knees.  She had been on Vioxx for her spinal stenosis but stopped it because it was not helping her spinal stenosis pain.  Instead for her shoulder pain she has been taking Advil 200 mg 2 and up to 6 per day. She takes the Advil with food or milk and is not having any GI upset from it.  



She is having a lot of stresses with her husband, whom she feels may have some early memory problems.  His mini-mental status on his last exam was a 30/40.  However, he makes, according to her, arbitrary decisions, does not complete projects he starts, and not as task-oriented as he used to be.  He does not complete tasks or shopping errands that she would like him to do.  We discussed that he should make a follow-up appointment to see me to repeat his mini-mental status exam, but that some of these problems are not likely to be easily resolvable, and that she might benefit from finding ways to manage her anxiety and stress level.  She does get very anxious and upset at times.  She had been considering taking Ativan p.r.n. when she gets very upset and frustrated.  She is also having stressors with her grandson, who lives next door and has a problem with substance abuse and questionable money issues.  



She denies chest pain, PND, orthopnea, or edema.  She is on her diabetes medication.  She likes going to work because that gets her out of the house.



ON EXAMINATION:  She is a pleasant, animated woman in no acute distress.  Her blood pressure initially was 160/80.  After discussing her situation with her husband, her blood pressure was 180/85.  Neck supple without JVD or bruits.  Lungs are clear without rales or rhonchi.  Cardiac exam shows a regular rate and rhythm and normal S1, S2 without S3, S4, or murmurs.  She has no peripheral edema.

 

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



(1)	Hypertension, poor control.  Will increase her Zestril to 40 mg p.o. q.d.  Her daughter, Iyanna Field who is a registered nurse, will continue to monitor her blood pressure.  

(2)	Right shoulder pain.  On exam she has good range of motion of her shoulder and her muscle strength and reflexes are intact.  She can continue the Advil p.r.n. but should take it with antacids or something to protect her stomach.  



(3)	Adult-onset diabetes.  We will check her Hemoglobin A1c.  



She will follow up for her complete physical in May.  





Ida Xayachack, M.D.



IX/delarosa/austin







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-05-11




NAME:    Justus, Quiana
MRN:       9814048

Quiana is a 73-year-old woman with hypertension, diabetes and spinal stenosis who
comes in for a physical.  She has spinal stenosis as documented by her prior MRI's. 
She can usually walk about 5 minutes and then develops pain in her thighs and
calves.  She has some knee pain with walking, but it is not consistent and does not
occur after short 5-minute distances.  The thigh and calf pain resolve with rest.  She
does not always have back pain with the thigh and calf pain.  She also has occasional
right lateral foot pain that feels like an achy arthritic pain in her foot.  She takes
Vioxx occasionally for that foot pain.  She does not have any dysesthesias or
numbness in her feet or hands.  She has no recent trauma, fevers or chills.  She has
no change in her bowel or bladder.

She has type 2 diabetes.  She has been taking Glyburide 5 mg p.o. q.d.  Her weight is
stable.  She does get annual ophthalmology evaluations.  

She has a history of hypertension. She has not had any chest pain, PND, orthopnea,
dyspnea on exertion or edema.  Her blood pressure is never well controlled when she
comes for her visits here, but her daughter, Iyanna Field, a nurse takes her
blood pressure at home and she reports that it is typically 120/70.  She is currently on
Propranolol LA 160 2 tabs p.o. q.d., Dyazide 1 tab p.o. q.d., Captopril 50 mg t.i.d.

She has a history of hyperlipidemia.  She was intolerant of Lipitor in the past.  She
has been taking the Lopid 600 mg p.o. b.i.d. without complications.  She does not do
regular breast self-exams but has not noted any masses.  She is status-post
menopause.  We discussed DEXA bone density scanning, but she did not want to do
it at this time.

We also discussed colon cancer screening.  For now she elects to do stool guaiacs x 3. 
She has not had any nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, melena or hematochezia, abdominal
pain or weight loss.    

Please see her complete medication update in the LMR. 

SOCIAL HISTORY: She is married.  She drinks occasional but not excessive alcohol. 
She does not smoke.  There is no history of domestic abuse.

FAMILY HISTORY: Please see family history update in the LMR.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Negative.

She has not had a recent tetanus shot.

PHYSICAL EXAM: She is a very pleasant woman in no acute distress. Her blood
pressure here is 150/90.  Her neck is supple without JVD or bruits.  Lungs are clear
without wheezes, rales or rhonchi.  Her breasts are without masses or adenopathy. 
Her cardiac exam shows a regular rate and rhythm, normal S1, S2 without S3, S4 or
murmur.  Abdomen is soft, nontender without hepatosplenomegaly.  She is
moderately obese.  Her rectal exam is without masses.  She has no spinal tenderness
on palpation.  Her lower extremity strength is 5/5.  She does not have any peripheral
edema.  Her distal pulses are 2+.  Her sensation is intact to light touch in her feet.  

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  

(1)  Back pain with calf and thigh pain with walking.  This is probably due to her
     spinal stenosis.  However, she is at risk for claudication given her diabetes,
     hypertension and hyperlipidemia.  We will check lower extremity noninvasive
     arterial studies to rule out claudication.  She can take the Vioxx p.r.n. for her
     foot pain which I do not think is related.

(2)  Type 2 diabetes.  She needs a hemoglobin A1c.  Her blood pressure ideally
     should be under 130/85.  She reports that it is consistently below that level
     when her daughter checks it.  She needs as chem-7.  She has no evidence for
     neuropathy at this time.

(3)  Health maintenance.  She needs a tetanus shot which she was given today. 
     Will check stool guaiacs x 3.  

We discussed calcium supplementation for osteoporosis prevention.  She will follow
up in six months and p.r.n.  She has not had a recent tetanus shot. She was given a
tetanus shot in the left deltoid without complications.


Ida Xayachack, M.D.

IX/delarosa/bishop




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-09-11







NAME:    Justus, Quiana

MRN:     9814048



The patient comes in today for follow up of several medical problems. She has a

history of type 2 diabetes. Her sugars have not been optimally controlled. They are

usually in the 190-200 range in the morning. Her weight is stable. She has no lower

extremity numbness or weakness.  



She has a history of hyperlipidemia. She stopped her Lescol 2 weeks ago because it

was expensive. She also never increased the dose above 20 mg. She has had side

effects with atorvastatin and pravastatin in the past. Please see her allergy list in

LMR.



She has a half sister who had colon cancer at age 88. Quiana has had rare

occasional blood streaking when she wipes herself after being constipated. She is

aware of what a colonoscopy is but absolutely refuses a colonoscopy. She is aware

that she is at increased risk for colon cancer given her family history. She has no

nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, melena or weight loss.



She has chronic lower back pain and bilateral leg pain that is probably due to spinal

stenosis. She has lower back pain and pain in her legs that is worse with walking. It

helps when she uses a carriage to walk around in the store. She denies lower

extremity numbness, change in her bowel or bladder, fevers or chills. Her last MRI

was done in Walsenburg in a wide body machine and was consistent with spinal stenosis. 

She has taken Ultram. She is aware that Vioxx may increase people's risk for cardiac

disease and has stopped taking it. Dr. Yeager, her rheumatologist, referred her to Dr.

North in Internal Medicine for possible injections. 



PHYSICAL EXAM: No acute distress. Her blood pressure is 180/90. However, her

daughter,Iyanna Field, checks her blood pressure at home and it is very well controlled. 

The patient gets very anxious here in the clinic. Neck supple without JVD or bruits.

Lungs clear without wheezes, rales or rhonchi. Cardiac: Rate regularly regular,

normal S1, S2 without S3, S4 or murmurs. No C/C/E. Distal pulses intact.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



(1)  Type 2 diabetes. Check hemoglobin A1c. Continue current medications.



(2)  Hyperlipidemia. She should be on medication to keep her LDL below 100. She

     said that she would resume the medication.



(3)  Hypertension which is never well controlled on her visits here. Her daughter is

     a nursing professional and does report that her blood pressure is very well controlled

     in the 120/80 range when she checks at home. We will continue her current

     regimen.



(4)  Lower back pain. Probably secondary to spinal stenosis. She has an

     appointment with Dr. North.





    

 





Ida Xayachack, M.D.



IX/delarosa/bishop





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-03-19



CCU Admission Note
Patient Name: Justus, Quiana
MR# 9814048
Location: Internal Medicine
PCP: Xayachack, Ida, M.D.
Date of Admission: 3/18/91
CC: STEMI


HPI: 
79 yo lady with DM, HTN, HL who presented with new onset chest pain and shortness of breath and was found to have lateral STEMI. It began last Sunday, when she noticed the new onset of back pain, which progressed and was associated with shortness of breath by Monday. She apparently called EMS on Tuesday then and en route she had a long run of VT, which responded to 50mg of Lidocaine IV. She was intubated on arrival in the ED for progressive respiratory distress. ECG showed lateral ST elevations and a CT scan of her chest was negative for any signs of aortic dissection. Of note, she was also noticed to have elevated blood sugars in the 500s in the ED with an AG of 20, that came down to 16. 


On immediate LHC, a 100% occlusion of her OM1 was found and recannalized as well as stented with a Vision BMS, resulting in TIMI 2 flow. Her LAD was found to be patent but and her RCA showed diffuse atherosclerosis up to 60% stenosis at most. LV ventriculogram showed inferior hypokinesis with moderate MR.  An IABP was placed with her initial augmented diastolic pressures recorded in the 80s, which led to the initiation of Levophed, Dobutamine and Dopamine.


A PAC was placed in the cath lab as well with her initial Wedge reported as 19-20,  PAPs in the 50s.


On transfer to the CCU, she was intubated, sedated, being on IV Levophed at 20/hr, Dobutamine at 200/hr and Dopamine at 300/hr. Her CO was recorded as 6.0, her CI 3.5 with an initial SVR of 1012. Her Temp. was 96.1, HR 115 bpm, augmented diastolic BP of 124, which subsequently ranged between 70 and 100 on the day of her admission. She spiked a temperature up to 101 on the evening of admission after she received a dose of Levaquin IV in the setting of a rising WBC up to 40K. Vasopressin was added IV, which provided further support of her MAP. Intermittent NS fluid boluses helped to bring her HR down per RN and supported her MAPs with her PAD ranging between 18-24 and a urine output between 30 and 100 cc/hr. When her CI dropped to 1.9 around 9.30 pm with an increased SVR of 1550, the cardiac fellow was called and the decision was made to wean her Levophed as tolerated, which was then brought down to 16/hr with her Dopamine having been weaned off and continued Dobutamine and Vasopressin. The patient was also maintained on Reopro and Heparin IV for her STEMI.


PMHx:
Hypertension
DM type 2
Hyperlipidemia
Iron deficiency anemia with pt refusing colonoscopy for several months
DJD of hands - involving PIP's, DIP's, 1st CMC's.  
Spinal Stenosis L3-4
Bilateral carpal tunnel syndrome - s/p bilateral releases in spring 2090.
Cataracts
Hyperparathyroidism
Thyroid nodule - benign, biopsied 2089.


Allergies:          
Atorvastatin - myalgias
Pravastatin &#8211; myalgias


Medications prior to Admission:
Atenolol 100 MG PO QD
Ativan 0.5 MG PO TID
ASA 81 MG PO QD 
Colace 100 MG PO qd 
Glyburide 5MG PO BID
Ibuprofen 800 MG PO TID
K-dur 10 MEQ PO QD
Lasix 20 MG PO qd
Lescol 20 MG PO QHS
Lisinopril 40 MG PO QD
Metformin 1000 MG PO BID
Norvasc 10MG PO QD
Ultram 50 MG PO BID


SH:  Lives in Racine. She is married. She lives with her husband. They often argue with each other but there is no history of domestic violence. Retired credit manager.
FH:  Sister s/p thyroid surgery. No h/o RA, SLE, psoriasis.
ROS:   As noted in HPI.


Exam:    VS: T=96.1  HR=115 SR  Augment. DBP= 124   MAP=86  RR=12   SaO2=92-100% on FiO2 0.5
General:  elderly Caucasian woman, intubated, sedated 
HEENT: PERRL, OGT in place with dark output on low vacuum to wall suction
Neck:    Supple, full ROM, no LAD , no central line in the neck region (PAC via R groin) 
Chest: CTA b/l from anterior, no wheezing, crackles, or ronchi
CVS:      RRR nl S1 S2, no m/r/g, CVP 9-14, IABP in place, running at 1:1
Abd:      soft, nontender, nl BS, no rebound, IABP via right groin
Extr:     trace edema b/l, 2+ DP pulses present b/l, warm and well perfused
Neuro:  sedated, not moving spontanously
Skin:      no rashes, jaundice or cyanosis


DATA:
Lytes on admission were normal except hyponatremia, metabolic acidosis, Bicarb of 15.9, which remained around 16 on the day of her admission. 
Mg was 1.2 only, which was repleted with 4g of Mg IV.
Initial glucose above 500, which came down to 200s
Lactic acid was 6.4 on admission, which came down to 4.8 at 1pm.
LFTs were only slightly abnormal with normal bilirubins.
Initial WBC 22, which increased to 40 and then returned to 28. Hct dropped from 40 down to 29 on day of admission over 24 hours. Plts were normal and stable. 
Coags normal except elevated PTT in setting of IV Heparin.
                                03/18/91                 03/18/91                 03/18/91                 03/18/91                 03/18/91  
                                20:25    13:26    11:08     11:06     07:05     
NT-BNP                                                                                 3161(HT)                                                          
CK        4877(H)                  5811(H)                                                  4268(H)                  382(H)                              
CK-MB                  348.0(H)                 393.7(H)                                                 30.4(H)                   
CKMBRI                7.1(H)    6.8(H)                                                                                                   
TROP-T                25.56(H)                18.01(H)                                               13.89(H)                0.66(H)                  


Fasting lipids:
CHOL                     195(T)                                                              
TRIG      155(H)                                                                              
HDL       31(L)                                                                 
LDL       133(T)                                                                                                                              


Initial ABG was 7.12/39/61, which gradually improved up to 7.37/32/110 in the evening of her admission.


CXR:
Bilateral somewhat symmetric perihilar airspace opacities both lungs.  This could be edema or pneumonia. No large pleural effusions or pneumothoraces. Interval placement of the due left lower lobe monitor line below. Endotracheal tube and 4.6 cm.  NG tube to stomach.


CT Chest/Abdomen/Pelvis &#8211; AD protocol:
No evidence of aortic dissection, narrowed SMA at its origin. Bilateral consolidation in the dependent portions of the upper and lower lobes, consistent with aspiration and/or pneumonia. Interlobular septal thickening and small bilateral pleural effusions, consistent with pulmonary edema. Indeterminate hypodense lesion in the body of the pancreas. Differential considerations include a cyst and IPMN. Bilateral renal hypodensities, the largest of which are consistent with simple cysts. Heterogeneous thyroid gland, with areas of hypodensity.
 
Bedside TTE: no evidence of papillary muscle rupture, moderate MR present


EKG in ED at 6.32AM: NSR, STE in I, II, aVF, V5, V6
EKG in ED at 7.31AM: RAD, VT, STE in I, aVL, V5,V6
EKG on CCU Admission: NSR at 113 , RBBB, left posterior fascicular block, 3-4 mm STE in V4-V6, 2-3 mm in II,III, AvF
Repeat EKG 9 hours after CCU Admission: NSR at 99 , RBBB, left posterior fascicular block, 3-4 mm STE in V4-V6, II,III, AvF resolving.


Impression:
79 yo lady with DM, HTN, HL who presented with lateral STEMI with occluded OM1, s/p BM stent and is now in cardiogenic and septic shock.


Plan: 
1.        CV Pump: cardiogenic shock: continue vasopressor and inotrope support with Dobutamine, Levophed, Vasopressin, goal to wean Levophed to reduce afterload and increase CI, continue to give fluid boluses intermittently as she appeared preload dependent possibly due to RV involvement, MAP goal above 65, goal to keep CI above 2.2, f/u urine output with goal to keep above 25, trending lactic acid
2.        CV Ischemia: STEMI, cont. ASA, Plavix, Heparin, Reopro, holding BB and ACE in setting of hypotension, will check HbA1c
3.        CV Rhythm: currently NSR, on Tele
4.        Septic shock: aspiration event vs. possibly CAP, no evidence of other infectious source, covering empirically with Vancomycin/Levaquin IV given absence of recent hospitalization over the past 90 days, checking C.diff, will have low threshold to broaden coverage further if necessary
5.        HTN: currently hypotensive, holding BP meds
6.        DM: holding Metformin, RISS
7.        FEN: NPO for now with NGT on continous suctioning
8.        Prophylaxis: Heparin IV, PPI IV bid
9.        Code Status: Full Code 
10.   Dispo: pending resolution of acute medical issues
____________________________________
Xai-Micah Church, MD  -  Pager #73615
Junior resident, Department of Internal Medicine



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-07-24



Visit Note


Patient Name: JUSTUS, QUIANA                       MRN: 9814048
Dictated Date: 07/27/2091                      Dictated By: Ida Xayachack, M.D.


Date of Visit: 07/24/2091




The patient is a 79-year-old woman with a history of diabetes, hypertension, coronary artery disease who comes in today for followup. Please see the recent note from cardiology from 06/27/2091. She is status post stenting in 03/2091 and 06/2091. Post her second procedure she also had a large hematoma which has been gradually resolving. 


She has type 2 diabetes and her fasting sugars have been very well controlled. She is currently on metformin 1000 mg b.i.d. and glyburide 5 mg b.i.d. She is trying to watch her diet and salt intake. She has not had any symptoms of hypoglycemia. She had lost some weight after her first heart attack but her weight has been stable. 


Her lisinopril was recently increased by cardiology. She has no exertional chest pain, PND, orthopnea, edema, or claudication. 


She has a history of iron deficiency anemia and had refused colonoscopies in the past. At the time of her heart attack she had been intubated and had some coffee grounds noted and also required a blood transfusion. She has not noted any epigastric pain, abdominal pain, melena, or hematochezia. She does take her iron supplements and her stools are dark on the iron supplements. I had discussed with patient and daughter several times that she should get a colonoscopy to evaluate her guaiac iron deficiency anemia but she continues to refuse one. 


Also noted on her admissions was that she had a lung nodule and possible pancreatic mass on CT from 03/2091 and 06/2091. She should get a repeat CT in 12/2091. 


She is not having any abdominal pain. 


She has chronic back pain and osteoarthritis pain. Of note she also had elevated parathyroid levels in the past but refuses to see Endocrinology either in Fayetteville or at United Methodist Behavioral Hospital. 


Please see her medication list which was reviewed with the patient and her daughter. 


PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: She is in no acute distress. Blood pressure 132/70. Neck: Supple without JVD or bruits. Lungs: Clear without wheezes, rales, or rhonchi. Cardiac: Rate regularly regular, normal S1 and S2. No S3, S4 or bruits. Abdomen: Mildly obese, soft, nontender. She still has some residual hematoma near her right groin. She has a left femoral artery bruit. The hematoma has significantly decreased in size compared to prior visit. No CCE. Distal pulses intact. 


1. Coronary artery disease. She has no symptoms of decompensated heart failure on her current regimen. Her blood pressure is well controlled with the recent increase in the lisinopril from 20 to 40 mg daily. Check Chem-7. 


Hypomagnesemia. Check followup magnesium level. 


Type 2 diabetes. Her last hemoglobin A1c was 6.1 which is excellent. Continue current medications. 
Iron deficiency anemia. She should have a colonoscopy +/- an upper endoscopy but she declines these procedures. She is aware that we have not ruled out colon cancer or adenomatous colonic polyps or other cause for her iron deficiency anemia. Check CBC. 


History of lung nodule and possible pancreatic mass versus IPMN. These were both stable on imaging from 03/2091 and 06/2091. She needs repeat imaging in 6 months. She will follow up with me in 10/2091 so we can get a flu shot and schedule these procedures. 




___________________________
Ida Xayachack, M.D.






cc:






TD: 07/28/2091 04:38:30
TR: 7999590
BackJob ID:  411287
VoiceJob ID:  17480048








****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>