<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2095-02-16

EDVISIT^75659490^ROOT, PERCY^02/16/95^CARR, RACHEL

The patient was seen in conjunction with resident, Dr. Anderson.

 PA's note was reviewed.  The patient was seen and examined by

me.  Please see the PA's note for details of the patient's past

medical, social, family history, review of systems, and physical

exam.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Rash on legs.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  A 79-year-old man brought in by his

family complaining of a pruritic rash on his bilateral ankles and

today, both ankles are slightly more swollen than usual.  He has

no difficulty breathing, no chest pain.  The patient used to live

in England 4 days ago, arrived in Frankenmuth to live now

permanently with his family here.  He has a history of "heart

problems for which he is taking Lasix, enalapril, and amlodipine

and is compliant with these medications.  He says initially his

legs were not swollen.  It was only today that the family

happened to notice as he was complaining of a rash that he had

slightly increased swelling of these ankles bilaterally.  The

patient's daughter reports that she bought him new long underwear

and noticed that the rash began where the underwear elastic band

hit his ankles in that similar distribution, there is pruritus

with evidence of excoriation.  He also does have evidence of

chronic venous stasis changes in his legs.  The leg swelling is

equal bilaterally does not extend to the calf and is minimal. 

The patient reports that he coughs when he is out in the cold

Frankenmuth air, but does not produce any sputum.  Has baseline

orthopnea and PND of 3 pillows which has not changed.  He has had

no worsening shortness of breath and no chest pain.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for hypertension, TIA.  He has

no history of DVT.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  No significant surgical procedures.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a past smoker, does not drink or use

drugs.  Lives with his family.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative.

ALLERGIES:  Has no allergies.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is awake, alert, in no distress,

afebrile.  Normal and stable vital signs, saturating 96-97% on

room air.  His exam is unremarkable except for excoriation to the

bilateral ankles with chronic venous stasis changes bilaterally

and trace 1-2+ edema bilaterally equal and the ankles only down

to the mid foot.  He has strong and equal, 2+ dorsalis pedis

pulses in the feet.  The rest of his examination is unremarkable

with clear lungs and breath sounds.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient said has no plans to

get a doctor in America.  He filled out an application

for Frankenmuth Care on arrival to the Emergency Department.  I spoke

with him and his family at length about the need to immediately

get a primary care doctor.  He was given the numbers for the

Tobey Hospital and Heritage Residence.  He has about 3 weeks of his

medications left and he is told that he will need to see ____. 

The family understands the urgency of this situation.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Today is dermatitis.  He is told to continue

his medications as prescribed to elevate the feet to decrease the

swelling.

DISPOSITION:  Discharged in satisfactory condition to follow up

with the primary care physician.

______________________________

CARR, RACHEL M.D.

D: 02/17/95

T: 02/17/95

Dictated By: CARR, RACHEL

eScription document:2-8880418 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-05-15

EDVISIT^75659490^ROOT, PERCY^05/15/95^JUSTUS, ELLIS

I saw this patient with Dr. Queen Pickett.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient. 

Please see the resident's note for further details.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Syncopal event.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 70-year-old male

with a history of atrial fibrillation for which he is on

Coumadin, congestive heart failure, coronary artery disease,

hypertension, and prior transient ischemic attack, who had a

syncopal episode yesterday.  As per report, the patient felt

lightheaded and passed out while he was shaving.  The patient

passed out while using in the bathroom.  The patient was actually

caught by son before he actually hit the floor.  The patient did

not strike his head.  There was no loss of consciousness.  The

patient then awoke once he was supine.  The patient later felt

normal.  The patient states that he did have some antecedent

diaphoresis and shortness of breath and possible chest

palpitations.  The patient states that he felt like something was

jumping inside his body.  The patient does complain of some

fatigue and malaise.  The patient denies having any lower

extremity swelling or pain.  The patient denies having any chest

pain at this time.  The patient did have an adenosine MIBI in

March 2095, which showed some areas of reversible ischemia over

the distribution of the left circumflex artery.  The patient's

transthoracic echocardiogram from March 2095 did show some LVH as

well as for an ejection fraction of 50% with some global

hypokinesis.  The patient was seen by his primary care physician,

specifically, Dr. Ross.  The patient was instructed to come to

the Emergency Department for further evaluation and admission.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient's vital signs revealed the

following:  The patient's temperature was 99 degrees Fahrenheit. 

Heart rate 63 beats per minute, respiratory rate 18 breaths per

minute, blood pressure is 151/18, and oxygen saturation was

interpreted as normal.  General:  Mild-to-moderate discomfort

noted, daughter at bedside, pleasant.  HEENT:  The patient's head

is normocephalic and atraumatic, no scalp hematomas.  Mucous

membranes were somewhat dry.  Posterior oropharynx was clear. 

Neck:  Supple, no JVD.  Respiratory:  Clear to auscultation

bilaterally.  No focal rhonchi, rales, or wheezes. 

Cardiovascular:  Irregularly irregular, distant heart sounds, no

definite murmurs, rubs, or gallops were appreciated.  GI: 

Abdomen:  Soft, no rebound or guarding, no focal tenderness to

palpation, no palpable pulsatile mass appreciated.  Rectal exam

deferred.  GU exam deferred.  Skin:  Warm and dry, no rash or

lesions were noted.  Back:  No costovertebral angle tenderness. 

There was no presacral edema.  Extremities:  Warm and well

perfused, trace lower extremity edema noted, no asymmetrical

lower extremity edema.  There were no palpable cords.  Neuro: 

The patient was alert and oriented x3, motor, strength, and

sensation were all grossly intact.  The patient's cranial nerves

are grossly intact.  I did not ambulate the patient.

INITIAL IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  The patient is a 70-year-old male

with a history of coronary artery disease, congestive heart

failure, prior transient ischemic attack, and atrial fibrillation

for which he is on Coumadin, who presents with a syncopal

episode.  The patient was sent in to the Emergency Department for

further evaluation and workup for this syncopal event. 

Differential diagnosis at this time includes a syncopal event

secondary to dehydration versus arrhythmia.  I do not feel that

the patient had a cerebrovascular accident.  The patient will

need to have screening laboratory studies and formal imaging.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Upon arrival to the Emergency

Department, the patient had history and physical exam performed. 

The patient then had a 12-lead EKG performed.  The patient's

12-lead EKG was consistent with atrial fibrillation with some

T-wave flattening noted.  There were no definite acute ischemic

changes appreciated.  The patient had laboratory studies sent. 

The patient's laboratory studies were notable for a creatinine of

1.69.  The patient does have a history of renal insufficiency. 

The patient's cardiac markers were negative.  The patient's BNP

was elevated at 1380.  The patient's complete blood count was

normal.  The patient's coagulation studies were normal patient's

coagulation studies were notable for an INR of 2.2.  The patient

then had a noncontrast head CT scan performed.  The patient's

noncontrast head CT scan results are still pending at this time. 

The patient also had a 2-view chest x-ray ordered.  The patient's

chest x-ray results are also still pending at this time.  Dr.

Ross kindly and promptly saw the patient here in the Emergency

Department.  He was in agreement with admitting the patient to

Internal Medicine at this time.  The patient will be admitted

to a monitor bed.  The patient will need to rule out for possible

acute coronary syndrome or cardiac ischemia.  The patient will

need further monitoring for possible arrhythmia.  The patient was

in agreement with this plan for admission at this time.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSES:

1.  Syncopal event, possibly secondary to an arrhythmia.

2.  Atrial fibrillation.

3.  Renal insufficiency.

DISPOSITION:  The patient was admitted to Internal Medicine

and to a monitor bed.

CONDITION AT THE TIME OF DISPOSITION:  Stable and satisfactory.

______________________________

JUSTUS, ELLIS M.D.

D: 05/15/95

T: 05/15/95

Dictated By: JUSTUS, ELLIS

eScription document:4-4238782 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-06-27

Problem List 
1) CAD
         -Cath: 5/95:  LAD (Proximal), Discrete Discrete 70% lesion; LAD (Mid), Discrete Discrete 80% lesion              DIAG1 (Proximal), Discrete Discrete 95% lesion Left Circumflex Artery CX (Mid), Discrete Discrete 95% lesion              MARG1 (Ostial), Discrete Discrete 95% lesion. Right Coronary Artery  Discrete Discrete 95% lesion       -s/p CABG6/95  
 SVG-OM, SVG to ramus, LIMa to LAD 
2) Sick sinus syndrom
         -s/p PPM 5/95
3) CHF
      -EF 45% prior to surgery
      .
       
Dear Dr. Regan: 


I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Percy Root in the Cardiovascular Clinic at the Shady Brook Hospital today.  As you know, he is a 70-year-old man who is s/p CABG in May of this year. Today he is doing well folloing his surgery . 



His past medical history is significant for a coronary artery disease, status post IMI,afib,  CABG, PPM,  hypertension, hyperlipidemia, question of an old stroke.  His current medications include aspirin 81 mg, amlodipine 5 mg, lisinorpill 40 mg, Toprol-XL 10 mg, Prilosec 20 mg, Zocor 40 mg, Hydralazine.Coumadin as directed.


Allergies:  No known drug allergies.


He lives in Claxton with his wife, daughter, and grandkids and son-in-law.  He does not drink, smoke or use IV drugs.  He is originally from England.  


Family History:  noncontributory.


On physical examination, his heart rate was 60 and regular,  his blood pressure was 125/70.  Carotids are 2+, good upstrokes, no bruits.  Jugular venous pressure was flat.  Lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally.  He had a regular rate and rhythm with a 2/6 systolic ejection murmur at the right upper sternal border.  Abdomen was benign.  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema of the extremities. Good peripheral pulses.





In summary, this is a 70-year-old man with coronary artery disease,  At this time he is NYHA II. Hre appears a bit volume overloaded. I will add ACE and lasix. Follow up in 1 month. 




____________________________________
Xavier Ross, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-12-21






December 21, 2095



 Attending Note


I performed a history and neurological examination of the patient and discussed his management with the resident.  I reviewed the resident's note and agree with his documented findings and plan of care.


The patient is a 71 year old man with HTN, DM and high cholesterol, PPM on coumadin for AF, glaucoma, who presented 4 w/a with R facial droop and dysarthria lasting &lt; 1 minute.  Was admitted for TIA w/u and CT scan was negative.  CTA was also normal.  He had had a similar episode in the UK in the past. Was started on a statin and ASA and discharged.  His wife feels he may not be that compliant but his INR was 2.3 today.  It had been 2 when he came in with the TIA&gt;


The exam today showed:
Acuity was 20/70 OD and Hand motions OS.
Left APD
Fundi with large C/D OD and diffuse pallor OS with an opticociliary shunt vessel along the nasal disc.
Right facial weakness in the sense of eyebrow drop and less wrinkles in the forehead but smile equal.  Was not in UMN fashion.
Motor, sensory, gait otherwise normal.


Assessment:  
Status post TIA possibly related to AF

Left optic neuropathy with signs of chronic compression or ischemia.  The latter is more likely cause (especially since I did not see any mass lesion compressing the L optic nerve on the CT) and is proably secondary to glaucoma.


Plan:
Reviewed coumadin food rules with him.
Continue 
ASA and coumadin and statin
Continued HTN and DM control
Will touch base with ophthalmology regarding the left optic neuropathy

Return in 6 months.




Sincerely,




Victor Meadows, M.D.
Shady Brook Hospital
Neurology

745-456-4769
vmeadows@sbhnc.org
  





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>