<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2098-08-18



Jensen Clinic

745 Greenfield Drive



75 y.o. here infection on arm. Two days ago injured forearm on sharp corner of counter. Thin flap of skin lifted up. Self treated with irrigation and comporession. Noted redness last night and today. No fever or chills.



Medications

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81MG, PO QD

Albuterol Inhaler 2 PUFF INH QID PRN shortness of breath

Premarin (CONJUGATED Estrogens) 0.3MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QOD

K-dur (KCL Slow Rel.) 10MEQ, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

LISINOPRIL 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Synthroid (LEVOTHYROXINE Sodium) 25MCG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Celexa (CITALOPRAM) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 





Allergies

Halothane Gas - Unknown : liver 





Social Hx

widowed '91, lives alone, tob 1 ppd x 35,  began @ 11, quit 10/94!, etoh none, no exercise, hobbies: none, TV, friends



ROS: no polyuria/polydipsia



Exam

T 97, well appearing, nontoxic

pleasant affect, oriented x 3, cooperative

Chest: cta, spine nontender

CV: rrr, nl s1 s2

Ext: no c/c/e. R arm with lipoma, no change in size, 2+ distal pulses

derm: shallow ulcer L foream, curvilinear shape, 3sx1 shallow ulcer, surrounding erythema 5x 4 cm diameter, no red streaks, no lad





Data

tsh wnl Oct '96

ldl 75, glucose 113 mg/dl Oct 2097

tsh qns to run '97



Assessment/Plan

1. cellulitis s/p abrasion. No foreign bodies. Treat with Keflex 500 qid x 7 days. rtc < 1 wk to reassess.

Td booster given today as patient cannot recall last booster. Believes it is more than 5 years, maybe longer ago than '91 which is the estimate in the chart.



2. HTN:  Tolerating lisinopril 20mg po qd.



3. hypothyroid: stable dose. recheck TSH



4. obesity: reviewed options to cut calories, increase exercise





_______________________________________

Eric A. Morgan, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2100-04-27

 

HAWTHORNE STATE HOSPITAL

REDDING, LOUISIANA



GI CONSULT NOTE

4/28/2100



Patient name: Oreilly, Gabrielle

MRN: 9868572

Consult Attending: Matthew Vieira



Reason for consult: BRBPR, some black stool



HPI: The patient is a 76 year old female on chronic aspirin therapy, with distant history of PUD admit with three days of BRBPR.  Passed moderate volume of BRB into bowl, with some loose black stool at the bottom.  No tarry stool, mostly red.  Started to take peptobismol and from then on passed mostly red blood with some dark stool.  Two episodes each day since then.  Felt lightheaded the first day, none since.  Overall, feels weak, but not ill.  No abdominal pain or even significant cramping.  No epigastric discomfort.  No nausea, vomiting, fevers, chills.  No unusual ingestions or sick contacts.  Currently feels well, hungry.



Takes aspirin daily, baby.  In past occasionally took NSAIDs for leg pain, none recently.  History of non-bleeding gastric ulcers - three on imaging study - presented with excess gas, managed medically.  Colonoscopy seven years ago with two small polyps, one retrieved, path below, not adenomas.  No rectal bleeding since.  Does have hemorrhoids.  



Appetite good, weight stable.  No FH of GI malignancy.



PMH:

Gastric ulcer : 2060's, no recurrence

PFT's mild obstructive disease

Hypertension

Peripheral neuropathy

Hypothyroidism s/p surgery for goiter



MEDS:

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81MG TABLET PO QD 

Albuterol INHALER 2 PUFF INH QID PRN shortness of breath 

Premarin (CONJUGATED ESTROGENS) 0.3MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QOD , Take one tablet every other 

Celexa (CITALOPRAM) 40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Flonase (FLUTICASONE NASAL SPRAY) 1-2 SPRAY NAS QD , taper to lowest effective dose

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Synthroid (LEVOTHYROXINE SODIUM) 25MCG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

K-dur (KCL SLOW REL.) 10MEQ TABLET CR take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take as directed 

Lisinopril 30MG TABLET PO QD , this replaces prior dose 



ALL: Halothane Gas - Hepatoxicity : liver 

SH: Lives alone, adult children, widowed.  No regular ETOH

FH: no FH GI malignancy



PE:

VS: 98, afebrile ever since admission, 68   145/69, 94% RA

Gen: appears well, but fatigued

Heent: anicteric, OP clear

Chest: CTA B

Cor: RRR nl s1 s2, no mu

Abd: soft, NT, ND, nl BS.  Medium sized umbilical hernia, nontender, reducible.  RUQ scar

Rectal: hemorrhoids, red tinged liquid stool s/p prep



LABS:

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            

04/27/2100        138            4.5            107            26.6                    



Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            

04/27/2100        40 (H)         1.1            127 (H)        

04/27/2100        38 (H)         1.0            147 (H)        



Date/Time         CA             PHOS           MG             TBILI          

04/27/2100        9.1            2.8            1.9            0.5                     



Date/Time         DBILI          TP             ALB            GLOB           

04/27/2100        0.2            7.2            3.9            3.3                       



Date/Time         AMY            LIPS           

04/27/2100        32             3.7            



Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          

04/27/2100        19             23             48             0.5                       



Date/Time         DBILI          

04/27/2100        0.2    



Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            

04/28/2100        15.3 (H)       2.90 (L)       9.2 (L)        27.7 (L)       

04/28/2100        17.5 (H)       2.90 (L)       9.4 (L)        27.9 (L)       

04/27/2100        18.9 (H)       3.34 (L)       10.5 (L)       32.2 (L)       

04/27/2100        11.8 (H)       3.31 (L)       10.6 (L)       31.4 (L)       

04/27/2100        11.7 (H)       3.42 (L)       10.8 (L)       32.5 (L)  



Date/Time         HCT                  

03/29/2095        43.1             



Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            

04/28/2100        96             31.8           33.2           282                     



Date/Time         RDW            

04/28/2100        13.7                     

        

Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            

04/27/2100        95             31.9           33.6           292                       



Date/Time         RDW            

04/27/2100        14.1                  



Date/Time         PT             PTT            

04/27/2100        13.7 (H)       22.7           



Date/Time         HPYAB          

04/05/2094        POSITIVE [1]   

08/05/2092        POSITIVE [2]   



COLONOSCOPY -  3/31/93 10:00:00 AM

              One sessile polyp with no bleeding was found in the

              transverse colon.  The polyp was three mm in size.

              Polypectomy was performed with a cold snare.  Resection

              was complete.  Retrieval was not done.

              One sessile polyp with no bleeding was found in the

              transverse colon.  The polyp was three mm in size.

              Polypectomy was performed with a cold snare.  Resection

              was complete.  Retrieval was complete.

              Hemorrhoids with no bleeding were found.

              A few diverticula were found in the sigmoid colon and in the

              hepatic flexure.

Impression:   1) Single polyp - three mm.  Complete removal was accomplished.

              3) Hemorrhoids.

              4) Diverticulosis.



     COLON (TRANSVERSE), POLYPECTOMY:

         LOCALIZED AREA OF MILD ACUTE INFLAMMATION WITH CRYPTITIS,

         DYSTROPHIC GOBLET CELLS IN CRYPTS, AND RARE METAPLASTIC PANETH

         CELLS.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:

76 year old female with three days of painless BRBPR, also reports of black stool, history of PUD.  Source of bleeding not clear.  Pattern most typical of LGIB, likely diverticular with significant decline in hematocrit, painless, moderate volume BRBPR.  Agree no real pain for ischemic colitis, though wbc elevated.  No fevers, chills, other GI symptoms or exposure for infectious colitis.  Given black stools, aspirin use, history of PUD, upper bleed also possible, though presentation with red blood and hemodynamic stability atypical for this.  Given insecurity in type of bleed, agree with both EGD and colonoscopy.  



EGD and colonoscopy this morning

Hold aspirin

Continue QD PPI

If hematocrit drops further, would transfuse 1-2 units to hct of 28-30



Whitney Short, MD

GI Fellow

Page 67094











                   



















      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2101-06-04



			CARDIOLOGY

			

			HAWTHORNE STATE HOSPITAL

			



Dear Dr.  Morgan:



  Thank you very much for your referral of Gabrielle Oreilly for evaluation of coronary artery disease and a right coronary artery aneurysm as documented on CT scanning.  She is a 77-year-old woman with longstanding history of tobacco use of greater than 100-pack years quitting approximately eight years ago. She suffers from hypertension, hyperlipidemia, glucose intolerance, and what appears to be a recent diagnosis of COPD. She has always been very limited in her activity suffering from back pain, and has never been in any type of regular exercise routine. She recently has noticed dyspnea on exertion over the past two to three months and has been treated with several prednisone tapers as well as an albuterol nebulizer at home and an albuterol inhaler. With these treatments, her dyspnea improved, but would worsen as the steroids were tapered.  She does report some episodes of chest heaviness, which she describes as a heavy feeling in her chest, which will last for minutes at a time. These are not exertionally related and are occurring approximately once per week. She was placed on Nexium with some improvement, but does feel as if she will still develop these episodes. 



To further evaluate her symptoms of persistent cough and shortness of breath, she underwent a CT scan to evaluate for pulmonary embolus. This was performed on 05/20/2101 and did not show any evidence of PE, however, there was coronary artery calcification with plaque noted in the left main coronary artery. There was a focal 9 mm aneurysm of the right coronary artery. She was then referred to me for further evaluation.



			Past medical history:

   Hypertension. 

Hyperlipidemia. 

Glucose intolerance. 

Left bundle branch block. 

Diverticular bleed. 

Gastroesophageal reflux disease. 

Hypothyroidism. 

COPD.



Current Medications:

 prednisone taper

hydrochlorothiazide 50 mg qd

potassium chloride 10 mEq qd

lisinopril 30 mg qd

aspirin 81 mg qd

calcium supplement 600 mg qd

levothyroxine 25 mcg qd

Lipitor 10 mg qd

Celexa 40 mg qd

albuterol inhaler; Dir: and nebulizer

multivitamins



Allergies:

			

Allergy   She reports receiving Halothane gas remotely with the development of jaundice at the time of her hysterectomy.

Drug allergy   Halothane gas, which caused hepatitis per her report.



			Family history:

   Notable for her father with myocardial infarction at 54.  Mother with "an enlarged heart," who died at 82.



			Social history:

   She quit smoking eight years ago, previously smoked two packs per day for 35 years.  She lives alone but her daughter lives above her in the same building.



			Review of systems:

   She denies any significant change in weight.  She has intermittent headaches relieved with Advil.  She reports chronic cough and wheeze, which has been improved on prednisone.  She has shortness of breath with exertion but denies exertional chest pain.  No lower extremity edema, palpitations, or dizzy spells.  She reports her reflux symptoms are improved on her Nexium.  She has no history of stroke, no history of anemia.  She reports her sugars have been diet controlled.  Otherwise extended review of systems was negative.



Physical examination:

			

-Pulse:   70

-BP: 142/70  

-General:   She is an elderly woman in no distress and comfortable at rest

-Skin:   Free of rashes

-Heent:   benign

-Neck:   JVP was at 5.  She had 2+ carotids without bruits

-Chest:   Lungs are clear without significant wheeze

-Cardiac:   Regular, S1 and S2 without murmurs

-Abdomen:   Soft with a nontender reducible ventral hernia

-Extremities:   She had no edema in her extremities with 2+ distal pulses

-Neuro:   She is alert and oriented

-weight:   185 pounds



			EKG:

    demonstrated sinus rhythm at 70 with a left bundle branch block.



			Assessment and plan:

   Gabrielle Oreilly has multiple risk factors for coronary disease including hypertension, hyperlipidemia, a positive family history, and heavy tobacco use in the past. She presently has had recurrent bouts of a COPD flare, which has been responsive to prednisone and albuterol nebulizer therapy. Her chest CT scan demonstrates plaque in the left main coronary artery as well as a right coronary artery aneurysm. I do believe she needs further evaluation first by functional study, and I will arrange an adenosine stress test and consider cardiac catheterization to further define her anatomy with her multiple high-risk features and abnormalities as seen on her recent CT scan. She will continue a slow taper with possible addition of other inhalers to control her COPD.



Plan: 

1. Adenosine MIBI to evaluate for ischemia in distributions of the left system as well as the RCA aneurismal segment. 

2. Treatment of her emphysema as per your office. 

3. I will see her again in follow up in one month and consider cardiac catheterization for further evaluation. 

4. I have instructed her to proceed to the emergency room with the development of any significant chest pain or progressive shortness of breath.



Changes to Medications this visit

			

prednisone     taper

hydrochlorothiazide 50 mg   qd

potassium chloride 10 mEq   qd

lisinopril 30 mg   qd

aspirin 81 mg   qd

calcium supplement 600 mg   qd

levothyroxine 25 mcg   qd

Lipitor 10 mg   qd

Celexa 40 mg   qd

albuterol inhaler     and nebulizer

multivitamins    

potassium supplement 10 mEq   qd

Albuterol Nebulizer    



It is a pleasure to share in her care and I will continue to keep you updated. 



Sincerely,

			

			

			

Wendy Tapia M.D.



			Signed electronically by   Wendy  Tapia M.D.  on  Jun 17, 2101     

		



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2102-01-07

 Oreilly, Gabrielle  #9868572

Pulmonary Consult by Dr. Trujillo for management of PE

I have seen and examined the patient and agree with the history including HPI, PMHx, Meds, All, Family Hx, ROS; Pexam, labs, studies, assessment and plan as per Dr. Chavez.

Briefly, 78 YO female with recent hip fracture in 8/01 (not surgically repaired) who did well until 3 days PTA when she developed sudden onset CP, non-productive cough and was noted to have RA sat of 89%.  In ED, patient was hemodynamically stable.  CTPE protocol bilateral PE   s in both main PA   s and clot in LLE DV system.  Patient was started on UF heparin.  

PMHx notable for NSTEMI, diffuse CAD, left pleural mass followed by Fidious, COPD, HTN, hyperlipidemia, took coumadin after surgery 30 years ago 

Meds include:  Advair, Lipitor, HCTZ, heparin

Smoked 50 pk-years, quit 8 years ago.

Family hx notable for:  Son passed away in    01 with blood clots.

Pexam:
Sats 94% on 4L, T 98, P 78, BP 186/86 R 20
Gen Comfortable.
O/P Clear
Heart RRR no m/g/r
Lungs decreased BS throughout
Ext:  Superficial varicosities, minimal bilateral edema

Labs notable for:  WBC 15
Trop 0.22
Ntbnp 500

CT scan     multiple large central PE   s and bilateral upper and lower arteries; +emphysema; clot in left popliteal and distal and superficial femoral veins.

ECHO     EF 60%, mod TR RA dilation, RVSP>=54; RV hypokinetic, PFO with R   shunting   (increased RVSP, RA size since last ECHO)

Impression:

Large bilateral PE, hemodynamically stable
Evidence of RV strain, elevated cardiac enzymes, BNP which when combined put patient in risk group for increased mortality
Persistent DVT
PFO with right to left shunt
COPD

Recs:

Recommend retrievable IVC filter.  Rationale is that the patient has persistent clot in LE   s and has a PFO with right to left shunt and is at risk for CVA (though filter will not prevent small clots from embolizing) and that +cardiac enzymes, BNP, and ECHO place patient in risk group for increased mortality.
Do not recommend lytics in that patient is hemodynamically stable and risks for hemorrhage outweigh potential benefits in our opinion.
Can change to low molecular weight heparin.
Hypercoag w/u
Start spiriva, albuterol for COPD



Thanks for allowing us to participate in the care of this patient,




______________________
Earnest Vanwinkle, pager 90009



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>