<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2087-02-21

                     DAMERON EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

VALENZUELA,BRIAN   036-89-96-4                     VISIT DATE: 02/21/87

The patient was seen by me in the emergency department on 02/21/87 

with the resident.  The resident's notes were reviewed and the 

patient interviewed was examined by me.  The patient's complete 

history is limited by change in mental status and multiple 

sclerosis.  The patient was transferred from an Ellijay home.

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Nausea and vomiting.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 49-year-old with 

nausea and vomiting for the past 24 hours, rigid abdomen and no 

bowel sounds.  He has had some feculent emesis over the last day.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  No fevers or chills, no bright red blood per 

rectum or melena but did have liquid stool earlier today.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, multiple sclerosis and anemia. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  The patient is awake.  LUNGS:  

Scattered rhonchi, otherwise clear.  HEART:  Regular rate and 

rhythm.  ABDOMEN:  Distended with absent bowel sounds, nontender.  

NEUROLOGICAL:  Nonfocal.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Remarkable for a glucose of 100, BUN 13, 

creatinine 0.6, sodium 141, potassium 3.9, chloride 108, bicarb 25, 

lipase 144, calcium 9.4.  White count 10.4, hematocrit 41, platelet 

count 250.  KUB reviewed by me shows distended small bowel and 

large bowel consistent with a large bowel obstruction versus an 

ileus.  

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  A nasogastric tube was placed. 

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Surgery.  

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Large bowel obstruction.  

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 

be admitted.  Surgery was consulted.  The patient was admitted in 

stable condition. 

___________________________________                    GJ089/08607 

HAROLD OSBORNE, M.D.       HO97                         D:02/21/87 

                                                       T:02/21/87 

Dictated by:  HAROLD OSBORNE, M.D.       HO97 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-08-03

                     DAMERON EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

VALENZUELA,BRIAN   036-89-96-4

The patient was seen by the resident, seen and examined by me.  I 

have taken the history and reviewed the medical record as well as 

the vital signs, medication and allergy list as well as the past 

medical history.   

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Fever of unknown cause with mental status 

change.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 51-year-old man with a 

history of multiple sclerosis, initially diagnosed in 2063 and also 

a history of hypertension, history of anemia and has sacral 

decubitus that has been debrided in the past who was transferred to 

the emergency department today from a nursing facility.  The 

patient is bedridden for the last few years and today the nursing 

home personnel noted confusion and the patient had a fever.  The 

nursing personnel at the nursing home also, after speaking with 

them states that he has chronic abdominal distention at baseline. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Positive for fevers and chills.  Negative for 

abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, chest pain or palpitations.  The 

patient also has no urinary symptoms.  He also denies a cough, 

denies neck stiffness and denies a headache.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  The patient wears a condom cath at baseline.

MEDICATIONS:  Baclofen, atenolol, Lactulose and Lasix as well as 

vitamin E.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Here his temperature is 101.8. 

He is tachycardic with a pulse rate of 112, respiratory rate 24 but 

he is maintaining a normal blood pressure of 131/79.  His oxygen 

saturation is also 99%.  GENERAL:  He is awake and alert, in no 

distress.  He is communicative but some times difficult to 

understand.  He is oriented x2.  He is somewhat dysarthric.  His 

dysarthria is at his baseline according to nursing personnel.  

HEENT:  Otherwise normal.  He has no evidence of an ear infection.  

His oropharyngeal examination is normal.  He has no 

lymphadenopathy.  NECK:  Supple and nontender.  There is no 

cervical adenopathy.  No signs of meningitis.  Full range of 

motion.  Normal flexion and extension.  LUNGS:  Clear.  No rhonchi 

heard.  No wheezes or rales heard.  Good air movement bilaterally.  

CARDIAC:  Tachycardic but no murmurs or rubs appreciated.  No 

friction rub.  The patient is well perfused.  Pulses are normal 

throughout.  Good capillary refill.  SKIN:  Warm to the touch 

indicating good perfusion.  Warm and dry.  No lesions seen.  He has 

a right gluteal ulcer but is healing.  ABDOMEN:  Somewhat distended 

and mildly tympanitic but no tenderness, no guarding, rebound or 

masses.  No liver edge palpated.  No spleen edge palpated and no 

evidence of a hernia.  Bowel sounds are normal.  Again, it is soft 

and nontender. GENITOURINARY:  He has a condom cath.  Cloudy urine 

in the Foley.  MUSCULOSKELETAL:  Normal examination.  He is 

somewhat contracted in his lower extremities but for the most part, 

no evidence of ulceration and no pedal edema.  There is no evidence 

of trauma.  NEUROLOGICAL:  Grossly intact.  Oriented x2 with some 

dysarthria at baseline.  RECTAL:  Heme negative with good rectal 

tone.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Chest x-ray was done which showed no 

evidence of an infection, no evidence of a pneumonia.  Because of 

his abdominal distention, a KUB was done but there was no evidence 

of air fluid levels and no evidence of intestinal obstruction.  He 

had a lot of gas but otherwise normal.  There was also no evidence 

of constipation.  Electrocardiogram showed a sinus rhythm with some 

nonspecific ST and T-wave changes.  Old electrocardiogram was 

compared with new one and there was no significant change.  His 

white count was 14,000 with a hematocrit of 36.  His electrolytes, 

BUN and creatinine as well as blood sugar was normal.  Amylase and 

lipase, also normal.  Liver function tests, normal.  Urinalysis 

showed too numerous to count white cells and also has bacteria.    

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Management in the emergency 

department consisted of IV fluids.  Blood cultures and urine 

cultures were sent.  The patient was immediately started on 

intravenous antibiotics, was given Tylenol, placed on oxygen and 

was being hydrated.  Again, a urine culture was sent as well as 

blood cultures.  A 51-year-old man with a history of multiple 

sclerosis, bedridden, also has a history of hypertension who has 

been experiencing fever, chills, tachycardia, tachypnea and mental 

status change over the last twenty-four hours at his nursing home 

who presents now with urosepsis.  Cultures done, antibiotics given, 

IV fluids given, Tylenol given.  Vital signs are normalizing.

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Medical.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Urosepsis. 

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 

going to be admitted to the medical service.  The patient is 

admitted to the medical service in stable condition.  Primary care 

physician is aware.

___________________________________                    VI752/79442 

KEITH TOLLIVER, M.D.       KT40                           D:08/05/88 

                                                       T:08/05/88 

Dictated by:  KEITH TOLLIVER, M.D.       KT40 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-10-15

EDVISIT^03689964^VALENZUELA, BRIAN^10/15/92^BENSON, KAILEE

I saw this patient in conjunction with Dr. Otis. I confirm

that I have interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the

resident's documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed

the evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  A 55-year-old male with vomiting.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient with end-stage multiple

sclerosis as well as neurogenic bladder and chronic indwelling

Foley who presents from the nursing home after 4 episodes of

vomiting since 10:00 a.m.  He has had also progressive abdominal

distention, he reports over the last 3-4 weeks.  Nursing note

also reports decreased urine output for the last 2 days.  He had

a KUB done at the referring facility that demonstrated a question

of a small bowel obstruction but this film was not sent with him.

 He also had a fever today per report.  The patient denies any

abdominal pain, shortness of breath, chest pain, or other

complaints.  He does have a history of an ileus and prior

admissions for urosepsis with levofloxacin resistant E. coli.  He

reports a mild cough.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Remarkable for hypertension, multiple

sclerosis, anemia, decubitus ulcers, neurogenic bladder, and

urethral strictures.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  He is status post urethral stenting.

Social history, family history, and review of systems are as per

written note.

MEDICATIONS:  Prozac, Actonel, ferrous sulfate, aspirin,

multivitamins, lisinopril, Lipitor, and Prilosec.

ALLERGIES:  None.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is awake and alert, generally

chronically ill appearing, quite pleasant.  Vital signs are

within normal limits as documented except for an elevated pulse

rate of 120 beats per minute, respiratory rate of 24, room air

saturations of 93% and a temperature of 99.2.  For full physical

exam findings, please see the resident's written note. 

Specifically, HEENT exam is atraumatic.  There is a 1-cm ulcer on

roof of his mouth.  He has synechiae of his pupils that are 2 mm

and nonreactive.  His extraocular movements are not alignment. 

Neck exam is normal as documented.  Respiratory exam reveals

scattered bronchi.  There is no chest wall tenderness. 

Cardiovascular exam reveals tachycardia without murmur. 

Abdominal exam is distinctly distended and slightly firm with

hypoactive bowel sounds but no tenderness, no rebound or

guarding.  Skin is intact, warm, and dry on my exam. 

Musculoskeletal exam is nontender with no edema or bony point

tenderness.  Neurologically, the patient has increased tone in

his lower extremities and weakness of all of his extremities. 

His mood and affect is normal but he is dysarthric.  He is

neurologically, however, appears to be at his baseline.

LABORATORY DATA:  CBC and electrolytes remarkable for white blood

count 16.2, BUN and creatinine ratio of 40 and 1.0 respectively. 

Last creatinine was 0.5.  LFTs and lipase are within normal

limits as documented.  INR is 1.1.

IMAGING STUDIES:  EKG demonstrates sinus rhythm with nonspecific

ST-T wave changes.  Plain films of the abdomen demonstrates

scattered dilated loops of small bowel but no clear obstruction

consistent with possible ileus versus early obstruction.  Chest

x-ray shows low lung volumes without any focal consolidation.

IMPRESSION:  This is a patient with abdominal distention, is

quite impressive as well as a firm belly with dilated loops of

bowel on his KUB as well as history of vomiting earlier this

evening.  He has had no vomiting here and does not feel

nauseated, however, does not have an appetite.  He has had

decreased urine output and managed to put out a total 25 cc of

urine through his Foley since 2:00 p.m. today.  Presently, he was

not tender over his bladder.  Upon flushing the Foley, there is a

large amount of debris.  They came out and followed by high

pressure urine that had malodorous character to it.  I think this

patient likely has an ileus and urinary tract infection.  He

received antibiotics wide spectrum including vancomycin,

levofloxacin and Flagyl initially followed by gentamicin given

his prior levofloxacin resistance.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Urinary tract infection.

SECONDARY DIAGNOSIS:  Ileus versus SBO.

The patient was admitted to the ED Observation Area for CT

imaging, however will eventually require admission for this

problem likely to Medicine Service.

DISPOSITION:  Admitted to ED Observation Unit.

______________________________

BENSON, KAILEE MD

D: 10/15/92

T: 10/15/92

Dictated By: BENSON, KAILEE

eScription document:7-8396761 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-08-09

EDVISIT^03689964^VALENZUELA, BRIAN^08/09/93^BOYER, DAWN

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Fever.

I saw this patient with Dr. Edwards.  Please see his note for

further details.  I confirm that I have interviewed and examined

the patient, reviewed the resident's documentation, and

discussed, plan of care, and disposition with the patient. 

History is obtained through discussion with the patient who says

yes or no, as well as transporting paramedics.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 56-year-old

gentleman with end-stage MS at nursing home.  He has indwelling

Foley catheter.  He was transported from nursing home to ED as he

has had a fever today to approximately 100.5.  Per EMS, they were

told that the patient has also been more lethargic with decreased

POs today.  He received Tylenol and defervesced somewhat.  He

then received 400 mL of fluid en route and he has become more

awake and alert.  He is telling the paramedics that he is at his

baseline.  He denies to me any headaches, neck pain.  No chest

pain, shortness of breath, no abdominal pain, no cough, no fevers

or chills.  He reports that he is able to discern when he has

abdominal pain.  He has intact sensation.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As per HPI.  In addition, CAD, diabetes,

hypertension, CHF.

Please see resident note for list of medication and allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He does not smoke.  He does not drink.  He is at

a nursing home.  He is married.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per resident note and my HPI.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is awake, alert, and nontoxic, in no

distress.  Afebrile, pulse in 90s, respiratory 18, blood pressure

102/66, O2 saturation 99% on room air.  HEENT exam: 

Normocephalic and atraumatic.  Neck:  Supple.  He has coarse

upper airway sounds bilaterally anteriorly.  Heart is regular

rate and rhythm.  His abdomen is slightly distended.  He is

nontender.  He has sacral decubitus ulcers that are well healing,

no evidence of acute infection, contractures in his lower

extremities.  He is alert and does say yes or no to questions.

The most likely etiology in this patient for an infection is his

urinary tract infection.  His urine and his catheter was cloudy. 

Prior to sending the urine for evaluation for urinalysis to the

lab, the patient had his catheter changed.  He then began to no

longer drain urine.  Accordingly, a bladder probe was put on

using ultrasound and clearly showed a distended bladder. 

Attempts were made to change the catheter, but they were

unsuccessful.  There was pus found at the meatus.  At this point,

the patient is awaiting a CT scan of his abdomen and urology

evaluation.  He is also receiving antibiotics for presumed UTI

and/or abscess.

LABORATORY DATA:  Include sodium 136, K 4.5, chloride 102,

bicarbonate 22, BUN 22, creatinine 0.45, and glucose 136.  LFTs

within normal limits.  Normal lipase.  White count of 5.7,

hematocrit 35.5, and platelet count 306,000.  Coags within normal

limits.  UA again is pending at this time.

He will be admitted to the hospital.  I attempted to reach the

patient's primary care physician, Dr. Earle to contact from the

WBM office, however, my calls went unanswered.  At this point, I

am signing out the patient and he is awaiting his CT scan and

urology evaluation.

DIAGNOSIS:  Urinary infection, mild dehydration, end-stage MS.

CONDITION:  Stable.

DISPOSITION:  Will be admitted.

______________________________

BOYER, DAWN MD

D: 08/09/93

T: 08/10/93

Dictated By: BOYER, DAWN

eScription document:6-1950972 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-10-23

Patient: VALENZUELA,BRIAN   03689964Date of Admission: 10/23/2094
Attending: Davila


Internal Medicine Intern Admit Note


CC: fever, lethargy, confusion


HPI: 57M who lives in NH and has h/o severe MS-partially verbal at baseline, bedridden- recurrent UTIs and urosepsis with chronic indwelling foley, HTN, CAD,and CHF (EF 35-40%) who presents from NH with confusion, lethargy, and fever to 102.  Per patient's daughter, he becomes lethargic and confused whenever he has fevers.  Patient was doing well at NH until day prior to admission when he became lethargic.  The day of admission he had fever and was confused so daughter brought him to ED.  ED vitals notable for T101.8, HR 140s, BP 110/80s, 98% RA.  WBC notable for 13.3.  Patient was given tylenol, 1LNS, Blood and urine cultures were sent.  Pt given IV vanc and ceftriaxone.  Per daughter patient's foley is supposed to be changed every 15 days at NH, but she does not believe that it has been changed.  Last documented changed at the WBM was 12/93 by urology.  Patient is able to nod and answer questions although he is difficult to understand.  He is cooperative and responds to commands.  Pt reports feeling fatigued, lethargic x 2 days, but denies fevers, chills, chest pain, SOB, dysuria, suprapublic pain, n/v/diarrhea, or CVA tenderness.


PMHX: 
severe/end-stage MS
DM
atonic colon 

with history of constipation
neurogenic bladder with chronic indwelling foley
chronic urethral strictures and bladder calculi (including staghorn calculi)
CAD s/p STEMI in 2091 in setting of sepsis/pressors
CHF (EF 35-40%)
recurrent UTIs and urosepsis
decubitus ulcers
ulcers toes/heels
chronic sinus tachycardia 



Medications: (from NH)
Acetaminophen (tylenol) 1000mg PO Q6H prn headache
Acetylsalicylic Acid 81mg PO QD
Albuterol Neb 1.25MG INH Q6H prn Wheezing
Alendronate (Fosamax) 70mg PO Qweek on Wednesdays
Artificial Tears
Ascorbic Acid (vit C) 500mg PO BID
Baclofen 10mg PO TID
Bisacodyl Rectal 10 MG PR QOD prn Constipation
Docusate Sodium 100mg PO BID
Caltrate 500 (calcitrate) 2 tab PO TID
Insulin Aspart Sliding Scale SC AC
Lacri-Lube Ointment 1 Appl OU QHS
Latulose 15mL PO QD prn constipation
Metformin 500mg PO BID
Metroprol 25mg PO BID
Naphazoline 0.012% Ophthalmic Solution 1 drop OD BID prn redness drainage
Omeprazole 20mg PO QD
Sennosides 2 TAB PO BID
Simethicone 80 mg PO BID
Simvastatin 80mg PO QD
Therapeutic MV 5 ML PO BID
Tolteroidine Tartrate Long Acting 4mg PO QHS


Allergies
NKA 




Studies:
10/22/94 CXR PA view: Single frontal portable upright radiograph of the chest     is reviewed with comparison made to prior PA and lateral study     dated December 03, 2093. Lungs are clear without focal     consolidation. Lung volumes are low. Cardiomediastinal silhouette     is stable. There is no pleural effusion or pneumothorax.
LABS: 10/22/94:
NA 155 (*#),  K 4.3,  CL 118 (*),  CO2 27,  BUN 48 (*#),  CRE 0.53 (*#),  EGFR 160,  GLU 164 (*) 
ANION 10
CA 9.3,  PHOS 2.6,  MG 3.2 (*#),  TBILI 0.3,  TP 8.1 (*),  ALB 3.3 (*),  GLOB 4.8 (*),  LACT 1.6
bPO2 72,  bPCO2 38,  bPH 7.46 (*),  UBASEX 2,  O2 Sat 96.1,  CO2-PL 27,  HGB BG 14.9,  HCT-BG 44
ALT/SGPT 11,  AST/SGOT 9,  ALKP 116,  TBILI 0.3
 WBC 13.30 (*),  RBC 5.30 (#),  HGB 13.6 (#),  HCT 43.6 (#),  MCV 82.4,  MCH 25.7 (*),  MCHC 31.2 (*),  PLT 373
RDW 15.7 (*#)
%BAND-M 1,  %POLY-M 77 (*#),  %LYMPH-M 16 (*#),  %ATYPS 0,  %MONO-M 6,  %EOS-M 0 (#),  %BASO-M 0
PLT-EST NL
PT 15.7 (*),  PT-INR 1.2 (*),  PTT 33.9
UA-COLOR LT BROWN,  UA-GLUC NEG,  UA-BILI TRACE,  UA-KET NEG,  UA-SPGR 1.010,  UA-BLD 3+ (*),  UA-PH 8.5 (*),  UA-PROT 2+ (*)
UA-UROBI NEG,  UA-NIT POS,  UA-WBC 3+ (*)
UAS-RBC 4-10 (*),  UAS-WBC &gt;200 (*),  UAS-BACT 4+,  UAS-SQHI 1+,  OCAST NEG,  HCAST 0,  UAS-CRYS 1+,  UAS-COM NEG
UA-EPIS NEG


Physical Exam:T 98.6 HR 150 BP 113/83 18-20 97% RA
Gen: pleasant elderly gentleman, trying to speak but is not understandable;
HEENT: mucous membranes dry
Neck: JVP flat
Chest: CTA anteriorly; pt was unable to roll or sit up
CV: RRR no m/r/g
Abd: + BS, soft, NT, ND, no grimace to palpation, no rebound or guarding
Extr: no edema, thin frail with multiple ulcers on big toes, small toes and R heel
SKIN: several large decub ulcers below buttocks 
Neuro: Alert &amp; Oriented x 3, CN II-XII appear intact
no focal deficits


A/P: 57M h/o severe MS who is bedridden and partially non-verban with PMHx significant for atonic bladder with indwelling foley and recurrent UTI and urosepsis who presents with urosepsis/UTI picture.  
1) UTI/urosepsis- Urology changed foley which had notable purple growth on both foley and bag, suggestive of Psuedomonas.  Patient will be double covered for Pseudomonas with ceftaz and cipro.
-follow blood cultures
-follow up urine culture
-new foley
2) decub ulcers and toe ulcers
-do not appear infected, dressings c/d/i
-vascular wound care consult
-order special bed for ulcers
-order for heels to be wrapped/padded
3) DM- d/c metformin and use ISS
4) holding antihypertensives given possibly septic
5) Continue 1/2NS to bring down hyernatremia NA 155
6) Contine pureed, netcar thick consistency with encourage PO intakes between meals
7) enoxaparan 40SC prophylaxis
8) Full code 




____________________________________
Heather T. Quinonez, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>