<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2081-06-22

                     AH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
BRANCH,EARNEST   530-23-69-1                      VISIT DATE: 06/22/81
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient was examined and 
treated in conjunction with a resident.  Briefly, the history is as 
follows:  The patient is a 47 year old male with end stage renal 
disease on hemodialysis who was referred for abdominal discomfort 
and fever.  His abdominal discomfort had begun within the preceding 
24 hours and had gradually worsened.  He had pain in the left lower 
quadrant radiating to the rectal area.  He did have one diarrheal 
bowel movement.  He specifically denied bleeding. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL APPEARANCE:  The patient was awake 
and alert, although somewhat sluggish and apparently uncomfortable. 
VITAL SIGNS:  Blood pressure was 177/90, pulse 117, initial 
temperature 103.3, respiratory rate 20.  HEENT:  Pupils were equal. 
Sclerae were anicteric.  The oropharynx showed normal architecture. 
NECK:  Supple.  CARDIOVASCULAR:  Regular rate and rhythm.  LUNGS: 
The breath sounds were essentially clear.  ABDOMEN:  There was mild 
to moderate diffuse tenderness.  No definite mass can be 
appreciated.  Bowel sounds were diminished.  RECTAL:  Stool is 
guaiac-negative, per the resident's examination.  EXTREMITIES: 
Examination of the left thigh showed slight drainage at a recent 
surgical incision site. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrolytes showed sodium 139, potassium 
4.3, chloride 99, CO2 27, BUN 12, creatinine 2.2, glucose 230. 
White blood cell count was 30,000, hematocrit 38.  Chest x-ray 
showed no definite infiltrate.  Abdominal x-ray showed dilated 
loops of small bowel.  EKG showed no change from previous tracings. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The assessment and plan were 
reviewed with the resident. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  I confirm the provisional diagnosis of abdominal 
pain with question of deep venous thrombosis versus sepsis from as 
yet unidentified source. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The care plan 
was reviewed.  The patient was started on antibiotics and 
ultimately admitted to the hospital for definitive evaluation and 
further care. 
___________________________________                    RD883/1008 
FRANK E. BENDER, M.D.  FB25                             D:07/25/81 
                                                       T:07/25/81 
Dictated by:  FRANK E. BENDER, M.D.  FB25 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-07-07

July 8, 2081
 
Francis Xayarath, M.D.
Integra Health Center
487 Jackson Street
La Grulla, ME 21614
 
RE:  Branche, Earnest
MRN: 53023691
 
Dear Dr. Xayarath:
 
Your patient Mr. Earnest
Branche returned to the
office today for a follow
up visit.  As you know,
Mr. Branche underwent a
left femoral to posterior
tibial bypass one month
ago followed by
amputation of a
gangrenous first toe.
After being discharged
from our service he was
readmitted to the Medical
Service with a severe
case of C. difficile
colitis.  Ultimately this
resolved and he was
discharged.  Today he
reports that the diarrhea
has again resumed and he
was placed back on an
oral antibiotic
yesterday.  He complains
of only mild incisional
discomfort in his left
leg.
 
On examination, there is
a strong pulse easily
palpated over the left
lower extremity bypass
graft.  The old right
lower extremity bypass
graft was also palpable.
The left foot itself is
warm.  The great toe
incision site, however,
has developed necrotic
tissue all along the
incision, which was
sharply debrided to clean
margins.  This will now
need to be treated as an
open wound.  The calf
portion of the left lower
extremity incision also
has a narrow zone of
superficial skin slough
which was gently
debrided.  The graft is
not exposed and there are
no deep wounds in the
leg.
 
Mr. Branche's left lower
extremity bypass graft is
functioning well.
However, he will require
significant ongoing wound
care for the immediate
future.  Daily dressing
changes will be arranged
with visiting nurse
services.  We plan to
follow him closely and an
appointment was given for
two weeks.
 
Thanks again for allowing
us to participate in the
care of this delightful
and challenging patient
and please don't hesitate
to contact me at any time
if I can
RE:  Branche, Earnest
MRN: 53023691
7-8-81
Page 2
 
 
 
be of further assistance.
 
Sincerely,
 
 
Luis J. Nicholas, M.D.
 
NU:UJ:4653/DD:7-8-81/DT:7-13-81/DV:7-8-81
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-01-10

                     AH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
BRANCH,EARNEST   530-23-69-1                      VISIT DATE: 01/10/82
The patient was seen by me in the emergency department with Dr. 
Whittaker.  The resident's note was reviewed and the patient was 
interviewed and examined by me. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a very pleasant, 
50 year-old gentleman who presents with gross hematemesis and 
coffee-ground emesis.  He had it during the night and then this 
morning developed coffee-grounds turned to red blood emesis.  He 
denies any light-headedness, chest pain or abdominal pain.  He has 
had some diarrhea over the last seven months, of unclear etiology. 
No melena. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Chronic renal failure, myocardial 
infarction, insulin dependent diabetes. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  The patient was hemodynamically 
stable, well-appearing, nontoxic.  LUNGS:  Clear.  HEART:  Regular 
rate and rhythm.  ABDOMEN:  Soft with tenderness to palpation in 
the bilateral lower quadrants.  NG tube lavage showed 200 cc of 
pink tinged fluid, cleared after 50 cc. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Hematocrit was 46, white count 11, 
potassium 6.6, moderately hemolyzed.  BUN was 62, creatinine 6.9. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient will be seen by the 
renal service and admitted to the medical service.  The patient 
will need dialysis and endoscopy tomorrow.  See resident's note for 
details. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Upper GI bleed. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 
admitted in satisfactory condition. 
___________________________________                    ED832/1818 
CHRISTOPHER LEMUS, M.D.       CL58                         D:01/10/82 
                                                       T:01/11/82 
Dictated by:  CHRISTOPHER LEMUS, M.D.       CL58 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-03-08

 
 
March 8, 2082
 
Francis Xayarath, M.D. 
Integra Health Center
 Derry Street
La Grulla, ME 21614
 
RE:Branch, Earnest
MRN:53023691
 
Dear Dr. Xayarath:
 
Your patient Earnest Branch came in the office today for a follow up 
visit.  Mr. Branch is now two years out from a right femoral-
tibial bypass and nine months out from a left femoral-tibial 
bypass with subsequent transmetatarsal amputation of the left foot 
and split-thickness skin grafting.  Over the last several months, 
he has been undergoing dressing changes to remaining, small, 
superficial, open wounds on the dorsum of the left foot.  Over the 
last one to two weeks, he began to note the development of a new 
area of dark skin on the lateral aspect of the left foot and 
recently has noted some drainage.  He denies any fevers.  In 
addition and of note, he complains of recent onset of pain in the 
right eye and has an appointment at the Ophthalmology Clinic 
immediately following his visit with us.  He last underwent 
vascular lab studies in September at which time both lower 
extremity bypass grafts were widely patent and without stenoses.
 
On examination today, there are strong, easily palpable pulses 
over both lower extremity bypass grafts.  The right foot is warm 
and without any new ischemic skin changes or lesions.  On 
examination of the left foot, there is a large area of full-
thickness skin necrosis on the lateral aspect of the foot where 
there had never been any previous open wounds.  This area 
encompasses a significant proportion of the lateral aspect of the 
foot from the end of the transmetatarsal incision to the proximal 
mid foot.  On probing, purulent material drains from the margins 
and there is obvious significant sepsis.  The foot itself is warm 
and there is a good posterior tibial Doppler signal at the ankle.
 
Unfortunately, Mr. Branch has developed a new, large wound on the 
left foot which likely began as a pressure (decubitus) ulceration 
due to his severe neuropathy.  This is now complicated by 
significant local sepsis and there is a large area of soft tissue 
loss on the foot.  He will require urgent admission and operative 
debridement today.  In addition, given the extent of the problem, 
it is likely that he will ultimately come to below-knee amputation 
in the end.  Immediately following his visit to the Ophthalmology 
Clinic, he will be admitted to the
 
 
RE:Branch, Earnest
MRN:53023691
3-8-82
Page 2
 
 
 
hospital with the hopes of performing debridement and drainage 
later today.  I will certainly continue to keep you apprised of 
his progress.
 
Sincerely, 
 
 
 
Luis J. Nicholas, M.D. 
 
RH:KU:0156/DD:3-8-82/DT:3-14-82 
 
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-12-31

                     AH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

BRANCH,EARNEST   530-23-69-1                      VISIT DATE: 12/31/82

This patient was seen primarily by Dr. Xavier Whittaker.  I also saw 

the patient, reviewed the resident's note, and discussed evaluation 

and plan. 

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Shortness of breath and nausea.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This 49-year-old man has been 

complaining of shortness of breath for the last 24 hours.  He came 

in complaining of that plus some nausea and was found to have a 

highly elevated glucose and was sent over here.  The patient denies 

any chest pain or pain any place else, but he does state that he 

feels poorly.  Of note, on transport and on arrival here, his blood 

sugar was noted to be greater than 600.  The patient does not 

complain of blurry vision and does not complain of 

light-headedness, just the nausea and the shortness of breath. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per the resident's note. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Cardiomyopathy.  Otherwise, as per the 

resident's note. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  As per the resident's note. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Significant findings include a pulse of 76, 

respirations 22.  The patient appears to be in no acute distress.  

The lungs display crackles bilaterally to the mid lung.  There is 

jugular venous distention elevation to the angle of the jaw.  

Cardiac examination is otherwise normal.  Abdominal examination is 

within normal limits.  The patient has a colostomy.  The patient 

has a left below-knee amputation and toe-digit-toe amputation on 

the right side.  Otherwise, there are no musculoskeletal 

abnormalities.  There are some decubitus ulcers which are stable.

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Laboratories are significant for a glucose 

of 934, sodium 127, anion gap 17, bicarb 19, creatinine and BUN 5.8 

and 37, hematocrit 30, which is not too different from his usual.  

His pH is 7.42.  CK is 54, but troponin is 1.45.  Of note, however, 

the patient does have renal conditions.  EKG shows new deep Qs in 

2, 3, and F compared to one done a month ago.  Chest x-ray shows 

some excess interstitial markings indicative of increased fluid.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  This patient appears to have 

congestive heart failure.  He may be having new cardiac event, 

although after a consultation with the Integra Health

cardiologist, he felt that perhaps this might not be a new event, 

but rather due to axis deviation.  The patient is being treated for 

his hyperglycemia and is being admitted.

FINAL DIAGNOSES:

1.  Rule out myocardial infarction.

2.  Hyperglycemia.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted to the hospital in stable condition. 

___________________________________                    ZI623/55469 

FAITH GALINDO, M.D.       FG9                         D:12/31/82 

                                                       T:12/31/82 

Dictated by:  FAITH GALINDO, M.D.       FG9 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>