<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2084-04-12

RACHAEL G. OBRYAN, M.D.
 
VALLEJO GENERAL HOSPITAL
ENDOCRINOLOGY DIVISION                        Workman, Edwin
534 Lunar Lane                           61248040
Brookshire, MO  15345                             4-12-84
 
 
Referring Physician:  Dr. Kenyon, Dr. Elmer Ure, Vallejo General 
Cardiology.  
 
Referring Diagnosis: Status post cardiac transplant. Rule out 
osteoporosis.  
 
HPI:  Patient is a 48-year-old gentleman with a history of lymphoma, 
diagnosed in 2070 when he presented with left axillary enlargement.  At 
the time, he was staged by bone marrow transplant which was negative.  
Whether this was a Hodgkin's or non-Hodgki's lymphoma is unclear to us, 
but he was treated with bleomycin, adriamycin and prednisone for 
approximately 26 weeks.  At that point, he was believed to be in 
remission and stayed in remission since then.  
 
In 2077, the patient was first diagnosed with diabetes mellitus when he 
presented with polyuria, polydipsia and blurred vision.  Subsequently he 
was treated with oral hypoglycemic agents for one to two years and since 
that time has been on insulin therapy, currently on 64 units of NPH and 
six of regular in the morning with 30 NPH and six of regular pre-supper.  
He currently checks his blood sugars four times a day and runs in the 
100-200 range with average being about 130 and is followed by Dr. Nicodemus 
Paz of Queenstown, WI, his primary care doctor, for this.  The patient's 
complications of diabetes mellitus are possibly non-existent.  There is 
no peripheral neuropathy.  There is no autonomic neuropathy.  No retinal 
disease.  However, the patient does have renal disease, with baseline 
creatinine currently of 2.4.  
 
Recently the patient developed congestive heart failure with initial 
symptoms in the early 80s.  By June of 2082, the patient had fairly 
severe symptoms requiring hospitalizations and in the period of July 
2082 to June of 2083, the patient apparently had 5 myocardial 
infarctions.  In June 2083, the patient underwent orthotopic cardiac 
transplant here at the VGH under the care of Dr. Quentin Fitzpatrick.  Since 
that time, the patient has done very well without evidence of rejection 
with relatively good exercise tolerance and with basically a minimum 
degree of symptoms.  
 
The patient's current medications include cyclosporine 150 mg. twice a 
day; prednisone 8 mg. a day.  Azathioprine 250 mg. a day; Axid 150 mg. 
twice a day; Cardizem 300 mg. a day; baby aspirin once a day; Cardura 4 
mg. once a day; and amitriptyline 25 mg. a day for cramping in his legs.  
 
Review of Systems:  Has had one fracture of his right ring finger that 
was from a trauma some years ago.  Other past medical history includes 
history of sleep apnea and depression and the things mentioned.  
 
RACHAEL G. OBRYAN, M.D.
 
VALLEJO GENERAL HOSPITAL
ENDOCRINOLOGY DIVISION                        Workman, Edwin
179 Lunar Lane                           61248040
Brookshire, MO  15345                             4-12-84
Page 2
 
 
Family History:  His sister, aged 54, and mother, have osteoporosis with 
his mother having fairly severe osteoporosis with a normal of vertebral 
collapses and some nerve damage.  His father and mother have had 
diabetes mellitus, his father dying of heart disease.  There is a 
19-year-old daughter who has a history of migraines.  There is no 
history of thyroid disease in the family.
 
Social History:  He currently works at Belkin and has a desk job 
there.  He quit smoking and drinking 15-20 years ago.  He has been 
married for over 20 years.  His review of symptoms revealed the absence 
of GI symptoms.  There were no orthostatic symptoms, no angina.  Normal 
sexual function.  He denied any skin problems or rashes.  He denied 
numbness and tingling in his feet, etc.  There is a history of 
hypertension.  
 
Other review of systems:  His height has been stable at 6'2" tall.  
 
Physical Examination:  Blood pressure 130/93.  Heart rate 96.   The 
patient is a well-appearing gentleman, somewhat obese.  His height is 
6'2".  Weight 294 lbs. which is apparently steadily been increasing.  He 
has a mild Cushingoid appearance with a little bit of posterior cervical 
and supraclavicular fat.  Retina appeared without lesions.  Normal 
extra-ocular movements.  His oral mucosa was moist without evidence of 
thrush.  Neck exam:  He had a supple neck with no carotid bruits.  
Normal thyroid.   His chest exam revealed clear lung fields with normal 
excretion.  There was no bony tenderness or abnormalities on his back.  
His cardiac exam:  He had a soft, S1, S2.  Cardiac exam otherwise 
unremarkable.  His abdomen was soft.  He had some evidence of insulin 
injections, but no significant hypertrophy.  He injects both in his 
abdomen and rotates with his arms.  His extremities revealed minimal 
stasis dermatitis, normal pulses, and were symmetric.  No edema.  
Neurologically he was diffusely hyporeflexic.  He had normal to slightly 
decreased vibratory sensation in his big toes.  
 
Laboratory Exam:  Most recent laboratories that I could find were 
February 09, 2084.  Sodium 141.  K 5.1; chloride 105.  Bicarb 20.  BUN 
39.  Creatinine 3.4; glucose 136.  His CK was 219.  Calcium 9.7.  
Albumin 4.3; phosphate 4.0.  Alkaline phosphatase was 90.  Uric acid 
5.1; magnesium 1.9.  TSH was 1.6.  Cholesterol 242.  Triglycerides 226.  
His cyclosporine level was in the therapeutic range at 273.  His CBC 
revealed a hematocrit of 43 and a white count of 8.9 thousand with a 
normal differential.  
 
Assessment and Plan:  This is a 48-year-old gentleman with a history of 
multiple medical problems.  The one's most pertinent to us currently are 
RACHAEL G. OBRYAN, M.D.
 
VALLEJO GENERAL HOSPITAL
ENDOCRINOLOGY DIVISION                        Workman, Edwin
007 Lunar Lane                           61248040
Brookshire, MO  15345                             4-12-84
Page 3
 
 
the fact that he is post-transplant, has several risk factors for 
osteoporosis, including prednisone use and a family history of 
osteoporosis.  The total amount of exposure to prednisone sounds like it 
is about a year-and-a-half or so with half a year during his 
chemotherapy 14 years ago and then about a year since his transplant.  
The patient's history of never having had fractures, no bone pain, no 
height loss and his body habitus are consistent with someone who might 
be somewhat more resistant to osteoporosis than many transplant 
patients.  However, getting a bone density study in the patient like 
this makes sense.  We will therefore schedule a spinal bone density on 
his follow up visit, since he cannot have one today for scheduling 
reasons.  We will also check vitamin D levels given patient's history of 
renal failure and the fact that the one thing that we might be able to 
do for him is to give him vitamin D.  His calcium intake was estimated 
to be about 1,000 mg. a day including one cup of milk, green leafy 
vegetables and one cup of ice cream each day.  We would be a little 
reticent about starting higher doses of calcium given his renal failure, 
without more information about this patient.  The patient's diabetes 
seems to be in pretty good repair at the moment with blood sugars under 
fairly good control, sounding like they are in the 130 range although we 
don't have access to hemoglobin A1C.  Given the fact that it sounds like 
he has got pretty good care by Dr. Paz, we will not pursue this at 
the current time unless asked, and we will focus primarily on the bone 
situation.  Otherwise, we will see the patient back or at least talk to 
RACHAEL G. OBRYAN, M.D.
 
VALLEJO GENERAL HOSPITAL
ENDOCRINOLOGY DIVISION                        Workman, Edwin
315 Lunar Lane                           61248040
Brookshire, MO  15345                             4-12-84
Page 4
 
 
the patient after we get a bone density and decide when he next needs to 
be seen.  
 
 
 
______________________________
Rachael Obryan, M.D. 
 
 
 
______________________________
Edwin Foss, M.D. 
 
cc:  Nicodemus Paz, M.D. 
     Queenstown, WI
 
     Kevin Kenyon, M.D. 
     Cardiology
     Vallejo General Hospital
     49 Pheasant Lane
     Brookshire, MO  15345 
 
     Elmer Ure, M.D. 
     Cardiology
     Vallejo General Hospital
     02 Pheasant Lane
     Brookshire, MO  15345 
 
WJ:KY:1946
DD:4-12-84
DT:4-13-84
DV:4-12-84
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-10-17

 
 
 
 
 
 
October 17, 2085
 
 
Nicodemus S. Paz, M.D.
5 Fox Meadow Road
Hebron,  WI  31155
 
RE:  Edwin Workman
     MR #612-48-04-0
 
Dear Dr. Paz:
 
I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Workman in follow-up today. 
Overall, he is doing very well from a cardiovascular perspective. 
Unfortunately, he continues to gain weight but overall he is doing
well. 
 
His current medical regimen includes cyclosporin 150 b.i.d.,
prednisone 6 mg q.d., Imuran 275 q.d., Cardizem CD 300 mg q.d.,
Cardura 4 mg q.d., one baby aspirin a day, Axid 150 b.i.d.,
pravachol 20 q.d., magnesium oxide 250 mg b.i.d., calcium and
vitamin D, insulin NPH 54 units and 10 Regular in the morning, 32
units of NPH and 8 of Regular in the evening.  
 
On physical examination, he was obese.  Blood pressure of 150/90
with a heart rate of 85, weight was 305 pounds which is increased
5 pounds from September 21st.  Chest was clear to auscultation and
percussion.  Cardiac exam reveals a flat JVP at 30 degrees, a non-
displaced PMI with a normal S1, S2 without murmurs, rubs or
gallops.  Carotids are 2+ bilaterally without bruits.  His abdomen
is obese, soft and nontender.  It is difficult to appreciate any
organomegaly.  There is no hepatojugular reflux.  Extremities are
without edema. 
 
Electrocardiogram reveals normal sinus rhythm with a rate of 85. 
Intervals of .16/.08/.34 with an axis of 60 degrees.  This is a
normal tracing unchanged from previous tracing.
 
Therefore, Mr. Workman is doing well from a cardiovascular
perspective.  We will make the necessary adjustments in his medical
regimen according to his laboratory results.  Unfortunately, he did
take his cyclosporin this morning and therefore he will mail his
labs back to us.
 
I did discuss with him attempting some weight loss with portion
control.  I think it might work to give him some reasonable goals
such as a weight loss of 30 pounds as apposed to 130.
 
Workman, Edwin
MR #612-48-04-0                    -2-            October 17, 2085
 
Mr. Workman will return in January for a biopsy and clinic visit.  
Best regards.
 
Sincerely,
 
 
 
Elmer Knott, M.D.
Vallejo General Hospital
39 Lacy Street
Brookshire,  MO  15345
 
DD: 10/17/85
DT: 10/18/85
DV: 10/17/85
 
/ingalls
 
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2086-11-09

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
November 09, 2086
 
 
 
Nicodemus Paz, M.D.
40 Harvard Street
Queenstown, WI    
 
RE:  Edwin Workman
     #612-48-04-0
 
Dear Dr. Paz:
 
I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Workman in follow-up today. 
Overall he is relatively stable from a cardiac standpoint.  Most
importantly, recently he was laid off from his job at Belkin.  He
has been quite depressed about this.  
 
His medical regimen includes Cyclosporin 150 b.i.d., prednisone 6
q.d., Imuran 275 q.d., Cardizem CD 300 q.d., Cardura 4 mg. q.d.,
Pravachol 40 mg. q.d., Axid 150 b.i.d., Calcium, vitamin C and D,
Mag. Oxide 250 q.d., Paxil 300 q.d., NPH Insulin.
 
On physical examination he was well appearing in no distress.  He
had a blood pressure of 136/80 with a heart rate of 90, weight was
309 pounds which has increased eight pounds from July.  Chest was
clear to auscultation.  Cardiac exam revealed a flat JVP at 30
degrees, non-displaced PMI with a normal S1 and S2 without murmurs,
rubs or gallops.  Carotids are 2+ bilaterally without bruits.
Abdomen was soft, nontender. There is no organomegaly, no
hepatojugular reflux. Extremities without edema.
 
Electrocardiogram reveals normal sinus rhythm with a rate of 90. 
Intervals of .16/.08/.33 with an axis of 70 degrees. This is a
normal tracing and unchanged from his previous tracing on 9/20/86.Edwin Workman
#612-48-04-0                  - 2 -          November 09, 2086
 
Therefore, Mr. Workman is stable at this time from a cardiac
perspective.  We will make the necessary adjustments in his medical
regimen according to his laboratory results.
 
Best regards.
 
Sincerely,
 
 
 
Elmer Knott, M.D.
 
/ismail
 
DD: 11/09/86
DT: 11/11/86
DV: 11/09/86
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-02-01

ADMISSION NOTE
02/01/97


HPI: 61y/o male who underwent heart transplant in 2083 and has ESRD on HD (recently started -&gt; 9 sessions so far FAT). 
He is been electively admitted from his cardiologists office w/ slightly elevated troponins peaked at 0.41, most recent 0.24.  He is CP free and stable and is being transferred for further evaluation and work up.  Last HD session on Tuesday. 


Last dobutamine echo last year showed some LV apex hypokinesis, which augments in response dobutamine. 


ECG revealed NSR at 82 w/ poor R wave progression on anterior leads. Qwave on AvL but no new TWI or ST changes. 


Echo at OSH reveiled lower EF at 30-35% with HK on anteroseptal, mid anterior, apical lateral and apical inferior walls segments. 


He reports chronic dypsnea on moderate exertion. He is quite sedentary. 


ROS: preserved appetite. 


PMH: CAD, obesity, diabetes, obstructive sleep apnea wears cpap at night, ESRD hemodialysis dependent, depression and GERD.  


His current medications include aspirin 81 mg p.o. daily, Axid 150 mg p.o. b.i.d., Cardizem CD 360 mg p.o. daily, Effexor 125 mg p.o. daily, , Lantus 120 units subcutaneously b.i.d., Lasix 60 m p.o. BID nonHD days, lexapro 10 mg p.o. daily, Lipitor 10 mg p.o. daily, cyclosporine 75 mg p.o. b.i.d.,  Toprol-XL 50 mg p.o. daily, vitamin C 500 mg p.o. b.i.d., and vitamin E 400 international units p.o. b.i.d.


All: pravastatin


SH: lives w/ wife. Ex-smoker


FH: positive for DM and CAD


PE:  96.3  130/74  16 100% 2l
NAD, JVP flat
RRR distant HS
CTA b/l
Abd obese, soft, NT, ND
L forearm AVF w/ good thrill and bruit
LE no edema


LABS
pending


IMPRESSION
61 yo M s/p heart transplant and ESRD on HD presenting with elevated troponin. The trend of his creatinine from outside hospital is not suggestive of acute coronary syndrome. Troponin leak is a common finding in patients with ESRD on hemodialysis since the hemodynamic changes lead to subendocardial ischemia during short-time ultrafiltration. On the other hand, due to the difficulty in evaluating ACS in patients that had undergone transplant, will repeat cardiac markers for the next 12 hours and meanwhile, continue medical management with ASA, statin, BB and heparin. The lower EF on outside echo could suggest as well recent past event of myocardial infarction, especially with the multiple walls demonstrating hypokinesis. 
&gt; Continue other home meds.
&gt; Check CSA level in am.
&gt; Since stable volume status, consider contacting renal in am for further decision about next HD session depending on lab results. 
&gt; Will continue lasix on nonHD days. 
&gt; Will defer further testing to primary cardiologist in am.
&gt; CPAP at night
&gt; Keep NPO after MN. 
&gt; Will check PTH, iron store, Ca/PO4 and 25 vitD. 


_________________
Henry Norris, MD
    



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>