<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2080-07-28

 

 

July 28, 2080

 

 

 

Dr. Keys

 

 

 

RE:Fair, Bill

MR#:220-41-86-4

 

Dear Dr. Keys:

 

Dr. Oates and I saw Bill Fair today with regard to his troublesome 

right knee.  As you are aware he is a 56 year old man who is a convenience store manager.  He has had a lot of trouble with his right knee over the years, 

mainly related to sports injuries.

 

He has had in particular 2 years of pain now in his right knee.  It got so 

bad 6 months ago that he required large amounts of ibuprofen to relieve that. 

 

It has slowly got better since then.  

 

At present his main problem is pain in the knee which mainly occurs with 

activity but he also has rest and night pain.  He has a restricted walking 

distance.

 

With regard to function, he is able to carry out his work with difficulty and 

requires periods of rest in the evening on returning home from work.  He has 

noticed his knee is becoming slowly more bowed.  

 

With regard to treatment he has is taking regular analgesia in the form of 

Tylenol but has recently noticed blood in his stool for which he is going to 

have a colonoscopy in the near future.  

 

He has not tried any canes and has not had any physical therapy as yet.

 

On examination I note he has bilateral varus knees, worse on the right than 

the left.  He has an antalgic gait and marked varus thrust.  

 

He has a marked effusion that does not have any gross swelling indicative of 

arthritis.  He has a 5 degree fixed flexion deformity and flexes up to 115 

degrees.  His varus deformity is not fully correctable.  He has grade 5 

quadriceps power.  

 

X-rays reveal marked degenerative changes in his right knee with complete 

obliteration of joint space on the right side.  

 

I note he also has changes in his left knee indicative of medial compartment 

arthritis but his left knee is currently asymptomatic.  

 

We have discussed the operative options for him which consist of high tibial 

osteotomy, a unicompartmental knee replacement, and a total knee replacement. 

 

At present neither he not Dr. Oates feels that his symptoms are severe 

enough to warrant operative intervention.  We would certainly reconsider 

should he run into trouble in the next few months aspirating his knee, 

instilling some corticosteroids.  We have advised him that this will only 

provide him with short term relief but may allow him enough relief to begin 

some walking and fitness in an attempt to lose some weight.

 

We have organized to see him again in 4-6 month's time at which stage we will 

reassess him.  Should he run into trouble in the meantime he cal certainly 

ring up and make an appointment to come and see us and we will aspirate the 

knee and instill some corticosteroid.  

 

With kind regards.  

 

Yours sincerely, 

 

 

 

 

_______________________________

Oliver M. Oates, M.D.

 

DD: 07/28/80

DT: 07/31/80

DV: 07/28/80

 

 

Dictated by Xavier Embry, M.D. for Oliver M. Oates, M.D. 

/OMO/vaught

RJdkyfbv

 

 

 

 

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-12-12



Internal Medicine

030 Nashua Mall Street                                      FAIR, BILL

Plymouth, IN 46368                                      22041864

-----------                                           12/12/84





ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  Elizabeth Keys, M.D.



CHIEF COMPLAINT:  diabetes management.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Fair is a 61-year-old patient with a history of diabetes diagnosed more than 20 years ago.  He has known complication of retinopathy and is status post bilateral laser surgery about one year ago.  He has no known neuropathy or nephropathy.  He has no known history of CAD, CVA or PVD.  He had previously been followed by Dr. Elizabeth Keys at Pioneer Hospital at Findlay until June of this year which time he switched to a new primary care doctor.  At that time, he had been on glyburide, metformin and Avandia, his new PCP increased his glyburide and his Avandia.  He also stopped his hydrochlorothiazide out of concern that this is not an ideal agent for a diabetic patient. Over the next weeks to months, the patient had progressive peripheral edema, fluid weight gain and ultimately development of dyspnea on exertion, orthopnea and paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.  He returned for care and was started on furosemide and has been recently titrated up to a dose of 60 mg orally on this.  He self adjusted his Avandia dose from 4 mg twice daily to 2 mg daily.  His prebreakfast blood glucose has been elevated ranging from 160-200.  He has had some resolution of his fluid overload with the Lasix and lower dose Avandia.  He says he has persistent feeling of swelling and tightness in his fingers and toes with episodic ankle swelling as well.  He denies chest pain, claudication polyuria, polydipsia.  He has been losing weight since starting Lasix.  He has never had hypoglycemia.



DIABETES SURVELLIANCE AND MANAGEMENT:

Hemoglobin A1c 11.4% (10/01/84).

Cholesterol 190, LDL cholesterol 190, HDL 49 (10/01/84) and LDL 118 (07/02/84).

Microalbumin to creatinine 19 (07/02/84).

Creatinine 0.9 (07/02/84).

Last eye exam 09/83.

Pneumovax never.

Influenza vaccine never.

Aspirin 325 mg daily.

ACE inhibitor yes (lisinopril 10 mg daily,).

Statin yes (Lipitor 40 mg daily).



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:

Diabetes as above.

Diabetic retinopathy.

Hypertension.

Osteoarthritis of the knees.

Status post hammertoe repair.

Pilonidal cyst status post I&D.

Severed Achilles tendon status post repair.

Right meniscus removal.



MEDICATIONS: Glyburide 10 mg twice daily, metformin 1000 mg twice daily and the Avandia 2 mg daily, Lipitor 40 mg daily, lisinopril 10 mg daily.  furosemide 60 mg daily, multivitamin one tablet daily and Viagra as needed.



ALLERGIES:  Amoxicillin gives him a rash.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  He works as a manager in a convenience store, he lives with his wife.  He has no kids.  He does not exercise secondary to joint pain.  He tends to eat a lot of carbohydrates and meats although he does not have a sweet tooth.  He denies tobacco, alcohol or recreational drug use.  



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As per HPI, otherwise, negative.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  His weight is 270 pounds, his blood pressure is 150/92 and then 155/92 to my a repeat exam, pulse is 70 and regular.  In general, he is a well-appearing gentleman in no acute distress.  His skin is warm and dry.  Extraocular movements are intact.  Oropharynx is clear.  Mucous membranes are moist.  He has no carotid bruits.  His thyroid is normal in size and contour.  Lung exam reveals crackles at the bases.  His heart is regular in rate and rhythm with an S1, S2, without S3 or S4.  Abdomen is obese, soft and nontender.  There is no hepatosplenomegaly.  His extremities are without clubbing or cyanosis.  There is 2+ pitting edema to the ankles.  His foot exam reveals that his distal pulses are okay.  Sensation is intact to monofilament.  There is no skin breakdown or ulcerations.  He has an extensive onychomycosis of the nails bilaterally.



Glucose 132.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  This is a 61-year-old gentleman with type II diabetes complicated by retinopathy and erectile dysfunction.  He has had inadequate glycemic control on oral agents which are currently at their maximal doses given the intolerable side effects of Avandia.  He has plans for elective knee replacement during the spring and we have advised him that before he consider that he should get his diabetes under better control, should make sure his blood pressure is controlled and should seek cardiac evaluation, especially given his history of pulmonary edema symptoms on Avandia.



1.  We will start insulin today initially NPH 25 units at bedtime to replace his evening dose of glyburide.  We have instructed him on use of the Inolet for insulin administration.  He will continue his glyburide 10 mg each morning, continue metformin 1000 mg twice daily and Avandia 2 mg each morning.  We will check hemoglobin A1c today as a baseline. We will follow up to determine appropriate titration of his insulin as well as addition of other doses during the day.

2.  His blood pressure is not optimally controlled at this time.  We will increase his lisinopril to 40 mg daily. He will continue his furosemide 60 mg daily and he will continue to titrate his Lasix dosing at the guidance of his primary care doctor.

3.  His last microalbumin to creatinine ratio and creatinine were normal.  Testing is up-to-date.

4.  The patient has an LDL that was above target this summer and Lipitor was initiated; however, he has not been on this long enough to see an effect. At his next visit, we will reevaluate his lipids to determine if his Lipitor needs titration.

5.  He is overdue for an eye exam and will contact Dr. Xuereb at Findlay him to have this done.

6.  We have made a referral to Dr. Liam Mcmahon for cardiology evaluation.  We have ordered an echocardiogram to be performed prior to this visit. We have also referred the patient to a number of possible PCPs in the OMC/CBC system. 



The patient was advised to return to the office in two months for follow up.











______________________________

Florence Mildred Yuan, MD





Dictated By: Florence Mildred Yuan





eScription document:2-8940866 EMSSten Tel







DD: 12/16/84

DT: 12/16/84

DV: 12/12/84



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-02-18


KH Cardiovascular Division
CVD RM5
75 Weymouth Dr                                      FAIR, BILL
Plymouth, IN 46368                                           22041864
(958) 688-5162                                           02/18/85


Florence Mildred Yuan, M.D.
Endocrinology/Osteopathic Medical Center
02 Weymouth Dr
Plymouth, IN  46368

Dear Dr. Yuan:

I saw your patient, Bill Fair, in the Cardiology Office today for evaluation of his coronary artery disease in anticipation of knee replacement on March 23, 2085, and thank you for having him come here for evaluation.  I will be sending a copy of this letter to
Dr. Oliver Oates as evaluation for preop assessment as well.

Mr. Fair is a 61-year-old male who has a number of risk factors for coronary artery disease but is unaware of any known prior manifestations.  He has had diabetes mellitus for about 20 years.  About two months ago, he started on insulin, and he is now followed by you at the Endocrine Group.  His most recent glucose had been in the range of 86 with his lipids including total cholesterol of 157, triglycerides 103, HDL of 42, and LDL of 94.  His current medical regimen for these and his other problems include insulin NPH 10 units in the morning, 25 units in the afternoon, glyburide 20 mg q.d., and metformin 1000 mg q.d..  He also takes Lasix 60 mg per day, lisinopril 40 mg per day, and Lipitor 10 mg q.d.

His other risk factors are notable for hypertension, which has been labile and borderline high in the past.  He is currently on the lisinopril with apparently good control of his pressure.  He has had hypercholesterolemia and is now doing well on Lipitor.  He does not smoke cigarettes, but he is obese.

He has no known history of MI, angina, or shortness of breath.

His other risk is notable for his family history, which includes his father who died at the age of 72 of an MI as well as leukemia.  His mother died at the age of 74 of mesothelioma, and he has two sisters and one brother who are well.

He had an echo performed on February 2, 2085, in anticipation of his knee surgery in March 2085, and this was notable for a mildly dilated left ventricle with mild concentric LVH.  Overall LV function is mildly-to-moderately reduced with an estimated ejection fraction of 40%.  The entire inferior and posterior walls were akinetic and thin consistent with myocardial scar.  The apical anterior wall, apical lateral wall, and left ventricular apex were hypokinetic suggestive of myocardial hibernation or scar.  The right ventricle was normal in size and function, the left atrium was mildly dilated, the aortic valve was unremarkable, the mitral valve was slightly thickened with mild-to-moderate mitral regurgitation, and the tricuspid valve was structurally normal.

His past medical history is notable for kidney stones, which he has had over the past 10 years or so.  He has had three or four attacks, the most recent one was two years ago.
He also has the severe osteoarthritis of the lower extremities predominantly affecting the knees.  Both Achilles tendons have been damaged as well apparently.  He is anticipating knee replacement with Dr. Oates on March 23, 2085.

Social history is notable for no cigarette or alcohol use.  He has a convenience store and frequently eats out of it throughout the day with poor dietary habits.

His review of systems is otherwise unremarkable.

On exam, he is obese but comfortable.  Blood pressure is 150/80, heart rate of 67 and regular, and weight of 278 pounds.  Head and neck are unremarkable.  Chest is clear.  Cardiac exam shows no jugular venous distention at 30 degrees.  PMI is normal.  S1 and S2 are normal with a physiologic split.  There is an S4 and 1/6 systolic ejection murmur at the left lower sternal border.  Abdominal exam is unremarkable without organomegaly.  The abdomen is obese.  Extremities show no edema or cyanosis.  Carotid upstrokes are normal in contour and volume without bruit.  Distal pulses are normal.

His resting 12-lead electrocardiogram demonstrates normal sinus rhythm with evidence of previous inferior MI and poor R-wave progression, V1 through V3.  He has a superior axis likely related to the inferior MI.  The QRS is increased with nonspecific intraventricular conduction delay.

Mr. Fair clearly has evidence of coronary artery disease with at least one myocardial infarction.  This had been entirely asymptomatic and was quite a shock for Mr. Fair to hear this information.  We will obtain an adenosine MIBI scan prior to his surgery to be sure we have a better idea of the status of his myocardial perfusion.  In addition, I strongly encouraged him to lose as much weight as possible.  He seems both very interested in losing weight but at the same time somewhat cavalier an overly confident that he will be able to do so.  I think the most important thing is going to be dietary management, since I doubt he will ever be able to do enough physical activity to burn sufficient calories to lose weight on that basis alone.  We will check his Chem-25 today as well as CRP, and I will review these results with him as soon as they are available.
I also asked him to check on his blood pressure at home and let me know the results.
If any problems develop in the interim, please do not hesitate to contact me.  We will hopefully be able to identify his preop risk factor status with his perfusion scan within the next week.  Thank you for allowing me to help with his care.

Kindest personal regards.





______________________________
Liam Mcmahon, MD


Dictated By: Liam Mcmahon


eScription document:6-8059879 SFFocus


CC: Oliver Oates M.D.
Osteopathic Medical Center
73 Weymouth Dr
Plymouth, IN 46368

DD: 02/18/85
DT: 02/18/85
DV: 02/18/85



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-03-21

 









21 March 2085





Liam K. Mcmahon, MD

Division of Cardiology

Osteopathic Medical Center



Re:	Bill FAIR

	OMC 220-41-86-4



Dear Dr. Mcmahon:



I had the pleasure of caring for Mr. Fair at OMC 03/20-21/05.  He is a 61-year-old man with CAD, DM, high cholesterol, HTN, and family history of early CAD, who had a stress test that showed peri-infarct ischemia in the left circumflex and PDA.  Angiography showed a codominant system, a 100 percent left circumflex occlusion, an 85 percent RC lesion, and nonobstructive LAD lesions.  The left circumflex was recanalized and a Taxus 2.5mm by 32mm stent was placed.  The procedure was done with Angiomax and the sheath was pulled manually.  There were no complications.



He spent an uneventful evening without complaints or complications, ambulating without difficulty.  His groin was soft and tender with ecchymosis but no hematoma.  Extremities were warm with 1+ edema to the ankles; pulses were 2+ throughout.  Morning labs included cholesterol of 114, triglycerides 109, HDL 34 and LDL 58.  He was discharged home on NPH insulin; Mucomyst, 600mg bid; aspirin, 325mg qd; atenolol, 25mg qd; Lasix, 60mg qd; glyburide, 10mg qd; lisinopril, 40mg qd; Lipitor, 40mg qd; Diovan, 80mg qd; Plavix, 75mg qd; metformin, 500mg bid to be restarted on 03/23/85; and sublingual nitroglycerin, prn chest pain.  He will require aspirin for life and Plavix for six months; he will not stop either medication unless told to do so by you.  His HDL is low and given his degree of atherosclerosis, you may wish to start gemfibrozil or Niaspan.  He will see you in follow-up in the next two weeks.  Thank you for allowing us to share in his care.  Please call if you have questions.



Sincerely,







Rodger Lester, MD

RL/ferreira

cc:	Uriel Lim, MD, 2192 Manatee Street, Plymouth, IN 74489

DS:   03/21/85

DD:   03/21/85

DT:   03/25/85

     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-11-12



Reason for Visit

This is a  61 year old  male referred to the diabetes management service for poorly  controlled diabetes



Chief Complaint

This patient is admitted to the hospital for right knee replacemnet



History of Present Illness

The patient has a 20   year history of Type 2 diabetes.  He originally was treated with oral agents with poor control.  Currently the patient is treated with  70/30 15 qam,, nph 25 hs  and metformin 1 grm qd  . The control has been improved with recent a1c 8%.  The patient tests his blood sugar qd or bid   .  Exercise is  limited because of joint problems     ,

and the weight decreased 10 pounds prior to this surgery The patient has  not been bothered by 

hypoglycemia.  Diabetic complications include  nephropathy with moderate albunimuria.

Patient underwent right total knee replacement and he should be eating supper tonight. While in the hospital glucose levels have been  140 on D5W drip.



Past Medical History

Concurrent medical problems include:CAD,recent stent,kidney stones,htn,hyperlipidemia,toe ulcer resolved, DJD lumbar spine



Family History

Family history is negative for diabetes       



Social History

The patient is currently disabled       .



Habits

The patient is not a smoker.





Review of Systems

ROS: multile joint problems

Feels well in general. No polyuria, dysuria, polydipsia, change in bowel habits or GI distress. Denies symptoms of skin, bladder upper respiratory infections. Energy appropriate, sleep unremarkable, mood stable. No palpitations or dizziness, headaches or visual symptoms.



Meds

lasix

atenolol

diovan

lisinopril

lipitor

asa

plavix

insulin/metformin





Laboratory Data

Relevant lab data:

HgA1c 8%

Cholesterol profile  LDL  64  

Creatinine .8

Urine microalbumin screen 80



Physical Exam

Vitals Bp 140/80 P  75 Wt.270

Skin no acanthosis, no diabetic dermopathy

Heent no asymmetry, no lid lag

Neck no bruits heard no thyromegaly 

Chest clear

Cor S1, S2 normal, no murmurs

Abd obese,  no tenderness, no masses

Extremities no edema, no ulcers dorsalis pedis pulses intact, right knee surgery 

Neuro    Vibratory sense intact  Monofilament testing intact



Impression

My impression is that he is currently moderately controlled on his current regime. While in hospital would start with close to his usual dosing and adjust as needed.



Recommendation

My recommendations are:

1.NPH 10 qam and 25 qhs

2.novolog 5 units ac

3.novolog sliding scale ac use default scale to start

4.Pneumovac

5.Flu shot



___________________

Elizabeth M Keys, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>