<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2062-09-09

  



Internal Medicine Medical Student Admit Note



Patient: Xavier S. Kaufman

CCH Unit Number: 9141027

Date of Admission: September 06, 2062

Attending Physician: Patrick Yeates

Code Status: Full



Source:

Patient and chart



Chief Complaint: 

Shortness of breath



History of The Present Illness:  

	Mr. Kaufman is a 53 year old man with a history of Insulin-requiring DM, HTN, chronic renal failure and Hepatitis C presents with a chief complaint of acute onset shortness of breath. He was in his usual state of health when one week PTA he decided to abruptly discontinue his Fentanyl patch, which he had for three years at 75mg for pain associated with peripheral neuropathy and gastroparesis. He recently decided he no longer wanted to wear the patch because he was concerned about personality changes and side effects of the medication. His PCP instructed him to taper the medication, switching him to a 50 mg patch, but Mr. Kaufman removed the patch without a taper. 

He felt fine for a few days, but began to experience pain in his feet, LE edema, insomnia and rhinorrhea.  On the day of admission, he was watching television when he experienced the acute onset of shortness of breath and chest tightness. He described the chest tightness as    like someone sitting on    his R chest below his shoulder, with a band-like distribution across his upper chest, intermittent, non-radiating and somewhat relieved by moving his R shoulder.  This pain lasted 4-5 minutes but his shortness of breath persisted. The shortness of breath was worse with exertion, not improved with rest and caused his to take rapid shallow breaths. He also began to have a non-productive cough this same day. This was the first time he has ever experienced this chest discomfort and shortness of breath. He denies nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis, acid reflux sensation, PND, orthopnea, fever or sick contacts.



ED Course:  

Vitals: T: 97.9  BP:  195/115  HR: 84  RR: 28  Sat:  95-96% on RA

Interventions: 

	1.5-2.0L NS

	Kayexcelate 45mg PO

	ASA 325mg

	Norvasc 5mg PO

	Nexium 40mg PO

	Toprol 100mg PO

	Lopressor 5mg IV

	Morphine sulfate 1mg IV

	MSO4 1mg IV

Studies:

	K+=5.6  (9/06/62 5:02AM)

	EKG: see Data section

	CXR: see Data section



Past Medical/Surgical History:

Diabetes Mellitus: dx 18 years ago, used Insulin in past, has only used for 1-2 weeks in 

past year, last HgbA1c 5.4 (8/17/62), complications include peripheral neuropathy, retinal disease, gastroparesis and numerous LE ulcers

Hypertension: initially labeled as    labile hypertension   , SBP's often in 190's-200's, on 

multiple medical regimens in past

Chronic renal failure: creatinine >1.5 starting in 9/61

Hepatitis C: viral load >1,000,000 in 2/22, thought to be acquired through sexual contact, 

denies IV drug use



Allergies:

Reglan- dystonia



Medications: 

HCTZ 25mg PO QD

Lisinopril 20mg PO QD

Toprol XL 100mg PO QD

Norvasc 5mg PO BID

Neurontin 600mg PO QD

Protonix 40 mg PO QD

Insulin ? (pt states he hasn't taken Insulin in months)



Social History:

	Lives in Altavista, VA with wife and their two children, ages 24 and 26. Retired as statistical programmer at Electronic Data after DM diagnosis 18 years ago. No smoking history, heavy drinking history, stopped 10 years ago, remote drug history of acid and speed use.



Family History:

Father had MI age 59



Review of Systems:

Please see pertinent positives and negatives in HPI.



Physical Examination:

Vitals upon arriving on floor: T 96.8  BP 191/109  HR  88  RR 16  Sat  92 % on 2L

General - appears stated age, well-nourished, increased work of breathing, NAD

HEENT - NC/AT, PERRL, moist mucous membranes, dentures upper palate

Neck/Nodes - no cervical or supraclavicular LAD, no carotid bruits, JVP 5cm

Pulmonary - crackles at R base, good air movement bilaterally

Cardiac -  regular rate and rhythm, normal S1, physiologic splitting of S2, no murmurs

Abdomen - non-distended, bowel sounds present, soft, non-tender, no HSM, no HJR

Skin - numerous lesions on LE's in various stages of healing, fibroma on upper back

Extremities - no cyanosis or clubbing, trace edema in LE's bilaterally, 1+ pedal pulses on R, 2+ pedal pulses on L

Neurology - alert, oriented and appropriate, occasionally tangential

     -decreased vibration sense on R to lower calf, vibration sense intact on L



Data: 

Chemistry

Plasma Sodium                    142                       (135-145)        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.5                       (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  114              H        (100-108)        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            19.1             L        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             44               H        (8-25)           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                2.9              H        (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl



Cardiac Enzymes: 

          	09/06/62  	09/06/62  	09/06/62  	09/06/62  

          	22:13     	20:26     	13:51     	05:50     

CK        	357       	          	380       	611(H)    	          

CK-MB     	6.3       	          	12.0(H)   	12.0(H)   	          

CKMBRI    	1.8       	          	3.2       	2.0       	          

TROP-T    	0.29(H)   	0.21(H)   	          	0.20(H)   	          



Hematology



WBC                              13.3             H        (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                              31.4             L        (41.0-53.0)      %

PLT                              166                      (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                              87                        (80-100)         fl

MCH                              28.9                      (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                             33.4                      (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                              15.5             H        (11.5-14.5)      %

Poly                             86               H        (40-70)          %

Lymphs                           8                L        (22-44)          %

Monos                            5                         (4-11)           %

EOS                              1                         (0-8)            %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)            %

Absolute Neuts                   11.42            H        (1.8-7.7)        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  1.07                      (1.0-4.8)        th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   0.62             H        (0.2-0.4)        th/cmm

Absolute EOS                     0.19                      (0.1-0.3)        th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.04                      (0.0-0.3)        th/cmm



Urine

          	09/06/62  	09/06/62  

          	10:20     	10:17     

UA-GLUC   	          	Negative  	          	          	          

UA-KET    	          	Negative  	          	          	          

UA-SPGR   	          	>1.030    	          	          	          

UA-BLD    	          	see detail	          	          	          

UA-PH     	          	5.5       	          	          	          

UA-ALB    	          	3+        	          	          	          

UA-NIT    	          	Negative  	          	          	          

UA-WBC    	          	Negative  	          	          	          

MIC-SED   	Completed 	          	          	          	          

HCAST     	None      	          	          	          	          

GCAST     	3-5       	          	          	          	          

UAS-RBC   	3-5       	          	          	          	          

UAS-WBC   	3-5       	          	          	          	          

UAS-BACT  	Negative  	          	          	          	          

UAS-SQHI  	Negative  	          	          	          	          



Radiology

	CXR 9/06/62: IMPRESSION: MILD INCREASE IN LINEAR OPACITIES LIKELY SECONDARY TO INTERSTITIAL EDEMA.



Cardiogram

EKG 9/06/62 04:41- 87 BPM, NSR, non-specific T wave abnormalities consisting of inverted T 

waves in aVL (unchanged from previous EKG 12/30/60), no evidence of ischemic changes



Assessment/Plan:

	In summary, Mr. Kaufman is a 53 year old man with a history of insulin-requiring DM, hypertension, chronic renal failure and Hepatitis C who presents with acute onset shortness of breath and chest tightness in the setting of opioid withdrawal. His initial cardiac markers were positive, but are hard to interpret as a sign of ischemia in the setting of renal failure. He has clinical evidence of pulmonary edema and findings on CXR suggestive of interstitial edema. However, his JVP was not elevated and he only presented with mild LE edema.  His symptoms of shortness of breath are consistent with left-sided heart failure, possibly caused by an ischemic event. His acute renal failure has multiple possible etiologies (some of which could occur concurrently) including CHF, drug toxicity (lisinopril and NSAIDs), DM-associated nephropathy, chronic hypertension and renal artery stenosis.



Problem List and Plan:

SOB/Chest tightness:

	--continue to cycle enzymes for R/O

-CXR AP and lateral to assess presence of pulmonary edema

	-TTE

	-diuresis with Lasix 20mg IV

	-Hydralazine 10mg QID & Isosorbide dinitrate 5mg PO TID 

	-d/c Lisinopril

-continue O2 at 2L, monitor O2 sat

	-monitor ins and outs, daily weights

	-obtain lipid panel to assess CAD risk factors and need for statin

Renal failure: acute over chronic, baseline nephropathy due to DM and HTN, history of 

+protein in urine, urine sediment spun, no signs of active sediment 

-urinary electrolytes to measure FENa

-d/c Lisinopril

-dose Neurontin according to renal function

-consider ruling out renal artery stenosis

-obtain urinary eosinophils to evaluate for interstitial nephritis

Hypertension: hypertensive emergency considered, but determined to be unlikely due to 

chronity of elevated SBP at similar values, under treatment

	-continue Toprol XL 100mg QD, Norvasc 5mg BID

-add Hydralazine 10mg QID, Isosorbide dinitrate 5mg PO TID

-monitor BP and signs and symptoms of target organ damage closely

Opioid withdrawal/pain management:

	-Morphine PRN

	-consult pain service

DM:

	-sliding scale insulin

	-obtain Insulin and C peptide levels because unclear if currently taking Insulin

Prophylaxis:

	-20mg Nexium PO QD

	-Heparin 5000 units SC BID

                                        							___________________________

						           Udo O. Zeitler, GMS III

						           Pager # 61303					

     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2062-09-25





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

CAPE CORAL HOSPITAL



Personal data and overall health   The patient is a 53-year-old white male, who presents for followup of multiple medical problems.



Major Problems

Diabetes mellitus

Very noncompliant for many years.  Previously had blood sugars as high as 400 to 600 and would not take any medications.  Diabetes complicated by peripheral neuropathy, which is severe; gastroparesis, which has been severe; recurrent skin abscesses; and probable coronary artery disease.

Hypertension

This has been also severe for many years and noncompliance is a significant issue.  Now complicated also by significant orthostatic hypotension presumably on the basis of autonomic insufficiency.

Coronary artery disease

He is status post recent non Q wave MI with elevated troponins presenting with congestive heart failure and chest pain in the setting of an elevated creatinine.

Chronic renal insufficiency

Creatinine approximately 3.

Pyelonephritis HISTORY OF



Anemia

Chronic.    Extensive workup negative.

Sinus tachycardia

Chronic.  This has been present for many years.  Etiology unclear.  Recent stress test does not show evidence of more complicated arrhythmia.  Cardiac ultrasound was done on his recent admission, and he has an ejection fraction of 63% with no significant valvular disease.  He has symmetric left ventricular hypertrophy.

Migraine headache HISTORY OF



Hepatitis C

Chronic.



Allergies

No known allergies   



Change in therapies and Renewals

senna 2 teaspoons  BID

aspirin 325 mg  qd

hydralazine 25 mg  TID

Imdur 30 mg  QD

Lasix 20 mg  qd

Nexium 20 mg  qd

Norvasc 5 mg  BID

Neurontin 100 mg  TID

labetalol HCl 100 mg  BID

losartan 25 mg  qd

erythromycin 250 mg  TID

Epogen 3000 units sq qwk

Colace 100 mg  BID



Family history   Notable for diabetes, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia.



Social history   He was previously the head statistical programmer for electronic data systems for many years and now disabled.  He is married and has a daughter.  Cigarettes, none times years.  Alcohol, previously heavy.  There was a history of previous illicit drug use.



Review of systems   Since he has been home, he has done reasonably well though he has noted increasing leg edema bilaterally with a significant weight gain.  He denies chest pain or palpitations.  He denies shortness of breath.  He has not been vomiting, and he actually self-discontinued both OxyContin and methadone because he felt that they did not make him feel well.



Physical examination

Pulse   86 per minute

Blood pressure 150/90    Today, 150/90 then 144/86

Weight   185 pounds

Heent   Eyes, ears, nose, and pharynx are normal, but dentition is poor

Neck   No bruits

Nodes   None palpable

Chest   Lungs, clear

Cor   Regular rate and rhythm without murmur

Abdomen   Benign

Extrem   With 3+ massive edema

Neuro   Abnormal gait due to peripheral neuropathy



Assessment and plan   Leg edema is uncertainly due to his vasodilators.  We will discontinue hydralazine and Norvasc.  He has already stopped his OxyContin and methadone.  We will see him back in approximately two weeks to follow up on his blood pressure.  He will have routine laboratory studies done today.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Patrick I Yeates MD on Oct 1, 2062     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2063-06-12

       



Internal Medicine Intern Admit Note



Pt:	Xavier Kaufman

MR#: 	 9141027

Date of Admission: June 12 2063

Attending: 	Yeates

Renal: Dr Iliff



CC:  fever 102



HPI:  53 M with ESRD on HD and chronic HCV presents with nausea, vomiting, watery diarrhea (4 episodes daily) x 2 days. His sxs started at the end of his last HD session on Tuesday. Today, he was noted to have a temperature of 102 at HD and was sent to the CCH ED for further evaluation. Feels weak, dizzy. Poor po intake. No cough, no rhinorrhea, no CP, no SOB. No sick contacts, no new/different foods.



In the ED, the patient received vancomycin 1 gram and cefepime 1 gram, blood cultures were obtained, CXR preformed and the patient was sent to the floor. 



PMH:  

1.	ESRD on HD T, TH, S

a.	Biopsy 2062 DIFFUSE AND NODULAR DIABETIC GLOMERULOSCLEROSIS. HYPERTENSIVE VASCULAR DISEASE;

b.	H/o L arm AV fistula in 2062 which was scheduled for graft next week

2.	HCV

3.	DM

a.	w/ retinopathy

b.	peripheral neuropathy

4.	gastroparesis

5.	Anemia - chronic worked up several times per PCP note

6.	HTN- negative MRI for RAS

7.	sinus tachycardia- etiology unclear, longstanding

8.	CAD- recent non Q wave MIs 2/2 demand ischemia

a.	Nl stress 9/62

b.	Nl EF 63% 9/62

9.	h/o pyelonephritis

10.	h/o migranes

11.	cataract surgery 3/63



Meds:  	

1.	NPH 25 u sq qam

2.	labetalol 400 mg bid

3.	neurontin 300 mg bid

4.	klonopin 1 po qhs prn

5.	epogen 3000u sc qw

6.	losartan 100 mg po qd

7.	nexium 20 mg po qd

8.	colace, senna

9.	asa 325

10.	nephrocaps 1 po qd

11.	lipitor 10 qd

12.	simethicone 80 po qid

13.	fioricet prn

14.	methadone 5 mg po bid

15.	renaphro cap po qd

16.	oxycontin 10 SR po q6h prn

17.	phoslo 667 tid



All: percocet, reglan  	



SH:  Married, disabled. Has 2 children. Prior h/o heavy ETOH and tob. H/o prior drug use. 

	



Exam:  	 NAD non toxic

	VS:  	T 100.2 HR 80 BP 106/65 RR 18	weight at HD today 85.9 kg  (est dry weight 87)

HEENT: clear

Neck:  	no increased  JVP R subclavian cath non tender, no erythema

Lungs:  CTAB

Cor:  	 RRR no m/r/g	

Abd:  	+BS soft NT ND

Extr:  	2+ DP no edema

Neuro: 	 awake, oriented, non focal exam





Labs:  



NA        	          	          	          	133(L)    	          

K         	3.6       	          	5.6(H)    	5.4(H)    	          

CL        	          	          	          	95(L)     	          

CO2       	          	          	          	30.5      	          

BUN       	          	16        	49(H)     	48(H)     	          

CRE       	          	2.7(H)    	6.6(H)    	6.9(H)    	          

GLU       	          	          	          	254(H)    	          



CA        	          	9.1       	          	          	          

PHOS      	          	4.0       	          	          	          

MG        	          	1.4       	          	          	          

TBILI     	          	1.0       	          	          	          

DBILI     	          	0.5(H)    	          	          	          

TP        	          	7.7       	          	          	          

ALB       	3.5       	3.8       	          	          	          

GLOB      	          	3.9       	          	          	          

AMY       	          	66        	          	          	          

LIPS      	          	3.8       	          	          	          



ALT/SGPT  	50        	          	          	          	          

AST/SGOT  	63(H)     	(stable baseline)          	          	          	          

ALKP      	134(H)    	          	          	          	          

TBILI     	1.0       	          	          	          	          

DBILI     	0.5(H)    	          	          	          	          

 

PTH       	PEND      	          	          	          	          



WBC       	6.3       	          	          	          	          

RBC       	4.10(L)   	          	          	          	          

HGB       	13.1(L)   	          	          	          	          

HCT       	37.6(L)   	          	          	          	          

MCV       	92        	          	          	          	          

MCH       	32.0      	          	          	          	          

MCHC      	34.9      	          	          	          	          

PLT       	103(L)    	          	          	          	          

RDW       	14.7(H)   	          	          	          	          

DIFFR     	Received  	          	          	          	          

METHOD    	Auto      	          	          	          	          

%NEUT     	81(H)     	          	          	          	          

%LYMPH    	10(L)     	          	          	          	          

%MONO     	8         	          	          	          	          

%EOS      	0         	          	          	          	          

%BASO     	1         	          	          	          	          

ANEUT     	5.14      	          	          	          	          

ALYMP     	0.63(L)   	          	          	          	          

AMONS     	0.53(H)   	          	          	          	          

AEOSN     	0.01(L)   	          	          	          	          

ABASOP    	0.03      	          	          	          	          

ANISO     	None      	          	          	          	          

HYPO      	None      	          	          	          	          

MACRO     	None      	          	          	          	          

MICRO     	None      	          	          	          	          



PT        	12.9      	          	          	          	          

PTT       	29.0      	          	          	          	          



Blood cx x 2 sets pending



CXR:	IMPRESSION:

	1.  The double lumen right IJ catheter terminates in the right	atrium.

	2.  No evidence of pneumonia or pulmonary edema.  Resolved	bibasilar partial atelectasis.  Resolved pleural effusions.

3.	Normal cardiac silhouette and mediastinum.  Visualized skeleton unremarkable.	



EKG:	NSR @90 with LVH with stable TWI I, AvL, V6 since jan30. 

_____________________________________________________________________________________



Assessment / Plan: 53 M with ESRD on HD TTSa presents with 2 days nausea, vomiting, diarrhea (4/day) x 2 days. Noted to have temp 102 at HD today. Tmax in ED noted 102 @ 15:30. Sources of infection include subclavian line v. viral gastroenteritis. Symptoms most c/w GI etiology although line infection could cause these systemic sxs.

1.	ID. Received 1 g vanc 1 g cefepime in ED. Continue empiric abx while awaiting identification of source of infection. CXR neg for pna, panc enzymes WNL, LFTs at stable baseline. No elevated WBC currently. 

a.	Monitor CBC and fever curve

b.	blood cultures x 2 sets pending

c.	urine GS and cx

d.	stool gram stain and cx, O+P , c.diff

e.	vancomycin dose by level

f.	check vanc level qd

g.	cefepime 500 mg qd after dialysis on TTSa

2.	HTN. Not hypertensive since labetalol given at 15:30.

a.	Labetalol 400 mg po bid with hold parameters given wide range SBP today (100-170)

b.	Hold on losartan until proves HD stable

3.	ESRD. HD today. 

a.	Continue renal medications as ordered

4.	Anemia

a.	Continue epogen

5.	Prophylaxis

a.	Nexium, heparin sc

6.	FEN

a.	Clears as tolerated by nausea

b.	Symptomatic rx for nausea with phenergan prn (reglan listed as allergy)

7.	FULL Code



_______________________________

Patricia Keating MD

#03533





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2063-07-12

HISTORY AND PHYSICAL NOTE



Reason for referral:	53 year old male with ESRD here for dialysis access consultation.



History of Present Illness:	Mr. Kaufman had a left AVF constructed in November 2062 and had an angiographic procedure to dilate the fistula recently.  This eventually thrombosed.  He doesn't want a right hand procedure and is here for evaluation for a graft.



Past Medical History:	

diabetes

hypertension

CAD

  	

Medications

Labetalol HCL 400 MG (200MG TABLET take 2) PO BID 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 

Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Neurontin (GABAPENTIN) 300 MG (300MG CAPSULE take 1) PO BID 

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325 MG (325MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Renaphro 1 TAB PO QD 

Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 20 MG (20MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO QD 



Allergies:	NKDA	 



Family History:	Non contributory 



Social History:	Non contributory 



Review of Systems:	Negative x 10 systems other than noted above.	



Physical Examination:

General:	WNL

Vital signs:	WNL

Head:		Normal

Oropharynx:	WNL

Neck:		WNL

Skin:		WNL

Lymph:		WNL

Chest/back:	WNL

Coronary:	Normal S1,S2, no murmur, gallop or rub appreciated.  No lifts, RRR

Lungs:		Clear to Percussion and Auscultation

Abdomen:	Soft, NT, without hepatomegaly, splenomegaly, bladder distention or masses, NABS, no bruits

GU:		Normal external genitalia

Rectal:		Normal tone, without masses or tenderness, stool hemocult ___________

Vascular:	Femorals, DPs, PTs intact, no bruits

Extremities:	No evidence of any usable cephalic vein, need arteriovenous graft 

Neuro:		Nonfocal and intact to a screening exam



Laboratory:



Impressions:   In summary, Mr. Kaufman can have a left AV graft placed from AVF to antecubital region using an ARTEGRAFT.  We will schedule this procedure and he knows the risks and benefits of the procedure and wishes to proceed.













_____________________________________________

Carroll Nolan, MD















****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-02-25





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

CAPE CORAL HOSPITAL



Personal data and overall health

			

  53-year-old white male with multiple medical problems on dialysis for control of fluid overload and hypertension in the setting of worsening renal dysfunction.



Reason for visit

			

  worsening right foot ulcers



History of present illness

			

  Ulcers noted over past month, increasing size, no fever---lateral aspect of heel and lateral aspect of 4th toe.  DM control fair



Problem List (reviewed)



Hepatitis c MAJOR 

Diabetes mellitus MAJOR 

Anemia MAJOR HISTORY OF

Hypertension MAJOR 

Sinus tachycardia MAJOR 

Coronary artery disease MAJOR STATUS POST

Pyelonephritis MAJOR HISTORY OF

Chronic renal insufficiency MAJOR 

Migraine headache MAJOR HISTORY OF

Chronic hepatitis MAJOR HISTORY OF



Major Problems





Hepatitis c

Chronic---cirrhosis on CT.



Diabetes mellitus

Normal to low blood sugars.  Running about 140  On Insulin 25u NPH q day and prn CZI with meals



Anemia HISTORY OF

This is chronic.  He has had an extensive workup in the past---ACD due to renal disease---is currently on Epogen.



Hypertension

Again, it is a longstanding issue.  Extensive workup negative including MRI of the renal arteries.  BPs much improved now if anything low---so daughter has on her own reduced meds prescribed at DC. Occas orthostatic and BPs lower



Sinus tachycardia

Chronic.  Etiology unclear.  This has been present for many years.



Coronary artery disease STATUS POST

recent non-Q-wave MIs.  Normal stress test and normal EF. Never cathd.  Eval by Dr. Jeffers in the past



Pyelonephritis HISTORY OF

No recent UTIs



Chronic renal insufficiency

Now being dialyzed 3 days per week/Mon-Wed-Fri with improvement  in SOB and BP which were refractory to meds



Migraine headache HISTORY OF

He uses Fioricet PRN.



Chronic hepatitis HISTORY OF

type C.  chronic-  no signs of major liver dyfunction



Allergies

Allergy   Current and listed in On-Call.

No known drug allergy   Allergies to medication none.

Drug reaction   Hydralazine leg edema but no actual allergic type rashes or shortness of breath.



Active Medications



Ascensia contour test strips 

aspirin 325 mg  qd

calcium acetate 133mg po tid

Colace 100 mg  BID

Cozaar 100mg po qd

Epogen  sq qwk 30000

Fioricet 325/50/40mg po QD PRN

Humulin r  use prn fingersticks prior to meals

Insulin syringes (lowdose) 

labetalol hcl 300 mg  BID

Lancets 

Lipitor 10mg po qd

methadone 5mg po BID

Nephrocaps one po q day

Neurontin 300 mg  PO BID

Nexium 20mg po qd take 1h before meal

nortriptyline 10 mg po qhs

Norvasc 5mg po bid

nph insulin humulin n  SQ 25u am and 10 u pm

Onetouch strips 

Oxycontin 10mg sr po q 6 hrs hours PRN do not cut/crush/chew

Plavix 75mg po qd

prednisone 10mg po qd

renaphro  po take 1 cap daily

senna 2 teaspoons  BID

simethicone 80mg  po QID

tizanidine 2mg half po bid

tramadol 50 mg po q12h PRN pain



Family history

			

  Notable for diabetes, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia.



Social history

			

  He was previously the head statistical programmer for electronic data systems for many years and now disabled.  He is married and has a daughter.  Cigarettes, none times years.  Alcohol, previously heavy.  There was a history of previous illicit drug use.  Cigarettes, none.  Alcohol, rare.



Habits/Risk Screening

Smoking status: former smoker  none times years.

Alcohol use status: none/minimal  



Procedures and Immunizations 

Influenza vaccine 

 11/63

Pneumovax 

 1/19/2064 left arm



Review of systems

			

  He denies chest pain, shortness of breath, or palpitations. His weight has stabilized.  He has actually gained weight since his hospitalization.  He has not had any problems with diarrhea and no urinary symptoms.  Neurologically, he denies any falls or changes in his headaches, which continue but seem to be less frequent.  He has had no bleeding disorders or easy bruising.  Vision decreased as above.  The rest of his review of systems is negative in detail.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 130/82  no ortho change

Pulse 76  per minute

Weight 194  no change

General appearance   Thin middle-aged white male in no apparent distress

Skin   Notable for scattered excoriations

Heent   Eyes--pronounced right eye ptosis now much improved

Neck   thyroid without palpable nodules, normal texture and size, carotids without audible bruits

Nodes   No cervical, axillary or groin adenopathy appreciated.

Chest   no deformity, lungs clear

Cor   regular rate and rhythm, no audible murmurs or click

Abdomen   bowel sounds normal, no palpable hepatosplenomegaly

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, edema.  2+ pedal pulses.

Neuro   Oriented times 3, Cranial nerves normal, speech normal, gait normal using cane, full strength

Foot exam   large superficial ulcerations lateral aspect right foot and 4th toe, minimal cellulitis

Preventive eye exam   twice yearly with optho

Mini mental state exam (best=30)   intact without evidence of anxiety, depression, delusions or paranoid ideation



Selected recent labs

			

    02/25/64 PLT 116 L, 02/25/64 HCT 40.1 L, 02/25/64 Glucose (Stat Lab) 160 H, 02/25/64 Creatinine (Stat Lab) 6.5 H, 02/25/64 BUN (Stat Lab) 29 H, 02/25/64 Potassium (Stat Lab) 4.4



Assessment and plan

			

  Foot ulcers---needs admit, IV ABx, debridement?  Cover DM with NPH and prn CZI.  BP is OK.  Will ask Dr. Urzua of Vasc Surg to see Mr. Kaufman--- LENIS or angio to eval flow to foot



Signed electronically by Yeates, Patrick I on Feb 25, 2064     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>