<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2076-02-07

                     BOWNE EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

GODWIN,YAIR   914-64-15-0                    VISIT DATE: 02/07/76

This patient was evaluated and treated in conjunction with a 

resident.  I confirm the history and physical findings as 

documented on the handwritten record. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this is a 70-year-old 

patient with a history of mild weakness and easy fatigability who 

was thought to be anemic with a hematocrit of 25 on evaluation at 

an outside facility.  He was referred here for further evaluation. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL APPEARANCE:  The patient is awake, 

alert, and in no acute distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Normal, with the 

exception of a low grade temperature of 99.7.  HEENT:  Benign.  

LUNGS:  The breath sounds are clear.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Hematocrit is determined to be 42.  EKG is 

normal.  Chest x-ray shows no evident abnormality.

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  The patient is seen in the 

emergency department by the LMC physician as well.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Mild progressive unexplained fatigue.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 

ultimately discharged with followup for further investigation as an 

outpatient.  Condition upon discharge is stable. 

___________________________________                    JZ339/6381 

HECTOR V. OBRYAN, M.D.   HO78                            D:02/07/76 

                                                       T:02/07/76 

Dictated by:  HECTOR V. OBRYAN, M.D.   HO78 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-04-24

EDVISIT^91464150^Godwin, Yair^04/24/76^MURRAY, MARION OSCAR

The patient was interviewed and examined primarily by me.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Right chest wall pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 70-year-old male

who presents to Bowne Hospital Emergency Department with no

one-week history of right-sided lateral chest wall pain.  The

patient states the pain is worse with movement including

stretching, bending, and reaching.  The patient states that

patient had slept with a hot water bottle on his right chest wall

for pain relief and had pain relief and was sitting in a chair. 

His lying down on his right side was painful, and this morning,

sat up and while getting up, exacerbated the chest wall pain. 

The patient discussed this pain with his primary care physician

during the past 2 weeks and who had been in agreement that it is

probable muscle strain.  The patient denies any headache, visual

changes, and dizziness.  Denies any neck pain.  Denies any

left-sided chest pain.  Denies any nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis,

or dyspnea.  Denies any abdominal pain.  He has been afebrile. 

No cough.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Includes hypertension and non-insulin

dependent diabetes.  The patient also has exposure to asbestos

and asbestos changes on CT scan previously.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Past tobacco, past ETOH, no IV drug abuse, lives

with his family, and he is retired.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As indicated in the history of present

illness, otherwise negative.

MEDICATIONS:  See nursing note for full list of medications.

ALLERGIES:  The patient has no known allergies to medications.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is awake and alert in no acute

distress.  Temperature 95.4, pulse of 67, respiratory rate of 16,

blood pressure 179/78, and O2 saturation 95% on room air.  HEENT

is atraumatic.  ENT:  No infection.  Pharynx is normal.  Neck is

supple and nontender.  Respiratory exam:  Chest wall is tender. 

Patient has reproducible, palpable right-sided posterior lateral

and anterior lateral chest wall tenderness.  Normal breath sounds

bilaterally, no rales, rhonchi, or wheezing.  Cardiac exam: 

Regular rate and rhythm, no murmur, and normal pulses throughout.

 Abdomen is soft.  The patient has some minimal amount of right

upper quadrant tenderness just subcostal at the infracostal

margin.  No rebound or guarding.  Skin is warm, dry, and intact,

no lesions, or rashes.  Extremities are nontender. Normal range

of motion.  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  Neurologic exam: 

Cranial nerves II through XII intact bilaterally.  No motor or

sensory deficits.

LABORATORY DATA:  Significant for white count of 10.6, hematocrit

of 38.5, platelets of 244,000.  Sodium 138, potassium 4.1,

chloride of 105, bicarbonate 23, BUN 38, creatinine 1.9, and

glucose of 165.  ALT of 11, AST of 16, amylase of 71, and lipase

61.

Given the fact that the patient had some right upper quadrant

pain and pain was radiating laterally to the right anterior

aspect, patient received a right upper quadrant ultrasound, which

was negative.  No evidence of stones or gallbladder changes,

consistent with cholecystitis.  The patient had a chest x-ray,

which showed no new changes from prior studies.  No evidence of

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

The patient received morphine IV, and subsequently received 2

Percocet tablets, and had resolution of his pain.  Patient's case

was discussed with Dr. Rivers, who is the patient's primary care

physician, and who is in agreement to discharge the patient home

with pain medications and muscle relaxants.  The patient is being

discharged home in satisfactory condition.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Right chest wall pain.

______________________________

MURRAY, MARION OSCAR M.D.

D: 04/24/76

T: 04/25/76

Dictated By: MURRAY, MARION OSCAR

eScription document:8-7695417 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-08-02

 

Intern Admit Note



Patient: 		Godwin, Yair	

MRN:		6894069	

Admit Date:	8/01/76

PCP:		Xavier Rivers (SHMC)	

ID/CC:  	Shortness of Breath

	 	

HPI: 	Mr. Godwin is a 70 year old man with PMH of HTN, hyperlipidemia, DM type II, chronic back painand empyema in remote history, who presented to the ED by EMS after awakening from sleep at approx 3:00 am with acute shortness of breath and back pain.  Pain was not shooting toward back, but radiated to the left shoulder.  Accompanied by nausea and vomiting X 1, diaphoresis.  No chest pain.  Has never experienced such awakening previously.  No orthopnea or LE edema.  No fever or cough.  No change in bowel habits.  No blood per rectum or melena.  



	In ED, vital signs as follows: afebrile, BP 195/77, HR 72, RR 22, 98% on RA.  Received ASA and lasix, NTG without effect, some morphine and ativan with better effect, and hydralazine IV and then PO.    

	

PMH:	

-NIDDM - on metformin and pioglitazone

-Hypertension - chronically elevated on therapy, per patient runs in 150-160 range/80.  On atenolol and irbesartran

-hyperlipidemia 

-History of asbestos exposure while a community organizer, corresponding pleural changes on CT

-psoriasis

-chronic back pain



ALL:	NKDA



MEDS:	

-Lasix 20 mg po qd, atenolol 100 mg po bid, glipizide 5 mg po qam, 10 mg po qpm, simvastatin, irbesartan 150 mg po qpm, lansoprozole 30 mg po qd, pioglitazone 



FH:	-Non-contributory



SH:	-Retired worked as 

 		-ETOH: one glass of wine per night

	-TOB: remote

	-IVDA:none



ROS:	No F/C/S/N/V/D/hematochezia/hemoptysis.  No CP/palps /LE edema. No change in appetite or weight. No cough, sore throat, rash. No pain.  No rashes.





EXAM:

V/S: 	T 97.6, HR 56, BP 148/64, RR 22, 98% on 2L, 94% RA 

Gen: 	cantankerous, conversant, obese, lying in bed in NAD

Skin:	no rash/lesions/bruises

HEENT: 	NCAT, PERRLA, EOMI, sclera anicteric, o/p pink and clear, moist mucosa, normal dentition

Neck: 	supple, FROM, thyroid not palpable, JVP at 5 cm

Pulm: 	symmetric chest, CTAB, no egophony, no tactile fremitus

CV:  	NR RR S1, S2, II/VI systolic murmur, PMI not palpated

Abd: 	obese, atraumatic, NT, ND, +BS, no HSM, no striae, ventral hernia present on valsalva

Back:	Paraspinal tenderness, minimal spinal tenderness at approx t10

Ext: 	no edema, clubbing or cyanosis, warm, pulses weak but present

Neuro: 	AAOX3, MS agitated, CN III-VIII intact, Moves all four extremities, Sensory intact. DTR's 2+ and symmetric in bilat LE and UE. Toes down bilaterally.





LABS:

Chemistry:

Chemistry Detail for GODWIN, YAIR J



01-Aug-2076 16:58  



Test Description        Result   Flags           Ref. Range     Ref. Units



Plasma Sodium          141                       135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium       3.5                       3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride        105                       100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide  27.3                      23.0-31.9      mmol/L

Osmolality             301        H              280-296        mosm/kg

Calcium                8.9                       8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus             2.7                       2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium              1.5                       1.4-2.0        meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen   24                        8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine      1.6        H              0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose         160        H              70-110         mg/dl

Creatine Kinase Isoenz 1.9                       0.0-6.9        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                             0.0-3.5        %

  Result Text:

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T             <0.01                     0.00-0.09      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase        69                        60-400         U/L





01-Aug-2076 04:35  



Calcium                9.3                       8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus             2.2        L              2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium              1.5                       1.4-2.0        meq/L

Total Protein          7.3                       6.0-8.3        g/dl

Albumin                3.9                       3.3-5.0        g/dl

Globulin               3.4                       2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin       0.1                       0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin        0.5                       0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase   101                       45-115         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT      11                        10-55          U/L

Creatine Kinase Isoenz 2.0                       0.0-6.9        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                             0.0-3.5        %

  Result Text:

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T             REFUSED                   0.00-0.09      ng/ml

  Result Text:

     HEMOLYZED SPECIMEN

Transaminase-SGOT      16                        10-40          U/L

Creatine Kinase        105                       60-400         U/L





 01-Aug-2076 10:01  



Creatine Kinase Isoenz NEGATIVE                  NEG

Troponin-I             NEGATIVE                  NEG





    

Hematology:

01-Aug-2076 04:36  



Test Description        Result   Flags           Ref. Range     Ref. Units



WBC                    9.0                       4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                    40.6       L              41.0-53.0      %

HGB                    14.0                      13.5-17.5      gm/dl

RBC                    4.80                      4.50-5.90      mil/cmm

PLT                    232                       150-350        th/cumm

MCV                    85                        80-100         fl

MCH                    29.1                      26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                   34.4                      31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                    14.2                      11.5-14.5      %

Superstat PT           12.6                      11.1-13.1      sec

Superstat PT-INR       1.0

  Result Text:

     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.

Superstat APTT         23.5                      22.1-35.1      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST   RECEIVED

Diff Method            Auto

Poly                   73         H              40-70          %

Lymphs                 19         L              22-44          %

Monos                  3          L              4-11           %

EOS                    4                         0-8            %

Basos                  1                         0-3            %

Absolute Neuts         6.70                      1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs        1.67                      1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos         0.25                      0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS           0.33       H              0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos         0.04                      0.0-0.3        th/cmm

Aniso                  None                      NORMAL

Hypo                   None                      NORMAL

Macrocytes             None

Microcytes             None





EKG:

Old left bundle branch block, normal sinus 66. 



CXR:

FINDINGS:

	No infiltrates or evidence of CHF is present.  There is a three cm

	mass in the right lower lung.  This was shown to be rounded

	atelectasis on chest CT.  Pleural changes are consistent with

	asbestos related pleural disease.

	



IMPRESSION:

	Asbestos related pleural disease

	Right lower lobe mass shown to be rounded atelectasis on chest CT.

	

CT:



CT Chest	

	FINDINGS:

	No comparison.  The aorta is of normal caliber.  There is

	atherosclerotic calcification of the aorta.  Classic arch anatomy

	is present.

	Bilateral pleural calcific plaques are demonstrated consistent

	with asbestos related pleural disease.  In addition, in the

	posterior segment right lower lobe there is 2.7 cm mass.  The mass

	has a linear pleural attachment adjacent to pleural plaques.

	There is also present swirling vessels around the mass and volume

	loss.  The findings are consistent with rounded atelectasis.  A

	smaller focus of rounded atelectasis is present in the left lower

	lobe.

	Coronary artery calcifications present.  No mediastinal or hilar

	or axillary lymphadenopathy is present.  There is no

	supraclavicular adenopathy.

	The osseous structures are unremarkable.

	Please see dictated abdomen report.

	



IMPRESSION:

	1.  Normal caliber aorta please see MRA report regarding

	evaluation of dissection.

	2.  Bilateral rounded atelectasis and asbestos related pleural

	disease.

	

	



   WMC  MRA AORTA + &  01-Aug-2076 09:10 





REPORT:

	This study was reviewed with Dr. Upshur.

	MRA OF THE THORAX WAS WITH AND WITHOUT GADOLINIUM.

	Technique: Standard departmental MRA protocol of the chest and

	upper abdomen was performed with and without gadolinium. 3-D

	images were obtained and interpreted.

	Findings:

	There is a three vessel aortic arch.  There is no evidence of a

	flap within the aorta to suggest a dissection. The takeoffs of the

	great vessels are normally patent. There is no evidence of

	aneurysm.

	The celiac artery and SMA are patent. There are single renal

	arteries bilaterally.  There is mild narrowing of the proximal

	right renal artery.  The left renal artery is patent.

	



IMPRESSION:

	Unremarkable MRA of the thoracic aorta, without evidence of

	dissection or aneurysm.

	Mild narrowing of the proximal right renal artery.

	

	____________________________________________



A/P:	This is a 70 year old man with acute shortness of breath and back pain. 



1.	 Cardiology - Will rule out for MI

Received ASA, SLNG, Lasix, beta-blocker in ED

Cardiac monitor, cycle enzymes

On atenolol, irbesartan as outpatient;  will continue hydralazine for better management.	

  	2.	Renal - cr 1.8, appears close to baseline, consistent with chronic renal insufficiency, likely due to hypertensive disease

Will continue to follow

  	3.	Endo - diabetic, non-insulin dependent

SS insulin, will convert to NPH once daily requirement is clear

  	4.	Musculoskeletal - history and present complaint of chronic back pain, low to mid-back

Percocet for pain relief as NSAID contraindicated in CRI

  	5.	Psych - volatile personality, significant anger toward doctors after wife's death 8 years ago

Will attempt to minimize aggravating situations

  	6.	FEN

Repleted phosporus

  	7.	Prophylaxis

Ambulating, on nexium.

  	8.	Dispo

Home after acute cardiac workup complete; will have further risk stratification done through Shenandoah Hospital.

  	



	___________________________

	Vera Winn  pager 12081





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-03-31

Harper Hospital Intern Admission Note

Pt: Godwin, Yair

MR# 6894069

Admit Date: 3/31/77

PCP: Rivers, Xavier (Westlake-Shenandoah Hospital)



CC: chest pain

 

HPI: 71M hx DM, HLP, HTN, p/w chest pain. Pt reports having markedly reduced right eye visual acuity this evening, subsequently became increasingly anxious and    nervous    and developed chest tightness across chest at level of xiphoid. Intermittently had sharp pains in same distribution, reaching 5/10 in severity. Associated nausea and dry heaving, only briefly SOB. No associated lightheadedness, diaphoresis, or palpitations. Called daughter who then called Shenandoah Hospital emergency line, then called MVH and came into their emergency room where he was referred to WMC ER secondary to chest discomfort. Symptoms had resolved by time of being seen in WMC ER. 



Of note, pt admitted to LMC (9/76) for acute onset SOB/CP. At that time, had negative PE protocol CT and adeno-MIBI. Just prior to that was admitted to WMC for similar symptoms and had negative dissection protocol CT at that time. At baseline, walks up to a mile without symptoms, also climbs stairs without symptoms. 



In ER, vitals: T 98.2, P 69, BP 180/79, RR 18, 98% RA. Tx ASA 325mg, lopressor 25mg PO/5mg IV. Pain-free while in ER and transferred to floor in stable condition.



PMH:

DM-2

HTN

GERD

TURP

DJD of the spine

Chronic back pain

Hypercholesterolemia

Psoriasis

Chronic renal insufficiency

Macular degeneration

-reports having    attack    in 2/77, characterized as having acute vision blurriness, told at MVH he had macular degeneration



Adenosine-MIBI (9/76):

The ECG response to Adenosine was non-diagnostic. The scan results demonstrated no evidence of ischemia and/or scar. EF 54%.



Medications:

Glipizide 5mg po bid

Atenolol 100mg po bid

Irbesartan 150mg po qd

Pioglitazone 30mg qd

Lasix 20mg qd

Simvastatin 20mg qd

Aspirin (just started 1wk ago)

Vertigo

Gait disturbance

	-thought secondary to peripheral neuropathy



Allergies:  NKDA



SH: Patient is widowed and lives alone. He quit smoking 30 years ago and denies alcohol use. He is a retired community organizer. Known prior asbestos exposure.



FH:  Unknown



Exam:  	VS  T 97.5  P 62  BP 152/69  RR 20  95% 2L



Gen:  NAD, anxious. Pain-free. A&Ox3.

HEENT: EOMI. No nystagmus. MMM.

Skin:	No changes.

Neck:  Supple. Brisk carotids, no bruits.

Chest: CTAB.

CVS:  RRR. 2/6 early systolic murmur, maximal at RUSB, no radiation to carotids.

Abd:  	 Obese, protuberant. Normoactive bowel sounds. Non-tender.

Extr:  2+ DP pulses. No edema.

Neuro: Markedly decreased visual acuity of right eye, otherwise CN 2-12 intact. Strength 5/5 throughout, sensation intact. 



DATA:

Chemistry

Sodium (Stat Lab)                139                       (135-145)        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)             5.4              H        (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

     HEMOLYZED SPECIMEN

Chloride (Stat Lab)              110              H        (100-108)        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)                   23.1                      (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)                   48               H        (8-25)           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)            1.8              H        (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

	(baseline Cr ~1.6)

Glucose (Stat Lab)               169              H        (70-110)         mg/dl



Calcium                          9.0                       (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus                       2.3              L        (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.4                       (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       1.9                       (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                                       (0.0-3.5)        %

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T                       <0.01                     (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase                  106                       (60-400)         U/L



Hematology

WBC                              11.5             H        (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                              35.1             L        (41.0-53.0)      %

HGB                              12.4             L        (13.5-17.5)      gm/dl

RBC                              4.15             L        (4.50-5.90)      mil/cmm

PLT                              227                       (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                              85                        (80-100)         fl

MCH                              30.0                      (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                             35.4                      (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                              15.1             H        (11.5-14.5)      %

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED

Diff Method                      Auto

Poly                             83               H        (40-70)          %

Lymphs                           13               L        (22-44)          %

Monos                            2                L        (4-11)           %

EOS                              2                         (0-8)            %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)            %



Imaging:

CXR (3/31/77): No acute process



EKG: NSR. LBBB. 1mm STD I/II/aVf/V5-6. 2mm STE V1-3. TWI I, biphasic T-wave V5-6. (No change from prior ekg)



Impression: 71M hx DM, HTN, HLP, p/w chest pain likely GI related and not cardiac in origin.



Plan: 

1.	chest pain: Unlikely cardiac in origin given negative EKG, recent normal stress test, and atypical nature. Likely GI related as pt with dry heaving around time of chest tightness.

-cont asa, simvastatin, atenolol, irbesartan, and lasix

-repeat EKG in AM

-cycle cardiac enzymes, telemetry

-check lipid panel

-maalox prn



2.	decreased visual acuity: Most likely worsening macular degeneration given recent chronic history of symptoms. Absence of pain makes retinal vascular occlusion very unlikely, no other neurological symptoms to indicate CVA. 

-refer pt back to MVH once ruled out for MI

-consider I- CT if more neuro symptoms develop to r/o acute stroke



3.	Diabetes: -check lipid panel, hemoglobin A1c

-RISS, glipizide

-hold pioglitazone (not in formulary)



4.	proph: nexium, heparin



Full Code





_________________________________

Victor Tolbert M.D.

Pager 73483



Call Internal Medicine intern in AM for pt management issues.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-08-07



Date 08/07/2081                                     WMC VASCULAR SURGERY ADMISSION NOTE



Patient: Godwin, Yair                                                         

MRN: 91464150 

Attending: Orellana


HPI: 

CC: newly developed vision deficit in the L lower quadrant of the L eye



HPI: Patient is a 75 y/o M, a former smoker, with Hx of multiple medical problems including macular degeneration in the R eye, CAD, NIDDM, HTN and hypercholesterolemia.  A month ago he first noticed what he describes as &#8220;blue floaties&#8221; in the LLQ of his L eye&#8217;s visual field.  He then saw his ophthalmologist at the Shenandoah Hospital in Parchman who concluded that this is not due to macular degeneration.  He denies having headaches or any other symptoms at that time.  He denies similar episodes of &#8220;floaties&#8221; in the past and he has no Hx of headaches, disarthria, motor deficits, sensory loss and has never been hospitalized with a stroke or TIA.  He recalls having &#8220;high kidney function&#8221; in the past, but does not recall details.  His PCP arranged for an U/S evaluation, which was done on 8/05/81 and showed 80-85% stenosis of the L proximal ICA.  Patient has had surgeries in the past and had no adverse effects to anesthesia administration.  He considers himself fit and in good shape.  



PMH:

- CAD

- CHF

- NIDDM

- macular degeneration

- HTN, hyperlipidemia

- impotence

- COPD and empyema R lung 15 years ago

- abdominal hernia

- spinal stenosis and chronic neck pain (developed after MVA)

- arthritis and chronic L shoulder pain

- BPH

- asbestosis

- GERD

- migraines

- PNA

- psoriasis



PSH:

- s/p L knee replacement (2079)

- TURP (2075)



Meds on admission (patient does not know meds, below is per MVH records):

  1. Atenolol  100 MG PO BID

  2. Glimepiride (Amaryl)  1 MG PO QD

  3. Hydrochlorothiazide  25 MG PO QD

  4. Irbesartan (Avapro)  150 MG PO QD

  5. Lisinopril  40mg mg PO QD

  6. Omeprazole  40 MG PO BID

  7. Pioglitazone (Actos)  30 MG PO QD

  8. Simvastatin (Zocor)  40 MG PO QHS

  9. Tamsulosin (Flomax)  0.4 MG PO BID


10. Lorazepam (Ativan)  0.5 MG PO QHS prn Insomnia


11. Finasteride  5 mg PO QD


12. Fluticasone Nasal Spray  2 SPRAY NAS BID


13. Multivitamin With Betacarotene (Ocuvite)  1 TAB PO QD



Allergies: Levofloxacin (pedal edema)



SH: The patient has a 60-pack year smoking history (quit smoking in 2063).  He drinks ~ 3 glasses of wine per year. He is a widower, has three children and lives with his daughter in Lyndonville.  He is a retired community organizer.



FH: There is no Hx of strokes. His mother passed away from at 90 (no significant medical problems) and father at 66 from MI.



PE:

T 95.7  P 74  BP 181/93  RR 24  O2 Sat 97%RA

Gen: NAD, well developed and appears younger than his stated age

Neck: prominent neck musculature, trachea midline, no masses or LAD, no signs of previous surgeries, no carotid bruits appreciated

CV: RRR, + S4

Pulm: CTAB

Abd: soft, non-tender, midline hernia present, no HSM

Ext: no femoral bruits appreciated; 2+ femoral, 2+ DP and 2+ PT pulses bilaterally; BL ankle edema (trace) 

Neuro: cranial II-XII grossly intact, 5/5 motor strength and sensation bilaterally, cerebellar function intact



LABS:

BMP: 140/ 4.3/ 105/ 29/ 39/ 1.95/ 155

CBC: 8.58/ 38.6/ 265

Coags: 13.8/ 27.3/ 1

Blood bank sample sent



Radiology/Studies:
Chest PA and LAT (8/07/81): 
Prelim read &#8211; costophrenic angles are blunted bilaterally, hazy opacities present bilaterally with R&gt;L, cardiomegaly, trachea is midline; this appearance is comparable to previous CXR (2/81)

EKG (8/07/81): Sinus, rate ~ 70, wide QRS (LBBB), St segment elevation in v1-v3 seen on previous EKGs, overall comparable to baseline

Carotid Duplex U/S (8/05/81):
RIGHT Carotid Artery
          Plaque                     Surface         CA++  Velocity  % Stenosis
CCA Prox  no plaque                                        69                  
CCA Mid   no plaque                                        75                  
CCA Dist  no plaque                                        66                  
ICA Prox  hyperechoic homogeneous    mild irregular        135         25-49   
ICA Mid   hyperechoic homogeneous    smooth                108         25-49   
ICA Dist  hyperechoic homogeneous    smooth                65          1-25    
ECA       hyperechoic heterogeneous  mild irregular        97          &lt;50     

LEFT Carotid Artery
          Plaque                     Surface         CA++  Velocity  % Stenosis
CCA Prox  no plaque                                        78                  
CCA Mid   no plaque                                        71                  
CCA Dist  no plaque                                        52                  
ICA Prox  hypoechoic homogeneous                           427         80-85   
ICA Mid   hypoechoic homogeneous                           150         50      
ICA Dist                                                   118                 
ECA       hyperechoic homogeneous    mild irregular        90          &lt;50     

A/P: 75 y/o M with multiple risk factors, presenting with amaurosis fugax of 1 month in duration in the setting of significant L ICA stenosis, as determined by U/S. His Sx most likely due to the observed stenosis.  He is pre-op for L CEA for tomorrow.
N: no issues
CV: continue home meds;
P: no issue; follow up official read of CXR
GI: diabetic diet; NPO midnight
GU: IVF after midnight
Heme: start ASA 325 QD
Endo: RISS
ID: no issues 
Labs: Chem7, CBC, Coags, type and screen 
Other: patient consented  

_____________________
Taylor Otero FSM IV
(42745)

--

Patient seen and examined. Agree with above student note. In brief, 75yM with PMH significant for DM, HTN, high cholesterol, and macular degeneration who presents with recent onset of intermittent, transient &#8216;blotches&#8217; in left eye. Carotid US evaluation showed left sided velocities consistent with 80-85% stenosis of left proximal ICA. He is admitted pre op for operating room tomorrow. Home meds with exception of oral antihyperglycemics will be resumed. See detailed plan above.



Discussed w/ Arthur Tisdale, chief resident, who agrees w/ assessment and plan.





________________

Virginia Roman

PGY-2

28793






****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>