<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2088-03-08

Patient Name: YOUNT, PATRICIA;  MRN: 4711083
Dictated at: 03/08/2088 by BRANDON VICENTE, M.D. 

RENAL CONSULT NOTE 
 
It is a pleasure seeing seeing Ms. Yount in consultation.  She was referred to us by Dr. Michael.  Ms. Yount has a history of diabetes mellitus for the last seven years.  She also has a long history of hypertension.  She retired from IBM in 2085 after working there for many years.  Her last posting was as a electrical mechanic.  She is feeling well.  She denies headaches, nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain.  She also denies shortness of breath or complex partial seizures.  She denies swelling and presence of dysuria, fever, chills.  She is taking her medications regularly.  
 
ALLERGIES 
No known drug allergies.  
 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY 
1.  Diabetes mellitus for about seven years.  
2.  Hypertension.  

3.  PVD

4.  Hypercholesterolemia

 
SOCIAL HISTORY 
She denies smoking or drinking.  She has one son living with her.


FAMILY HISTORY 
Positive for diabetes.  
 
MEDICATIONS 
Norvasc 10 mg q. day,

Glucophage 500 mg twice a day,

Glucotrol 5 mg twice a day,

Avandia 4 mg q. day, (she had incresed skin itching with attempts to increase the dose)

Lipitor 10 mg q. day,

Aspirin 325 mg a day (she is not taking aspirin).   


REVIEW OF SYSTEMS 
Ms. Yount denies any recent visual change, headaches.  She denies chest pain, shortness of breath, nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, diarrhea, constipation, dysuria, fever, chills.   


PHYSICAL EXAM 
Ms. Yount looks well.  Blood pressure is 148/90.  Body weight is 188.  Repeat blood pressure is 170/80.  On examination of head and neck - no absolutely.  Thyroid is soft, nontender, no nodules.  Chest is clear to percussion and auscultation.  Heart - regular rate and rhythm, no S3.  Abdomen is soft, bowel sounds present.  Extremities - trace edema.  
 
LABORATORY 
Pending.  
 
IMPRESSION 
Ms. Yount has diabetes and hypertension with a mildly elevated creatinine.  Her urine shows presence of protein, which suggests diabetic nephropathy.  Upon review of her medications, she is on a very good medication control, and  her blood pressure has been well controlled.  However, today the blood pressure is running higher.  I will see her in about two to three months.  If her blood pressure continues to be high, we should try to increase her dose of ARB.  I also explained to Ms. Yount the importance of taking aspirin and that she should continue her daily aspirin.   
 
_______________________________ 
Brandon Vicente, M.D.  
 
DD:03/08/2088 
DT:03/10/2088 
JM:99704     :137 
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-10-23

Patient Name: YOUNT, PATRICIA;  MRN: 4711083

Dictated on: 10/24/2088 by YOEL NEWCOMB, M.D. 



 

Patricia is a 70-year-old retired woman, right-hand dominant, who comes with complaints of soreness in her right wrist.  She apparently had a fall, which caused substantial pain and some swelling, but no bruising.  Brought her in to have an evaluation.  X-rays showed no fracture and over the last few weeks things have improved substantially, and she comes in just because she was told to get it checked out by her doctors, but otherwise feeling quite good and wondering if the appointment is even necessary.  

 

Past medical history includes high blood pressure and diabetes.  

 

No prior surgeries.  

 

No medications.  

 

No known drug allergies.  

 

Lists no family history of any problems.  

 

Lives alone and used to smoke, but quit.  

 

On examination, she has full range of motion of her wrist compared to the opposite side.  No atrophy, ecchymosis, edema or deformity.  Negative scaphoid shift test.  Slight tenderness over the distal radius.  Normal tendon function.  

 

My impression is that she must have got a mild sprain, which has recovered or possibly even a nondisplaced fracture given her age and osteoporotic bone, but whatever this was, it has resolved almost entirely, she is functioning well, and there is no apparent problem, so I will see her back as needed.   



__________________________ 

Yoel Newcomb, M.D.  

 

CC:  Dustin T. Michael, M.D.

       SBH - IMA

       YRUK 7  

 

DD:10/24/2088 

DT:10/25/2088 

VT:32367     :9154 

 





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-03-29





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

SOUTH BAY HOSPITAL



Major Problems

Diabetes mellitus

She takes Glucotrol 5 mg BID in addition to Avandia 4 mg PO QD and a Glucophage 500 mg PO BID.  Her last hemoglobin A1c was 7%.  She saw her eye doctor last year who recommended seeing her in another two years.  She is on Lipitor. 

  O:  Examination below. 

  A:  Type 2 diabetes. 

P:  Repeat hemoglobin A1c with microalbumin.  She is on Cozaar.



add: A1C 3/23/90 8%.  increase glucophage to 1000mg po bid. 



Change in therapies and Renewals

Glucophage 1000 mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 2/16/2086 take with meals



Signed electronically by   Dana  Michael MD  on  Mar 30, 2090     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-02-04



Oconnell, Philip D

Internal Medicine Associates, Suite Y

Mount San Rafael Hospital, 2nd Floor , Room 205

Snowflake, HI, 99981-2297



		RE: PATRICIA  YOUNT

2/04/2092

Admission Note

HPI: 73 year old woman with hypertension, DM, peripheral vascular disease presents with dyspnea on exertion for 2 days. Th patient was well and normally active with walking and usual activities without DOE until 2 days ago. Last routine visit was in 9/91 w/ her PCP and was fine. 2 days ago noted DOE when going to store. This persisted w/ activity only. The patient was fine at rest and was able to sleep without difficulty. There were no recent changes in her meds. She had no other symptoms including CP, dizziness, URI symptoms, fever, chills, GI symptoms. No PND, orthopnea.



She previously had a cardiac evaluation during a similar presentation in 2085. She had a low level stress test and echocardiogram. No ischemia was demonstrated at a very minimal exertion. The echo showed LVH and an EF of 61%. Because of an impending snow storm, she decided to come to the hospital for evaluation. In the ED her BP was elevated and her 02 sat was only 78% on RA.



PMH:

1. Diabetes mellitus: on medical regimen, HgA1c 7.3 (9/91).



2. Hypertension: Blood pressure is 140/72.  Echocardiogram 12/85 - EF 61%, LVH. ETT 12/85 - 4 METS, no wall motion abnormalities.



3. Hypercholesterolemia: on Lipitor 10, LDL 78 (4/91).



4. Peripheral vascular disease: arterial studies 10/90 - left SFA occlusion, and bilateral distal popliteal/ tibial

vessel disease.  She is well collateralized across the ankles at rest and poorly collateralized across the ankles post exercise.  Perfusion is adequate to the TM level, and poor to the digital level, bilaterally



5. Anemia: normocytic normochromic anemia with a normal SPEP and UPEP and iron studies. Baseline hematocrit of low 30's.



6. Obesity. 



7. Osteopenia with a history of right radial fracture.



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:

Tenormin 150mg po bid

Glucotrol 5mg PO as directed 2 tab po qam, 1 tab po qpm Cozaar 100mg po QD

hydrochlorothiazide 50mg po qd 1 tab po qd

Lipitor 10mg po QD

Norvasc 10mg po qd

Glucophage 1000 mg po bid take with meals

Avandia 4 mg PO QD

buffered aspirin 325mg po qd

vitamin d2 800 iu po qd



ALLERGIES: No known drug allergy.



SOCIAL HISTORY: Lives in Glencoe. Has one son. Originally from Clearlake. Previously worked as a engineer at IBM research, retried a few yrs ago. Exercises twice a wk for 1/2 hour, aerobic exercises and treadmill at the gym.



FAMILY HISTORY: Father has DM. One sister diabetes father - diabetes. Sister - diabetes..



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Negative in detail except as otherwise noted.



PE:

GEN: WD, BF in NAD.

VS: BP 115/53, HR 55 reg, temp 97.7, 02 sat 97% 2L, RR18

HEENT: anicteric, oropharynx neg.

NECK: supple, no JVD.

CHEST: fine crackles 1/3 bilaterally, no dullness to percussion.

COR: reg, s1, s2 normal w/o s3, s4, m.

ABD: soft, NT, large, no mass.

EXTR: no c/c/e, 2+ pulses.

SKIN: no lesions noted.

NEURO: A&Ox3, nonfocal.



LABS ON ADMISSION:

02/04/92 Sodium (Stat Lab) 128 L, 

02/04/92 Potassium (Stat Lab) 3.8, 

02/04/92 Chloride (Stat Lab) 96 L, 

02/04/92 CO2 (Stat Lab) 25.8, 

02/04/92 Transaminase-SGPT 18, 

02/04/92 Transaminase-SGOT 30, 

02/04/92 Alkaline Phosphatase 80, 

02/04/92 Total Bilirubin 0.7, 

02/04/92 Albumin 4.3, 

02/04/92 Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes NEGATIVE, 

02/04/92 Troponin-I NEGATIVE, 

02/04/92 BUN (Stat Lab) 27 H, 

02/04/92 Calcium 9.8, 

02/04/92 Creatinine (Stat Lab) 1.1, 

02/04/92 Glucose (Stat Lab) 200 H, 

02/04/92 Magnesium 1.6, 

02/04/92 Phosphorus 3.1, 

02/04/92 WBC 7.1, 

02/04/92 HCT 30.7 L, 

02/04/92 PLT 277, 

02/04/92 Superstat PT 13.0, 

02/04/92 Superstat APTT 29.1, 

02/04/92 NT-proBNP 1086 H



CXR (AP): No radiographic evidence of an acute cardiopulmonary process.



CT chest/abd/pelvis: 1. No evidence for pulmonary embolus to the level of the segmental pulmonary arteries.  However, evaluation of the pulmonary vasculature is suboptimal due to respiratory motion. 2. No evidence for deep venous thrombosis. 3. Small right pleural effusion. 4. Intravenous contrast noted within the hepatic veins which could be secondary to CHF.



EKG: NSR, LVH, 1st degree AVB, nonspecific ST, TW changes.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN: 73 year old woman with hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidemia who presents with exertional dyspnea. The patient's history, exam and CXR are not consistent with CHF. The CT scan r/o PE and may be consistent w/ failure, but not clear. More likely would be ischemia and is ruling out for an MI. Clearly needs cardiac reassessment with echo and ETT. Last ETT in 2085 but was normal at a very low level of exertion. Finally, could this be a primary pulmonary process? If her 02 sat of 78% in the ED is true, this should be pursued if cardiac evaluation is negative. Specifically could she have an interstitial pulmonary process corresponding to imaging and exam w/ fine crackles. Arguing against this is the acuteness of her symptoms. Continue current regimen w/ holding Avandia and metformin.



Page #96082



Signed electronically by Oconnell, Philip D on Feb 05, 2092     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-08-02



Michael, Dana

Internal Medicine Associates, Wuite K

Mount San Rafael Hospital, 2nd Floor , Room 205

Snowflake, HI, 99981-2297

		RE: PATRICIA  YOUNT

8/2/2092

Admission Note

cc: SOB

HPI: please refer to prior d/c summaries (April and May 2092) for details of PMHx.  Patricia is a 73 yo female from Clearlake with a recent diagnosis of pulmonary venoocclusive disease by bx in 4/92 with chronic hypoxia on n/c oxygen, diastolic dysfunction, HTN, diabetes, chronic renal insufficiency and hyperlipidemia.  She was discharged from SBH in 4/92 and had spent some time at PMSC prior to that.  Has been doing fairly well at home over the last few months but presented with increasing shortness of breath. Denies chest pain,n/v/f/chills/cough, new orthopnea or edema or wt gain. She'd been seen 2-3 weeks ago in the ED with similar symptoms and was successfully treated with IV lasix and sent home.  Yesterday she was admitted to ED obs unit but because of persistent hypoxia and concern she is being transfered to medical service. 



In ED/obs unit given IV lasix, albuterol (stopped d/t short run of Vtach).



PMHx:

as above,

popliteal aneurysm

mild anemia (chronic dz)

osteopenia s/p right radial fracture





Medications:

Cozaar 100mg po QD

free text medications install two holders for o2 tanks on w/c (e-tanks)

Norvasc 10mg po qd

Glucophage 1000 mg po bid take with meals

vitamin d2 800 iu po qd

Lasix 80 mg po qd

Coumadin 2.5 mg po qpm 4 tabs po qhs

hydralazine 100mg po qid

Protonix 40 mg po qd do not cut/crush/chew

potassium chloride 20meq po qd

Ativan 0.5mg po q6-8h PRN anxiety

glyburide 5mg po qd take with breakfast or first meal

carvedilol 3.125mg po bid

simvastatin 10mg po qpm



Allergies:

No known drug allergy







Family history:

Father has DM. One sister diabetes father - diabetes. Sister - diabetes..



Social history:

Lives in Glencoe. Has one son -- recently died. Originally from Clearlake. Previously worked as a engineer in IBM research, retried a few yrs ago. On chronic nasal canula oxygen at home 3 l/min.  Able to get around house and out occasionally.



ROS: otherwise negative



Exam 11:34am

GEN: comfy appearing, not tachypneic above baseline

VITALS:96.8, P88 NSR, R20, 95% on 3.5l, BP 125/80

HEENT: no elevated neck veins, op clear, large tongue

NECK: supple no goitre, lad

CHEST: fine crackes both bases (chronic) no wheezes/ronchi

CVS: RRR no m/r/g

ABD: obsese, s/nt/nd, nl BS, no mass or organomegaly

EXT: no edema.

CNS: wnl







Selected Recent Labs: 08/01/92 Sodium (Stat Lab) 132 L, 08/01/92 Potassium (Stat Lab) 4.5, 08/01/92 Chloride (Stat Lab) 101, 08/01/92 CO2 (Stat Lab) 24.7, 08/01/92 Transaminase-SGPT 89 H, 08/01/92 Transaminase-SGOT 54 H, 08/01/92 Alkaline Phosphatase 108 H, 08/01/92 Total Bilirubin 0.9, 08/01/92 Direct Bilirubin 0.1, 08/01/92 Total Protein 8.5 H, 08/01/92 Albumin 4.4, 08/01/92 Globulin 4.1, 08/02/92 Creatine Kinase 64, 08/02/92 Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes 2.0, 08/02/92 CPK Isoenzymes Index , 08/01/92 Amylase 120 H, 08/02/92 Calcium 9.6, 08/01/92 Creatinine (Stat Lab) 1.6 H, 08/01/92 Glucose (Stat Lab) 175 H, 08/01/92 Lipase 6.8 H, 08/02/92 Magnesium 1.8, 08/01/92 HCT 31.5 L, 08/01/92 HGB 10.9 L, 08/01/92 RBC 3.50 L, 08/01/92 PLT 205, 08/01/92 MCV 90, 08/01/92 MCH 31.3, 08/01/92 MCHC 34.8, 08/01/92 RDW 18.0 H, 08/01/92 DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST RECEIVED, 08/01/92 Aniso 1+ H, 08/01/92 Hypo None, 08/01/92 Macrocytes None, 08/01/92 Microcytes None, 08/02/92 PT 42.2 H, 08/01/92 Superstat APTT 38.8 H, 08/01/92 UA-Glucose NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 UA-Ketones NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 UA-Specific Gravity 1.015, 08/01/92 UA-Occult Blood NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 UA-pH 5.0, 08/01/92 UA-Albumin 2+, 08/01/92 UA-Nitrite NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 UA-WBC Screen NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 Hyaline Cast 0-2, 08/01/92 UA-SED-RBC 0-2, 08/01/92 UA-SED-WBC 0-2, 08/01/92 UA-SED-Bacteria NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 Squamous Cells NEGATIVE, 08/01/92 EOS 3, 08/01/92 Basos 0, 08/01/92 Lymphs 14 L, 08/01/92 Monos 3 L, 08/01/92 Absolute EOS 0.24, 08/01/92 Absolute Basos 0.03, 08/01/92 Absolute Lymphs 1.04, 08/01/92 Absolute Monos 0.23, 08/01/92 Poly 80 H, 08/01/92 Absolute Neuts 5.93, 08/01/92 Diff Method Auto, 08/01/92 NT-proBNP 263



CXR: 1.  Small bilateral pleural effusions and mild interstitial pulmonary edema, consistent with CHF. 2.  No radiographic evidence of pneumonia.





EKG: no ischemic changes



Impression:  pulmonary veno occulsive disease, diastolic dysfunction with mild CHF exacerbation.  Her resting O2 sats are back to baseline and she does not appear to be in significant decompensated failure.  Unfortunately, we don't have much more to offer her in the way of cure (she has declined other interventions with pulmonlogist), as this is generally a terminal illness.



Plan:



--admit to medicine for further obs on tele.

--complete cycling enzymes

--continue outpatient lasix dose.

--adjust n/c oxygen as needed

--pulm/pt rehab consult -- pt has declined inpt rehab, but whatever might be offered as outpt would be helpful.

--i will speak with her re: potential for hospice care since she has declined inpt rehab at last and with this admission.  This might help forgo further hosptilizations with similar treatment at home.

--Continue DM treatment w/ glucophage/glyburide.

--anticipate d/c in 1-2 days.

-- pls offer pneumovax if she'll accept it.

-- hold coumadin, recheck INR (pls have anticoag clinic leave note with dosing of coumadin)

-- OOB to chair, ambulate with assistance.



Signed electronically by Michael, Dana on Aug 2, 2092     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>