<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2084-10-19







                                                                                                                                   Mae Paul

                                                                                                                                   LMC# 100-57-08










LMC SURGERY

CLINIC NOTE   October 19, 2084







CC:

Consult for hemorrhoids.  



HPI:

This is a 73-year-old female.  Five- to six-year history constant anal protrusion and bloody discharge and mucus nearly constantly (wears a pad).  No anal pain.  Usually has 1-2 BMs a day, solid or liquid (her chronic pattern).  No abdominal pain or weight loss.  No history STD.  No rectal surgery.  Status post left and right kidney transplants 2078 and 2075, which have failed.  Status post supracervical hysterectomy (no BSO) for benign disease.  Status post appendectomy.  4/82 underwent left salpingo-oophorectomy for serous cyst (Dr. Sutton).  No other abdominal OPs.  8/81 she was treated for CMV colitis.  No FH colon neoplasms.  



PFSH:

Chronic renal failure from glomerulonephritis.  Has had two failed transplants as above.  Now on dialysis every Monday, Wednesday and Friday.  On waiting list for another transplant at EHCC.  



Hypertension.  



Spinal stenosis and sciatica.  



Lower extremity PVD.  This was shown on angio 9/83 (Dr. Xayasane), but she denies claudication.  



Right foot-drop due to shingles.  



Hypercholesterolemia.  



Ectopic beats as below.  



Nonsmoker.  



She takes Pravachol 40 mg q.p.m., PhosLo 1300 mg t.i.d.-q.i.d., Sensipar 30 mg daily (for calcium), Restoril 30 mg q.h.s., Neurontin 900 mg every Monday, Wednesday, Friday, Norvasc 10 mg b.i.d., Nephrocaps one tablet daily, plus vitamins.  No allergies.  



Retired Mathematician at Vassar.  Widow.  Lives alone.  Has daughter in the area (an surgeon).  



PE:

Appears a little frail.  No neck masses or bruits.  Chest clear.  Heart:  Frequent ectopic beats.  4/6 systolic murmur.  Mild abdominal adiposity.  Palpable LLQ kidney.  No other masses or organomegaly.  Groins normal.  No pedal edema.  3/4 femoral pulses, with nothing below.  Large non-thrombosed permanently prolapsed right anterior internal hemorrhoid and associated large external hemorrhoid.  Moderate external hemorrhoids elsewhere.  Digital rectal exam normal.  Anoscopy shows large internal hemorrhoids.  







                                                                                                                                   Mae Paul

                                                                                                                                   LMC# 100-57-08










Flexible sigmoidoscopy to 25 cm (sigmoid) normal except mild diverticulosis.  



IMPRESSION:

Large symptomatic hemorrhoids.  They are too big for office treatment.  Therefore discussed the option of hemorrhoidectomy, which would probably give her a nice result.  She wishes to think about it for now, however, which is fine.  In the meantime, gave her info brochure plus instructions in conservative RX hemorrhoids.  



Thomas Y. Ontiveros, M.D.



cc:	Jack John, M.D., LMC

	Harvey Ethridge, M.D., LMC

	E. K. Sutton, M.D., LMC

Herman Lemus, M.D., EHCC



TYO/ellington		04-14609701.doc





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-12-27

 



JAR Night-float Admission Note

Internal Medicine



Patient: 			Mae Paul	

MRN: 			1005708

Date of admission:	12/27/2084

Renal Attending:		Dr. John



Cc: cough, SOB, failed Z-pk x2



HPI: 

Pt is a 73yo female with ESRD on HS s/p kidney transplant x2.  She has had a cough for over the past week.  No fever; no sputum production. Also reports 1 day of sore throat, now resolved and nasal congestion forh te past week.  Her grandson (age 4) has had a cough/head cold.  Her daughter is a surgeon and has prescribed her a Z-pk x 2 which she has failed and yesterday gave her a dose of levaquin 500mg on 12/26/2084. Last HD on 12/22; missed on 12/25.

	On presentation to the ED her Vs were: T=97.9 P=118 BP=173/93 sat=91%RA. Saturations decreased to 91%on 4L in setting of SBP to 221/119.  She was treated with IV lopressor 2.5 x2 and lopressor 12.5 po. Saturation improved to 95%4L. Renal team evaluated her and she will have dialysis this am. She was admitted to floor for further evaluation.



ROS: as above. No chest pain.? Wheezing today. + SOB. No N/V/D. No rashes. No HA, muscle aches. + fatigue/generalized weakness.



PMH:	

1.	ESRD 2/2 GN on HD; Status post left and right kidney transplants 2078 and 2075, which have failed. Off immunosuppressive for the past 4 years.

2.	Htn

3.	PVD: Lower extremity PVD.  This was shown on angio 9/83 (Dr. Xayasane), but she denies claudication.  

4.	R foot drop  due to shingles

5.	hemorrhoids: Five- to six-year history constant anal protrusion and bloody discharge and mucus nearly constantly (wears a pad).  No anal pain. No rectal surgeries.

6.	Status post supracervical hysterectomy (no BSO) for benign disease. 4/82 underwent left salpingo-oophorectomy for serous cyst (Dr. Sutton).

7.	Status post appendectomy.  

8.	8/81 she was treated for CMV colitis.

9.	Spinal stenosis and sciatica.  



Current Meds: daughter not present; need to verigy meds/doses

  	Pravachol

  	Norvasc

  	Phoslo

  	Nephrocaps

  	Neurontin



Allergies:

Vasotec

tape



Fam Hx:

NC



Social History:

Retired Mathematician at Vassar.  Widow.  Lives alone.  Has daughter in the area (a surgeon).

No smoking.



Physical Examination:

Exam:  	VS:	T=99.7	HR=101 	BP=159/88	RR=22	SaO2= 92%6LRA

General:  

HEENT: NC/AT,  PERRL, anicteric. OP w/ DMM, no erythema or injection.

Skin:	No rashes

Neck:  	Supple, 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no thyromegaly or nodules, no nodes

Chest: 	inspiratory crackles in right lower and mid lung fields, left side clear, no wheezing

CVS:  	RRR nl S1 S2, no m/r/g

Abd:  	nl BS, soft, non-tender

Extr:  	no c/c/e 2+ DP's bilaterally

Neuro:  AAOX3, MS nl  



Data:

Chemistries:

          	12/27/84  	12/26/84  

          	00:46     	16:08     

NA        	139       	138       	          	          	          

K         	4.9(H)    	5.6(H)    	          	          	          

CL        	100       	95(L)     	          	          	          

CO2       	24.4      	21.8(L)   	          	          	          

BUN       	122(H)    	110(H)    	          	          	          

CRE       	12.7(H)   	11.7(H)   	          	          	          

GLU       	100       	109       	



          	12/26/84  

          	16:08     

CA        	10.1      	          	          	          	          

PHOS      4.0       	          	          	          	          

MG        	2.1(H)    	          	          	          	          

TBILI     	0.3       	          	          	          	          

DBILI     	0.1       	          	          	          	          

TP        	8.1       	          	          	          	          

ALB       	3.7       	          	          	          	          

GLOB      	4.4(H)    	          	          	          	          

AMY       	114(H)    	          	          	          	          

LIPS      	3.9       



          	12/26/84  

          	16:08     

ALT/SGPT  	12        	          	          	          	          

AST/SGOT  	21        	          	          	          	          

ALKP      	221(H)    	          	          	          	          

TBILI     	0.3       	          	          	          	          

DBILI     	0.1      



          	12/26/84  

          	16:08     

CHOL      189(T)    	          	          	          	          

TRIG      	224(H)    	          	          	          	          

HDL       	65        	          	          	          	          



Heme:

          	12/26/84  

          	15:52     

WBC       	8.1       	          	          	          	          

HCT       	37.7      	          	          	          	          

MCV       	81        	          	          	          	          

PLT       	326       	          	          	          	          

METHOD    	Auto      	          	          	          	          

%NEUT     	81(H)     	          	          	          	          



Studies:

CXR: PA and lateral chest 12/26/2084

Comparison: 6/15/84.

There are small bilateral pleural effusions.  There is a new right  lower the lobe opacity which appears to the heart border.  This likely represents a right middle lobe pneumonia. There is atherosclerotic calcification of a tortuous aorta.  The heart is enlarged.  The mediastinal flow is unremarkable.  There is stable mild wedge compression deformity and sclerosis of the thoracic spine.



EKG: NSR, nl interval, nl axis, resolved TWI isolated to III



Assessment/Plan: 73yo female with ESRD presents with SB/ cough and RML pna on CXR.

1)	PNA: levo 250 qod; RML lobe on CXR. Check sputum/blood Cx. Rapid flu neg; on precautions until final.

2)	ESRD: Renal aware; HD in am 12/27; CA-phos product<50; cont phoslo.

3)	CV:

Ischemia: ? dynamic TWI: cycle enzymes, asa/ lopressor/ pravachol

Pump: EF=66%; HD in am; lopressor/ norvac for BP

4)	FEN: s/p kayexcelate in ed; watch K

5)	Proph: Nexium, heparin

6)	CODE: full







_____________________________

Elinor Keenan #10985





      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-03-06

 


Ravenna Medical Clinic RMC
7785 Marlowe Street              PAUL, MAE
Barnesville, TN  13351                    83288425
(665) 578-7821                     03/06/2087


CHIEF COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 75-year-old woman, new patient who comes in to establish primary care and for followup of multiple medical problems including end-stage renal disease, hypertension, peripheral vascular disease, history of foot drop, etc.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:
1.  End-stage renal disease.  Because of her original end-stage renal disease was reportedly FSGS, she had a preemptive transplant in 2068, which was complicated by rejection and ultimate loss of the graft.  She resumed dialysis in 2072.  She had a second transplant in 2075, which was also complicated and ultimately rejected.  She resumed hemodialysis in 2082.  She does have a match with her only daughter, but apparently the Transplant Service feels that she would not be a good candidate and I think she would be reluctant to go through two surgeries, which would be required, one to remove the old graft and one for the new transplant.  She currently is dialyzed at the Overbrook Hospital.  Her dialysis physician is Dr. Lemus.
2.  Hypertension.
3.  Peripheral vascular disease.  She had an angiogram in 2083 at LMC and an MRA in 2085, which showed bilateral iliac and femoral artery stenoses.  She apparently does not have claudication despite this.
4.  History of right foot-drop.  She had a severe episode of shingles in 2077 with associated sciatica and foot-drop.
5.  History of hemorrhoids for at least six years with occasional bleeding and with anal protrusion.
6.  History of CMV colitis in 08/2081.
7.  Secondary hyperparathyroidism.  She is on Sensipar and has been on this since early 2085.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  She had a supracervical hysterectomy for benign disease in 2061 and a left salpingo-oophorectomy for a serous cyst in 04/2082.  She is status post appendectomy.  She is status post bilateral cataract surgery.

MEDICATIONS:  Norvasc 10 mg per day, lisinopril 20 mg per day, metoprolol 50 mg b.i.d., Lipitor 40 mg per day, aspirin 81 mg per day, Nephrocaps 1 mg per day, Restoril 15 mg nightly, Hectorol 4 mcg per 2 mL three times per week, B6 200 mg per day, vitamin E 400 mg per day, flaxseed oil 1000 mg per day and B12 4000 mcg per day.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Significant for diabetes in her father and grandfather, negative for cancer.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She is a widow.  She is a lifetime nonsmoker.  She does not drink alcohol or use drugs.  She is a retired mathematician at Vassar.  She came from Turlock 10 years ago to Pecos to be with her daughter who is a surgeon in the area.  She never has felt the Pecos as home and is home sick for Turlock.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She has had some problems with left shoulder pain and immobility.  She generally seems to be somewhat overwhelmed and a little bit sad.  She seems never to have adjusted to life in Pecos.  She has had the loss of two the kidney transplants and then the foot-drop, which has made walking difficult.  She did have a brace at one time, which helped her to walk, but it was irritating.  She had seen Dr. Yim to get another one, but that never worked out.  She did not complain of any chest pain or shortness of breath, no constipation.  She does have hemorrhoids that are active as above.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is a well-developed, well-nourished, very pleasant, but somewhat sad-appearing white female.  Her blood pressure is 140/60.  HEENT, pupils equal, round and reactive to light.  Extraocular movements are intact.  Throat is clear.  Neck, supple, no adenopathy or thyromegaly.  Heart, regular rate and rhythm.  Lungs, clear.  Abdomen, soft, nontender, no organomegaly.  Extremities, no edema.  Neuro, absent reflex in the right patella and 2+ in the left patella.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:
1.  End-stage renal disease on dialysis, not considered to be a transplant candidate at this time as she has had two rejections.
2.  Hypertension, well controlled on medications.
3.  Hyperlipidemia, on Lipitor.  Last cholesterol was checked in 10/2086 with normal ALT and AST, but elevated alkaline phosphatase.
4.  Peripheral vascular disease, currently asymptomatic.
5.  Right foot-drop.  We may look into getting her another brace perhaps another consult with Dr. Yim.
6.  Left shoulder pain.  It did mention in her physical, but she can only abduct her left shoulder to about 90 degrees without pain.  We may look into this further and perhaps get some physical therapy for possible rotator cuff tendinitis.
7.  Hemorrhoids.
8.  Secondary hyperparathyroidism on Sensipar.
9.  Health maintenance.  Mammogram was done in 06/2086.  Pap smear was done in 04/2083.  Colonoscopy was done in 08/2081.
10.  ? Depression.  She seemed a little sad.  Has had a tough time with her medical problems and never adjusted that well to Pecos.  Will have her come back and discuss further.


______________________________
Qiana Solomon, MD





eScription document:9-2784353 KUQlhv Egq



DD: 03/06/87
DT: 03/07/87
DV: 03/06/87



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-03-29

Internal Medicine INTERN ADMISSION NOTE
PATIENT FH MRN: 57585291
ATTENDING: Dr. Olivia Perry
PRIMARY CARE: Dr. Qiana Solomon, Emmons Health Counseling Center, 665-578-7821
HCP: Quanita-Ella Paul-Doyle (daughter),: 448-876-4285


CC: Left thigh pain, inability to ambulate


HPI:  77F with ESRD (secondary to FSGS) on HD (Monday,Wednesday,Friday) s/p two failed renal transplants (2068, 2075), severe lumbar spinal stenosis and left thigh tendonitis presenting with worsening of chronic left thigh pain and inability to ambulate x3 days.


Patient with a history of left thigh pain since 6/2088. MRI showed tendinosis with parial tears of the hangstrings. Patient did not follow up with ortho or PT and managed pain at home with NSAIDs and Tylenol 3. Admitted again on 12/2088 with increasing pain. MRI showed severe lumbar spinal stenosis at L4-S1. Orthopedics consult recommended epidural steroids and physiatry follow up given that patient is a poor surgical candidate. Neuro posited possible uremic neuroapthy. She had one epidural steroid injection along with low dose gabapentin, lidocain patch, and oxycontin and oxycodone prn which relieved her pain. She was to follow up with the Pain Clinic at EHCC but did not and had no further epidural steroid injections. Patient managing well at home on oxycontin and oxycodone when she developed acute worsening of her left thigh pain on 3/27. She denied any prior trauma. Noticed onset of pain while lying flat at dialysis on 3/27. No numbness or tingling. No bowel incontinence. Pain is a stabbing, 10/10 pain. No redness in area of  pain. Worsening over past 3 days.


Patient seen after HD on 3/27 for ulcer over left AVF found at HD on 3/27. Completed HD without incident and got a dose of vancomycin. Wound culture sent and growing staph aureus. Started on PO Keflex and discharged home. Pain worsened at home. Patient took 20mg oxycodone IR, 10mg oxycontin, and 2mg dildaudid with minimal relief of pain.


No f/c/n/v/abdominal pain/BRBPR/diarrhea. Patient is anuric.


ED Course: Vitals notable for BP 164/100 (patient had not taken her BP meds). No medications administered. Labs notable for creatinine of 7.7.


PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:
-ESRD (FSGS) on HD Mon,Wed,Fri s/p failed renal transplants in 2068 and 2075
- HTN 
- PVD
- HLD
- Foot drop on R side (11yrs ago)
- Secondary Hyperparathyroidism
- Hemorrhoids
- Spinal stenosis L4-L5
- s/p appendectomy
- s/p TAH
- s/p cataract surgery
- s/p ovarian cyst removal
- carpal tunnel syndrome


ALLERGIES:  Enalapril


CURRENT MEDICATIONS:
Amlodipine 10 MG (10MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #1 Month(s) Supply, QSun,Mon,Wed,Fri
Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO 
Dilaudid (HYDROMORPHONE HCL) 1 MG (2MG TABLET Take 0.5) PO Q6H PRN pain x 30 days, note to pharmacist: please provide pt with brand-name version. #60 Tablet(s)
Keflex (CEPHALEXIN) 250 MG (250MG CAPSULE Take 1) PO as directed , please take 250mg orally after dialysis for 10d. #6 Capsule(s)
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 40 MG (40MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS #3 Month(s) Supply
Lisinopril 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS, 40mg QAM
Nephrocaps 1 CAPSULE PO QD 
Oxycodone 5 MG (5MG TABLET Take 1) PO 4-6 hrs PRN #540 Tablet(s)
Oxycontin (OXYCODONE CONTROLLED RELEASE) 10 MG (10MG TAB.SR 12H Take 1) PO BID #20 TAB.SR
Restoril (TEMAZEPAM) 30 MG (15MG CAPSULE Take 2) PO QHS PRN #180 Capsule(s)
Sensipar (CINACALCET) 30 MG PO BID 
Toprol XL (METOPROLOL SUCCINATE EXTENDED RELEASE) 150 MG (50MG TAB.SR 24H ) PO QD x 90 days #3 month(s) Supply


FH:- DM: father, brother- HTN: mother, father, brother- PVD: father, brother- CAD/CABG: brothers x2, in 60s- no cancer, sudden cardiac deathSH:- lives with daughter, who is a surgeon- formerly worked in mathmatics- does not smoke, drink etoh, or use any illicit drugsADMISSION EXAM:
VS: T 95.4 P 71, BP 132/60, RR 18, 97% on 2L
GENERAL: Frail, elderly woman in NAD
HEENT: MM dry, no cervical or supraclavicular lymphadenopathy, OP clear
CARDIO: RRR. Mid-peaking II/VI cres-decres murmur at RUSB radiating to clavicles bilaterally, Holosystolic II/VI murmur at apex
PULM: CTAB
ABD: Soft, NT, ND, +BSEXTREM: No c/c/e. Left arm fistula with shallow ulcer, no discharge or odor.
NEURO: 5/5 strength in LE with sensation to light touch in tact. Right foot drop.  Pain on abduction and straight leg raise of 40 degrees. No tenderness along trochanteric bursa. Near full ROM at the hip.


ADMISSION LABS:03/29/2089 NA 142,  K 4.6,  CL 99,  CO2 31,  BUN 65 (H),  CRE 7.7 (H),  GLU 9403/29/2089 CA 9.1,  TBILI 0.4,  TP 7.2,  ALB 2.9 (L)03/27/2089 CA 9.9,  PHOS 3.9,  MG 1.903/29/2089 ALT/SGPT 24,  AST/SGOT 15,  ALKP 130,  TBILI 0.403/29/2089 WBC 7.7,  RBC 4.84,  HGB 11.0 (L),  HCT 38.1,  MCV 79 (L),  MCH 22.7 (L),  MCHC 28.8 (L),  PLT 444 (H)03/29/2089 RDW 19.1 (H)03/29/2089 %NEUT 66.6,  %MONO 5.2,  %EOS 3.1,  %BASO 0.6,  %LYMPH-M 24.5 (L)03/29/2089 ANISO ++,  HYPO +++,  MICRO ++03/29/2089 PT 17.2 (H),  PT-INR 1.5 (H),  PTT 30.4 (H)Microbiology  Specimen: 82:F9402026Y          Collected 27-Mar-89 09:23                                                  Received  27-Mar-89 09:23                  Ordering Provider: LEMUS, HERMAN DR MD  Specimen Group:    BLOOD/SERUM  Specimen Type:     BLOOD  BLOOD CULTURE - Preliminary    Reported: 28-Mar-89 09:00    NO GROWTH TO DATE   Specimen: 38:Z8912708G          Collected 27-Mar-89 09:23                                                  Received  27-Mar-89 09:23                  Ordering Provider: LEMUS, HERMAN DR MD  Specimen Group:    TISSUE/BIOPSY/WOUND  Specimen Type:     FISTULA  Specimen Comment: WOUND CULTURE FROM AV FISTULA  GRAM STAIN - Final    Reported: 28-Mar-89 16:02    GRAM STAIN RESULTS  RARE POLYS                        MODERATE GRAM POSITIVE COCCI      WOUND CULTURE - Preliminary    Reported: 28-Mar-89 11:56    MANY Staph aureus      COMMENTS  SUSCEPTIBILITY TO FOLLOW 

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  77F with ESRD on HD and severe spinal stenosis, tendinosis, and left thigh muscle tears presenting with acute worsening of her chronic left thigh pain.


#) Left thigh pain: No recent trauma or clear trigger for exacerbation. No fevers or fluctuance on exam concerning for infection. 
-doubt imaging will change management as this is most likely secondary to known spinal stenosis
-augment PO pain regimen and, accordingly, bowel regimen
-PT consult, will likely need rehab


#) ESRD-Due for HD tomorrow
-HD in the AM
-continue renal meds


#) AVF ulcer: Growing staph aureus
-f/u sensitivities
-continue PO Keflex


#) HTN
-continue lisinopril, BB, 


#) CV:
-continue ASA, BB, statin
#) PPX: heparin sc


#) CODE: FULL




__________________________
Collette M. Kirkland, MD
EHCC Intern
 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-04-30

EDVISIT^83288425^PAUL, MAE^04/30/90^CORTES, ODESSA

The patient was seen in conjunction with resident, Dr. Peacock. 

Resident's note was reviewed.  The patient was seen and examined

by me.  Please see the resident's note for details of the

patient's past medical, social, family history, review of

systems, and physical exam.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Bleeding fistula.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 78-year-old woman with

end-stage renal disease, on hemodialysis, who is here with

bleeding of her left upper arm AV fistula that she uses for

dialysis that started today at dialysis.  When the patient pulled

up her sleeve, she scratched herself and it began to bleed. 

Blood pressure is 112/60.  The bleeding can be controlled with

compression and so she presented to the Emergency Department

where she was seen by the Internal Medicine for repair.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  The patient has a history of severe aortic

stenosis with 0.7 cm greater diameter, mitral regurg and

tricuspid regurg, end-stage renal disease on hemodialysis, PVD,

foot drop, anemia, sciatica, left thigh pain, hyperlipidemia,

secondary hyperparathyroidism, hemorrhoids, coronary artery

disease status post non-ST elevation MI, CHF with an EF of

35-40%.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Includes a TAH, appendectomy, cataract

surgery, ovarian cyst removal.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Never smoked, does not drink or use drugs.  She

is retired, lives with her daughter who is a surgeon.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Shows an extensive vascular history.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile, normal and stable vital

signs.  She has bilaterally faintly scattered rales on chest

examination and she has a small laceration on the left arm over

the fistula with an excoriation and this squirting blood would

not controlled with pressure.

LABORATORY DATA:  CBC is normal with a hematocrit of 43.  Chem-7

is otherwise normal.  Coags reveal an INR of 1.4.  Chest x-ray

shows no acute disease.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  She was seen by surgery who repair

her fistula.  She is due to go to dialysis now and due to sickle

nature of her disease, I think it is best that she keep her

dialysis appointment and so she is transferred from here with her

daughter to the EHCC Dialysis Unit to undergo full dialysis.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSES:  Bleeding aVF and end-stage renal disease.

DISPOSITION:  She is discharged in satisfactory condition.

______________________________

CORTES, ODESSA M.D.

D: 04/30/90

T: 04/30/90

Dictated By: CORTES, ODESSA

eScription document:5-52221754 FVQtwry

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>