<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2071-08-21

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

August 21, 2071

 

 

 

Aiden Geiger, M.D. 

Friendship Villa Care Center

58 Hyannis Street

Sioux City,  FL  76546

 

RE:  Vivian Lea Jorgenson

     MR#471-90-84-7

 

Dear Dr. Geiger:

 

Thank you for referring your patient, Victoria Carina Jorgenson to me for a

preoperative evaluation for thyroidectomy on September 17, 2071. 

As you know, she is a 64 year old woman with hypertension,

hyperlipidemia and a positive family history of coronary disease. 

She noticed a nodule in her neck in April or May of this year and

brought it to the attention of her doctors and given that it has

increased in size, it is felt to be a potential malignancy and

she is currently scheduled to undergo thyroidectomy in September

of this year.  In terms of her cardiac history, she was well

until four years ago when she developed acute shortness of breath

and was admitted to Lake Park Hospital for congestive heart

failure.  At that time, she had an exercise Thallium scan which

revealed a low work load at only 3 minutes stopping secondary to

shortness of breath with a large fixed anterolateral defect and a

dilated left ventricle.  In addition, she had an echo in June of

2071, which shows an ejection fraction of 25% with 1+ mitral

regurgitation, left atrial enlargement and diastolic dysfunction. 

She has never been hospitalized since that time for her

congestive heart failure and has been treated medically with good

result. She currently denies any orthopnea, PND, angina or

claudication.  She does have chronic mild lower extremity edema.

In fact, she has never had chest pain or chest pressure to her

recollection.  She is able to walk up the 10 stairs to her house

and can unload groceries from her car, up those stairs. She is

able to shop, walk through the grocery store without difficulty

from chest 

 

Jorgenson, Vivian Lea

MR #471-90-84-7               -2-            August 21, 2071

 

pains or shortness of breath, although she occasionally stops

secondary to fatigue.  

 

Her past medical history includes hypertension, hyperlipidemia,

CHF, chronic anxiety and this thyroid nodule. She has never had

surgery. Her family history is significant for a mother who died

of myocardial infarction at the age of 55. 

 

Her social history, she smoked 1-2 packs of cigarettes a day for

40 years and quit four years ago. She denies alcohol, intravenous

drugs or cocaine use.  She lives with her husband and briefly

worked in Amy's Baking Company but for the past 20 years is an electrical engineer.  She

has no known drug allergies. 

 

Her current medications include Labetalol 100mg po BID, Captopril

50 po TID, Digoxin 0.25mg po QD, Coumadin 5 po QD, Lipitor 10 po

QD, Lasix 40 po QD, Coreg 12.5 po BID, Nitroglycerin patch daily

and Gemfibrozil 600mg BID.  

 

On physical exam in my office, her blood pressure was 170/85 in

her left arm and 165/70 in her right. Her heart rate was 104 when

I saw her, although it was 80 on her EKG today. Her JVP was 7

centimeters. Her carotids were brisk upstrokes without carotid

bruits. Her chest is clear to auscultation without crackles. Her

heart has a non displaced PMI with a regular rate and rhythm with

occasional ectopic beats. She has a normal S1 and S2 with a 2/6

systolic ejection murmur at the left upper sternal border without

radiation. Her abdomen is soft with positive bowel sounds. Her

extremities have 2+ distal pulses and trace peripheral edema.  

 

Her EKG today is normal sinus rhythm at a rate of 80.  She has a

diffuse ST and T wave abnormality consistent with Digoxin

effects.  She has poor R wave progression consistent with an old

anterior septal MI but no acute ischemic changes.  

 

In summary, Ms. Jorgenson is a 64 year old woman with hypertension,

hyperlipidemia and a positive family history of coronary disease

with congestive heart failure with an ejection fraction of 25%,

likely secondary to coronary disease from an anterior myocardial

infarction, although she has never undergone heart

catheterization.  She is currently undergoing evaluation for a

thyroidectomy for a thyroid nodule. 

 

Jorgenson, Vivian Lea

MR #471-90-84-7               -3-            August 21, 2071

 

Issue number one,  preoperative cardiovascular risk assessment: 

given that she has not had an assessment of her ischemic burden

since 2067, I have scheduled her for a repeat exercise test with

imaging. If this is similar to her previous study showing only

fixed defects and no reversible ischemia, then I feel that she

will be of low to moderate risk for surgery for perioperative

myocardial infarction and that her congestive heart failure is

well treated and therefore, will not preclude her from having

surgery.  

 

Issue number two, is her anticoagulation for low ejection

fraction.  She is currently on Coumadin for low ejection

fraction. As far as I know, she has never had atrial fibrillation

and she has never been told that she had an irregular rate or

rhythm.  Therefore, I recommend that she stop her Coumadin 6 days

prior to surgery and it can be restarted several days after

surgery without Heparin overlap at the discretion of the surgeons

as to how may days she should wait after surgery before

restarting that medication.  She will otherwise remain on her

current medical regimen as determined by her cardiologist and

primary care physician, Dr. Charles Van.  If her stress test

is without reversible defects, she need not follow up with me for

further evaluation.  

 

Thank you for referring this interesting patient. She was seen

and examined with Dr. Voss. 

 

Sincerely, 

 

 

 

Pamela Imperial, M.D. 

PI/waldron

 

cc:

Charles Van, M.D.

 

Jordan, FL  83712

 

 

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2071-11-24

 

 

Thyroid Division

Jeanes Memorial Hospital

89 Buck St

Sioux City, FL  76546

 

 

VivianLee Jorgenson

MR# 471-90-84-7

November 24, 2071

 

This is the first visit for Ms. Jorgenson who is a 64 year old woman who presents 

for management of papillary thyroid cancer.  Her symptoms began in May, 2071, 

when she felt a prominence in her neck.  She did not experience any dysphagia 

or voice changes, but presumably was felt to have an abnormality on thyroid 

examination.  She underwent a thyroid biopsy in June, 2071, at a local 

hospital.  The pathology which was read at JMH revealed numerous follicular 

cells with chromatin grooves suspicious for papillary carcinoma.  She was 

subsequently referred to Dr. Geiger at JMH for thyroidectomy and underwent 

thyroidectomy on 9/17/71.  The thyroidectomy was uncomplicated though there 

was inadvertent displacement of a parathyroid gland and this gland was then 

reimplanted.  According to the operative report, the carcinoma was felt to be 

locally extensive though no laryngo-tracheal nerve invasion was present.  The 

pathology revealed a (R) 6 cm papillary carcinoma with capsular and 

lymphovascular invasion.  There was an additional focus of papillary 

carcinoma, follicular variant, in the (L) thyroid lobe that was 0.3 cm.   Of 

note, the tissue was stained for calcitonin and this was negative.  The tumor 

did stain positively for thyroglobulin.  

 

Since undergoing thyroidectomy, Ms. Jorgenson has done fairly well.  She has been 

maintained on 75 mcg daily of Levoxyl.  She says that she feels generally 

well on this dose though she does endorse slight fatigue.  She denies any 

changes in her sleep, hair, skin or bowels.  She does endorse a one pound 

weight gain over the last two months.  She denies any paresthesias or other 

symptoms consistent with hypocalcemia.  She denies any history of thyroid 

disturbances prior to her diagnosis of cancer.  She is now referred for 

consideration of radioiodine ablation.  

 

Past Medical History:Notable for congestive heart failure.  She has an 

ejection fraction of 25%.  She also has a history of hypercholesterolemia, 

hypertension, and anxiety.  No history of childhood irradiation.  

 

Current Medications:Digoxin 0.25 daily; Coreg 12.5 mg daily; Levoxyl 75 

mcg daily; Lipitor 10 mg daily; Coumadin 5 mg daily; Lasix 40 mg daily; 

captopril 50 mg, tid; labetolol 100, bid; nitroglycerine.

 

Allergies:No known drug allergies.

 

Social History:Remote history of tobacco.  She quit 4 years ago.  She 

endorses rare alcohol use.  She is married with four children.  

 

Family History:Negative for thyroid cancer.  

 

Physical Exam:Blood pressure is elevated at 188/92.  Weight 208.  Pulse 

88.  In general this is a somewhat tired, slightly pale-appearing woman in 

NAD.  HEENT:  PERRLA.  EOMI.  No proptosis or lid lag.  Neck: supple with a 

large well-healed thyroidectomy scar.  No 

VivianLee Jorgenson

MR# 471-90-84-7

November 24, 2071

Page 2

 

remaining thyroid tissue or lymphadenopathy is appreciated.  Lungs: clear to 

auscultation bilaterally.  Cardiovascular: normal S1, S2, regular rate and 

rhythm.  Abdomen: soft, slightly distended, non-tender, moderately obese.  

Extremities: trace pedal edema, 1+ distal pulses.  Neurologic: reflexes are 

slightly delayed.  There is no tremor of outstretched hands.  

 

Review of Labs:Of note, include a TSH of 1.65 from August, 2071, that was 

prior to surgery.  Free T4 at that time was normal at 1.1.  Calcium prior to 

surgery was slightly elevated at 10.6 though several calciums drawn after her 

surgery were in the mid-8 range. 

 

Impression:This is a 64 year old woman with a history of congestive heart 

failure who is now s/p total thyroidectomy for papillary thyroid cancer.  Ms. 

Jorgenson is potentially at higher risk for recurrence given the fact that she is 

older at the time of diagnosis, she had a large-size tumor, and she had 

multifocal disease. 

 

Plan:Check a TSH and thyroglobulin today for a baseline.  We suspect that 

she may be undertreated on her current dose of Levoxyl.  I have recommended 

131I treatment.  Benefits and risks were discussed.  In addition, I think she 

would tolerate thyroid hormone withdrawal.  TSH and calcium were drawn today. 

 

We will plan to arrange  for 131I for January. 

 

 

 

 

Hilda Vincent, M.D.

 

 

 

Brittany Farrar, M.D.

 

 

 

BF/cooley

cc:Aiden Geiger, M.D.

 

 

_______________________________

Hilda Vincent

 

DD: 11/24/71

DT: 12/31/71

DV: 11/24/71

 

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-06-20


HHH Cardiovascular Division
CVD Rm 5
89 Buck St                                      JORGENSON, VIVIANLEE
Sioux City, FL 76546                                           47190847
(179) 732-8159                                           06/20/74


Charles F. Van, M.D.
66 Kessler Farm Drive, Puite #9488
Jordan, FL  83712


Dear Dr. Van:

I had the pleasure of participating in the care of VivianLee Jorgenson during her recent hospitalization at Goulds Hospital.  This lovely 67-year-old female ended up having no discernable coronary artery disease on catheterization.  At the time of the cath, her pulmonary capillary wedge pressure was 12.  During the course of her hospitalization, we noted as well that she had had runs of nonsustained VT and asked our EP colleagues to comment on the appropriateness of an ICD.  They felt that this could certainly be rediscussed in the future, but at the present time, there was no compelling indication for her to receive an ICD.

Her medications at discharge include Lipitor 20 mg p.o. q.d., digoxin 0.25 mg p.o. q.d., captopril 50 mg p.o. t.i.d., Lasix 40 mg p.o. b.i.d., enteric-coated aspirin 81 mg p.o. q.d., Nexium 20 mg p.o. q.d., Synthroid 300 mcg p.o. q.d., Aldactone 25 mg p.o. q.d., Coreg 25 mg p.o. b.i.d., and Norvasc 5 mg p.o. q.d.

It has been a delight to participate in the care of this lovely woman.  If there is any questions or issues, please feel free to call.

Sincerely,





______________________________
Vickie Frank-Jarvis, M.D.


Dictated By: Vickie Frank-Jarvis


eScription document:9-9294537 RFFocus



DD: 06/20/74
DT: 06/20/74
DV: 06/20/74



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-03-17



Patient Name: JORGENSON,VIVIANLEE [ 47190847(JMH) ] Date of Visit: 03/17/2078


CC: Syncope, Afib


HPI: 
71 year old lady with a history of A fib was seen in clinic today for complaints of DOE and increased wt. She was found to be in mild to moderate CHF and an increase in her torsemide dose was recommended. On her way to a blood draw, while in the elevator, she had syncope and hit her head. The fall was witnessed by her daughter. There was no prodrome, no nausea, no incontinence with the fall. The pt does not have any seizure or hypoglycemia history. She notes an 8 lb wt gain over 2-3 weeks and denies dietary indiscretions. She takes her medications faithfully which include an escalating dose of torsemide in over the last several months. She's been hospitalized twice for CHF - once in 2075 and again in 11/77.


The pt was brought to the ED. In the ED the patient had a head CT was done which did not reveal any acute pathology.


PMH:Cardiomyopathy : Nonischemic,   6/19/74 cath no significant coronary disease, 11/26/77 EF 20% with and global hypokinesis 
Coronary artery disease : 6/19/74 cath: RCA 30%
Thyroid cancer : Papillary nodule Ca, 2071, a/p thyroidectomy
Diabetes:  Had been on glyburide, currently diet controlled, 11/25 A1c 6.3
Hypothyroidism: 11/25:  1.4 normal
Elevated cholesterol:  11/26: LDL of 36 and an HDL of 26
Hypertension 
Atrial fibrillation on Coumadin
Non sustained ventricular tachycardia 


Medications
Ambien (ZOLPIDEM TARTRATE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS PRN 
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Celexa (CITALOPRAM) 20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Coreg (CARVEDILOL) 12.5 MG (12.5MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 
Coumadin (WARFARIN SODIUM) 1 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 1) PO QPM 
Digoxin 0.0612 MG (125MCG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Lisinopril 40 MG PO QD 
Potassium CHLORIDE SLOW REL. (KCL SLOW RELEASE) 20 MEQ (20MEQ TAB PRT SR take 1) PO BID 
Synthroid (LEVOTHYROXINE SODIUM) 150MCG TABLET PO variable 
Torsemide 200 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 





Allergies
NKA 
  
FH:  Mom had MI, age 50


SH: 
  Lives with husband (Blacksmith, recently had CABG) and has 4 grown children.

Health-Related Behaviors
Alcohol-social only
Tobacco-prior use, 60 ppy, quit 2067Drug use-no illicit drugs 


PE: 
T 98, BP 100/65, HR 131, RR 18, 96%RA
GEN: NAD
HEENT: PERRL, EOMI, mm moist
CV: irreg irreg, no murmurs appreciated. JVP 15 cm
LUNG: Rales in bases bilaterally
ABD: soft, non-tender, non-distended
EXT: no c/c/e
Neuro: A&amp;Ox3, moves all extremiteis.


CXR: enlarged heart. Minimal pulmonary infiltrate
EKG: A fib, no ischemic changes, poor RWP. Unchanged from previous.


Labs
ResultsDate/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            03/17/2078 [1]    139            4.6            103            28             03/17/2078        139            4.2            102            26             Date/Time         BUN            CRE            EGFR           GLU            03/17/2078 [2]    50 (*)         1.73 (*)       29 [3]         110            03/17/2078        50 (*)         1.66 (*#)      30 [4]         106            Date/Time         ANION          03/17/2078 [5]    8              03/17/2078        11             Date/Time         CA             MG             TBILI          TP             03/17/2078 [6]    9.7                           3.0 (*)        6.9            03/17/2078        9.7            2.2            2.9 (*)        7.0            Date/Time         ALB            GLOB           LIPS           03/17/2078 [7]    4.0            2.9            62 (*)[8]      03/17/2078        4.0            3.0                           Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          03/17/2078 [9]    8              24             106            3.0 (*)        03/17/2078        8 (#)          22             106            2.9 (*)        Date/Time         CK             CK-MB          TROP-I         03/17/2078 [10]   56             2.1            SEE DETAIL[11] Date/Time         TSH            03/17/2078        4.091          Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            03/17/2078 [12]   5.68 (#)       4.67           15.2           45.8           Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            03/17/2078 [13]   98.2 (*#)      32.6 (*#)      33.1           136 (*)        Date/Time         RDW            03/17/2078 [14]   14.6 (*)       Date/Time         %POLY-A        %LYMPH-A       %MONO-A        %EOS-A         03/17/2078 [15]   76.4 (*)       15.4 (*)       6.6            1.3            Date/Time         %BASO-A        03/17/2078 [16]   0.3            Date/Time         ANEUT-A        ALYMP-A        AMONO-A        AEOS-A         03/17/2078 [17]   4.34           .88            0.37           0.07           Date/Time         ABASO-A        03/17/2078 [18]   0.02           Date/Time         HYPO           MACRO          03/17/2078 [19]   +              +              Date/Time         PT             PT-INR         PTT            03/17/2078 [20]   24.1 (*)       2.1 (*)        39.2 (*)                             A/P: 71 year old lady with syncope of unclear eitiology with CHF/Afib. Ddx includes cardiac arrhythmia, hypovolemia, vaso-vagal. Neurologic causes less likely from history.

#CV - i. Low suspicion ACS- Rule out with serial CE
- Continue asa, statin#CV - p. Decompensated CHF- Diuresis with IV lasix. Consider lasix drip if inadequate response.
- Daily wt. Strict I/O.- Cont. digoxin- Will start amiodarone 400 bid- Discuss possible role of AICD with patient and family.#CV - r. - Telemetry#AFR - acute on chronic - likely from poor forward flow- reduce lisinopril- urine electrolytes, eos.
#Psych
- continue celexa
#Endocrine
- continue home thyroid regimen
#FEN
- low sodium, 2L fluid restricted diet#CODE: Full








____________________________________
Xavier B. Nix, M.D., Ph.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-05-29

EDVISIT^47190847^JORGENSON, VIVIANLEE^05/29/78^XUEREB, VESTER

I saw this patient with Dr. Wendy Wu, resident.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Chief complaint on the chart is ataxia, when I

speak with the patient chief complaint is weakness.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This 71-year-old female with a

history of atrial fibrillation on Coumadin.  She presents with

episodes of gait instability, diffuse weakness, multiple falls. 

She was brought in by her family for further evaluation.  She

also had dark stools over the past few weeks.  She denies any

associated chest pain, shortness of breath, lightheadedness, any

syncope, any nausea or vomiting.  She does have a bruise on her

chin.  She denies any focal weakness, numbness, or tingling.  No

hematuria, no epistaxis or gum bleeding.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Congestive heart failure, atrial

fibrillation, hypertension, coronary artery disease,

hypercholesterolemia, and thyroid disease.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She lives with family.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As noted in the written chart and the HPI,

otherwise negative.

MEDICATIONS:  Include ranitidine, baby aspirin, Coumadin, Lasix,

and digoxin.

ALLERGIES:  None.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature 96.5, pulse 60, respiratory

rate 20, blood pressure 136/60, and oxygen 95% on room air. 

General:  This is a pleasant female, elderly; she has got a 3-cm

ecchymosis over her mid left chin as well as over her left

shoulder.  Her pupils are reactive.  Neck is supple. 

Respiratory:  Clear to auscultation.  Cardiovascular:  Regular

rate.  Abdomen is soft.  Rectal is heme-positive, heme-positive

melena per the resident.  Skin is otherwise with bruises over the

left arm as well as a bruise over the right thumb that appears

healing.  Extremities are with good range of motion.  No focal

tenderness.  She is oriented x3.  Mood and affect are normal. 

She is moving all extremities equally.

LABORATORY DATA:  Chest x-ray shows no acute cardiomediastinal

process and head CT preliminary shows no intracranial

abnormalities.  Laboratory studies are remarkable for hematocrit

of 16, creatinine of 1.5, BUN of 95, troponin less than 0.04, and

platelets of 358.  INR of 2.  Urinalysis with 2+ ketones, no

blood.

INITIAL IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  This 71-year-old female presents

with generalized weakness and gait instability and frequent

falls, concerning for either an evolving intracranial process

such as a subdural or stroke.  This has been going on for several

weeks, however, but also presents with melena over the past

several weeks and profound anemia for which she required

transfusion in the Emergency Department.  We did order a CT of

the brain to evaluate for intracranial injury or abnormality both

given the frequent falls and as the cause of the falls.  This

does not show any large subdural or mass lesion.  She is quite

anemic has melanotic heme-positive stool.  I suspect this is the

etiology, but it seems like it has been a slow progression, and

concerned given her cardiac history also the weakness and could

represent coronary insufficiency.  She does not have an elevated

troponin at present.  She will need to be further monitored.  She

was transfused here in the Emergency Department given her

profoundly low hematocrit after consent was obtained. 

Clinically, feels better.  I discussed with the patient's family

because of the bleeding he will need to be evaluated as ____

further cardiac biomarkers and further monitoring as well as

physical therapy evaluation once the patient's acute medical

issues have been addressed.  She will be admitted to the medical

service with diagnosis of symptomatic anemia, gastrointestinal

bleeding, congestive heart failure, and atrial fibrillation in

stable condition.

______________________________

XUEREB, VESTER M.D.

D: 05/29/78

T: 05/30/78

Dictated By: XUEREB, VESTER

eScription document:9-7189367 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>