<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2088-01-20



PCC Internal Medicine PRIMARY CARE

630 Poliquin Drive, 642

Asmara, PA  96931



RE:		Jarvis, Amador

PCC#:		090-73-07



January 20, 2088



Reason for visit:  Mr. Jarvis comes to follow up on his hypertension, hyperglycemia, renal insufficiency and elevated PSA.  



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  He has seen Dr. Jose Quirk and a prostate biopsy has been recommended.  This is scheduled for next week and Mr. Jarvis is quite anxious about it.  



He began the Captopril and HCTZ (? or Maxide) and has noted good blood pressure control as checked at BH.  At first he developed a considerable cough but in the last two weeks this has largely resolved.  He states that the cough is productive of thick phlegm and may reflect a respiratory infection rather than the Captopril itself.  His blood sugars when checked at home have averaged between the 140 to 150 range fasting.  On one occasion a three hour postprandial was 170.  



He has had no attacks of gout or gout like arthritis in the past six weeks and is quite pleased about this. 



He has continued actively managing production and is planning a trip to Italy next month.  



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On examination today he looks well and comfortable.  His blood pressure is 140/76 right arm sitting with regular pulse of 68.  His weight is 173 (stable).  



IMPRESSION:  Doing reasonably well on the new blood pressure program.  Since the cough is resolving it would seem reasonable to continue the present program.  



We will look forward to seeing the results of the prostate biopsy and we will check glucose and glycosylated hemoglobin today.  He will return in four months for follow up.  





Orvell Oliver, M.D. 

Labs:  Hemolyzed sample shows K of 6.0.  Will check re HCTZ vs Maxide.  If the latter, will change it.

O



Plasma Sodium           138                      135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium        6.0       H              3.4-4.8        mmol/L

  Result Text:

     HEMOLYZED

Plasma Chloride         98        L              100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide   25.9                     24.0-30.0      mmol/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen    29        H              8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine       2.1       H              0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose          167       H              70-110         mg/dl

Transaminase-SGOT       26                       10-40          U/L





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-05-11

                                                       Patient Name: JARVIS,AMADOR [ MRN: 0907307PCC ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 05/11/2089





REASON FOR VISIT:  Mr. Jarvis comes for a regular 6-month followup 
visit.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  He has been feeling extremely well without 
any illness or any unpleasant symptoms.  He is working hard as a production manager, and he will have some time off this spring.  He and his wife are 
planning a trip to Italy and Greece, and following this, they will spend mostly 
long weekends in New Mexico.

He has not had shortness of breath, orthopnea, or edema.  The pains in his hips 
and legs have not been bothering him.  When he tests his blood glucose level, he 
gets results that range between 170 and 120.  He has not been specifically 
exercising, but does try to park his car at some distance from shops and stores 
and walk the intervening distance.  He continues on 1/2 tablet of atenolol 50 mg 
per day along with 1 Hyzaar tablet per day.  Otherwise, the review of systems is 
unremarkable.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He looks cheerful and fit.  Blood pressure in the 
right arm, sitting 140/86 with regular pulse 64.  Chest is clear to P&A.  Heart 
sounds are very faint, but appear normal with normal rate and rhythm.  Neck 
veins are not distended.  Abdomen is nontender.  Extremities have good dorsalis 
pedis pulses.  Sensation in feet is intact to light touch and vibration.

IMPRESSION:  Very stable with regards to hypertension.  He remains 
moderately hyperglycemic.  He has an appointment to be followed by the 
urologist, Dr. Jose Quirk, in the next month for his elevated prostatic-
specific antigen (the prostate biopsy showed intraepithelial neoplasia   
considered only a risk factor).

PLAN:  We will check the usual laboratory work, and we will let him know when 
the results are available.  He should return in 6 months.




Orvell Oliver, M.D.


Test Description        Result    Abnormal Flag  Ref. Range     Ref. Units



Plasma Sodium           140                      135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium        4.7                      3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride         103                      100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide   25.0                     24.0-30.0      mmol/L

Calcium                 9.0                      8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Plasma Urea Nitrogen    39        H              8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine       2.4       H              0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose          244       H              70-110         mg/dl

Cholesterol             245                                     mg/dl



Test Description        Result    Abnormal Flag  Ref. Range     Ref. Units



Hemoglobin A1C          7.70      H              3.80-6.40      %

Calc Mean Bld Glucose   171                                     mg%



Mr Jarvis: The glucose when you were here was 244 and the average calclated from the HbA1c is 171; despite your efforts and exercise and diet.  I think it would be wise to start on a low dose of a glucose-lowering medicine, glipizide (Glucotrol).  I would start on 1/2 of a 5 mg pill twice a day and continue checking your blood sugar levels from time to time.  If they stay a bit up, then increase to one whole pill (5 mg) twice a day.  Then we will see how that effects the blood sugar.  I don't think this will interfere with your trip.  Call me in a week to tell me how it is going.



Best wishes,

O



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-09-18



Reason for Visit

Mr. Amador Jarvis comes for an annual visit and physical exam, and to follow-up on his diabetes, hypertension and elevated serum creatinine



Problems

      Hyperexpanded lungs

      Hypertension

      Elevated creatinine

      Elevated glucose

      Elevated prostate specific antigen

      Elevated cholesterol



Narrative History

He has been generally healthy since last visit.  He notes that his morning fasting glucose values usually range between 130 and 140 mg percent.  He has not checked his blood pressure frequently but feels that it is under reasonable control.



He has been followed by Dr. Quirk for his prostate and has regular ophthalmological visits for his eyes.  He also has regular dermatology visits.



He does not notice any unusual shortness of breath with exertion, and in fact since he has been exercising regularly he feels that his breathing has improved.



Review of Systems

General - Neg; Weight stable.

Eyes - Neg; No problems with vision.

Ears - Neg; Hearing not impaired in a quiet room though some difficulty in a noisy environment.

Nose - Neg; No nasal allergies

Mouth - Neg; Teeth, throat, chewing normal.

Heart - Neg. No pain or abnormal heart beats.

Lungs - Neg; No cough or sortness of breath.

GI - Neg; No heartburn, abdominal pain,constipation, diarrhea, rectal bleeding.

GU - Neg; No pain or difficulty with urination.  t Musc-skel - Neg; No painful or swollen joints.

Skin - Neg; No rashes, severe acne, abnormal moles.

Neuro - Neg; No weakness, numbness, shakiness.

Emotional - Neg; No unusual sadness or anxiety.



Exam

Mr. Jarvis is a healthy, comfortable appearing man. Blood pressure right arm, sitting is 136/70 with regular pulse 72.  Weight is 174 lbs. Ears, drums, canals, hearing within normal limits. (Eyes are regularly examined). Mouth, teeth, tongue and throat normal.  Neck, thyroid, nodes, carotids normal. JVP fills below the sternal angle.  Chest is clear to percussion and to auscultation both quiet breathing and forced maximal expiration. Diaphragms are somewhat low. Heart is normal size and has normal rate, rhythm and sounds with no murmurs or gallops.  Abdomen has no tenderness, masses or enlarged organs.  There is an area of muscular weakness in the anterior abdomen producing a partial ventral hernia.  Extremities have good pedal pulses and no edema. Skin has many keratoses of various sizes and shapes but is free of suspicious lesions.

Rectal and prostate examination have been done by the urologist.



Assessment

Mr. Jarvis appears to be in stable health with hypertension and diabetes under good control.  His elevated serum creatinine seems to be causing no problems.  His prostate is being carefully followed and shows no signs of progression.



Disposition and Plans

We will check laboratory work today and let Mr. Jarvis know the results when they're available.  He will keep in touch and return as necessary but should return for a regular follow-up visit in six months.



Medications

      Centrum Vitamins      PO QD

      Hyzaar (25 Mg/100 Mg) (HCTZ 25mg + Losart...    1 TAB PO QD

      GLIPIZIDE   5MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO BID

      Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN)    10MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      ATENOLOL   50 MG PO QD



Allergies

      CAPTOPRIL    - possible rash



Health Maintenance

      Influenza Vaccine   11/28/2090   Aventis

lot # GL735LM

exp. 7/08/2091

VHS given 11/26/90

VHS Pub. 7/04/90

adm by A. Torres, RN

      Cholesterol   09/21/2090 179  

      M-alb/creat ratio   03/13/2091 34.4  

      Stool Guaiac   10/18/2090 times three Done - negative 

      Pneumovax   03/13/2091   adm. 0.5ml into r.arm

      UA-Protein   06/17/87 1+  

      Colonoscopy   08/21/2091 tubular adenoma  at Brewster Hospital

      HBA1C   03/14/2091 6.50  

      Triglycerides   05/15/2090 131  

      Cholesterol-LDL   05/15/2090 165  

      Microalbumin   03/13/2091 2.2  

      Hct (Hematocrit)   03/13/2091 43.2  

      Cholesterol-HDL   05/15/2090 51  

      Hgb (Hemoglobin)   03/13/2091 15.2  



Past Medical History

Former patient of Dr. Michael Jett.  Known hyperglycemia and hypertension for many years. Elevated blood creatinine level for many years dating back to a creatinine of 1.7 in 2068.  Hypertension noted in 2063.



PSA tests gradually rising from 2.9 and 2080 to 4.8 in 2091



Social History

Mr. Jarvis continues work as a  production manager, working seven days a week.  He does manage two months of vacation during the spring



Lab Tests

Amador:  the lab results show good levels of glucose and stasble prostate antigen and creatinine.  You look good, and lets stick with the present plan.

O





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-12-11

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.

CCU JAR ADMIT NOTE 




Name:    Amador Jarvis
MR #: 0907307
Date of admission: 12/11/95
JAR: Larry Oates MD PhD
Attending: Dr. Ickes
PCP:     Orvell Oliver MD


CC/ID: 82M w/ h/o HTN, CRI, DM2 and + h/o smoking w/ no known CAD p/w syncope and an inferior STEMI 


HPI:  82M w/ h/o HTN, CRI, DM2 and + h/o smoking w/ no known CAD p/w syncope and an inferior STEMI. Pt has been in his USOH.  This AM while shoveling snow he started to feel &#8220;unwell&#8221; c/o dizziness, slightly nauseous and sweaty.  He denied CP, SOB/V/diaphoresis. He may have had a similar event 3 years ago during heavy exertion (1 episode).  He felt this was like prior hypoglycemic episodes.  Pt went inside, called for his wife and then syncopized. Estimated total LOC ~5 min.  He awoke as his wife returned to give him the OJ and felt completely better after drinking it. arrived to find the pt with STEMI in inf leads. Pt was given asa and was taken to the ED for further management. 


ED course: Pt was bradycardic but hemodynamically stable P59, BP112/63). He was found to have a new RBBB and new STE in 2, 3, avf and V3-V6 with depressions in 1, avl. Pt had no chest pain through out the entire duration, but felt generally unwell. Was started on heparin, lipitor, NAC and cardiology was called. 


Pt was taken to the cath lab and found to have 3VD w/ severe proximal LAD lesion, a diffusely diseased Cx/OM2, and a severe RCA lesion, which was felt to be the culprit. A BMS to RCA lesion. Pt was plavix loaded and started on a bicarb drip.   


ROS:  Per HPI. No F/C/NS.  No SOB/cough/hemoptysis/wheezing/sore throat/rash.  No GI/GU complaints. 


PMH:  

Hypertension
CRI b/l 2.5
DM2
Elevated PSA
HL
Colonic tubular adenomas - 8/2091
Gout
Depression


Medications on admission:

ATENOLOL   50 MG QD
Centrum Vitamins   QD 
CITALOPRAM   40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) QD 
Enteric Coated Aspirin (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated)   81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) QD 
Hyzaar (25 Mg/100 Mg) (HCTZ 25mg + Losart...   1 TAB QD 
Prandin (REPAGLINIDE)   0.5 MG (0.5MG TABLET take 1) as directed x 90 days, 1 tab before breakfast and lunch. 2 before dinner.
Pravachol (PRAVASTATIN)   20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 


ALL:      captopril  - possible rash, cough
SH: Lives with wife of 57 years. Has several kids all grown. Former smoker 7 years, 30 years ago. No IVDU or ETOH.
FH: M &#8211; CAD 60s, F &#8211; CAD 80s


Physical Exam:  
V:  HR: 55 BP 131/50 100% 2l
Gen:  AAox3 NAD well appearing elderly man
HEENT: PERRL, EOMI, sclera anicteric.    
Neck:  Supple, no thyromegaly, no carotid bruits, JVP 8-9 
Nodes: No cervical or supraclavicular LAN
Cor: RRR S1, S2 nl.  No m/r/g.
Chest: CTA laterally   
Abdomen: +BS Soft, NT, ND.  No HSM, No CVA tenderness. 
Ext: No C/C/E.  
Pulses: Carotids 2+, no bruits, +2 DP/PT, 2+ radial. Venous and art sheath in right groin. B/l no fem bruits w/ 2+ pulses.
Skin: No rashes.        
Neuro: non-focal


Labs and Studies:


              12/11/95  
              11:50     


NA            137                                                               
K             5.1(H)                                                            
CL            103                                                               
CO2           26.5                                                              
BUN           54(H)                                                             
CRE           2.5(H)                                                            
GLU           184(H)                                                            


              12/11/95  
              11:53     


CA            9.6                                                               
PHOS          3.0                                                               
MG            1.6                                                               


              12/11/95  
              12:03     


CK-MB         Negative                                                          
TROP-I        Negative                                                          


              12/11/95  
              11:50     


WBC           7.1                                                               
RBC           3.99(L)                                                           
HGB           12.9(L)                                                           
HCT           39.8(L)                                                           
MCV           100(T)                                                            
MCH           32.3                                                              
MCHC          32.5                                                             
PLT           267                                                               
RDW           13.8                                                              
DIFFR         Received                                                          
METHOD        Auto                                                             
%NEUT         66                                                                
%LYMPH        25                                                                
%MONO         5                                                                 
%EOS          4                                                                 
%BASO         0                                                                 
ANEUT         4.64                                                              
ALYMP         1.76                                                              
AMONS         0.38                                                              
AEOSN         0.25                                                              
ABASOP        0.02                                                              
ANISO         None                                                              
HYPO          None                                                              
MACRO         1+(H)                                                             
MICRO         None                                                              


              12/11/95  
              11:50     


PT            12.4                                                              
PT-INR        1.1                                                               
PTT           23.7                                                              
                                             


CXR: No acute process


EKGs: 
2085: sinus brady, nl PR, LAHB
12/11 11:25A sinus 1st degree AVB, LAHB, w/ RBBB ~0.5-2 mm STE in III. TWF in aVL
12/11 11:35A 1st degree AVB, LAHB, RBBB, 4 mm inf STE, 3-4 mm STE in V3-5
12/11  3:35P CCU admit / post cath: 1st degree avb, LAHB, RBBB Resolving inf STE.




A/P: 82M w/ h/o HTN, CRI, DM2 but no known CAD p/w syncope, new RBBB and inferior STEMI.  Intervention on acute lesion today and possible may get re-eval for left-sided circulation with either staged PCI v. CABG.  



Ischemia: 

ASA/plavix, heparin, integrilin. Lipitor.
CE until peak
A1c/lipids, BB if room. 
Staged PCI vs. CABG
Pump: Pending TTE 

Has not tolerated ACEI before. Can consider ARB if BP room. If difficulty w/ hyperkalemia could consider small standing doses of kayexolate.
Currently appears euvolimic
Rhythm: Sinus w/ old LAHB, new 1st degree AVB and new RBBB.  Given right-sided lesion at risk for complete HB.  

Observe for now. Hold BB
Per AHA guidelines class I transcutaneous if develops CHB.
Holding BB for now.  
Daily EKGs. Tele.
Renal: NAC, gentle fluids (bicarb)
DM2: f/u A1c. RISS
FEN: cardiac/diabetic
PPx: heparin for now, ppx when sheath out
Dispo: pending
Code: FULL




_______________________________________________________________________
Name     Larry Q. Oates MD PhD                          
Pager # 34071
PGY-2









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-04-15


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	PRIMGHAR CARE CENTER
	


	Reason for visit:
   Elective cardiac catheterization prior to CABG


	Interval History:
   Cardiology admission note for Dr. Ickes 
This is an 82 year old male with CAD, DM, HTN, hyperlipidemia, and CRI who presents for elective cardiac catheterization for reevaluation of an RCA stent, which was placed in 12/95 in the setting of an STEMI. This catheterization is in preparation for planned CABG by Dr. Xaysana on 4/23/96. 

Mr. Jarvis's cardiac history began in 12/95, when he was shoveling snow.  At that time, he developed dizziness, diaphoresis and nausea. He went inside and had an episode of syncope which lasted approximately 5 minutes. His initial EKG showed 1 mm STE in II, III and aVF and 1 mm STE in V5 and V6. An EKG seven minutes later showed an increase in STE in the inferior leads and STE in V3 to V6 with a max of 4 mm in V3. He never developed chest pain. An emergent cardiac catheterization at that time showed a left main with minor distal disease. The LAD had a proximal 80% stenosis. The LCx had mid 40% diffuse disease. The 1st OM had a tandem lesion of 90%. The RCA was large and dominant and had a proximal ulcerated 90% stenosis with haziness. Given these findings, a 2.5 X 15mm BMS was placed into the proximal RCA with and excellent result. His peak CK was 305 during that admission. An echo performed at that time was a technically difficult study, which showed diffuse inferior hypokinesis. He was discharged home in 12/95 in stable condition and follow-up with Dr. Xaysana in his office to discuss possible CABG. It was decided that the patient should have a repeat cardiac catheterization prior to the CABG to determine whether RCA restenosis is present. He is then scheduled to have CABG with Dr. Xaysana on 4/23/96. 

The patient has been feeling well at home from a cardiac standpoint. He denies any chest pain, dyspnea, dizziness, pedal edema, orthopnea, PND, or syncope. He does report some bilateral thigh claudication, noting that he can walk about 0.5 miles before he has to stop secondary to leg pain. He denies any calf pain. 


	Past medical history:
   1. CAD 
2. DM 
3. HTN 
4. Hyperlipidemia 
5. Gout. 
6. Chronic renal insufficiency 

Medications 
Atenolol 25mg po daily 
Cozaar 25mg po bid 
Ecotrin 325mg po daily 
Lipitor 80mg po daily 
Nitroglycerin 0.4mg sl every 5 minutes PRN chest pain 
Plavix 75mg po daily 
Prandin 0.5 mg BID 
Citalopram 40mg daily 
MVI daily

	

	Changes to Allergies
	
CAPTOPRIL - reaction: cough [reviewed]


	Family history:
   His mother died at the age of 56 from a MI. His father died from unknown causes in his 80s. His sister committed suicide. His son had a MI at the age of 55- he had 2 stents placed.


	Social history:
   Remote tobacco history-he has a 15-20 pack year history, quitting about 40 years ago. He drinks about 1-2 glasses of wine per week. He denies any illicit drug use. He is married with 2 children. He is a Primary Production Manager and has been doing so for the past 40-50 years. 


	Review of systems:
   GEN: No fevers, chills, night sweats 
HEENT: No hearing or vision changes 
PULM: No cough, wheezing, or hemoptysis 
CARDIAC: See HPI 
GI: No nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, diarrhea, melena, or BRB per rectum 
GU: No dysuria or hematuria 
MS: Occasional gout pain in his bilateral feet with no other arthritis or arthralgias 
NEURO:No dizziness, syncope, headaches, or seizures

Physical examination:
	
-BMI: 22.8  Normal, low risk
-Pulse: 60  regular 
-resp. rate: 16  unlabored
-height: 69  in.
-weight: 154  lbs.
-General:   Elderly male, lying in bed in NAD
-HEENT:   Sclera anicteric
-Neck:   No JVD.  Carotid volume and upstroke nl, no bruit or transmitted murmur.
-Chest:   Clear to auscultation bilaterally. 
-Cardiac:   RRR. S1 and S2 normal.  No S3, S4, murmur, gallop, or rub.
-Abdomen:   Soft, nontender.  No hepatomegaly or splenomegaly.  No bruit.
-Extremities:   No edema. 2+ femorals with no bruits bilaterally. 1+ DP/PT bilaterally. 
-Neuro:   A &amp;O X 3. MAE. 
-BP:   right 130/67 left-146/40

Selected recent labs:

	 Metabolic
Date     NA       K        CL       CO2      BUN      CRE      GLU      
04/10/96 143               109      26.7                                
04/15/96          4.7                        47       2.72     134      

Liver and Pancreatic Enzymes
Date     ALT/SGPT AST/SGOT 
12/13/95 11       33       

Lipid/Thyroid
Date     CHOL     TRIG     HDL      LDL      
12/12/95 141      111      49       70       

Hematology
Date     HCT      WBC      PLT      
04/10/96 37.0     7.3      255      

Coagulation
Date     PT       PT-INR   PTT      
04/10/96 12.8     1.1      30.0     

Immunology
Date     HGBA1C   
02/08/96 5.40     

other
Date     HGB      
04/10/96 12.6     


	


	Assessment and plan:
   This is an 82 year old male with CAD, HTN, hyperlipidemia, DM, and CRI who is s/p BMS to the RCA with residual 3-vessel disease who presents for elective cardiac catheterization for evaluation of the RCA stent prior to planned CABG next week. 
-Proceed with cardiac catheterization today 
- He will be premedicated with Mucomyst and Bicarb. given his renal function. 
-Continue ASA and statin 
-Will need to stop Plavix given upcoming surgery next week. 
-BP borderline high today- will monitor during the procedure, adjusting his medications as needed. 
Further recommendations per Dr. Ickes

	
Jenna H. Whittaker, PA

	
Signed electronically by  Jenna H. Whittaker, PA
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>