<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-10-20




NAME:     Fonsea, Lydia
MRN:      7090253

The patient is a 58-year-old white female, who presents in follow up of type 2
diabetes mellitus.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Review of systems is positive for mild nocturia and
negative for chest pain, dyspnea, bleeding, heat or cold intolerance.

HOME BLOOD GLUCOSE MONITORING: Semi-compliant.

DIET: Semi-compliant with low-salt ADA.

ACTIVITY LEVEL: METS 2. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: Vital signs: Blood pressure 114/68. Weight 198
pounds.  Heart rate 68. Respiratory rate 18. General appearance: Overweight. 
HEENT: No retinal bleeding.  Neck: No JVD, no bruits, no masses.  Heart: Heart
sounds normal. Lungs: Clear. Extremities: No peripheral edema.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  

(1)  Type 2 diabetes mellitus.  I suspect the control is not adequate.  The last
     hemoglobin A1C was 7.9% on 04/29/73.  Plan: Repeat hemoglobin A1C. 
     Diet and increase activity level.  She most likely is going to need a second
     nighttime injection. 

(2)  Depression.  Plan: Continue the same medications.  

(3)  Mild diabetic nephropathy.  Plan: Check urine microalbumin.  Blood
     pressure is excellent today.  

(4)  Health maintenance.  The patient will need a lipid profile and flu vaccine.

The patient will follow up in one month.

Austin Jaeger, M.D.

AJ/yeung/updegraff



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-11-20

JMH Internal Medicine Intern Admit Note



Patient name:  Linda Fonseca

MR#  7090253

Location:  Rm 4103

Admitting MD:  

PCP:  Dr. Austin Jaeger (Dr. Lenard Wyatt covering)

Wards

CODE:  Full

Date of admission:  11/19/2076



CC/RFA:  abdominal pain



HPI

60 year old woman with diabetes and depression presents with abdominal pain.  She has had constipation and gas beginning approximately 6 weeks ago and for the last two weeks has had watery diarrhea, cramping and gas.  She vomited once yesterday, producing a yellow non-bloody discharge.  She complains that her abdomen is increasingly distended.  She notices no particular association between eating and abdominal complaints, and has not had any relief with Tums, the only medication that she has tried.  She denies fever, chills, thin stools, hematochezia, melena, sick contacts, travel or change in diet or medication.  She has had no shortness of breath, chest pain or palpitations.  She has had no recent change in her weight, no pruritus and has not had any increased bruising or bleeding.



ED Course

Given zofran 4 mg IV x 2, MSO4 2 mg IV x 3, Abdominal CT, then sent to floor.



PMH

Breast cancer

Depression & anxiety



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION

Buspar 10 mg PO TID

Clonazepam 1 mg PO BID

Effexor 75 mg  5ID

Humulin  n 18 QPM

Humulin  n 50 QAM

Humulin  r 20 QAM

Lescol 20 mg PO QHS

Metformin 500 mg PO BID

Tamoxifen 20 mg PO QAM



ALLERGIES/ADVERSE DRUG RXN:  sulfa drugs cause rash, tricyclic antidepressants cause cough



SOCIAL HISTORY

Tob:  50 pack year, current smoker @ 1 pack/day

EtOH:  none.

IVDU:  none.



FAMILY HISTORY

Father died of lymphoma at age 78, uncle died of leukemia at age 78



ROS

Generalized weakness

No change in appetite, no sore throat, no cough, no dysphagia, no heartburn.

No change in sensorium, no toxic ingestions.

Other systems negative in detail.



PHYSICAL EXAM

VS:   T 99.2   HR 92   BP 144/72   RR 18   SO2 93% RA 

Gen:  Lying in bed, NAD

HEENT:  PERRLA/EOMI, MMM

Neck:  fleshy, supple, no carotid bruit, JV flat

Lungs:  CTA bilaterally without rales or rhonchi

Heart:  RRR, no murmur rubs or gallops

Abd: Obese, non-protuberant, BS+, no shifting dullness, increased tympany, slight tenderness to palpation in LLQ, no rebound tenderness, no tenderness to percussion, soft, no masses

Extr:  1+ DP pulses, no cords, clubbing or edema

Neuro:  A + Ox3; MS normal; CNs II-XII intact; Babinski sign absent

Skin:  No rashes or open wounds

Guaiac negative stool x 2



LABS

Sodium (Stat Lab)        138                         (135-145)        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)     4.1                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)      105                         (100-108)        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)           23.5                        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)           17                          (8-25)           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)    1.0                         (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)       261                H        (70-110)         mg/dl



Calcium                  8.6                         (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus               2.2                L        (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                1.3                L        (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Total Protein            7.6                         (6.0-8.3)        g/dl

Albumin                  3.6                         (3.3-5.0)        g/dl

Globulin                 4.0                         (2.6-4.1)        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin         0.1                         (0-0.4)          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin          0.3                         (0-1.0)          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase     67                          (30-100)         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT        27                          (7-30)           U/L

Lipase                   3.7                         (1.3-6.0)        U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT        33                 H        (9-32)           U/L



WBC                      8.2                         (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                      42.6                        (36.0-46.0)      %

HGB                      15.2                        (12.0-16.0)      gm/dl

RBC                      4.34                        (4.00-5.20)      mil/cmm

PLT                      190                         (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                      98                          (80-100)         fl

MCH                      35.1               H        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                     35.7                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                      13.6                        (11.5-14.5)      %

PT                       12.8                        (11.1-13.1)      sec

PT-INR                   1.1

APTT                     24.8                        (22.1-35.1)      sec

Diff Method              Auto

Poly                     76                 H        (40-70)          %

Lymphs                   19                 L        (22-44)          %

Monos                    5                           (4-11)           %

EOS                      0                           (0-8)            %

Basos                    0                           (0-3)            %



MICRO:  BCX sent; stool sent for fecal leukocytes, C. diff, O&P



Colonoscopy:  08/20/2073 - normal colon.



Abd/Pelvic CT:  

Air within the gastroepiploic and portal vessels as described, without specific bowel pathology.  Heterogeneously enhancing masses within the pelvis as described, likely representing exophytic uterine fibroids.  Recommend ultrasound of the pelvis for confirmation.  Possible small gallstone within the gallbladder without CT evidence for cholecystitis.  Fatty liver.



CXR:  	NO EVIDENCE OF PNEUMONIA OR CHF.



KUB:  NO EVIDENCE OF OBSTRUCTION OR PERFORATION.



EKG:  NSR at 90 bpm, diffusely flattened T waves, no ST abnormalities 



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN

60 year old woman presents with a history of watery diarrhea, gas and diffuse abdominal pain for the past two weeks that has increased in intensity in the last 3 days.  For the month prior to the onset of diarrhea she reports that she had been constipated.  No fevers or chills; patient is afebrile and the WBC is not elevated.  Her abdominal exam is remarkable for obesity, tympany and mild LLQ tenderness.  Finding of air in the gastroepiploic and portal vessels with no associated intraabdominal pathology is of uncertain significance.  Fibroids, which have been previously diagnosed, are seen.  Normal colonoscopy 08/20/2076.



1) GI:  Constipation for a month followed by diarrhea for two weeks.  This history is suggestive of overflow diarrhea.  Patient denies recent narcotic usage and no obstructing lesions are seen on CT scan.  May also be infection, malabsorption, osmotic, inflammatory, secretory or a motility defect.  No evidence is seen for ischemia, inflammation or infection.  Bowel dysmotility resulting from DM may play a role in a motility disorder.

 - Diet: clears now, NPO after midnight

 - Stool for fecal leukocytes, O&P, C. diff

 - Bowel regimen:  colace, senokot, miralax

 - Reglan PRN nausea

- Follow clinical exam

 - Follow WBC, T, lactate for signs of acute sepsis or ischemia

 - Appreciate GI input (Dr. Utterback)

 - Apprecate surgery input (Dr. Espinosa)

 - Ranitidine prophylaxis, zofran PRN nausea



2) Gyn:  Patient is s/p breast cancer and has fibroids.  No evidence of abdominal mass other than fibroids.

 - Continue on tamoxifen 20 mg PO QAM



3) Psychiatric:  Depression & anxiety

 - Buspar

 - clonazepam

 - effexor



4) DM2:  Continue home meds (metformin + insulin), hold when on diet without substantial calories (clears, NPO)



5) Prophylaxis:  patient is ambulatory; ranitidine; commode by bedside.



	

Vernon Ewing, JMH Internal Medicine intern

Pager #71151





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-03-11

EDVISIT^30921467^FONSECA, LINDA^03/11/78^ULLOA, CHRISTOPHER

I have interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the

resident's documentation, and concur except as noted.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 61-year-old female who

presents complaining of chest pain and lightheadedness for the

past 4 days.  The patient has a medical history remarkable for

breast cancer, status post mastectomy and node dissection, which

have given her chronic left axillary pain.  The patient states

that this chest pain that she felt is distinct and is

nonexertional.  It is associated with increased fatigue and

shortness of breath associated with it.  Today, states that the

dyspnea resolved after being given oxygen in the ambulance en

route and called her primary care physician who told her to come

to the Emergency Department.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Remarkable for diabetes and

hypercholesterolemia.

OTHER MEDICAL HISTORY, SURGICAL HISTORY, SOCIAL HISTORY, FAMILY

HISTORY, REVIEW OF SYSTEMS, MEDICATIONS, AND ALLERGIES:  As

noted.  The patient is an active smoker.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  In the Emergency Department, the patient

is awake and alert, nontoxic appearing, afebrile, with stable

vital signs.  HEENT:  Atraumatic, normocephalic.  Oropharynx

clear, moist mucous membranes.  Neck:  Supple, without

meningismus or midline tenderness.  Respirations clear with no

rhonchi, rales, or wheezes.  Cardiovascular:  Regular rate

without murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  Abdomen:  Soft, nontender,

without rebound or guarding.  Skin is warm, well perfused without

petechiae or lesions.  There is no edema, no calf or thigh

tenderness, no CVA tenderness.  Neurologically, she is alert and

oriented x3, normal mood and affect.  No cranial nerve

abnormalities.  No sensory or motor deficits.

LABORATORY DATA:  The patient had an unremarkable CBC and

chemistry panel with flat enzymes and normal coags.  EKG was

sinus with no ectopy, interpreted as normal, chest x-ray, which

showed postoperative changes but no infiltrate or edema in this

patient with nonvertiginous lightheadedness and chest discomfort

in the context of shortness of breath and generalized malaise.

PLAN:  Plan is for admission, serial enzymes, and risk

stratification.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

DISPOSITION:  The patient is admitted.

______________________________

ULLOA, CHRISTOPHER 

D: 03/13/78

T: 03/13/78

Dictated By: ULLOA, CHRISTOPHER

eScription document:7-3872310 CB





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-06-24

Dunn County Associates 
Internal Medicine Admission Note



Patient: Fonseca, Linda

DCA MRN: 7090253

Date of Admission to Internal Medicine: 06/24/81 

Attending: Dr A Jaeger

PCP: same

Code Status: Full code



CC: abdominal pain



Source: electronic records, patient



HPI: 

Mr Fonseca is a 64 yo F h/o breast cancer, insulin-requiring DM2, lupus, anxiety who is p/w 10 days of diarrhea, N/V and anorexia. Pt had originally presented to the DCA ED on 06/15/81 with 2 days of profuse watery diarrhea; treated with IVF and discharged. No fevers or chills at that time. Reports that she felt better, and experienced complete resolution of her diarrhea. Over the next week, pt had anorexia, and was able to tolerate soups and clears. 2 days prior to this current admission, pt had recurrence of her watery profuse diarrhea.  She endorses increased frequency (almost q1h diarrhea) that does not seem correlated with food intake. Wakes her at night.  Recently has been associated with worsening epigastric and LUQ tenderness. On the day of admission, pt had 3 episodes of non-bloody, non-bilious emesis. She denies dysentery, BRBPR, or melena. Denies ingestion of raw or undercooked foods.



Pt presented to the DCA ED again,  vitals 97, 85, 109/57, 99%ra. Given 1L NS, D51/2 NS at 125cc/hr, levofloxacin 250 mg PO x1 for white blood cells in urine, and zofran.  Admitted to Internal Medicine for further management.



Review of Systems:

(+) fatigue, now x 1 year

Denies visual disturbance, headaches

Denies dysphagia, odynophagia, or oral ulcers

Denies chest discomfort, palpitations, shortness of breath, DOE. 

(+) abd pain, N/V, diarrhea as above. 

Denies melena/hematochezia. 

Denies dysuria, urethral discharge or increased urinary frequency

Denies rashes, photosensitivity

(+) intermittent chronic joint tenderness (hand, fingers, wrists, back)



Past Medical/Surgical History:

Lupus; (+) ANA, dsdna, smith; f/b Dr Merritt

Breast ca s/p bilateral mastectomies w/positive nodes; f/b Dr Land

Depression and anxiety

DM2; insulin-requiring, well controlled A1c 6.9% (2/81), malb 11 (2/81)

Hyperlipidemia

h/o back pain

h/o ear infection s/p Augmentin 



Home medications (confirmed with patient):

Asa 81 MG PO QD 

Clonazepam 1MG PO BID PRN

Effexor (VENLAFAXINE HCL) 150MG (75MG TABLET ) PO BID

Humulin N 40 qAM / 22 qPM

Humulin R (INSULIN REGULAR HUMAN) Variable (100 U/ML VIAL ML) SC 

Hydroxychloroquine 200 MG PO QD 

Letrozole 2.5 MG PO QD 

Prilosec 20 MG PO BID 

Simvastatin 40 MG PO QHS 

Topamax 100 MG qAM / 50 MG aPM 



Allergies: 

Tricyclic Antidepressants - cough, 

Sulfa - Rash, 

EZETIMIBE - lethargy, GI Intolerance



Family History (from PCP note and patient):

Mom: stroke, CAD, leukemia, ms

Dad: breast cancer, CAD, DM, stroke, leukemia, ms

Siblings: thyroid cancer



Social History:

Lives with mother and cousin in house in 3 family house. No pets, or recent travel. Not married. 



Tobacco: active smoker, &#189;  to 2 ppd &gt;50yrs. Not interested in quitting at this time. Does not want a nicotine patch.

Etoh: denies

Illicits: denies 



Physical examinations:

Gen: pleasant, smiling, coomfortable

Vitals: 97, 81, 128/56, 97%ra

HEENT: anicteric, MMdry

Cor: regular, no murmurs or rubs

Lungs: CTAB w/mild rhonci in lower fields, no wheezing or crackles

Abd: soft, mildly distended, mild epigastric/LUQ pain, no HSM, hypoactive BS

Ext: stable joint tenderness over wrists, fingers, knees, ankles. Joints do not exhibit erythema, warmth or ballotable fluid. 



Labs:

Na 141, K 3.7, Cl 105, CO2 22.5 BUN 17, Cr 1.13, glu 205

Ca 9.3, alb 4.1, glob 3.8, amy 90, lipase 103

ALT 24, AST 24, AP 115, TB 0.3, DB 0.1



INR 1.0

TSH 1.28, FT4 1.0

UA: clear, trace ketone, &gt;1.030, gluc neg, 1+ prot, Hcasts neg, 1+ WBC



WBC 15.1, HCT 43.6, PLT 211

P  74%, L 11%, M 4%, Bands 10%



CXR- no acute process, clear lungs

ECG- NSR 80, nl axis, nRWP, no concerning STTW changes



Assessment:

64 yo F h/o breast cancer, insulin-requiring DM2, lupus, anxiety who is p/w 10 days of recurrent diarrhea, N/V, bandemia and anorexia consistent with infectious etiology. Interestingly, pt also has an elevated lipase, alk phos and some mild epigastric tenderness that suggest a mild pancreatitis. Distended abdomen c/f third-spaced fluid.



Plan:



Diarrhea

&#183;         Follow-up stool cultures

&#183;         Support with IV fluids

&#183;         Consider CT scan if w/u is negative



Pancreatitis

&#183;         Bowel rest, NPO

&#183;         Aggressive IVF w/D5NS x 2 liters

&#183;         Pain control with morphine prn (but discomfort is very mild)

&#183;         Check RUQ US to assess for gallbladder/pancreatic pathology



DM2

&#183;         &#189; dose insulin while NPO

&#183;         RISS

&#183;         Consider adding very low dose ACE I after diarrhea resolves



UTI: no sx or indication for abx. Will hold on abx, and check urine culture

SLE: will cont plaquenil. Appears to be clinically mild, no evidence of flare. ?etiology of chronic fatigue

Depression/anxiety, breast ca: cont home medications

PPX. Lovenox, PPI (reflux)

FEN. NPO. D5NS 150 cc/h x 2 liters

CODE: Full code 



Case discussed with Dr Ritter, coverage for Dr A Jaeger, Medicine Attending.



_________________________

Virginia N Volk, MD, PhD

PGY-3 Internal Medicine, DCA

Pager 48249














****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-04-07

































 
SDU JAR Admission Note



Patient:    Fonseca, Linda

DCA MRN:    7090253

Date of Admission: 04/07/82

Attending: 
Asia Doty

PCP:        Austin Jaeger
 (Whitehouse)
Code Status: Full code



CC:         chest pain

  

HPI:

This is a 65 yo female with T2DM, HL, active smoking, breast cancer s/p BL mastectomy and chemoradiation, and a question of a lupus-like disorder who presents with chest pain.  She was seated at breakfast this AM when she developed sudden onset ripping chest pain which radiated &#8220;like a knife&#8221; to her upper back.  It was associated with nausea but no vomiting or diaphoresis or shortness of breath.  It did radiate down both arms, but she her arm pains are now new.  It was not relieved by any positioning, or largely affected by taking deep breaths.  It tapered off over about 20 minutes.  She felt fatigued and layed down, when it occurred again several hours later, again lasting for about 20 minutes.  She then presented to DCA-ED for evaluation.  She had a negative adenosine MIBI at JMH in 2078.



She has had a difficult time recently, she is under evaluation for a lupus-like syndrome (she has noted positivity for ANA, anti-smith, anti-dsDNA).  She has had progressive joint and muscle pain of all of her major joints (ankes, knees, hips, wrists, elbows, shoulders, neck, lumbar back) and the muscles of her arms and legs.  She endorses progressive mental &#8220;cloudiness&#8221;, frequently dropping items like cutlery and cups, and increasing tremor in her hands.



DCA ED Course:

Initial EKG NSR without ischemic changes

Initial biomarkers strongly positive with CKMB 33 and Troponin 0.36.  CXR unremarkable.

She was treated for NSTEMI with ASA 325 mg X 1, heparin gtt, IV lopressor.

She had a brief episode of CP which was relieved by SL NTG and morphine.

She was sent to SDU for further evaluation and treatment. 



ROS (positive findings denoted)

Constitutional: fatigue

Head/Eyes: occ dizziness

ENT/Neck: URI sx two weeks ago, chronic neck pain

Chest/Respiratory: See HPI

GI/Abdominal: denies

Cardiovascular: See HPI

Musculoskel/Extr/Back: See HPI

Neuro: See HPI



MEDICAL HISTORY

Hx of pancreatitis

Question of SLE; (+) ANA, dsdna, smith; 

Breast ca 

-                    s/p bilateral mastectomies w/positive nodes

-                    s/p chemoradiation on femara

Depression and anxiety

T2DM; insulin-requiring

Hyperlipidemia

h/o back pain

h/o ear infection s/p Augmentin 



FAMILY HISTORY

Mom: stroke, CAD/CABG

Dad: CAD/CABG, DM, lymphoma



SOCIAL HISTORY

Lives with 90 yo mother and cousin.

Etoh - denies

Tobacco &#8211; &#189; PPD, down from &gt; 2 ppd.

Drugs - denies



ALLERGIES: 

Tricyclic Antidepressants - cough, 

Sulfa - Rash, 

EZETIMIBE - lethargy, GI Intolerance



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION

  1. Asa (Acetylsalicylic Acid)  81 MG PO QD

  2. Clonazepam   PO as directed prn

      PAML medication information: unit strength: 1MG form: TABLET take: 1  Tablet(s)

      Take one half tab twice a day and half tab upto twice a day. if needed for anxiety. #QJ1829196

  3. Cyclobenzaprine Hcl  5 MG PO as directed

      1 hs for 5 nights, the 1 tid thereafter

  4. Humulin N (Insulin Nph Human)  Variable SC 

      40 UNITS QAM x   HOURS

      22 UNITS QPM x   HOURS

  5. Insulin Regular Human (Humulin R)  Variable SC 

      20 UNITS QAM x   HOURS

      16 UNITS QPM x   HOURS

  6. Letrozole  2.5 MG PO QD

  7. Omeprazole Otc (Prilosec Otc)  20 MG PO Q12H

  8. Simvastatin  40 MG PO QHS

  9. Topiramate (Topamax) 
50 MG PO  TID

      Take two tabs in AM and two tabs at night.


10. Effexor (Venlafaxine Hcl)  150MG PO BID

      Take two tabs twice a day.



PHYSICAL EXAM

VITALS:     T-98  BP-134/60R 125/55L P-55 
SAO2 100 % on RA



GEN&#8217;L:      awake, alert pleasant, in no distress

HEENT:      JVD not elevated, no carotid bruits 

Heart:      bradycardic, regular, no murmurs (no diastolic murmur at RUSB while leaning forward).  Endorses tenderness to pressure on sternum (different from CP earlier today)

LUNG:       CTAB no wheezes.  s/p BL mastectomy

ABD: 
      obese, soft, nontender, +BS

EXT:        warm without edema, 2+ DP pulses bilaterally

NEURO:      A&amp;OX3, CN unremarkable, no dysmetria, no obvious tremor on examination



&#183; Chemistries:   



Plasma Sodium                    135                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.3                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  100                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            24.0                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 11                        (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          10.0                      (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             16                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.01                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             58                                       mL/min/1.73m2

Plasma Glucose                   345              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



&#183; Cardiac:  



Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       32.8             H        (0.0-6.9)      ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index             7.7              H        (0.0-3.5)      %

Troponin-T                       0.36             H        (&lt;0.03)        ng/ml

Creatine Kinase                  428              H        (40-150)       U/L

&#183; Hematology:  



WBC                              9.0                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              44.9                      (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              15.1                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              4.62                      (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              202                       (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              97                        (80-100)       fl

Poly                             77               H        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           19               L        (22-44)        %

Monos                            4                         (4-11)        
%

EOS                              0                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %



&#183; Coags:  



Superstat PT                     12.9                      (10.8-13.4)    sec

Superstat PT-INR                 1.1

Superstat APTT                   25.5                      (21.0-33.0)    sec



&#183; Imaging:  CXR &#8211; no acute processes



&#183; EKG: (admit to SDU) 



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN

This is a 65 yo female with T2DM, HL, active smoking, breast cancer s/p BL mastectomy and chemoradiation, and a question of a lupus-like disorder who presents with chest pain, + troponins, unremarkable EKG.  Cardiac RF = age, DM, HL, active smoking.  TIMI score = 3 (age, asa use, + biomarkers).  DDx = ACS (high risk NSTEMI), aortic dissection (concerning elements of hx), PE (given cancer hx, on SERM), or perimyocarditis (question associated with lupus-like condition).  The lack of hypoxia or tachycardia argue against PE.  Given her risk factors, after exoneration of her aorta by CT scan, she should undergo cardiac catheterization to assess for epicardial disease.  She is currently CP free.



1.    Chest pain

-     CTA chest to rule out aortic dissection now

-     If CTA negative, heparinize, begin integrilin drip (given TIMI of 3), continue ASA, statin, SL nitrate prn, likely coronary catheterization in AM.  Cycle serial cardiac enzymes and EKGs.

-     If positive, transfer to unit for invasive hemodynamic monitoring, aggressive dP/dT control, and CV surgical consult

-     TTE in AM

-     Check amylase, lipase 

-     Risk stratify with HbA1c and FLP in AM

-     Smoking cessation consult



2.    Lupus-like condition

-     Alert rheumatology team to admission in AM



3.    DM

-     Check HbA1c

-     BID NPH and AC+HS RISS



4.    Renal

-     renal prophylaxis give planned dye loads &#8211; mucormyst 1200 BID + IV bicarbonate



5.    Psych

-     continue home regimen &#8211; klonopin, effexor, topamax



Code status &#8211; Full code







__________________________________

Eli S Lindsay, MD PhD PGY-2

Pager #46656






****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>