<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2094-05-20

ZELDA UPHAM

SMC Unit No:  



MOLLY STARK HOSPITAL



ADULT MEDICINE





Date:  May 20, 2094



70-year-old female, first visit to MSH AMED. 



MEDICATIONS:  Ibuprofen 800 mg 1 p.o. b.i.d., has taken for years. Self-d/c'd meclizine, unclear status on H2 blocker.



ALLERGIES: Percocet, codeine, sulfa.



PMH: Includes fibromyalgia with chronic pain, osteoarthritis, recurrent vertigo, cervical spondylosis, lumbar spondylosis, carpal tunnel syndrome, myofascial pain, dizziness, syncope, chest pain of unclear etiology, sinusitis, DJD. Status post laminectomy 2062. 



S:	70-year-old female accompanied by daughter, Qazi, here to initiate primary care closer to home. Previously followed by Dr. Faust, but daughter needs closer PCP. In addition, patient followed in arthritis clinic by Dr. Solomon and has received injections per patient report from severe muscle spasms of both arms. Also seen by pain clinic. Main issue is continued lower back pain and primary care. Of concern is patient reveals an unclear history of chest pain which was thought to be arthritis, but is accompanied by episodes of syncope, witnessed in a grocery store. Patient has not had to her knowledge a cardiac workup for this. Also had some vascular studies done at that time and was told they were normal. The patient is unclear on status of recent pelvic exam. GYN - G7, P7, still with uterus but not sexually active. Denies any change in bowels. Denies any change in appetite. 



The patient has been complaining of animals crawling across her chest. States she used a cream for 1 week with resolution but now feels the animals are back, and she has been using a pesticide agent which sounds like a Kwell agent to resolve these. 



Recent testing - L-spine films confirm grade 2 anterospondylolisthesis L4-L5 with disc space changes at L1-L2. Negative allergy testing. 1/1 immune globulin testing significant for an IgG of 15/40 and positive ANA at 1:40 and 1:60. MRI of spine 12/93 shows degenerative changes of lumbar spine. No evidence of disc herniation or canal stenosis. 11/92 - Paranasal sinus films show no evidence of sinusitis. Mammo 3/94 WNL. Carotid ultrasound done 12/93 shows minimal disease of right and left carotid bifurcations. TCDs 12/93 suggest a stenosis of the left vertebral artery with an RVA WNL. Velocity suggests a mild stenosis. EKG 12/93 shows sinus brad with an LAE. No other significant changes. Nonspecific ST changes. 



O:	HEENT - Unremarkable. Skin - No obvious sign of rash or infection where she states the animals are present. CV - BP is 170/88. RR at 60. No murmurs, gallops, rubs present. Lungs - Clear to P&A. B12 was 331. Attempted Pap smear. External genitalia unremarkable. Vaginal introitus is very small. Patient got very cold and clammy and nervous throughout the tried Pap smear; so Pap smear attempt was terminated at that time. Consent was obtained to conduct Pap smear. Lungs - Clear to P&A. 



A/P:	(1)	Dizziness of unclear etiology. Neuro consult had been done when the patient was hospitalized, and meclizine has not been of any benefit. Will refer patient to Vascular to ascertain whether the TCD findings are related. 



(2)	Report of syncope. Will obtain stress test.



(3)	Chronic NSAID usage. Add ranitidine HCL 150 mg to 1 p.o. q.h.s. to regime. Patient will follow up with Dr. Helen Whitehead as  her new PCP.





Frieda Nadeau, RN, ANP



FN/warren/forbes





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-09-28

 

 

CHOL 210 (T) 244 (H) 243 (H) 256 (H) 

TRIG 50       

HDL 62       

LDL 138

F/u: CAD, LBP

Saw  Dr Mora of Cardiology, who she says kept her on ASA and SL NTG.  Says told to attend cardiac rehab 2 x week, but that a nurse later told her she didn't need it.  Appt with him pending 10/28/94. Saw nutritionist.  Still gets exertional CP in same pattern.



C/o severe, chronic low back for 10 years.  Followed by Dr. Solomon for 3 years.  DJD  on MRI 12/93 and told  of sciatica.  Uses ibuprofen  800 po tid.  Not sure about cox 2 inhibitor use in the past and Ultram made too groggy.Became tearful when discussing this issue, statingthat paincanbe excruciating.

Notes anxiety due to terrorist attacks and is not sleeping well.  Lives alone.  Asks for some Valium. 

PE: WD/WN in NAD

 

BLOOD PRESSURE  140/70  

TEMPERATURE   

PULSE  64  

RESPIRATORY RATE   

O2 SAT   

HEIGHT   

WEIGHT  151 lb  



lungs clear

back no CVAT or ST

cor RRR S1S2, no murmur

extrem no LE edema



A/P:

1)CAD- will look for correspondence from Dr. Mora re: his thoughts.  Consider adding low dose beta blocker, since BP is a little.  Needs mor aggressive lowereing of lipid.  At next visit, repeat lipid, and consider lipitor.

2)Back pain- suspect there is some somatization, but patient is far from being able to accept this.  For now, refilled Ibupfofen and follow how often she refills.  Note in record of patient requesting Vicodan, which was given to her before by Dr. Solomon.  Would avoid if possible.

3)Anxiety- Valium 5 mg #15 mg, prn. Offer counseling at next visit if persists.

4)HMC- will ofer colonoscopy at next visit.



RTC 6 weeks 





















RTC 6 weeks













--------------Vital Signs----------















****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-05-10







NAME:     Upham, Zelda

MRN:      9656797



Patient is here for a follow-up.  Patient has returned from her trip to Hong Kong.  Says

that it was a bit stifling, because she cannot drive and was dependent on other people

for transportation.



Still has severe right shoulder pain.  Still also complaining of left jaw pain, that is

worse when she has to open her mouth very widely.  Reviewed x-rays, which were

negative for fracture of frontal facial bones, and did not reveal obvious abnormality in

the TMJ area.  Has yet to receive an appointment from Dr. Vann for this

shoulder pain.



Patient was afraid to try the Vioxx, because she was told by the pharmacist that she

could not take it with ibuprofen. I explained to her that she should take the Vioxx in

place of the ibuprofen and she understands.  Is not willing to try Flexeril. 



Patient spent approximately 20 minutes describing her dissatisfaction and difficult

interactions with her children.  Has not asked for more Valium.  Has never been

interested in counseling prior to today.  Did not become tearful like she has in the

past.  



Asked for refill of sublingual nitroglycerin.  Prescription apparently was given to her

last spring.  Complains also of upper chest wall tenderness.  No clear to me what

causes her to take the sublingual nitroglycerine, but says when she takes it, it relieves

her symptoms.  I have asked her if this pain is ever exertional, or is the same pain

that is reproducible when she touches her chest.  The patient seems to label her chest

wall pain as the same as pain that she gets with exertion.  



PROBLEMS: As per LMR.



MEDICATIONS: As per LMR.



ALLERGIES: As per LMR.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: WD/WN female in NAD. Blood pressure 150/80.

Pulse 80 and regular.  Weight 152 pounds.  Lungs: Clear bilateral breath sounds. 

COR: RRR. S1 and S2 without murmurs noted.  Extremities: No lower extremity

edema.  Soreness over posterior right upper trapezius.  Full range of motion of

shoulders. No tenderness over AC joints.  Chest wall tenderness over superior aspect

of sternum and its border on left.  No masses or deformity noted.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



(1)  Chest pain: Certainly overdue for a follow-up with her cardiologist, Dr. Hunter

     Mccarthy.  Referral done.  Also referred sublingual nitroglycerin.



(2)  Elevated blood pressure.  Better than last visit, but remains slightly elevated. 

     At last visit, patient was reluctant to start a beta blocker.  Think she may need

     this at future visit.  Will also refer back to her cardiologist.



(3)  Elevated lipids, last checked last year. Several medications that patient appears

     to be sensitive to side effects.  At next visit, will give lab slip to repeat fasting

     profile. Positive checkup.  Would probably benefit from lipid lowering.



(4)  Leg cramps.  Toward end of visit, patient also complained of more than 25

     years of leg cramps.  Unable to take quinine because of allergic reaction. 

     Patient already takes Valium p.r.n. and I am reluctant to start any other

     anxiolytics.  Will check electrolytes and calcium at next visit. 



(5)  History of sciatica.  Patient states in past that she has received steroid injection

     for her lower back pain, which resolved.  Will simply follow with Vioxx, which

     will hopefully help other pains that patient is experiencing.  Also continue with

     her rheumatologist, Dr. Solomon, who has followed her chronic fibromyalgia and

     chronic low back pain.



Return to clinic with me in six to eight weeks. 



ADDENDUM: Patient's referral was receiving by Dr. Vann's office and they tell

me she should be able to get an appointment for 6/95.  



Helen Whitehead, M.D.



HW/warren/stark



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-12-07




NAME:     Upham, Zelda
MRN:      0308696

The patient is here for a scheduled visit, status post hospitalization for emergent
bypass surgery.  She is late for the visit.  She is accompanied by her daughter,
Qazi.  The patient denies chest pain and has done quite well, based on reports
from her rehab stay at the Miller County Hospital.  Currently complaining of
left-sided chest wall pain. No exertional chest pain and no shortness of breath.  Has
an appointment pending with her cardiologist tomorrow.  Also has an appointment
pending with surgeon Dr. Weeks for 12/13/95. Has been compliant with
medications.  

The patient's daughter is concerned that the patient is not eating enough.  Has lost
significant weight since hospitalization.  Patient did agree that she has been watching
what she eats because she did not want to gain much weight.  Explained to her the
importance of proper nutrition and getting back her strength.  

Asked if she can use an OTC pain patch called Salonpas. Says that the chest wall
tenderness is very different from any exertional chest pain that she may have had in
the past.  Would like some relief for this.  Uses it on her knees and finds it helpful
for the arthritic knee pain. 

Emotionally, the patient did admit to feeling depressed and did become tearful
during the visit. 

PROBLEMS: See extensive LMR list. 

MEDICATIONS:  See LMR list. 

ALLERGIES:  Sulfa, Percocet and quinine. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: Well-appearing female. Vital signs: WNL, as per flow
sheet. Lungs: Clear with rales. COR: RRR, S1 and S2 without murmurs noted. 

ASSESSMENT:

(1)  CAD: The patient is also on a cholesterol-lowering agent, but will update list
     at next visit.  Keep appointment with cardiologist. 

(2)  Chest wall tenderness status post CABG: Tried to encourage patient that there
     will be some persistent discomfort in her wound for several months.  Told her
     to hold off on using the OTC pain patch until I can verify the ingredients. 

(3)  Depressed mood status post surgery: Refuses referral to Mental Health. Not
     suicidal. Encouraged patient to eat more regularly. 

(4)  Return to clinic for follow-up in two weeks.  

This visit lasted for 35 minutes, half of which was spent trying to counsel the patient
to obtain proper nutrition and to go to Mental Health.  I was unsuccessful in
convincing her to attend a Mental Health session. 

Helen Whitehead, M.D.

HW/warren/stark



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-08-18



MSH Adult Medicine Office Visit                              PCP Dr Whitehead



73 yr old woman with HTN, SP CABG, fibromyalgia comes in for follow up of renal MRA done for evaluation of renal insufficiency and associated high K.

She was hospitalized in 7/97 for a fairly acute deterioration of renal function and hyperkalemia.  At that time she was told to DC Lisinopril and Vioxx.  Her renal function seemed to improve with that intervention though in early August her K+ rose a bit.  The VNA has been seeing her at home.  According to the patient her BP has been "normal".

She and her daughter come in now to review results of the recent renal MRA.  They are seeing me because there  were no appts available for her with her PCP.  

She denies any chest pain, shortness of breath.  Appetite is good.

She has been trying to avoid foods high in potassium but she is not sure about K+ content of many foods.

She has been taking Lisinopril at the same dose since her CBG in 2095 and has been taking NSAIDs for fibromyalgia for several years.



Medications

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 650MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 CAPSULE PO QD 

Ntg 1/150 (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 MG)) 1 TAB SL Q5 MIN X 3 

Meclizine HCL 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID 

Neurontin (GABAPENTIN) 300MG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s) PO QHS x 30 days

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS 

Atenolol 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , use pill cutter

Effexor (VENLAFAXINE HCL) 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 



Problems

Coronary artery disease : Sesta mibi EST 7/18/94 positive for inferoseptal and mild septal ishemia.  

       SP CABG X 5 2095

Low back pain : MRI, LS spine 12/05/93;DJD, no spinal stenosis, o disc herniation.

Sciatica : Dr. Solomon follows.

Syncope : etiology not clear; ? fainting.

Anxiety 

Fibromyalgia : Dr. Solomon

Pain in joint : Mild degenerative changes at the rightacromioclavicular joint. 

granuloma : RUL, stable

Acute renal failure : off vioxx and ACE resolved, 7/97 



Procedures

Cardiac bypass graft surgery: CORONARY ARTERY BYPASS GRAFT TIMES FIVE (LEFT INTERNAL MAMMARY ARTERY TO LEFT ANTERIOR DESCENDING, REVERSED SAPHENOUS VEIN TO POSTERIOR LEFT VENTRICLE AND POSTERIOR DESCENDING ARTERY, REVERSED SAPHENOUS VEIN TO DIAGONAL AND RAMUS INTERMEDIUS). 



Allergies

PERCOCET - abdominal discomfort, 

Codeine - GI upset, 

Sulfa - Rash, 

Quinine Sulfate - Unknown

Oxycodone 10 Mg/acetaminophen 650 Mg - Unknown

QUININE - LOC after dizzyness, 

ROFECOXIB - RI, 

LISINOPRIL - Renal Toxicity 



PE:  BP 140/80 R and L arms sitting P 60 reg

No JVD.

Chest is clear

COR:  RRR, no m, rub.

No edema.



Results

Radiology



Exam Number:  5998283                        Report Status:  Final

Type:  MRA 3D

Date/Time:  08/06/2097 10:00 AM

Associated Reports:  

   9899518:  MRA Renal + & -

------------------------------------------------------------------------------

HISTORY:  

     RENAL ARTERY STENOSIS, ACUTE RENAL FAILURE

DIAGNOSIS:  

     EPPS

REPORT

     EXAMINATION: MRA RENAL ARTERIES

     PROCEDURE: MRA of the aorta and renal arteries was obtained according

     to standard department protocol.  3D images were obtained and

     interpreted.

     FINDINGS: The celiac, SMA and IMA are patent.  There are bilateral

     single renal arteries.  There is a moderate length moderate stenosis

     of the right renal artery, and the left renal artery is widely patent.

     The solid abdominal viscera, as visualized, are unremarkable.  There

     is a prominent left gonadal vein.

IMPRESSION

      MODERATE STENOSIS OF THE RIGHT RENAL ARTERY

     

Type: Ultr., Kidney Date/Time: 07/23/2097 12:41 PM HISTORY: SOB AND DIZZINESS ASSESS HYDRONEPHROSIS REPORT History: Question hydronephrosis. Images from an ultrasound study of the kidneys and the bladder were acquired. There are no prior studies for comparison. Both kidneys are normal in size and lie. The right kidney measures 9.8 and the left kidney measures 9.7 cm in sagittal dimension. No hydronephrosis or dominant solid masses are seen. Notice made of a right extrarenal pelvis. The bladder is moderately distended without intraluminal lesions. 

IMPRESSION No hydronephrosis. 

   

         08/04/2097 08/02/2097 07/31/2097 07/24/2097  

NA       138                              140         

K        5.2(H)     5.6(H)     5.2(H)     4.5         

CL       105                              108         

CO2      20.5(L)                          23.7        

BUN      42(H)      47(H)      58(H)      38(H)       

CRE      1.5        1.7(H)     2.3(H)     1.3         

GLU      95                    75         187(H)      

     

         07/23/2097 07/23/2097 07/22/2097 07/22/2097 07/18/2097  

NA       140        142                   136        141         

K        4.8        4.7        3.8        6.5(HT)    5.3(H)      

CL       107        104                   106        105         

CO2      26.6       25.7                  24.6       24.8        

BUN      57(H)      74(H)                 67(H)      54(H)       

CRE      1.7(H)     2.4(H)                3.1(H)     2.3(H)      

GLU                                       75         83          

         

         02/11/2097 01/25/2097 11/12/2096 11/11/2096 02/23/2096  

NA       137                   143        137        142         

K        5.0(H)                3.8        4.2        4.8         

CL       104                   106        105        104         

CO2      24.9                  24.5       25.7       28          

BUN      40(H)      37(H)      26(H)      29(H)      26(H)       

CRE      1.4        1.6(H)     1.3        1.5        0.9         

GLU      124(H)     101                   127(H)     87          

    

         02/08/2096 11/28/2095 11/18/2095 11/14/2095 10/30/2095  

NA       136        142        142        141        137         

K        4.9(H)     4.5        4.9        4.8        4.2         

CL       100        108        107        109        97(L)       

CO2      22.1(L)    23         25         23         32(H)       

BUN      46(H)      33(H)      25(H)      21         18          

CRE      1.6(H)     1.2        1.0        0.9        1.0         

GLU      87         96         98         90         94          

 

         07/23/2097  

UA-COLOR Yellow    

UA-TURB  Clear         

UA-GLUC  NEGATIVE   

UA-BILI  NEGATIVE     

UA-KET   NEGATIVE      

UA-SPGR  1.018            

UA-BLD   NEGATIVE     

UA-PH    5.5       

UA-ALB   NEGATIVE      

UA-UROBI NEGATIVE      

UA-NIT   NEGATIVE   

UA-WBC   1+          

HCAST    0-2             

UAS-RBC  0-2           

UAS-WBC  3-5            

UAS-BACT NEGATIVE     

UAS-SQHI NEGATIVE      

 

According to discharge summary of hospitalization in 7/97, urine was negative for eosinophils.



A:  73 yr old with HTN has had deterioration of renal function since 2095 when she began taking ACEi concomitantly with NSAID.  The cause for more acute deterioration of renal function in 7/2097 and again in early August is unclear.

She has not been taking any NSAID including OTC forms. 

I don't think the moderate renal artery stenosis is a significant contributor to renal dysfunction and her BP is reasonable off the ACEi.  



P:  Her daughter had many questions about what this type of "blockage" means and about prognosis.  

I attempted to explain the differences between renal perfusion, renal function, and to advise her about the role/impact of ACEi for BP and her heart (her daughter is worried that her heart will suffer if she doesn't take the ACEi).  

I told her that it is unsafe for her to take any NSAID. 

I suggested that a renal specialist would be helpful in determining the role of renal artery disease in her renal dysfunction.

Provided her with detailed lists of low and high K+ foods.

Check lytes, renal function, Phos, Ca and Alb today.

Will discuss Nephrology consultation with Dr Whitehead.



She has an appt with Dr Whitehead on 8/27.



Length of visit was 45 minutes.





_____________________________________________

Carole B. Holland, M.D.



  

   

   

 



















****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>