<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2122-04-17

                     SRH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
JONES,URIEL   222-67-70-8                    VISIT DATE: 04/17/22
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 48 year old 
gentleman with a past medical history of hypertension, asthma, 
hypercholesteremia, and hypertension who presents complaining of 
chest pain.  The patient was seen in conjunction with the resident, 
Dr. Simmons.  Please see her note for explicit details of the visit. 
The patient was in his usual state of health until yesterday, when 
he noticed increasing shortness of breath with exertion, dyspnea, 
and diaphoresis and had an episode of chest pain radiating to his 
left neck.  The episode recurred this morning.  The patient 
presented to his primary care physician, who referred him to the 
Emergency Department for evaluation.  Upon presented to the 
Emergency Department, the patient was pain-free and symptom-free, 
denying shortness of breath, fevers, chills, nausea, or vomiting. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Normal.  HEENT: 
Normocephalic, atraumatic.  NECK:  Supple.  CHEST:  Clear. 
ABDOMEN:  Soft. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  EKG showed no significant changes when 
compared to old EKGs.  There was some confusion regarding ST 
elevations, but they were due to lead placement.  Troponin was 
0.42.  CPK was 175. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient received oxygen, 
nitropaste, aspirin, and 2 mg of morphine in the Emergency 
Department with complete resolution of his symptoms. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Rule out MI. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 
be admitted to the hospital.  Condition upon admission is good. 
___________________________________                    BE249/3185 
ULICES ZAMUDIO, M.D.  UZ8                                D:04/17/22 
                                                       T:04/17/22 
Dictated by:  ULICES ZAMUDIO, M.D.  UZ8 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2125-07-18

                     SRH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

JONES,URIEL   222-67-70-8                    VISIT DATE: 07/19/25

Seen with Dr. Person.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY, SOCIAL HISTORY, FAMILY HISTORY, REVIEW OF 

SYSTEMS, MEDICATIONS, ALLERGIES:  Were reviewed and confirmed.  

Please see Resident note for further details.  

HISTORY:  I interviewed and examined the patient myself.  The 

history briefly is as follows.  This is a 51 year-old male who was 

recently discharged from the hospital here after a successful 

percutaneous lithotripsy and nephrostomy placement.  He presented 

this evening for a leakage from his nephrostomy tube which he 

believes may have become dislodged or had its cap removed when he 

was sitting on the sofa and got up.  He has been leaking 

serosanguineous fluid since earlier today.  He has no fever, 

chills.  No other complaints.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Includes diabetes, hypertension, CAD, high 

cholesterol.  

MEDICATIONS:  He takes hydrochlorothiazide, Zestril, Calan, Zocor 

and Levaquin.   

ALLERGIES:  He has no allergies to medications.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise negative.  

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He lives with his family.  

FAMILY HISTORY:  He has no significant family history.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  His temperature is 99.2, heart rate 93, 

blood pressure 136/81.  He is an awake and alert male in no acute 

distress.  HEENT - Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Oropharynx clear.  

Neck is supple.  Chest clear to auscultation bilaterally.  

Cardiovascular exam is regular rate and rhythm without murmur, rub 

or gallop.  Abdomen is soft, nontender.  Mildly obese.  Skin is 

warm and dry.  Left flank is with some resolving ecchymosis.  No 

obvious subcutaneous fluid, and the area around the nephrostomy 

drain is intact.  His gurney linens are soaked with serosanguineous 

fluid.  Extremities without clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  

Neurologically alert and oriented.  Cranial nerves II-XII are 

intact.  No motor or sensory deficits.   

CONSULTATIONS:  He is seen in consultation by the Urology Service 

and his tubing was cut back and cap replaced.  It is unclear as 

this was placed by Radiology exactly the exact 

configuration of the tubing.  However, it appears to have ceased 

leak at this time.  

DISPOSITION:  He is discharged in satisfactory condition with 

instructions to return for return of symptoms or for any other 

concerns, and to call to have follow up arranged for early next 

week. 

___________________________________                    VJ645/69473 

ULICES ELLIOT, M.D.  UE57                            D:07/19/25 

                                                       T:07/19/25 

Dictated by:  ULICES ELLIOT, M.D.  UE57 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2131-05-30

EDVISIT^22267708^JONES, URIEL^05/30/31^COOKE, FREDI

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Shortness of breath.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  A 67 year-old male was seen in

transfer from Friends Hospital for evaluation of progressively

worsening shortness of breath over the last 2 days, associated

with increased fatigue and episodes of chest pressure yesterday. 

He did note increase weight for the last 1-2 months,

progressively worsening shortness of breath with minimal

exertion.  He did have chest pressure at rest yesterday, which

did radiate to his left shoulder.  This seemed to resolve

spontaneously and then he noted shortness of breath with any kind

of exertion at all.  The shortness of breath was exclusively

exertional.  He has not noticed nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis,

presyncopal symptoms or diarrhea.  No fevers.  He does have a

slight cough that is nonproductive.  He was seen at a local

Emergency Department today where he had laboratory studies as

well as was given Lasix, albuterol, and nitroglycerin and states

he has some relief of his symptoms associated with this.  He was

cardioverted 2 days ago for atrial fibrillation by his

cardiologist at SAH.  Additionally, at the outside Emergency

Department, his INR was therapeutic at 2 as he is on Coumadin,

but his troponin was elevated at 0.16.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for hypertension, orally

controlled diabetes, hypercholesterolemia, and atrial flutter. 

He has had a cardiac catheterization last in 2127.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a past smoker with 10 pack years of

smoking.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As noted in the written chart and HPI,

otherwise negative.

MEDICATIONS:  Coumadin, citalopram, metoprolol, lisinopril,

glipizide, Cipro, and simvastatin.

ALLERGIES:  He is allergic to penicillin.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature 99, pulse 63, respiratory rate

20, blood pressure 140/86, and oxygen saturation 96% on room air.

 HEENT:  Normocephalic and atraumatic.  Pleasant, calm.  Neck is

supple.  Respiratory:  Clear to auscultation, except for

scattered rales in the left lower lung field.  Cardiovascular: 

Regular rate and rhythm without murmur.  Abdomen is soft and

nontender.  Skin is intact, warm, and dry.  Extremities:  He has

got 1+ edema of the bilateral lower extremities that is

symmetric.  Neuropsych:  He is oriented x3, moves all extremities

equally.

LABORATORY DATA:  ECG shows a sinus rhythm at 65 with poor R-wave

progression, but no acute ST segment abnormalities.  Chest x-ray

shows interstitial increased markings with a small left pleural

effusion and prominence of the ventricle consistent with mild

pulmonary edema.  Cardiac biomarkers show troponin of 0.16 with

creatinine of 1.43, CK-MB of 3.2 with normal index, and CK of 87.

 BNP is still pending.  INR is 2.5, which is therapeutic on

Coumadin.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  At the outside Emergency

Department, he did receive Lasix and he put off approximately 2

liters of urine since then with significant symptomatic

improvement in his dyspnea.  He has no further episodes of chest

pain or pressure.  I did discuss the case with Dr. Davison,

the SAH cardiologist on-call.  I believe this patient has CHF

exacerbation.  He also was recently cardioverted, which ____

explain his troponin elevation.  Additionally, his CHF

exacerbation alone could explain his troponin elevation, and I

doubt the patient has an acute coronary syndrome.  At this point,

the patient is already anticoagulated by virtue of being on

Coumadin.  We will hold any further heparinization or Lovenox at

this time.  However, he will have serial cardiac biomarkers, will

be admitted to the Cardiology Service for evaluation and for

further evaluation and optimization of his congestive heart

failure and for monitoring of his troponin levels.

DIAGNOSIS:  Congestive heart failure exacerbation, troponin

elevation, and diabetes.

DISPOSITION:  Admission in stable condition.

______________________________

COOKE, FREDI M.D.

D: 05/30/31

T: 05/31/31

Dictated By: COOKE, FREDI

eScription document:0-8412167 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2133-08-02


Stallworth Rehabilitation Hospital/Newport Bariatric Surgery Program
 
Postop  Nutrition Assessment

Patient:  Uriel Jones                                     DOB:   1/7/74                  
Date:   
8/2/33

Surgeon:   Dr.  Black              Surgical date:    s/p gastric bypass 5/11/33 




S:

Hx:  Pt was seen by his request with his wife.  Pt is married and 3 children ages 27, 22, and 19.  Pt lives with wife and 2 children.  Pt work as Small Equipment Mechanic.     

Reported diet stage:  4

Adjustments:   tried soda

Issues with current diet:   chix, hamburger

Food intolerance:    soda in can

Nausea     
  
      no   

Vomiting   
  

    
yes, x1 pace, occ, 
with dry chix

Diarrhea        
    occ loose stools

Constipation       occ needs more

Hydration         
  needs more

Other:    

24-hour dietary recall:

B:        yogurt Yoplait with fruit and pb and some granola

Sn:    

L:       
chix, BBQ small thigh and 2 wings, brown rice

Sn:      oc carrots of fruit

D:       
1-2 eggs with shrimp and toast with marg and jelly

Sn:      none

Beverages:    G2 on walk, water, iced coffee with cream 

Supplements:   
most days walk, 3 miles



O:

Age:   59 y                               Sex:   male                            

Ht: 
5&#8217;7.5&#8221;                                   Wt:  
255#                             

BMI:   39.4

Previous weight:           273# 6/20/33    /   295#  5/24/33        

IBW: 138-168#              Excess Wt:  87-117#

Preoperative weight: 333#  1/11/33            Cumulative Wt Change:  down 78#

PMH:  
edema, type 2 DM, OSA with CPAP, hypercholesterolemia, HTN, cardiac myopathy, OA in knees, open chole

Medications:  lantus, humalog sliding scale, Coumadin

Current meds 5/24/33:  CPAP, coumadin, ASA 81 mg, K citrate, furosemide, fluoxitine, cordarone, metoprolol, glucosamine and chondroitin, lisinopril, crestor, norvasc, pepcid

Current meds 6/20/33:  off lantus, humalog, 

Current meds 8/2/33:  
CPAP, coumadin, ASA 81 mg, K citrate, furosemide, fluoxitine, cordarone, 
metoprolol, d/c glucosamine and chondroitin, lisinopril, crestor, norvasc, pepcid

Labs:  to be evaluated per surgeon, BS 110 am

Prescribed diet:  stage  4

Patient educational material used: Dietary Guidelines for Gastric Bypass, protein list

                                                                                                            

A:

59 y.o. male  referred to nutrition followup for gastric bypass.



Weight Assessment:  Pt weighs 255 lbs and is 68 inches tall with BMI of 39.4.     Obesity Class: 3



Est. Energy Needs: 
BMR 1940 kcal/day, ~2700-3000 cal/day for weight maintenance.



Dietary Assessment:


Pt presents with h/o edema, type 2 DM, OSA with CPAP, hypercholesterolemia, HTN, cardiac myopathy, OA in knees, open chole and morbid obesity s/p gastric bypass surgery x 3 months compliant with fluid, protein and vitamin and mineral supplementation recommendations

Pt to cont on stage 4





Issues discussed:

x  Diet stage:    4              x  Protein intake:  60 grams/day                     x  Fluid intake: &gt;64 oz/day

x  Multivitamin/mineral     x  Calcium w/Vit D:  1200-1500 mg calcium         Vitamin B12

x  Slowly eating and drinking, small portion sized, healthful food choices

x  Protein foods, food preparation methods

x  meal planning



P:

Recommendations:


Cont diet stage:  4

Expected adherence:  good

Goals:  &gt;64 ounces fluid/day, &gt;60 grams protein/day

Cont Multivitamin/mineral daily, cont 1200-1500 
mg calcium with added vitamin D daily 

Use protein list as guide

Increase food variety and consistency slowly

Cont current activity, increase as able

Call or email with any questions or problems





RTC 3 months postop surg, RD



Sonja Bauer, MS, RD, LDN

8/2/33




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>