<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2133-05-31

Attending History and Physical





HPI: This is a 59 year old PMP G0 who presents for evaluation and management of vulvar lesion. The patient reports a longstanding h/o a vulvar lesion in the same location. It was removed 5/24/2124 and the pathology revealed a sebaceous cyst. The patient reports feeling discomfort only with rubbing. No other skin changes. She desires surgical management at this time.



Problems

Diverticulitis : multiple surgeries

Hypertension 

Bronchiectasis 

Migraine headache 

Osteopenia 

Lactose intolerance 

Fibromyalgia 

Raynauds disease 

Mullerian Anomaly : "infantile uterus" per patient





Procedures

Laparotomy: multiple

Tonsillectomy: 2077

Appendectomy: 2093

Interstitial lung disease: right middle lobe of lung removed 2128 





Medications

Nortriptyline ( 75 MG (75MG CAPSULE take 1) PO HS 

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20 MG (20MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO QD 

Colace (DOCUSATE SODIUM) 200 MG (take 1) PO QD 

Inderal LA (PROPRANOLOL-LA) 120 MG (120MG CAP.SR 24H take 1) PO QD 

Estradiol 2 MG (2MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Medroxyprogesterone 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Vitamin C (ASCORBIC ACID) 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Vitamin E (TOCOPHEROL-DL-ALPHA) 400 UNITS (400 U/15ML LIQUID take 15 ML) PO QD 

Multivitamins 1 TAB PO QD 

Imitrex (SUMATRIPTAN) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO x1 PRN headache 

Fioricet (BUTALBITAL+APAP+CAFFEINE) 1 TAB PO Q4H PRN headache 





Allergies

percocet/darvon - GI upset, 

Sulfa - Unknown

Codeine - GI upset, 

ACETAMINOPHEN - migraines, 

Demerol - Unknown

METRONIDAZOLE - Unknown

LEVOFLOXACIN - Rash, Hives or Other Rash

AZITHROMYCIN - Hives or Other Rash 



Vital signs

BP 138/70, P 80, Ht 64 in, Wt 120.5 lb

LMP pmp 

Physical Exam

General Appearance:   NL Habitus. thin in nad

      Orientation:   Time; Place; Person

      Mood and Affect:   Normal

      Breasts/ Rectal: defered

      Ext. Genitalia:   Abnormal

1.0 x 0.3 cm cyst on right labia minor very close to clitoris. Appears to be consistent with a sebaceous cyst. No other skin changes are noted

      Ureth Meatus:   Normal

      Bladder:   Normal

      Vagina/pelv. supp:   Normal

      Cervix/ Uterus/ Adnexa/param. Anus/perin.: defered

Lungs: CTA A+P bilaterally

CV: RR, S1S2 wnl, no m/g/r

Abd: soft, nt, no masses, +BS

Ext: warm, no c/c/e

 

Labs:







A/P:This is a 59 year old PMP G0 with multiple medical problems who presents for evaluation of vulvar lesion. Physical exam reveals findings c/w sebaceous cyst. Surgical removal was recommended do to the increase in size and recurrance #4 of this lesion. Spinal vs epidural anesthesia was reveiwed. Possibility of abnormal pathology discussed. The patient states she understands and desires surgical treatment. Consent was signed. H+P done. Anesthesia consult and pre-operative labs ordered. NPO after MN discussed. 





_____________________________________________

Faithe W. Flynn, M.D.













 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2133-11-13

Rheumatology Consult Note



Name:  Vastie Uecker

MR#: 7045247

Date of Admission to PCH: 11/13/33

Consult Date: 11/13/33



ID/CC: 60 yo F w/FH scleroderma, personal hx of fibromyalgia, Raynaud's phenomena, GERD, HTN and bronchiectasis p/w diffuse arthralgias, myalgia



HPI: This is a 60 yo F w/a hx of fibromyalgia, Raynaud's, GERD, HTN, bronchiectasis and recurrent PNA who developed severe pain, swelling and stiffness in the MCP joints of both hands 2 nights ago. She says there was initially some redness, no warmth in these joints. She could not open or close her hands. She says the pain migrated to involve all of the joints in her hands, wrists, elbows, shoulders and knees. She noticed swelling in her R knee, no swelling or redness in other joints. Her muscles are diffusely tender. She recalls similar muscle discomfort in prior episodes attributed to fibromyalgia, although not as severe. She also remembers shoulder and elbow pain of similar but less intense character in 2128 while taking rifampin/cipro/azithro for MAC. These symptoms resolved when drugs were stopped. She denies recent fevers or chills. She completed an 8 day course of augmentin for MSSA PNA two days ago. Symptomatically she feels her PNA has resolved and she is at her baseline from a respiratory standpoint w/stable cough and SOB. She does report some mild L-sided pleuritic CP since yesterday. She denies weight loss, skin changes, rash, change in BMs, N/V, dry mouth, change in vision, weakness, paresthesias. ROS + for brittle nails, eye dryness not bothersome. FH notable for mother w/scleroderma.



Her symptoms did not respond to Excedrin and she presented to the ER 11/12. Exam notable for BP 212/93, HR 125, T 98, SO2 98%,    tenderness w/movement in UE's, R knee   . WBC 11.7, HCT 39.8, PLT 421, chem. 10 wnl, CXR w/stable bibasilar lung nodularity. She was admitted to Internal Medicine for further evaluation. She reports decreased pain with Demerol, interval improvement in hand joint swelling/erythema/stiffness.



PMH:

Bronchiectasis: Recurrent PNA since 3yo, s/p RML lobectomy 2128

MAC: Treatment interrupted 2/2 liver failure 2128

Diverticulitis c/b perforation and sigmoid resection 2129

Raynaud's

Fibromyalgia: Dx 2122 when she p/w neck, shoulder, hip, chest wall, knee and jaw pain; followed by Dr. Christopher Sharp at DCHC

Migraine headaches

HTN

GERD

Hiatal and ventral hernias

S/p appy

Osteopenia



Home Meds:  

Medroxyprogesterone 5mg qd

Estradiol 2mg qd

Prilosec 20mg qd

Inderal 120mg qd

Nortriptyline 75mg qd

Colace 100 bid

Vitamin C + E

Prn fioricet, Excedrin, imitrex



Current Meds:

Nortriptyline 75 mg qhs

Inderal 240mg qd

Nexium 20mg qd

Prn Demerol



All:

Percocet/Darvon/Codeine-GI upset

Sulfa-   kidney problem   

Flagyl-   throat closed   

Levaquin, azithromycin-rash

  	

SH:  	Retired Firefighter, no ETOH, tobacco or drugs 



FH:	Mother w/systemic scleroderma (joint pain and swelling, skin changes, Raynaud's), CAD, DM died at 68 yo



Exam:  	

	VS:  	Afebrile Tc 97.5; BP 164/80; HR 84; RR 20

	HEENT: Anicteric, OP clear no lesions

	Lungs:  Decreased BS at bases

	Cor:  	RRR no M/R/G, JVP 8

	Abd:  	Soft, NT, ND, reducible hernia R of midline

	MSK: Marked muscle tenderness to palpation, particularly involving chest, arms, legs; mild boney tenderness along entire spine; decreased lateral, forward flexion and extension of neck which she reports is baseline; shoulders, elbows and wrists with full ROM, NT; slight tissue swelling/?synovitis involving MCP joints bilaterally, particularly L first MCP, no warmth or erythema; no PIP or DIP finger joint abnormalities; hips somewhat stiff but w/full ROM; R>L knee crepitus, full ROM; ankles w/full ROM; strength intact

	Skin/nails: No rashes, petechiae, or nail changes  

	

Labs:

PCH  BLOOD          13-Nov-2133 09:58  Accession# 8326S84259



WBC                              9.9                       (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                              36.0                      (36.0-46.0)      %

HGB                              12.7                      (12.0-16.0)      gm/dl

RBC                              4.06                      (4.00-5.20)      mil/cmm

PLT                              437              H        (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                              89                        (80-100)         fl

MCH                              31.4                      (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                             35.4                      (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                              13.3                      (11.5-14.5)      %

ESR                              79               H        (1-25)           mm/hr



Plasma Sodium                    134              L        (135-145)        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 3.6                       (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  99               L        (100-108)        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            25.0                      (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

Calcium                          9.1                       (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus                       2.7                       (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.5                       (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             10                        (8-25)           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                0.8                       (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Thyroid Stimulating Hormone      0.96                      (0.40-5.00)      uU/ml



Blood Culture - Pending



PCH  PA & Lat. Chest              12-Nov-2133 18:34 Accession# 0152809   Final

	

	The faint areas of nodularity at the lung bases, slightly more

	prominent than seen on August 15, 2130.  The relative stability of

	these findings suggests an underlying benign etiology.  However,

	correlation with CT of the chest would be useful for further

	evaluation.



EKG:	NSR 80 LAD TWI V1-V5 similar to prior

____________________________________________



Impr:	60 yo F w/longstanding fibromyalgia and bronchiectasis s/p recent MSSA PNA p/w diffuse arthralgias, myalgias and pleuritic CP. The constellation of myalgias, arthralgias/synovitis, ?pleurisy, Raynaud's, GERD, HTN and +FH invoke the possibility of scleroderma. Rarely, a variant of this disease can present without skin manifestations (systemic sclerosis sine scleroderma). The transient nature of her joint symptomatology is c/w possible crystal disease. The bilateral hand distribution is typical, but progression to involve other joints such as the knee is not. Postviral arthralgias/myalgias is another consideration given the quick resolution of the process. Her myalgias may well represent underlying fibromyalgia. We recommend

  	If available, past ANA, RF, ESR

  	Please check ANA, RF, parvovirus IgM and IgG, uric acid level, U/A

  	Plain films of bilateral hands, R knee

Thank you for this interesting consult. We will follow with you.







_________________________________

Lauren Fontenot, M.D.

Pager 87566      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2134-12-14



 



Internal Medicine INTERN ADMISSION NOTE





Name: Vastie Uecker

MR #: 7045247

Date of admission: 12/13/34

Resident: William Uecker

Attending: Reynolds

 

ID/CC:  61 yo female w/ Hx of bronchiectasis presents with chronic productive cough.



HPI:  Pt is directly admitted to the Georgian Clinic with long standing pulmonary complaints with recent exacerbation of SOB, DOE, and cough productive of green sputum. She has had multiple episodes similar to this throughout her life with her first pneumonia apparently occurring when she was 3 years old. Her most recent episode peaked 3 weeks ago with a violent cough, sore throat, and ear pain. She was sputum culture positive for moraxella and started on a 19 day course of Ketek (Telithromycin) with some resolution of symptoms over the first 8 days. She reports worsening of symptoms over the last 4 days PTA to include increasing SOB, malaise, intermittent muscular back pain and worsening cough. She denies hemoptysis. She denies fever, nausea or vomiting. She does report 3 days of diarrhea which has subsided on the day of admission. She denies PND, or increased LE edema. She denies ill contacts or recent travel.



ROS:  Per HPI. 



PMH:   

Bronchiectasis: Recurrent PNA since 3yo, s/p RML lobectomy 2128

MAC: Treatment interrupted 2/2 liver failure 2128

Diverticulitis c/b perforation and sigmoid resection 2129

Raynaud's

Fibromyalgia: Dx 2122 when she p/w neck, shoulder, hip, chest wall, knee and jaw pain; followed by Dr. Christopher Sharp at DCHC

Migraine headaches

HTN

GERD

Hiatal and ventral hernias

S/p appy

Osteopenia



Home Meds:  

Medroxyprogesterone 5mg qd

Estradiol 2mg qd

Prilosec 20mg qd

Inderal 240mg qd

Nortriptyline 75mg qd

Colace 100 bid (held with recent diarrhea)

Albuterol Inhaler - usually requires BID

Nebulized Albuterol, occaisional use.

Vitamin C + E



All:

Percocet/Darvon/Codeine-GI upset

Sulfa-"kidney problem"

Flagyl-"throat closed"

Levaquin, azithromycin-rash

  	

SH:  	Retired firefighter, no ETOH, tobacco or drugs 



FH:	Mother w/systemic scleroderma (joint pain and swelling, skin changes, Raynaud's), CAD, DM died at 68 yo



Physical Exam:  

V:  T 98.6  HR 97  BP 187/97  RR 18  SaO2  99 RA

Gen:  Resting comfortably in bed, NAD

HEENT: PERRL, EOMI, sclera anicteric.    

Neck:  Supple, non-tender, no cervical LAD

Cor: RRR S1, S2 nl.  No m/r/g.  No S3, S4

Chest: predominantly clear, minor expiratory wheezes  

Abdomen: +BS surgical scars,  Soft, NT, ND.  No HSM, No CVA tenderness. 

Ext: No C/C/E, DP pulses present BL

Skin: No rashes.        

Neuro: non-focal



Labs and Studies: none available on admission



Previous Culture Data:

  Gram Stain - Final    Reported: 20-Nov-34 15:37

    Abundant POLYS, Rare SQUAMOUS EPITHELIAL CELLS, Abundant MIXED GRAM POSITIVE

    AND NEGATIVE ORGANISMS with GRAM NEGATIVE DIPLOCOCCI predominating



  Respiratory Culture - Final    Reported: 20-Nov-34 15:37

    Abundant MORAXELLA (BRANHAMELLA) CATARRHALIS

    NORMAL FLORA PRESENT



  Gram Stain - Final    Reported: 06-Nov-34 15:19

    Moderate POLYS, Rare SQUAMOUS EPITHELIAL CELLS, Moderate MIXED GRAM POSITIVE

    AND NEGATIVE ORGANISMS WITH NO SPECIFIC TYPE PREDOMINATING



  Respiratory Culture - Final    Reported: 06-Nov-34 15:19

    Abundant STAPHYLOCOCCUS AUREUS

      DISK METHOD

      Antibiotic                      Interpretation

      ----------------------------------------------

      Clindamycin                     Resistant     

      Erythromycin                    Resistant     

      Oxacillin(methicillin)          Susceptible   

      Penicillin G                    Resistant     

      Tetracycline                    Susceptible   

      Trimethoprim/Sulfamethoxazole   Susceptible   

      Vancomycin                      Susceptible   



    NORMAL FLORA PRESENT



A/P: 61 yr old female with likely bacterial respiratory infection in the setting of longstanding bronchiectasis. She has failed a recent course of Telithromycin in the setting of moraxella culture positive sputum. We will repeat sputum cultures and start vancomycin and ceftriaxone IV here. We will get Chest Films and supplement her home pulmonary regimen with Nebulized albuterol q 4 hrs.  I have encouraged frequent ambulation. She will continue to use her home flutter valve. Her husband provides Chest PT at home and we may order this if appropriate in house.



We will continue her home Inderal at 240 mg qd. This will be supplemented with an ACE I and hydralazine as necessary. The use of an ACE I will be discussed with her PCP as this may have been avoided second to chronic cough. She is not a candidate for Lasix or HCTZ due to her sulfa allergy. Her admission BP of 187/97 was in the setting of a delay in today's dose of inderal. She was asymptomatic with this high pressure. 



We will continue her hormone replacement, GERD prophylaxis with nexium and nightly nortryptiline.  She will be ambulatory and not require DVT prophylaxis. 





 

_______________________________________________________________________

Name: William Uecker                               

Pager #: 95321

PGY-1











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2136-03-30

SDU JAR Admission Note

Uecker, Vastie

MR# 3038560

Date of Admission: 3/30/36

Attending: Dr. Zehr

Admitting Resident: Patricia Nunn

Source of history:  records and pt



ID/CC:	62 yo F w/ hx of bronchiectasis s/p lobectomy, chronic MAC, HTN, fibromyalgia, and raynaud   s presented to OSH w/ chest pain, transferred to PCH w/NSTEMI and DVTs.



HPI: Pt at baseline occasionally gets SOB from her bronchiectasis if she has not had chest PT recently but otherwise is able to walk up multiple flights of stairs without SOB.  She has no known cardiac hx but does have HTN and + fam hx of early CAD.  Pt awoke this morning in her USOH but quickly had sudden onset of 10/10 sharp SSCP radiating to her right arm associated w/ right arm numbness.  Pain is slightly better w/ sitting up though pt denies pleuritic quality.  She then had a vasovagal attack, which she has had before in the setting of pain, and she started to feel lightheaded, nauseated, and diaphoretic.  She laid down on the floor and elevated her legs above her head which helped a little.  Her husband gave her Excedrin w/o improvement and called 911.  EMS gave her 3 puffs of NTG and 4 baby ASA w/o effect.  The ambulance brought her to the closest hospital, Colorow.  In the ED, she was found to be hypertensive w/ SBP 180s, for which she was started on TNG gtt.  She also underwent PE CT which per report was neg for PE but showed bilat DVTs, and she was started on heparin.  She was given fioricet, zofran, and fentanyl for her CP w/ relief.  She was then given a dose of IV lopressor and also had one episode of N/V.  Her labs were significant for + cardiac markers: 1st set w/ CK/MB/index 39/0.9/2.3, trop I 0.03, 2nd 443/57.3/12.9, trop 2.22, 3rd set 686/87.3/12.7, trop 4.18.  EKGs showed right-bundle morphology (though QRS not wide) w/ initial TWI V1-V3 which progressed to deepening TWI V1-V4 and some downsloping STD V3-V4.  Pt is currently chest pain free, no SOB, no palpitations.  She denies any preceding viral illness or any surprises or acute stressors in her life, though she has many chronic medical problems.



ROS:    as per HPI



PMH:

     1.  History of bronchiectasis s/p right middle lobectomy in 2128.

     2.  History of MAC with treatment interrupted by hepatitis in 2128.

     3.  Perforated diverticulitis with sigmoid resection in 2129.

     4.  Raynaud's.

     5.  Fibromyalgia.

     6.  Migraine.

     7.  Hypertension.

     8.  GERD.

     9.  Hiatal and ventral hernia.

     10.  Status post appendectomy.

11.	Osteopenia.

12.	Hx of serum sickness in the setting of Amox-clavulanate 11/33

13.	Mild pectus excavatum noted on CXR

14.	hx of Ophthalmic (V1) zoster in 10s

15.	hx of R OM c/b mild hearing loss (2130)

16.	newly-diagnosed DM



Medications:

  1. Albuterol Nebulizer  NEB 2.5 MG BID

  2. Ascorbic Acid (Vitamin C)  PO 500 MG BID

  3. Dicloxacillin  PO 250 MG QID

  4. Docusate Sodium (Colace )  PO 100 MG BID

  5. Butalbital+Apap+Caffeine (Fioricet)  PO 1 TAB Q4H prn headache

  6. Estradiol Tabs (Estradiol Patch )  PO 2 MG QD

  7. Medroxyprogesterone  PO 5 MG QD

  8. Multivitamins (Multivitamin)  PO 1 TAB QD

  9. Nortriptyline Hcl (Nortriptyline )  PO 75 MG QHS

 10. Omeprazole  PO 20 MG QD

 11. Propranolol Extended Release (Inderal La)  PO 240 mg QD



Allergies:  percocet/darvon/codeine    GI upset, sulfa        kidney problem, throat closed     flagyl       throat closed   



SH:  	 married, no children, lives w/ husband, retired firefighter

	Tob:		none

	EtOH:  		none

	Illicits: 	Negative



FH:	mother w/ multiple MIs (first age 40s), HTN, scleroderma, raynaud   s



Exam:  	VS:	T=99.4	HR= 77  BP 135/64    RR= 18	SaO2=  98%2L

general:  NAD, soft voice

HEENT: OP w/ MMM, NCAT

Skin:	No rashes

Neck:  	Supple, full ROM, 2+ carotids w/o bruits, JVP 7 cm

Chest: 	decreased BS, CTAB

CVS:  	RRR, nl S1 S2, no rub

Abd:  	nl BS, soft, non-tender, nondistended, no organomegaly, midline scar well-healed

Extr:  	2+ radial pulses, 2+ femoral pulses w/o bruits bilat, no LE edema, 2+ DPs bilaterally

Neuro: alert and oriented x3, grossly intact



DATA: pending

Chem:



Chemistry Comments               Fasting

Plasma Sodium                    130              L        (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 3.5                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  97               L        (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            22.4             L        (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Calcium                          8.7                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             9                         (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                0.8                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Plasma Glucose                   112              H        (70-110)       mg/dl

Triglycerides                    192              H        (40-150)       mg/dl

Cholesterol                      212                                      mg/dl

     DESIRABLE: <200

High Density Lipoprotein         44                        (35-100)       mg/dl

Low Density Lipoprotein          130                                      mg/dl

     DESIRABLE: <130

Cardiac Risk Ratio               4.8

     NORMAL RISK RATIO: 5.0 OR LESS

Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       80.4             H        (0.0-6.9)      ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index             9.8              H        (0.0-3.5)      %

Troponin-T                       1.26             H        (0.00-0.09)    ng/ml

Creatine Kinase                  818              H        (40-150)       U/L



Heme:



WBC                              14.2             H        (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              35.2             L        (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              12.5                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              3.94             L        (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              361              H        (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              89                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              31.8                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             35.7                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              13.6                      (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               14.7             H        (10.3-13.2)    sec

PT-INR                           1.3

APTT                             131.0            H        (22.1-34.0)    sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED

Diff Method                      Auto

Poly                             81               H        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           12               L        (22-44)        %

Monos                            6                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %

Absolute Neuts                   11.41            H        (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  1.76                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   0.88             H        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm

Absolute EOS                     0.08             L        (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.05                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm

Aniso                            None                      (None)

Hypo                             None                      (None)

Macrocytes                       None                      (None)

Microcytes                       None                      (None)



Micro:

pending



PE CT (reviewed w/ ED rads here): no PE to the level of subsegmental arteries, no dissection, no pericardial effusion or bowing of interventricular septum to suggest RV strain, lung parenchyma w/ scattered nodules, largest 6.5 mm, bilat fem veins w/ filling defects



EKG:  NSR 78 bpm, IVCD w/ right-bundle morphology unchanged w/ TWI V1-V2, flat Ts I, avL, 1 mm downsloping STD V3, < 1 mm horizontal STD V4



TTE: prelim read RV and LV function wnl, no segmental WMA



Impression:   62 yo F w/ hx of bronchiectasis s/p lobectomy, chronic MAC, HTN, fibromyalgia, and raynaud   s presented to OSH w/ chest pain, transferred to PCH w/ NSTEMI and DVTs, now chest pain free.  Possible etiologies for her chest pain w/ + cardiac markers include ACS, PE, myopericarditis, spasm, or apical ballooning syndrome.  Dissection less likely w/ equal pulses and not seen on PE CT.  Her EKG changes suggest an element of RV strain, though this is not borne out on TTE, and review of her OSH CT w/ radiology here did not reveal PEs (at least to the level of subsegmental arteries).  Her TTE did not show WMA, and her story could be c/w ACS or c/w myopericarditis or apical ballooning syndrome (esp w/ hx of fibromyalgia, raynaud   s, migraines, etc), though w/ + cardiac enzymes and dynamic EKG changes, need to have low threshold to cath if develops pain.



Plan: 



1.	ischemia

bblocker, ASA

check fasting lipids, start statin

cont heparin, restart TNG gtt if pain recurs

start IIbIIIa if persistent pain



2.	rhythm

NSR

On bblocker



3.	? DVT/PE

check LENIS

cont heparin



4.	leukocytosis

cx if spikes

f/u urine cx



5.	MAC

cont dicloxacillin



6.	DM

RISS

Diabetic diet



7.	FEN

Monitor hyponatremia (dates back at least as far as 10/35)



8.	prophy

heparin

nexium



FULL CODE (per my discussion w/ pt)



_________________________________

Patricia Nunn, MD

Pager #64177




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2137-02-27


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	PACIFIC COAST HOSPITAL
	


	Reason for visit:
    transfer from Colorow, chest pain in setting of known CAD


	Interval History:
   63-year-old woman with multiple medical problems, notably CAD, s/p RCA and LCx PCI in the context of NSTEMI in March, 2136, with return to PCH in July, 2136 with recurrent chest discomfort.  Cardiac catheterization during that visit revealed in-stent stenosis in LCx stent, successfully addressed with bare metal stent placement. Most recent nuc. stress 10/03/36 showed no definite ischemia, mild apical and mild inferolateral thinning not clearly outside normal per report.
She incidentally also was inpt. for small bowel obstruction surgery w/ ileostomy and subsequent takedown of ileostomy in January. has been doing well and only taking Fioricet for postop pain q 12 hrs (due to allergies to most other pain meds).
Now returned to Colorow ED due to recurrant SSCP c/w previously experienced CP - described as SS chest pressure rad. to right arm and back that started at 1:30 am rel. w/ 3 sl NTG, also had clammy skin and loose BMs after this , went back to sleep then CP recurred when up in am resolved with ASA in am, then recurred again in aft. so went to ED, states it was rel. after NTG again but has waxed and waned since going to ED at OSH - transferred to PCH per pt. request for further eval. and management. EKG there w/ no reported acute STAs at OSH. Biomarkers deferred to be drawn at PCH per pt. request.

On admit to Internal Medicine, pt. states has 3/10 SSCP, sbp 180/80. IV NTG started and enz, troponin to be drawn and cycled. EKG SR, LAD TWIs V1, V2 c/w previous comparison EKG. CP resolving after IV NTG started.


	Past medical history:
   1. CAD, s/p NSTEMI in March, 2136 with BM stent placement to LCx and RCA
Coronary angiogram in July, 2136:
- in-stent stenosis (diffuse, 80-90%) in the previously placed LCx stent.
- other stenoses included diagonal branch 60% stenosis, right PDA 70% 
- previously placed RCA stent contained 15% stenosis.  
- LCx in-stent stenosis presumed to be culprit lesion, and was re-opened successfully with 2.25 X 12mm MicroDriver stent.
2. Hyperlipidemia
3. Hypertension
4. MAC, previous treatment course terminated due to hepatitis in 2128
5. Bronchiectasis, s/p right middle lobectomy in 2128
6. Raynaud's Syndrome
7. Fibromyalgia
8. Migraine headaches
9. Hiatal and ventral hernias
10. Previous appendectomy
11. Osteopenia
12. Previous ophthalmic zoster infection
13. Mild hearing loss
14. Amoxicillin-clavulanate reaction in 2133
15. GERD
16. DM, on oral hypoglycemics as an outpatient
17. Prior GI bleed
18. 1/37 small bowel obstruction surgical repair and ileostomy and then takedown

Home medical regimen:
1. Aspirin 325mg daily
2. Plavix 75mg daily
3. Inderal LA 120mg bid
4. Tekturna 75mg daily
5. Lipitor 80mg daily
7. Hormone replacement therapy qd (estradiol 2mg, medroxyprogesterone 5mg)
 8. Amlodipine 10 mg po qd
9. Multivitamin qd
11. Metformin 1000mg bid
12. Albuterol neb 2.5mg bid
13. Colace 100mg bid
14. Fioricet PRN headache and q 12 hr prn postop pain (since allergic to usual pain meds)
15. Prilosec 20 mg po bid

Allergies:

Tylenol HAs
Azithromycin rash
darvocet GI upset
percocet GI upset
Darvon GI upste
codeine GI upset
sulfa angioedema
flagyl angioedema
levofloxacin rash
Hydrocodone GI upset
Onions/garlic GI upset
Peanuts HAs
 ACE I cough
ARB unknown

	


	Family history:
   Early-onset CAD in mother


	Social history:
   Married, lives w/ husband.
Retired firefighter
Tob: denies
EtOH: denies
Illicits: denies


	Review of systems:
    See interval history

Physical examination:
	
-temperature: afebrile   
-Pulse: 76    
-resp. rate: 16    
-General appearance:   No acute distress.
-Skin:   Warm, dry, no ecchymoses or lesions
-HEENT:   Unremarkable
-Neck:   Carotids 2+ without bruits. JVP no jugular venous distention
-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.
-Cardiac:   No lift or heave, non-displaced and discrete PMI, regular S1S2, no S3S4, no rubs or murmurs.
-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft, non-tender, abd. incision well healing, no erythema or drge., no masses or organomegaly
-Extremities:   No groin hematoma or bruits, femoral pulses +2 bilaterally, DP/PT pulses +2 bilaterally, no lower extremity edema
-BP: 148/76    
-Neuro:   A&amp;O x3, CN 2-12 grossly intact  

Selected recent labs:

	  pending
	


	Impression:
   63 y.o. female w/ knowd CAD as detailed above. With recurrant CP c/w previous  CP. Rel. w/ NTG. Biomarkers pending. EKG w/ no change from previous comparison EKG.
Dr. Aldrich covering for Dr. Zehr this eve notified of pts. admission.
Cycle biomarkers and EKGs tonoc.
On ASA, Plavix, statin, BB, IV NTG. Keep home med Inderal LA due to pts. many prev. problems w/ allergies as above. Allergic to ACE I  and ARB.
Tentatively plan cath on Saturday. Hold on Heparin gtt unless Sx recur. 
Monitor BS, prn sliding scale insulin. Hold Metformin precath.
Mucomyst precath ordered.
Check lipids, LFTs in am.
Diet consult ordered.
Consider stopping HRT. Pt. states she has discussed this w/ Dr. Zehr in the past and they have agreed for it ot continue.
NPo after MN Fri likely for cath Sat
Further recs. per Dr. Zehr.

	
Reema N. Imler pager #36201
	
Signed electronically by  Reema N. Imler
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>