<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2091-08-09



August 9, 2091





Billie Givens, M.D.

138 Cross Street

Juana Diaz, CT 89568 



Re:	Horn, Gregory

	BCC Unit #: 977-82-23



Dear Dr. Givens:



I had the pleasure of seeing your patient, Mr. Horn, in follow-up regarding possible interstitial lung disease. 



He has managed to lose 3 lbs. on his own personal diet plan, and feels his diabetes is coming under slightly better control.



His cough is virtually gone and now has only rare cough with a little bit of phlegm, grading it as 2 out of 10 vs. 8-9 out of 10, to which his wife agrees.  They both attribute it to the Prilosec.



He now sleeps well and does not use his wedge.  He has no snoring, daytime hypersomnolence, or morning headaches - no longer falls asleep at work.



Allergies and nasal congestion are not evident.



No lower extremity edema, swollen glands, or fevers.



Mildly less prominent exertional breathlessness - He now occasionally has to go up one flight of stairs without stopping.



On examination, he is well appearing.  Respiratory rate 22 and unlabored. Blood pressure 90/50 with a small cuff. Conjunctivae are clear.  Oropharynx is clear. Trachea is midline, no goiter or adenopathy. Back:  Normal configuration.  Chest:  Normal percussion note, good air movement bilaterally; fine expiratory crackles at the lateral bases.  Cardiac:  Faint left parasternal impulse, mildly prominent P2, normal S1, S2, without murmur, rub, or gallop.  JVP is 7 cm with borderline HJR.  Abdomen: Soft, nontender, no hepatosplenomegaly or mass. Extremities:  No cyanosis or edema, borderline clubbing.



Pulmonary function tests today show very stable values per spirometry, a slight down-   ..  in total lung capacity, but still approximately 70% predicted, and DLCO stable in the 60% predicted range.



My review of CT scan of the chest shows faint peripheral subpleural reticular pattern with cyst formation and no significant nodules.  



Impression:



1.	Interstitial lung disease - Mild objective impairment by functional status.  Pulmonary function tests - Overall, these were stable, and the CT scan is quite suggestive of pulmonary fibrosis.  However, as I reviewed with the patient and his wife, it is well established that 10% of the time, another disorder, such as occult hypersensitivity pneumonitis or nonspecific interstitial pneumonitis can be found on lung biopsy.  There is no evidence of a rheumatologic disorder nor any evidence of chronic aspiration, other than that associated with GE reflux, to explain his lung disease.  He would be a very reasonable candidate for gamma interferon, although this likely would necessitate low-dose steroids - the latter treatment would certainly have an impact on his diabetes.



2.	GE reflux - This is the main source of his cough and is well established to be associated with pulmonary fibrosis.  If he is able to lose weight and change his lifestyle, he can have very good control of this.



3.	Possible mild pulmonary hypertension related to the pulmonary fibrosis.



4.	Possible sleep disorder - Currently is entirely without symptoms, now that his reflux is well controlled.



5.	Chronic cough.



6.	Diabetes - Better controlled.



7.	Obesity - He continues to need aggressive weight loss program.  As I mentioned to him, he would not be a candidate for lung transplantation evaluation while he is at such as weight, but he is starting to make some progress.



Recommendations:



1.	Continue proton pump inhibitor at b.i.d. dosing, as well as lifestyle modifications, including marked decrease in caffeine intake.



2.	Referral to Dr. Harry Yerger for VATS lung biopsy.



3.	Cardiovascular evaluation by you, prior to his surgery, would be appreciated.



It has been a pleasure to participate in his care.  Please feel free to call with any questions or comments.



Sincerely, 





Paul N. Tam, M.D.



PNT/ivester/yanez

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-10-24



October 24, 2091





Billie Givens, M.D.

406 Cross Street

Juana Diaz, CT 89568 



Re:  	Horn, Gregory

      	BCC Unit #: 977-82-23



Dear Dr. Givens:



I had the pleasure of seeing your patient, Mr. Horn, today in follow-up.  



VATS biopsy on 9/27 showed usual interstitial pneumonitis with extensive smooth muscle metaplasia - a rather unusual reading.  



Since the biopsy, he has recovered well, but is mildly more short of breath than previous. For example, he notes that going up the four stairs to the house with bundles he is mildly short of breath and has to rest.



The cough is slightly increased to 3/10, but is markedly better than on presentation.



He has no leg edema, chest pain, skin rash, joint problems, or fevers.



He has managed to lose 6 lbs. by giving up sweets, and his sugars are slightly better.  



GE reflux is very well controlled.



Medications:  Prilosec 20 mg b.i.d., aspirin, Glyset, Actose, metformin, metoprolol, Lipitor, and Hyzaar.



On Examination:  He is well appearing. Blood pressure 110/60, respiratory rate 20 and unlabored.  Oropharynx is clear.  Conjunctivae are clear. Trachea is midline, no goiter.  Chest:  Normal percussion note, well-healed VATS scar; fine inspiratory crackles 1/3 of the way up bilaterally with coarser crackles over the axilla.  Cardiac:  Normal apex beat, normal P2, no murmur, JVP less than 8 cm with equivocal HJR.  Abdomen:  Obese, soft, nontender, no hepatosplenomegaly or mass.  Extremities:  No edema, borderline clubbing, no cyanosis. 



Exercise oximetry:  Saturation at rest 96% and after treadmill ergometry 94%.



Pulmonary function tests today by my review show an FEV1 and FVC that are decreased by approximately 10%, total lung capacity decreased by 1 liter, and DLCO down from 20 to 14.



Weight is 238 lbs. (BMI 38).



Impression:



1.	Biopsy-proven idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis - The biopsy reading is somewhat unusual, and I will review this at our Pulmonary group weekly meeting, particularly with an eye to agents that might possibly target to exclude muscle metaplasia.  I continue to think him a relatively high risk candidate for the low-benefit regiment of prednisone, with an immunosuppressant agent.  I think he may be a very good candidate for gamma-interferon, but unfortunately not every one benefits from this.  



I emphasized strongly to he and his wife that his disease may have progressed, or could be made worse by the recent chest surgery and worsened gastroesophageal reflux.  If the disease was, indeed, progressing, we would need to proceed with lung transplantation workup.  The most significant contraindication currently to transplantation is his substantial obesity.  I calculated with him that he needed to have his weight down to 190 lbs. to get to a BMI of 30, and that by the time of listing he needed to have a BMI of approximately 32.  Hence, he has his work cut out for him.



2.	Obesity - As above.



3.	Diabetes.



4.	Possible coronary artery disease - He apparently did fine on his preoperative cardiac workup.



5.	GE reflux - As mentioned.



6.	Cough - Mainly due to GE reflux, and less prominent contribution from the pulmonary fibrosis.



Recommendations:



1.	Add Reglan 10 mg b.i.d.



2.	Continue Prilosec 40 mg b.i.d. - as 20 mg b.i.d. did not give full control with the generic pills.



3.	We will review pathology.



4.	Follow-up visit with full pulmonary function tests in one month.



5.	I strongly urged him to continue a steady, but progressive weight loss program - I expect that his life will depend upon it.  



It has been a pleasure to participate in his care.  Please feel free to call with any comments or questions.  



Sincerely, 





Paul N. Tam, M.D. 



PNT/ivester/yanez

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-11-20

 
	977-82-23
	Horn, Gregory



November 20, 2093  Endocrine/Diabetes

Present Illness:  
Asked to see this 59 year old man with IPF, diagnosed in 2090, an admission to BCC last month with pneumonia, who presented with rapidly progressive respiratory distress last week and was admitted intubated to the MICU. He as treated with high dose Solumedrol and with antibiotics, and is improving nicely. He is extubated and has begun to eat. 

Diabetes was diagnosed 14 years ago. He was treated with pioglitazone 45 mg qd, metformin 2000 mg in divided doses and a sulfonylurea until February of this year, when the sulfonylurea was replaced with insulin. For convenience with his travel schedule, his insulin has been 70/30 administered by pen, with 30 U before breakfast and 40 U before  supper. He tests his BS before  breakfast and supper only and reports that, since he has been more careful with his diet recently, they have been in the low 100   s and mid 100   s, respectively. His hemoglobin A1c was 7.4 % a month ago.
Retinopathy:	He is due for his yearly appointment with his ophthalmologist. No retinopathy in the past.  
Nephropathy:	BUN/Cr 31/1.3 today. No microalbumin/creatinine ratio in CAS.
Neuropathy:	He has occasional paresthesias in his feet.
Cardiac:	He is s/p stent for coronary artery disease about 8-9 years ago.
Vascular:	No claudication.

His IPF is treated with Mucomyst and gamma interferon, which he administers to himself. 

Past Medical History:  
Surgery:	Coronary stent
	Lung biopsy at time of diagnosis of IPF 
Medical:	Hypertension	
	Hyperlipidemia
	GERD
Allergies:	No known drug allergies.
Smoking History:	No
Alcohol History:	No

Family History:  
There is a significant family history of diabetes, including his mother, maternal grandmother, one of his 5 siblings, and some paternal relatives as well.

Social History: 
Lives with his wife and their adopted son, who is a Recruitment Officer.
Computer and Network Technicians for General Dynamics, covering 8 states. His job entails travel.

Review of Systems: above
Ears: Mild hearing loss. 
Review of systems is otherwise negative.

Physical Exam:	
Very pleasant, ruddy complexioned man in no distress.
BP:   148/78		P:   76, regular	T: 98.0
Wt:   209 by history		Ht: 5    7.5    by history
HEENT:	Anicteric. Full EOM's. 
Fundi:	Not examined.
Carotids:	Normal pulses, without bruits
Thyroid:	Not palpable
Chest:	Few rales anteriorly, L>R.
Heart:	Normal S1; physiologic S2.  No gallops.  No murmurs
Abdomen:	No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness. No palpable AAA. 
Extremities:	No edema.  DP 2+ R, absent L. PT 2+,=.  Good foot care.
Neurological:	AJ 1+,=, with normal relaxation. 

Impressions and Plan:	
59 year old man with type 2 diabetes now on steroids for IPF flare, currently down to 125 mg q12h, given at noon and MN.
Having reviewed his recent data, would suggest that we change his current insulin to:
NPH 40 / Regular 10+ scale qAM before  breakfast
Regular 10+ scale qPM before  supper
NPH 30 at bedtime
QID Regular sliding scale
These initial doses will need to be adjusted based on experience and on any changes in the steroid doses.
I have no objection to resuming his pioglitazone, or substituting rosiglitazone while he is here, as long as you do not feel that volume overload is playing any role in his deterioration.
I would prefer not to resume the metformin while is at risk for acute respiratory deterioration with risk of acidosis.
Would change the steroid dosing to 8AM, 8 PM, hoping that we can also start to reduce the doses, PM first, if possible.
He appears to have an anemia that has at least a component of iron deficiency. If you agree, would start iron repletion. (Note that in addition to the iron studies, his MCV, though still normal, has come down over time.)

Thanks.


				Nicholas Q. Vasquez, M.D., Ph.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-04-07

 Surgery Admission Note


CC: Presents for lung transplant

HPI: Mr. Horn is a 59-year-old man with end-stage lung disease due to idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. He was admitted to the BCC from 1/8/94 to 3/15/94 with hypoxic respiratory failure requiring endotracheal intubation and admission to the medical ICU. During that admission he was listed for lung transplantation. He was discharged to a rehab facility and then to home two days ago. He returns now for single lung transplant from a deceased donor.

PMH:
Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis
Obstructive sleep apnea
CAD (last cardiac cath 1/15/94)
Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation
Diabetes
GERD
ESBL Klebsiella UTI
C. Difficile colitis
Bilateral pneumothoraces requiring chest tube
Right foot drop due to common peroneal nerve palsy

PSH: 
2091: Flexible Bronchoscopy, Mediastinoscopy, Right VATS with multiple right sided wedge biopsies (Dr. Yerger)
2/2093: Left chest tube
     
MEDICATIONS (Confirmed 4/7/94 on admission):
Reglan 10mg PO AC+HS
Lopressor 50mg PO TID
Prednisone 10mg PO QD
Potassium Chloride immed release 40meq PO QD
Digoxin 0.125mg PO QD
Omeprazole 40mg PO QD
Bactrim SS 1 tab PO QD
Sucralfate 1gram PO QHS
Mycophenolate Mofetil (Cellcept ) 750 MG PO BID
Clonazepam 1mg PO QHS PRN insomnia
Lipitor 20mg PO QD
Acetylcysteine 20%(200 Mg/ml)  PO 600 MG Q8H
Colace 100 TID
Senna PO 2 TAB BID PRN constipation
Fentanyl (Patch)  TRANSDERMAL 25 MCG/HR Q72H
Codeine 30mg PO 9am, 3pm, 9pm, 3am
Codeine 15mg PO 12am, 6pm, 6am, 12pm
Insulin NPH Human  SC 28 units before breakfast
Insulin regular SC 4 units before lunch
Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin )  PO 325 MG QD
Gamma interferon ?dose SC three times weekly
Multivitamin 1 tab PO QD

ALLERGIES: NKDA: No Known Drug Allergies

Exam:
VS: 97.3, 82 regular, 127/63, 20-24, 98% on 8LNC 
General: Pleasant man in NAD on nasal oxygen. Speaks a few words at a time. Here with his family.
Neck: Supple, no JVD
Lungs: Distant, clear, expansion symmetric.
Heart: RRR without appreciable MRG
Abd: Soft, nontender, nondistended
GU: Circumcised; hypospadias with very small urethral orifice
Sacrum: Area of redness over the sacrum with soft skin but no skin breakdown, drainage, or fluctuance
Extr: WWP, + trace digital clubbing.  Nail beds pink with brisk capillary refill.

Assessment: 59-year-old man with end-stage pulmonary fibrosis, admitted now for lung transplant

Plan:
-Pre-op labs and studies including crossmatch for 10 units each PRBC, FFP, platelets
-OR for lung transplant; surgical consent signed and on chart
-Antibiotics/inductions meds in OR per Dr. Patterson (ordered; availability confirmed)
-Urology re hypospadias
-SICU post-op


________________________ 
Nicholas Lange, MD
BCC Surgery PGY-1 14338




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-02-18


	PULMONARY
	

	BAUER CHIROPRACTIC CLINIC
	


	Interval History:
   Mr. Horn is a 60 y.o. male w/ h/o idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis s/p single right lung transplant in April 2094 whose post-op course has been complicated by CMV viremia, valcyte-induced myelosuppression and severe deconditioning.  Mr. Horn was most recently admitted from 12/11/94 through 12/30/94 for complaints of severe fatigue and dyspnea, although without symptoms of infection or acute graft rejection. His main complaint was generalized weakness and fatiguability even w/ very minimal activity.  Additionally, he reported a very poor appetite and continued weight loss. 

During that admission, he was transfused to a Hct&gt;30 and his PFTs ultimately returned back to baseline.  His weakness was felt to be primarily related to his malnutrition as he was documented as having an inadequate caloric intake. Nutrition was consulted, a PEG tube was placed and tube feeds were started to supplement his nutrition. He was discharged without incident on 12/30.

The patient continued w/ Nepro boluses and nocturnal TF at home and demonstrated an 8 lb weight gain in less than 2 months. He was improving until blood work revealed a positive CMV antigenemia (7 cells) on 1/29/95.  Transplant ID was consulted and the patient was restarted on Valcyte 450 QOD, and then later bumped up to QD dosing based on ID recommendations. He again experienced myelosuppression and was started on neupogen 300 mcg sc qd on 2/14/95 for a WBC of 0.6. At that time is HCT was 24.8 and PLTs 32K.  

A repeat CBC was obtained today and revealed worsening myelosuppression; Hct 21.6/Hgb 6.9, WBC 0.4 and PLTs 15K.   Case was discussed with Dr. Valerio and the patient was contacted and instructed to present to the BCC ER for further evaluation and treatment.  



	Past medical history:
   1. Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (pathology consistent with UIP), first
diagnosed in 2090.
2. Obstructive sleep apnea.
3. Coronary artery disease.
4. Type 2 diabetes.
5. GERD.
6. UTI (ESBL Klebsiella).
7. C. diff colitis.
8. Spontaneous pneumothoraces.
9. Right peroneal palsy and foot drop.
10. Valcyte-induced myelosuppression

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:
1. Right VATS and wedge biopsy 2091.
2. Left thoracostomy 2/2094.
3. PTCA, approximately 2085.

	

	Changes to Allergies
	
NKA: No Known Allergies - reaction: [reviewed]


	Medications (Confirmed):

	
children's aspirin  81 1 po daily
Citracal  2 tab po bid
dapsone  100mg po qday
diltiazem  30mg po bid
doxycycline  100mg po bid
erythromycin  250mg po daily
Flomax  0.4mg po daily
Flonase  50mcg/spray 1 nasal bid
insulin  2 units SC QAM
levothyroxine  50 mcg po daily
Marinol  5 mg po bid
multivitamins  1 tab po daily
NPH insulin  6 units sc daily
nystatin suspension  1 tsp BID
prednisone  5 mg po daily
Prilosec  40mg po daily
Prograf  0.5mgAM 1mgPM po bid
Valcyte  450 mg po every other day
Zofran  Take 1 tab q 6 hours prn nausea


	Social history:
   network technician, currently working from home. Lives with wife and son.
Quit smoking 20 yr ago.
Dog - cockapoo.

Selected recent labs:

	 2/05/95-Negative CMV Antigenemia Assay

	


	Assessment and plan:
   60 y.o. male s/p R lung transplant April 2094 for IPF with long, complicated hospital course, now presents with valcyte-induced myelosuppression. 

Patient instructed to present to ED at BCC.  Access nurse notified
Transfuse 2 units PRBC (CMV-reduced)
Transfuse 6-pack platelets
Continue neupogen 300 mg SC daily
Restart Aranesp 100 mcg SC weekly
Hold Valcyte
Please consult Infection disease



Problems:
	

Cytomegalovirus infection -  Please check a CMV antigenemia

	

Nausea -  Continue Zofran prn

	

Diabetes mellitus (adult onset) -  Continue w/ standing NPH and regular insulin 2 units QAM.
Continue to monitor FS in setting of chronic steroid therapy

	

Lung transplantation -  Continue prograf and check tacrolimus level in am. Adjust dose accordingly
Continue prednisone and doxycycline.
Continue ppx w/ dapsone and nystatin

	

Gastroesophageal reflux disease -  Continue prilosec, erythromycin, and anti-reflux measures.

	

Malnutrition -  Continue nocturnal TF (Nepro) at 60cc per hour
Continue marinol at 5mg per day with lunch and dinner
Please consult nutrition

	

Hypothyroidism -  Continue levoxyl

	

Seasonal rhinitis -  Continue flonase 1 spray bid

	

Coronary artery disease -  Continue diltiazem and ASA

	

Sleep apnea -  1.5LNC supplemental O2 at night.  
Repeat sleep study when he is stronger.


	

Changes to Medications this visit
	
Valcyte 450 mg  po every other day Start: 01/29/2095 End: 2/18/2095 DC reason: Intol - Inactivated

	
Ione Jean, NP

	
Transcribed by: Ione Jean

	
Signed electronically by  Ione Jean, NP
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>