<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2069-08-17





NAME:    Vines, Stephen

MRN:     1672569



Mr. Vines comes in today.  He has been feeling pretty well though he is

distressed at his 18-pound weight gain.  His sugars were in the 300s before starting

the insulin.  Since he started the insulin, his sugars have come down nicely.  His

fasting sugars have been in the 120s.  His afternoon sugars have been in the 70-90s. 

He had a few hypoglycemic episodes early on but has not had some in almost a

month.  Other than that, he really has no new complaints.  He is still not smoking. 

He is still on the patch.  His neuropathy has not gotten any worse and he thinks he

can stop the Neurontin now.  He has not had any shortness of breath, cough or

edema.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: As above.  No GI symptoms, no GU symptoms and no

new skin symptoms, no arthritic complaints. 



HABITS: Not smoking or drinking.  Not getting much exercise now.



PHYSICAL EXAM: His blood pressure is 140/80 on the left, 150/80 on the right. 

His pulse is 76 and regular.  Respirations are 16.  Lungs are clear. Heart: Regular

rate and rhythm, negative M/R/G.  No bruits heard.  Nasopharynx unremarkable. 

Abdomen is benign.  He has diminished pulses but good capillary refill in the feet. 

The cellulitis on the left ankle is completely resolved.  He has some neuropathy of

the feet with decreased sense to vibration in both feet, but his sensation to

monofilament is intact on both feet. 



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



(1)  Diabetes.  Will check his hemoglobin A1c today.  It may still be a little bit

     high as he has undergone a rather brisk change since starting his insulin.  I

     encouraged him to check his sugars a couple times a week, especially in the

     afternoon.  If he continues to get low sugars, will cut back on his morning

     insulin to 35 units.  He is going to bring in a form for custom shoes given his

     neuropathy and is followed closely by Podiatry.  He had an eye exam earlier

     this year with Dr. Yousif.



(2)  Hypertension.  Will increase his Mavik to 4 mg a day.



(3)  Hyperlipidemia.  Recheck lipids and SGOT today.



(4)  CAD prevention.  He can't take aspirin so we will start Plavix 75 mg a day.



(5)  Status-post splenectomy.  He needs a Pneumovax booster 0.5 cc was given in

     the left deltoid.





Scott Phipps, M.D.



SP/irons/quang







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-03-16




NAME:    Vines, Stephen
MRN:      1672569

Stephen comes in today.  He has been feeling pretty well.  Really has no new
complaints.  He still has 5 block claudication in his calves and he continues to smoke 
a half pack per day.  His neuropathy is stabilized and his sugars have been good for
the most part in the 140-150 range on insulin.  His weight has been stable.  He has
had no shortness of breath or chest pain and his review of systems is otherwise
negative.

HABITS: Smokes about a half pack per day.  Does not drink, not really getting much
exercise.  His legs hurt only when he walks over 5 blocks.  It doesn't hurt when he is
working in the McCormick Company.

PHYSICAL EXAM: He looks well.  His blood pressure is 142/80.  His pulse is 74
and regular.  Respirations are 16. Lungs are clear.  No worrisome skin lesions. No
bruits.  1+ carotids.  Abdomen is soft and nontender, no hepatosplenomegaly, no
pulsatile masses, no bruits. Decreased pulses in the feet and decreased capillary refill
and decreased sensation of vibration and fine touch.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  

(1)  Diabetes.  Will check his hemoglobin A1c to see where we stand.  Continue
     on his current regimen.  Encouraged him to increase his exercise and watch his
     diet.  He has an eye exam scheduled.  His feet look okay, though we will have
     to be careful given his neuropathy and peripheral vascular disease.

(2)  Claudication.  Once again, talked to Mr. Vines about the absolute
     importance of quitting smoking.  He is going to try using the Wellbutrin.  Gave
     him a prescription for #60.  He will take one a day for 3-4 days and then go
     up to 1 p.o. b.i.d.  He has no contraindications. I also encouraged him to use
     the patch.  Hopefully, we will be able to get him off the cigarettes.  I also
     encouraged him to walk until it hurts at least 3-4 x a day to try and train his
     legs.

(3)  Hypertension.  Our goal is to get his blood pressure down about 130.  Will
     increase the Mavik to twice a day.

(4)  Hyperlipidemia.  Well controlled on Lipitor.  Recheck his lipids.

(5)  Neuropathy.  Stable.  He doesn't feel the need for any medication for it.

(6)  HPDP.  Will check his guaiac cards.  He is not interested in a sigmoidoscopy. 
     He has had a Pneumovax.  Patient will follow up with me in 3 months. 

  

Scott Phipps, M.D.

SP/irons/quang




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-10-29

CCU JAR Admit Note

Name:  Stephen Vines

Unit#: 1672569

Admit Date: 10/29/72



CC: CP



HPI: Pt is a 69 y/o man w/ cardiac risk factors of DM, smoking, ? hyperlipidemia who had been feeling chest discomfort for 3 d PTA similar to his usual GERD and was relieved with mylanta. However today at work, 11AM he developed crushing substernal CP, and profuse sweating. No nausea or vomiting.  Coworkers were concerned so they brought him to the ED. On arrival in the ED, he was pain free.  EKG showed  ? old septal infart. He then developed CP again and repeat EKG showed 3 mm sTE II,II,vF,,V6. STD I,vL, V2. He received asa,heparin, tng.  At cath: L main ok,  LAD 50% at D2. Cx high grade stenosis. RCA 90% focal proximal stenosis and 50-60% proximal plaque. He was stented with 

3.0 diameter x 23 mm multilink BMS, received 300 mg plavix and started on integrilin.  Temp wire was placed. He arrived in the CCU comfortable and pain free. 



PMH:

DM - issulin dependant

s/p splenectomy for trauma

L leg superficial phlebitis



MEDS: insulin



All: PCN



Social: 100 pk yrs. Occ'l alcohol. Editor.



Family: no early CAD



PE: HR64 BP 145/61 MAP 92 100%2L T=98.0F

NAD, pleasant, AxO x3

No carotid bruits

JVP 7 cm

CTA anteriorly

Distant heart sounds but s1,s2 nl. no murmurs auscultated

NT, ND +BS

No peripheral edema. 2+dp pulses. R arterial catheter site: slight oozing of blood. nontender, no expansile mass.





LABS/STUDIES



WBC                              13.5             H        (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                              44.2                      (41.0-53.0)      %

PLT                              344                       (150-350)        th/cumm

Poly                             57                        (40-70)          %



Calcium                          9.4                       (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus                       2.5              L        (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Total Protein                    7.6                       (6.0-8.3)        g/dl

Albumin                          4.0                       (3.3-5.0)        g/dl

Globulin                         3.6                       (2.6-4.1)        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin                 0.0                       (0-0.4)          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin                  0.5                       (0.0-1.0)        mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase             77                        (45-115)         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT                14                        (10-55)          U/L

Amylase                          31                        (3-100)          units/L

Lipase                           3.7                       (1.3-6.0)        U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT                27                        (10-40)          U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       BORDERLINE                (NEG)

Troponin-I                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)



Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       6.4                       (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index             2.8                       (0.0-3.5)        %

Troponin-T                                                 (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

     <0.01Hemolyzed specimen; Troponin T result may be falsely low.

Creatine Kinase                  231                       (60-400)         U/L



FIO2/Flow                        4LNC                                       FIO2/L

Temp                             36.7                                       deg C

Unspecified pH                   7.37                      (7.32-7.45)

Unspecified PCO2                 40                        (35-50)          mm/Hg

Unspecified PO2                  128              H        (40-90)          mm/Hg

Potassium                        4.1                       (3.5-5.0)        mmol/L

Glucose                          270              H        (70-110)         mg/dL





 CXR: nl 





A/P 69 y/o man w/ DM, smoking, p/w cp found to have IMI.



Ischemia: IMI w/ RV infarction s/p BMS 

1.	asa, plavix, integrilin for 24 hrs, lipitor, ace if bp tolerates, BB if HR tolerates (currently HR 50's), sheath out per routine.

2.	RV infarct: avoid nitrates if CP recurs, fluid resuccitation if hypotension occurs. 



Rhythym: asymptomatic bradycardia. Temp wire in place. Monitor for heart block, etc.



Pump: Euvolemic. ECHO ordered. 

DM: RISS. Check A1C



GERD: start nexium 40 bid



FEN:  low fat, low cholesterol. Gentle IV hydration.



Prophylaxis: currently well anticoagulated. Nexium.









_____________

Orland Peralta, MD

22290

medicine      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-09-15

CARDIOLOGY

MAHASKA COUNTY HOSPITAL



Reason for visit:

   Angiography for claudication and chronic renal insufficiency



Interval History:

   Mr. Vines is a 70 year old male who has experienced claudication for approximately five to six years.  He describes his claudication as bilateral shin pain which radiates up to his knees.  His symptoms have worsened over the past two to three years and are now limiting his lifestyle.  He is able to walk approximately two to three city blocks when the pain starts and is relieved with rest.  He denies rest symptoms.  He was recently evaluated by Dr. Curtis Cochran for his claudication syjmptoms.  After an extensive conversation and a review of hsi options, Mr. Vines decided to pursue catheter based revascularization.



He underwent adominal aortography and iliofemoral angiography today which demonstrated:

-grossly patent celiac axis, SMA and IMA

-single renal arteries bilaterally with ostial/proximal 65-70% stenosis on the left; the right renal artery has proximal 30% stenosis

-diffuse atherosclerosis of the infrarenal abdominal aorta with 10-20% stenosis

-right common iliac artery diffuse 20-30% stenosis

-right internal iliac artery ostial 70% stenosis

-right external iliac artery patent

-right common femoral artery patent

-right profunda femoris patent

-right SFA with bulky, calcific eccentric 95% stenosis



-left internal iliac ostial 40% stenosis

-left external iliac aratery patent

-left common femoral artery calcific eccentric 70% stenosis

-left profunda femoris patent

-diffuse left SFA 60-70% stenosis in the mid vessel with supraimposed focal 80-90% stenosis

-total occlusion of the left popliteal artery with reconstitution at the TP trunk

-total occlusion of the left anterior tibial artery

-collaterals reconstitute the left peroneal and posterior tibial artery



Mr. Vines underwent dilation of the left femoral artery, dilation of the popliteal occlusion and overlapping Absolute stents to his left SFA.  He arrives to Internal Medicine mildly hypertensive with SBP 140-170s.



Past medical history:

   1.  CAD s/p MI 11/72

cath 11/72 with pRCA 90%-treated with stent, LAD 50%

2.  PVD

3.  Hyperlipidemia

4.  Hypertension

5.  Chronic Renal Insufficiency

6.  DM Type 2

7.  PUD/GIB

8.  Peripheral Neuropathy

9.  s/p splenectomy

10.  s/p appendectomy



Medications (home)

ECASA 325 mg po qd

Toprol XL 50mg po qd

Lisinopril 40mg po qd

Lipitor 40mg po qd

Nexium 20mg po qd

Ferrous Gluconate 325mg po bid

Imdur 30mg po qd

Humulin 10-20 units qam

Humulin 30-35 units qpm



Allergies:

Penicillin allergy   He has penicillin allergies which causes rash.



Family history:

   Mother died in her 50s of CAD, multiple siblings with CAD



Social history:

   He had a 100-pack-year smoking history and quit since his hospitalization.  He has not had any cigarettes since discharge from the hospitalization.  He drinks alcohol occasionally and currently is employed as an editor and works about 10 hours per week and during the day usually takes care of his grandchildren, and he currently lives in New Haven.



Review of systems:

   GEN:denies fever, chills, weight loss

RESP: denies shortness of breath, PND, orthopnea, cough

CV: denies chest pain, LE edema, +claudication as per HPI

GI: recent treatment for H.Pylori, denies nausea, vomiting, constipation, diarrhea, BRBPR

GU: denies hematuria, dysuria

NEURO: denies TIA, CVA



Physical examination:

-BP:   left arm 178/80, right arm 174/80

-Chest:   Lungs are clear to auscultation (anteriorly)

-Cardiac:   RRR S1 S2 early systolic ejection mumur, no rubs or gallops

-Abdomen:   Soft, nontender, +bowel sounds, unable to appreciate abdominal bruit

-Pulse: 62  

-General:   Pleasant male in NAD lying falt post procedure

-Neck:   Carotids 2+, normal upstrokes, + bilateral carotid bruits R > L, JVP 6cm

-Extremities:   Right femoral 1+, no bruit, no hematoma, PT 1+, DP 1+, Left femoral 1+, soft bruit, PT 1+, DP 1+, no ulcers

-resp. rate: 18  

-weight: 191  lbs.

-height: 71  in.

-BMI: 26.7  Overweight, moderate risk

-Neuro:   Alert and oriented X 3, grossly intact



Selected recent labs:

 09/10/73 - NA 142, K 4.5, CL 108, CO2 23.9, BUN 37, CRE 1.5, GLU 106, CA 9.7, HCT 37.2, RBC 4.09, WBC 9.4, PLT 309, ALYMP 4.00, %MONO 8, %EOS 3, %BASO 1, PT 12.4, PTT 26.1

07/24/73 - HGBA1C 8.10

07/22/73 - CHOL 148, TRIG 137, HDL 50, LDL 71

05/08/73 - PHOS 2.1, MG 1.4, PT-INR 1.1

05/06/73 - UA-GLUC NEGATIVE, UA-SPGR >1.030, UA-BLD NEGATIVE, UA-PH 5.0, UA-ALB , UA-NIT NEGATIVE

04/28/73 - TSH 0.62





Assessment and plan:

   Mr. Vines is a 70 year old male who presents today for angiograpy for lifestyle limiting claudication.  He underwent dilation of his left common femoral artery, dilation of his popliteal occlusion and placement of two overlapping Absolute stents to his left SFA.  There will be further discussion to undergo a staged intervention of his left reanl artery and right SFA calcific lesions as an outpatient.



1.  PVD-Plan to continue current medical regimen.  Plan for Plavix for one month.  Further discussions of his left renal artery and right SFA lesions to be discussed as an outpatient.  Patient would benefit from CNIS due t his bilateral carotid stenoses but may obtain as an outpatient.



2.  CARDIAC

ISCHEMIA-No symptoms.  Continue his current regimen.  His recent lipid panel is at target.  

PUMP-Euvolemic on exam.  Hypertensive on arrival to unit and received additional nitrates.  Will monitor response and consider added Norvasc.  

RATE/RHYTHM-Well controlled on Toprol.



3.  RENAL-Patient received sodium bicarbonate drip for renal protection.  Plan to add mucomyst.  Monitor renal function and urine output.  Continue lisinopril as he as been taking this as an outpatient and tolerating it.



4.  PUD-Continue PPI.



5.  DISPO-Anticipate discharge home in the am and follow-up with Dr. Cochran and his cardiologist Edward Benitez.





Further plans per Dr. Cochran.





Patricia N. Vallejo ACNP-BC



Signed electronically by   Patricia N Vallejo MS,RN,ACNP  on  Sep 15, 2073     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>