<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2075-01-31

PMH INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Westyn-Nuel, Kelli
                                              89897856
                                              1-31-75
                                              
                                              
 
HPI:  Patient is a 59-year old who has a history or active issues 
significant for hypertension first diagnosed on visit of 10-74.  She is 
currently maintained on furosemide 20 mg. PO q.d., nifedipine XL 90 mg. PO 
q.d., and potassium chloride 10 ml. equivalents PO q.d.  Patient comes in 
today for a routine follow up of her blood pressure, as well as routine 
baseline examinations.  On her last visit, her blood pressure was 160/90, 
and on check today it was 150/90.  We discussed the possibility that she 
continue her salt-restricted diet.  We also discussed that she continue 
her own exercise, both of which she does faithfully, and we also discussed 
the possibility of her trying to gradually lose weight.  She currently 
weighs 199 lbs. and stands approximately 4'9" tall.  
 
As far as long-term prognosis, my current plan is to evaluate her blood 
pressure on another subsequent visit in the next 6-8 weeks and at that 
time if it is elevated, we will consider either going up on her nifedipine 
XL dose or going up on her furosemide medicine, seeing if we can possibly 
gain some better control or possibly adding another agent.  However, at 
this point she seems to be doing much better with this new blood pressure 
and this is significant improvement maintenance from her previous blood 
pressure on her first admission, which was systolic blood pressures in the 
200s-190s.
 
 
Her family situation which was somewhat unstable at her first presentation 
now appears to be much more stable.  She is currently living with her 
mother and she says that she she is enjoying her new sense of feeling good 
about her self with regard to exercise and maintenance of her diet.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAM:  BP: 150/90   Lungs: clear bilaterally.  Heart: RRR, no 
murmurs.  Abdomen: distended, obese, no evidence of HSM or any focal 
tenderness.  She had good pulses distally with no evidence of trace 
swelling bilaterally at the ankles.   Breast exam: no evidence of masses 
or lumps.
 
She will follow up with me in 6-8 weeks, at which time she will have a 
mammogram performed as well as a Pap smear, cholesterol test, and stool 
guaiacs.  Advance directives were not discussed and it is not a pertinent 
issue at this point. 
 
 
_________________________
Quinton Lovett, M.D.
 
EF:AW:0810
DD:1-31-75
DT:2-01-75
DV:1-31-75
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-08-23

PMH INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          William-Nuel, Kelli
                                              89897856
                                              8-23-76
 
 
 
HPI: Mrs. William-Nuel is a 61-year old patient of mine who carries a 
diagnosis of essential hypertension and comes in today for a routine 
checkup. Patient appears to be doing fine. She has been compliant with her 
antihypertensive regimen, which consists of nifedipine and also 
hydrochlorothiazide. Since our last meeting, the patient has lost 
approximately 15 to 20 pounds. She has been exercising on a daily basis 
and eating very well, both of which have had very, very significant and 
beneficial results on her blood pressure and pressure today on examination 
was 120/80 in both arms. The patient was complaining of some ankle 
swelling, and in looking through her medicines I noted that she had been 
on furosemide, which was a holdover from the time of her most recent 
admission. I quickly switched to furosemide to hydrochlorothiazide, which 
I feel would give her much better diuretic response and relief of her 
symptoms over the next few days. 
 
The final issue with the patient today is low back pain, which she has had 
chronically for the last several years after suffering a fall in 2065. We 
have tried a whole host of conservative measures, which have included bed 
rest, nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory agents, and back exercises. The 
patient is referred now to the Paoli Memorial Hospital Spinal Clinic for 
services to obtain further help, and hopefully treatment, of her pain. 
Treatment recommendations from the Spinal Clinic will be forthcoming. 
Patient is scheduled to follow up with me again in two to three months.
 
ADDENDUM: The issue of her annual screening was addressed also and patient 
agreed to have her cholesterol checked today, but does not want to have 
either a mammogram or a Pap smear. She complains that she does not have 
faith in these procedures and that this is something that she is not used 
to and does not want to have done. I attempted to discuss the need and why 
it is necessary to undergo continued screening and will continue to do 
this with the patient in the future, but for now, the patient adamantly 
refuses either of the two examinations. 
 
 
 
_________________________
Quinton Lovett, M.D. 
 
pu:ZT:1220/0612
DD:8-23-76
DT:8-24-76
DV:8-23-76
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-02-13

                     PMH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
WESTYN-NUEL,KELLI   898-97-85-6            VISIT DATE: 02/13/79
This patient was seen with Dr. Quilla Uehara, an Emergency 
Medicine resident.  The PRESENTING COMPLAINT, HISTORY OF PRESENTING 
COMPLAINT, PAST MEDICAL HISTORY, MEDICATIONS, ALLERGIES, SOCIAL 
HISTORY, FAMILY HISTORY, and REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As noted on the 
record by Dr. Uehara, and as reviewed with the patient and with Dr. 
Uehara.  Briefly, the patient is a pleasant 64-year-old woman, who 
has had episodes of severe left-sided pressure-like chest pain off 
and on through the course of this week.  This has occurred with 
exertion and has always cleared with rest.  She is pain-free at 
present, but presents to the Emergency Department because she 
reported to her family that she had ceased taking her high blood 
pressure medications. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The physical examination is as noted by Dr. 
Uehara.  Basically, the examination is completely normal with the 
exception of the blood pressure, which ranges from 220 to 230 over 
100 to 110.  The patient's electrocardiogram does not show acute 
changes. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The cardiac troponin I is 0.53. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  I concur with Dr. Uehara that the 
patient has a strong history for unstable angina.  The patient will 
be admitted to the hospital for further evaluation.  She has 
remained pain-free while in the Emergency Department and has 
received nitroglycerin paste.  Her blood pressure will be treated 
with initiation of an ACE inhibitor. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Unstable angina. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 
admitted to the hospital in satisfactory condition. 
___________________________________                    IZ329/1982 
STEPHEN X. PIKE, M.D.  SP59                               D:02/13/79 
                                                       T:02/13/79 
Dictated by:  STEPHEN X. PIKE, M.D.  SP59 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-07-20

                           OFFICE NOTE
                                
 
Westyn-Nuel, Kelli
#898-97-85-6
July 20, 2079
 
Ms. Westyn-Nuel returns following myocardial infarction with
stenting procedure in February of this year. She continues to do
well and had an LDL of 90 in March. We will recheck it again today. 
She has no significant chest discomfort and is doing all of her
activities.  She has no syncope or paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.
She is tolerating her medications quite well and is happy with her
progress.  At home she takes her blood pressure and it's generally 
around 120/80.
 
Current medications are one aspirin per day as well as Isordil 20
mg. t.i.d., Labetalol 400 mg. t.i.d., Norvasc 7.5 mg. q.d., Lipitor
80 mg. q.d. and Glipizide.  She has not used sublingual
Nitroglycerin although she has this.  
 
Her blood pressure today is 128/80 and her heart rate is 50 and
regular.  Chest is clear. Cardiac exam reveals a II/VI left sternal
border systolic ejection murmur.  Abdomen is soft and nontender. 
Extremities are free of edema.
 
Ms. Kelli Westyn-Nuel is doing well. We will check her LDL
again today to make sure it did not rebound to a higher level
following her myocardial infarction.  We will also check her liver
function test because of her statin therapy.  We may in the future
need to adjust her nitrates to a more rational once per day
regimen, but her current situation is so stable that we will leave
her medications as is.
 
 
 
Spencer O. Wilhelm, M.D.
 
/keys
 
DD: 07/20/79
DT: 07/22/79
DV: 07/20/79
 
 
 
  
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>