<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2076-01-26



New Patient Visit







Chief Complaint of:  2nd opinion



History of Present Illness: 74 yo M who comes to the office in search of a second opinion about his care at the Boaz Nursing Home in Lynden. He has a hx of prostate CA diagnosed in 2059 at the BNH and had an RRP shortly thereafter at the BNH. Apparently his pathology showed extraprostatic extension and he received postop XRT. Apparently, he has remained disease free since this time until a PSA was checked this past October which was 3.53. He states that he had not had his PSA checked for a few years before this, admittedly perhaps because he had missed appointments. The Urologists at the BNH have since checked a bone scan and abdominal CT scan, all of which were negative. He has the reports here with him. The bone scan does show an abnormality at L5, but with data from plain films this appears to not be consistent with a met lesion. He also has had recurrent problems with bleeding from hemorrhagic radiation cystitis. This occurs once every few months or so and is not currently bothering him. He states that he is scheduled to have a cystoscopy at the BNH next week, however, is unsure if he has had a urine cytology done.





Impression: In reviewing the patient's limited records that he brings and his history, it appears that he has had the appropriate care at the BNH. I have reassured him of this, and have indicated that he should just make sure that a urine cytology is also checked and that a repeat PSA be performed in the near future. I also informed him that he will likely need anti-androgen therapy in the future for further treatment of his prostate CA. He may follow up with me if he has questions in the future.





Quinton H. Welch, MD

Urology - Laurens Memorial Hospital

Berkley Medical School

782-010-9623







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-03-08

INPATIENT CONSULTATION

PATIENT: Ulysses Quin
LMH NUMBER: 9523697
REFERRING PHYSICIAN: Dr. Ziemba 
DATE OF Consultation: 3/08/76

PATIENT ID: Mr. Quin is a 74 y/o gentleman with metastatic prostate cancer, new L4 met with pain who is seen for consideration of radiation therapy.
 
HPI:  
Mr. Quin's oncological history begain in 2061 when he was diagnosed with prostate cancer (unknown gleason, PSA).  He underwent radical prostatectomy in 2061 and salvage XRT in 2062.  His care was at BNH and we don't have his XRT records.  The patient recalls 37 treatments.   The patient was well until he had an elevated PSA of 3.52 in 10/75.  He underwent a bone scan in 11/75 showing worrisome uptake at L5. In 1/76 he had a PSA of 17.46.  He has also developed lower back pain requiring MS Contin for pain control.  His course was complicated by a possible bladder/urethral infection.  He is incontinent from his surgery.  In 2/76 he had a cystoscopy which revealed nodules in the bladder (TCC vs. prostatic scar/inflammation).  
The patient's LLP worsened.   He reports occasional severe shooting pain that lead to gait imbalance.  On the day of presentation, he experienced severe acute back pain while getting out of bed.  The pain was so intolerable that he asked his daughter to bring him to the emergency room. Just before arrival to the ED he developed stridor, in his words he was    sucking air in and out.     ENT was consulted in the ED and determined that he had a limited glottic gap, and that the acute stridor was most likely secondary to anxiety and increased air flow through a restricted glottic opening, recommending humidified air by shovel air mask, steroids, and outpatient followup.  MRI of the lumbar spine showed metastatic disease involving of the L4 vertebral body, extending into the pedicles, both L4-5 neural foramina, and the prevertebral soft tissues.  No compression of the thecal sac.

Mr. Quin reports improved pain since admission.  He still has some pain when moving from one position to anther.  he denies fecal incontinence, saddle anesthesia, LE weakness or paresthesia.  He would like to be cared at the LMH from now on.  The patient had an oncologist from BNH but does not remember his name.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  
Prostate Ca (history per HPI)
HTN
PVD
ED
Type 2 DM on oral agent
Vocal cord polyp excision in 2064
H/o COPD
 
MEDICATIONS:  
Bicalutamide 50 mg po qd
Glyburide 10 mg po qd
HCTZ 12.5 mg po qd
MS Contin 30 mg bid
Morphine 15 mg po q4h
Senna Colace and lactulose prn constipation
 
ALLERGIES: 
NKDA
 
SOCIAL HISTORY: Notary.  CPA and lives with wife in Tonganoxie.
Habits:  60 pack year smoking history
Past heavy alcohol consumption but none now
                                                                                                                                           PHYSICAL EXAM:  
General: Well-appearing, in no acute distress.  
HEENT: PERRL.  EOMI.  Oropharynx is clear.  
Neck: Supple 
Lymph nodes: No cervical, supraclavicular, axillary, or inguinal lymphadenopathy.  
Cardiac: S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  
Chest: Lungs clear to auscultation bilaterally.  
Abdomen: Soft, nontender, nondistended, with positive bowel sounds.  old midline surgical scars.
Extremities:  Well perfused with no edema. No bony pain to palpation.
Neurologic:  CN II-XII grossly intact with no focal neurologic deficits. 5/5 LE strength, movements limited by pain.  normal gait.  toes down bilaterally
GU: no penial or testicular abnormalities.  +pads

IMPRESSION and PLAN:   
74 y/o gentleman with metastatic prostate cancer, new L4 metastasis and pain.  The patient's LBP is likely due to his spine met.  Based on the MRI results, his symptoms and his exam we believe he is an appropriate candidate for palliative radiotherapy to his L-spine.  I discussed with Mr. Quin the likely cause of his pain.  We then discussed the treatment options.  Mr. Quin would like to undergo a course of palliative radiotherapy to relieve his pain.  We will simulate (plan) the patient's XRT tomorrow am, with a treatment to follow on the same day.  All of the patient's questions were answered to his satisfaction.  We would also recommend an GU oncology consultation regarding the patient's ADT and other possible systemic therapies.  The patient only had L-spine MRI, a bone scan may be of benefit to establish the extent of metastatic disease.

Quenton Zacharie Odell, MD
Quanita Ziemer, MD




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-05-04



Reason for Visit

patient is here to establish primary care

He has metastatic prostate cancer and has completed 12 cycles of radiation to the back with good effect. Last PSA was 1.7.  Is receiving Lupron every 3 months (after his 6 weeks pf Casodex).;





History of Present Illness

Mr. Quin presented in 2061 with a PSA of around 4 and a prostate cancer of unknown clinical grade. Radical retropubic prostatectomy was performed in the BNH system, and disease extended beyond the prostate to the margins of the resection and into the seminal vesicle. In early 2062 he received adjuvant radiation. His PSA remained undetectable throughout the 2060s, but was troubled by a great deal of radiation cystitis with hematuria, frequency, and dysuria. In addition, he was totally incontinent. In 2071 his PSA was undetectably low.   

Over the last 8 months, he has developed low back pain of progressively increasing severity. His PSA back in September 2075 was approximately 3 and when checked in November was 17. Early this year his pain was of great severity, and repeat CT scans and bone scans were performed. Destructive disease was seen in the body of L4 with foraminal encroachment. The thecal sac and the cauda quina were, however, intact. He was started in early February on bicalutamide and was scheduled to have a Zoladex injection, but his pain became more and more severe, and ultimately he was admitted to the LMH last week where I first met him. Since admission he was started on urgent radiotherapy and has completed 12 cycles of radation with a last PSA of 1.7.  He is due for Lupron injection on 6/13/76 at which time a PSA will be checked.

His oncologist Dr. Leblanc has helped him wean the MS Contin and tried to start adding low dose gabapentin as a narcotic sparing agent for presumed neuropathic pain.  He is not requiring his prn pain meds very often.

He has claudication.

He has symmetric leg edema worse right after lupron injection and improved with TEDS.  No chest symptoms.





Problems

      Prostate cancer

Plan as above

      Claudication    : has buttock pain when walking which resolves when stopping.  He has decreased pulses in his DPs bilaterally and has a h/o smoking and diabetes.

      Diabetes mellitus type 2

checks his sugars infrequently.  He is on glyburide 10 am 5 pm.  He had his eyes checked by an opthalmologist recently and no evidence of retinopathy was present. He has no early satiety, blurry vision, polyuria polydipsia, foot ulcers, chest pain, shorteness of breath, but does have some claudication.  He is not on an ACE- inhibitor, takes HCTZ for BP control and has had hematuria from aspirin.



Past Medical History

as above

see CAS note





Family History

see CAS



Social History

See cas



Habits

he has stopped smoking. good social support



Review of Systems

Positives noted in problem list.  Otherwise negative in detail.



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   150/93 

      PULSE   65 

      RESPIRATORY RATE   12 

      WEIGHT   202 lb



Physical Exam

General: Well appearing walking much better with his cane.



Skin: No rashes.



HEENT: NC/AT.  EOMs intact.  PERRL B.  VA OD [] OS [].  Hearing grossly intact.  TMs clear B.  OP clear without exudate.



Neck: Supple, FROM.  No thyromegaly or nodules.  2+ carotids B without bruits.  No LAD.



Chest: CTA B.  No wheeze, rales.



Cor: JVP 4 cm.  Nl S1, S2.  No S3, S4, murmurs.



Abdomen: +BS.  Soft, ND/NT.  No HSM.



Back: No spinous process tenderness or CVAT.





Ext: No cyanosis, clubbing but has mild bilateral ankle edema.

Decreased pulses in DP and PT but good capillary refill

No charcots joints or ulcers in his legs or feet

No cords or calf pain on palpation

 

Stocking glove sensory neuropathy to vibration temperature and proprioception

reflexes are normal





Medications

Glycuride 10am 5 pm

Hctz 12.5 mg po qd

Colace TID

MSCOntin 30 mg am 30 pm with Morphine 15 mg q4h for breakthough but not needing it.

Prilosec 40

Gabapentin Just restarted 100 mg po tid





Disposition and Plans

1. Pain- I think he has a component of neuropathic pain.  I think that we will start low dose neuronitni 100 tid for 7 days, he will email me about how his pain is and we will cut his pm MScontin in half if we can.  I do not want to have to use exteremely high doses of gabapentin to spare narcotics because he is not a drug seeker and I want him to be comfortable and he has no congnitive problems with safe adminstration or dosing.  His PSA is low and will continue to follow.  If his pain is at night which sometimes it is, he could have a component of restless legs from arterial insufficiency, will check PVRs anyway to rule that out

2. Cluadication- check PVRs, most likely has bilateral iliofemoral disease. He does not want to take aspirin given hiematuria in the past. I will broach this issue next time again

3. DM- will email me his sugars and will adjust oral agents as necessary,. He needs U/a for microalb, eas encourgagd to wear shoes in house, will check PVrs, will start low dose lisinopril for BP and prevention of diabetic nephropathy and heck creatinine and K one week after starting the medicaiton.  Will check lipids.  Will continue to monitor BP.  Will start aspirin when he is willing.

 

Plan to follow up with patient by email

will see in clinic RTC in 3 months

 

Eddie Zajac MD 94212

Seen w/ Dr. Alaniz who agrees with plan.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-09-08



			CARDIOLOGY

			

			LAURENS MEMORIAL HOSPITAL

			



			Reason for visit:

   Positive stress test.



			Interval History:

   The patient is a seventy-four year old man with multiple coronary risk factors.  As part of a work-up for his prostate cancer, stress test was performed on 6/30/76.  Myocardial scans showed old inferolateral MI with mild ischemia.  EF was 50%.  The patient denies any cardiac symptoms such as chest discomfort, SOB, palpitations, or dizziness.



			Past medical history:

   Prostate CA - RXT

DVT

Hypertension

PVD

DM x 2-3 yrs.

COPD

h/o vocal cord polyp resection - 2064



			Medications (Confirmed):

			

ASA 81 mg po qd

docusate sodium 100 mg po tid

free text medications

gabapentin 100mg po tid

glyburide 10mgqam, 5 mg. qpm po qd

HCTZ

Lipitor 20mg po qd

lisinopril 10 mg po qd

metformin hydrochloride 500 mg po bid

Prilosec 40mg po qd

Toprol XL



			Family history:

   Negative for CAD.



			Social history:

   The patient was a CPA and is now retired.  He lives with his wife.  



			Review of systems:

   Due to back pain, his physical activity is pretty much limited.  He quit smoking in 1/76.



Physical examination:

			

-BMI: 34.6  Obese, high risk

-Pulse: 72  

-height: 66  in.

-weight: 214  lbs.

-Neck:   JVP was not distended. Carotid upstroke was normal.  

-Chest:   Breath sounds were coarse. 

-Cardiac:   There was an S1 and S2.

-Abdomen:   Obese

-Extremities:   FA 2+/1+ with bilateral bruit. DP not palpable. Distal capillary filling - good.

-Neuro:   

-BP: 125/60  



			EKG:

   NSR @ 73 bpm. Mild non-specific STT wave changes.



Selected recent labs:

			 Liver and Pancreatic Enzymes

Date     ALT/SGPT AST/SGOT 

09/06/76 28       25       



Lipid/Thyroid

Date     LDL      

09/06/76 145      



Immunology

Date     HGBA1C   

09/06/76 6.80     





			



			Assessment and plan:

   It looks like Mr. Quin has had an MI sometime in the past. Myocardial scans showed only mild ischemia in the territory of the prior MI.  Since he is asymptomatic, I would continue medical therapy.  For some reason, he has not started Lipitor.  His LDL is markedly elevated.  My target LDL would be below 70.  For his myocardial protection, I have suggested that he increase the dose of Toprol from 25 mg. qd to 50 mg. qd.



Changes to Medications this visit

			

glyburide 10mgqam, 5 mg. qpm  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

metformin hydrochloride 500 mg  po bid Start: 09/08/2076

lisinopril 10 mg  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

Toprol XL 25 mg  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

Lipitor 20mg  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

Prilosec 40mg  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

docusate sodium 100 mg  po tid Start: 09/08/2076

HCTZ 12.5 mg  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

ASA 81 mg  po qd Start: 09/08/2076

free text medications     morphine Start: 09/08/2076

gabapentin 100mg  po tid Start: 09/08/2076



Disposition:

Follow-up in one year.



			CC:   Eddie Zajac, M.D.



			Signed electronically by   Freddie-Verne  Urie MD  on  Sep 13, 2076     

		



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-01-31



Chief Complaint

urosepsis



History of Present Illness

Mr. Quin is well known to me. He has a severely dysfunctional bladder and severe urethral stricture 2/2 radiation therapy for prostate CA. He has been dependent on a SP tube for bladder drainage, however, after the past 2 SP tube changes, he has developed urosepsis. He now presents again in urosepsis after his most recent SP tube change. He also complains of bilateral pelvic/hip pain which is limiting his ability to walk without a walker. This is a marked change over the past 3 months. 



Review of Systems

             No weight loss

             No difficulty with blurry vision or double vision, 

             No breathing problems, wheezing, or shortness of breath

             No blood clots or swollen glands





Past Medical History

Prostate cancer - s/p RRP and XRT

Claudication : has buttock pain when walking which resolves when stopping. He has decreased pulses in his DPs bilaterally and has a h/o smoking and diabetes.

Diabetes mellitus type 2 

Anemia 

Coronary artery disease 



Medications

Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)   81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      GLYBURIDE   5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO TID 

      LISINOPRIL   40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 30 days

      Neurontin (GABAPENTIN)   300 MG (300MG CAPSULE take 1) PO TID 

      Norvasc (AMLODIPINE)   10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      Percocet 10 Mg/325 Mg (OXYCODONE 10 Mg/acetaminophen 325 Mg)   -325MG TABLET take 1-2 PO Q6H PRN pain 

          Toprol Xl (METOPROLOL Succinate Extended Release)   50 MG (50MG TAB.SR 24H take 1) PO QD , please come to officein 1 months and have heart rate and blod perssure checked



Allergies

NKDA



Physical Exam

Vital Signs:

VSS

General appearance:  Well developed, well nourished

Respiratory:  Normal rate, breathing non-labored.  

Back/Flank:  No CVA tenderness or masses

Abdominal exam:  soft, NT, SPT in place

Obese, no organomegaly, no masses

Groin - no palpable fluid collections

Lymphatic exam:   No inguinal adenopathy

Neurologic:  Alert and oriented.  Conversant. Normal gait.

Psychiatric:  Affect appropriate, speech non-pressured.  Normal syntax.

Skin:  Normal turgor, no jaundice

Rectal Exam:  Normal tone, no masses

GU Complete

No scrotal lesions

Epididymis normal

Testes normally descended, no masses

Urethral meatus normal caliber, normal position

phallus without skin lesions

Prostate absent







Laboratory Data

Cr - 1.2

 

Microbiology Detail for QUIN, ULYSSES 

   LMH     URINE                     29-Jan-2078 04:19  Accession # 1263L4557

Detail:

  Specimen: 1263L4557        Collected 29-Jan-78 02:30                     

                             Received  29-Jan-78 04:19                     

  Ordering Provider: Unknown, Missing No Info

  Specimen Group:    URINE

  Specimen Type:     URINE

  Urine Culture - Final    Reported: 31-Jan-78 15:51

    Abundant (>=100,000 CFU/ml) ESCHERICHIA COLI

      RAPID METHOD

      Antibiotic                      Interpretation

      ----------------------------------------------

      Amikacin                        Susceptible   

      Amoxicillin/Clavulanate         Susceptible   

      Ampicillin                      Resistant     

      Aztreonam                       Susceptible   

      Cefazolin                       Susceptible   

      Cefepime                        Susceptible   

      Ceftriaxone                     Susceptible   

      Ciprofloxacin                   Susceptible   

      Gentamicin                      Resistant     

      Levofloxacin                    Susceptible   

      Nitrofurantoin                  Susceptible   

      Piperacillin                    Intermediate  

      Tetracycline                    Resistant     

      Trimethoprim/Sulfamethoxazole   Resistant     

    Confidential Material Please Handle Appropriately.

 





Assessment

1. Urosepsis - Treat as you are with Levofloxacin.

2. Bilateral hip pain - given subacute nature of this worsening problem, I would obtain a CT scan of the lower abdomen/pelvis to r/o any drainable fluid collections that we cannot appreciate on PE.

3. Long term plan - I have discussed with Mr. Quin that we are likely headed toward needing a surgical urinary diversion with an ileal conduit. He understands this and is still considering this. We will continue this discussion in outpatient follow up.

 

 



______________________________

Quinton H. Welch



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>