<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2086-08-13

Reason for Visit	

Annual physical exam.



Problems	  

breast carcinoma	      

S:  The pt. is five years S/P modified radical mastectomy, with 3 of 14 nodes involved, with a poorly differentiated intra-ductal carcinoma.  She's been on Tamoxifen 10 mg. b.i.d. since that time and is being followed by Dr. Quy Cherry.  For the past several years she has been on 20 mg. of Tamoxifen b.i.d.

O:  Well-healed L modified radical mastectomy.  No axillary notes noted.  R breast appears normal.  Pt. gets routine mammograms on the R breast.

A:  S/P left radical mastectomy for ca. of the breast, with no evidence of recurrence.

P:  No further therapy indicated.

Osteoarthritis	      

S:  Pt. takes Indocin intermittently for pain in her hips and hands.  She has a long history of osteoarthritis.

O:  Minimal degenerative joint disease, changes in hands and legs, with some distortion of the knees.

A:  Mild OA.

P:  Indocin was renewed.

Hypertensive heart disease	      

S:  Pt. has been treated for hypertension since 2064.  When she came to me in 2084 she'd been on Accupril 5 mg. a day, but her BP was 180/80.  Since that time, despite the administration of a variety of antihypertensives, her BP has rarely been normal and she insists that her BP is a function of having come to the doctor.

O:  BP 180/80.  Heart is NSR, without murmurs, gallops, clicks or ectopy.  EKG shows no LVH.  Fundi show some narrowing of the arterioles.

A:  White coat hypertension?

P:  Pt. told that we felt it was important to lower her BP.  She is on Accupril 20 mg. and Atican 32 mg. daily.  She finally accepted our medication to double her medication to Atican 64 and Accupril 40 mg. daily.  We will check her BP in three weeks.



Vital Signs	  

Pulse:	 96   

Weight:	 136   Pounds

Height:	 59   Inches

Blood Pressure:	 180/80   



Physical Exam	  

HEENT	

Bilateral arcus cornealis.  Pupils react = to light.  Fundi show mild narrowing of the arterioles.  Pharynx is clear.  Pt. has upper and lower dentures.  Ears negative.  

Neck	

No adenopathy or thyromegaly.  No bruits.

Breast	

R breast is free of nodules or nodes.  Axillae free of notes.  She has a L modified radical mastectomy with well-healed scar.  

Chest	

Chest is clear to P&A.



Cor/Cardiac	

Heart is NSR, without murmurs, gallops, clicks or ectopy, at 96 per minute.

Abdomen	

No liver, spleen or other organs or masses.  No tenderness or guarding.

Extremity	

Minimal DJD changes in her knees and hands.  Good peripheral pulses.  No cyanosis or clubbing.

Neurological	

Station and gait, cranial nerves and DTR's are all within normal limits.



Disposition and Plans	

Blood drawn for CBC, full profile and TSH.  Urinalysis shows a large amount of white cells; this was sent for culture.  EKG is WNL, at 100 per minute.  Pt. is to return in three weeks for a BP check.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-03-09

Reason for Visit	

Annual Physical Exam.



Problems	  

Hypertensive heart disease	      

S:  Pt. has been treated for hypertension since 2064.  When she came to me in 2084 she'd been on Accupril 5 mg. a day, but her BP was 180/80.  Since that time, despite the administration of a variety of antihypertensives, her BP has rarely been normal and she insists that her BP is a function of having come to the doctor. In Mar. 2087 she was hospitlaized with acute congestive heart failure and Lasix was added to her regimen that included at that time Norvasc, Atacand and Atenolol.  Despite some peripheral edema, she continues on this regimen and says that she feels well.  She recently celebrated her 81st Birthday surround by her seven children, and multiple grand- and great-grand children. O: BP 170/80; Heart-- NSR wiohtout murmurs or gallopr.  EKG shows no LVH or strain pattern.  A: Systolic Hypertension.  Patient is reluctant to increase or change her meds. P: Continue present meds and will try and increase her medications on her next visit, a month from now.

Osteoarthritis	      

S:  Pt. takes Indocin intermittently for pain in her hips, neck and hands.  She has a long history of osteoarthritis.

O:  Degenerative joint disease, with changes in hands and legs, and some distortion of the knees.  There is swelling of the joints of the hands, particularly both thumbs, but it does not interfere with her life.A: OA.  P:  Will make no changes at this time.

breast carcinoma	      

S:  The pt. is seven years S/P modified Left radical mastectomy, with 3 of 14 nodes involved, with a poorly differentiated intra-ductal carcinoma. She was T2 M1 N0.  She had been on Tamoxifen 10 mg. b.i.d. for 5 years, but this was d/c'd in March 2086 by Dr. Quy Cherry and she has had not sign of recurrence. She does, however, have a great deal of anxiety about the return of her malignancy and when her daughter found a "lump" in her back last week in the course of giving her a massage, she became convinced that her cancer had returned.O:  Well-healed L modified radical mastectomy.  No axillary notes noted.  R breast appears normal.  Pt. gets routine mammograms on the R breast. No lumps or masses were found in or on her back. Chest X-ray today shows no nodular densities.A:  S/P left radical mastectomy for ca. of the breast, with no evidence of recurrence. P:  No further therapy indicated, but Alk. Phos. drawn along with routine chemistries.





Review of Systems	

Patient says that she gets short of breath while climbing up stairs, and cannot walk more than a block or two without getting shortness of breath.  She always has edema in both legs, except when she arises in the a.m. at which time her legs are free of edema.  At the same time, she denies PND and says that she sleeps on only one pillow. She denies chest pain, says that she eats well and has regular BMs.  Her biggest complaint now is urinary pressure and urgency.  She had been using a Pessary for Uterine decensus, but it was removed by Gyn and she was prescribed local Estrogen cream, which has not yet helped.  She was advised to call Gyn for another visit, since she was scheduled about 6 weeks from now.





Medications	  

ATENOLOL	 25MG 2 Tablet(s) PO QAM

quinine	 260MG PO x1

LASIX (FUROSEMIDE)	 40MG 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

NORVASC (AMLODIPINE)	 5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

ATACAND (CANDESARTAN)	 32MG PO QD

K-DUR (KCL SLOW REL.)	 20MEQ 1 Tablet(s) PO QD



Vital Signs	  

Pulse:	 70   Regular

Height:	 57   Inches

Weight:	 140   Pounds

Blood Pressure:	 170/80   Left Arm



Physical Exam	  

 

HEENT	

Pupils react = to light. Conjunctivae and Sclerae - clear. Fundi-normal. She is s/p bilateral lens implants.Ears-clear. Pharynx-clear. Patient is completely edentulous with a well-fitting set of dentures.

Neck	

No adenopathy or thyromegaly. No Bruits.

Breast	

R breast is free of nodules or nodes.  Axillae free of nodes.  She has a L modified radical mastectomy with well-healed scar and no evidence of skin mets.  

Chest	

Clear to percussion and auscultation.

Cor	

Heart is NSR, without murmurs, gallops, clicks or ectopy, at 70 per minute.

Abdomen	

No liver, spleen or other organs or masses.  No tenderness or guarding.

Extremity	

Minimal DJD changes in her knees, but there are more marked DJD changes in her hands, particularly both thumbs with some early subluxation.  Good peripheral pulses.  No cyanosis or clubbing, but there is 1+ pitting edema of both ankles and the pre-tibial areas.

Neurological	

Station-Gait; Cranial nerves, DTR's, motor and sensory exams all WNL.



Disposition and Plans	

Blood drawn for CBC, profile, Lipids and TSH

Urine --N.A.

EKG--Junctional Rhythm without LVH or ectopy.



Patient sent for chest X-ray and to return in one month.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-05-19

CCU JAR Transfer Note

Pt: Tiffany Ulrich

MR#: 824-59-51

Date of Admission:  5/19/89

Cardiologist: Jewett



ID:   81 year old with cardiac risk factors of HTN, hyperlipidemia p/w IMI



HPI:   	 Ms Ulrich has the above risk factors which include HTN and hyperlipidemia and on the day of admission developed 6/10  left arm pain and lower gum pain associated with some nausea around 11: pm, she drove with her daughter to the GNC ED where EKG was positive for inferior STEMI and she was treated wit TNG, integrillin, lopressor and sent to cath.



In the cath lab she had a noted culprit PDA lesion and had a 2.25 mm by 18mm stent, the rest of her anatomy included 20% LM, 30% LAD, 30% LCX, 40% dominant RCA. She had an angioseal placed and was transferred to the CCU



CCU Course: Her stay in the CCU was uneventful, she had her integrillin continued for 12 hours and was started on ASA, Plavix, Lopressor and ACE 





PMH: 

HTN

Osetoarthritis 

Breast CA

Elevated Cholesterol

Recent admission for CHF

	 



Meds on admission:  	

Norvasc

Atenolol

Lasix 40

Atacand 32mg qd



Meds on Transfer:

ASA

Heparin SC

Nexium 40mg qd

Nitrofurantin

Pravachol 40mg qd

Plavix 75 mg qd

Atacand 16mg qd

Lopressor 37.5 mg tid

 	

All:  	Narcotics cause GI upset



SH:  	Non-smoker, rare ETOH

	

FH:  Father died of stroke in 80's, mother w/ CHF







Exam:  	



Please today's PN



Labs:  

	

Please see today's labs











CXR:	

There is increase in central lung markings. I cannot exclude

	developing pulmonary edema. The heart appears slightly larger in

	size but this may be due to lower lung volumes. The right

	diaphragm remains mildly elevated.







EKG:	NSR, w/ 1mm STE in III and AVF





____________________________________________

Impr:	:   81 year old with cardiac risk factors of HTN, hyperlipidemia p/w IMI



Plan: 	

	

CV:

Ischemia - s/p setnt to RCA, ASA, Plavix, Pravachol, Lopressor and ARB

                     Stress test  in 4-6 weeks



Pump - F/U ECHO in 3 days, prior h/o CHF



Rhythm --  Had some NSVT, increase B-Blocker, monitor lytes



	

FEN- Nexium, heparin SC	



UTI-  Marodantin for 3 days 	









_________________________________

Vernon Voorhees

95540









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-08-14

	CARDIOLOGY
	

	GRIFFIN NURSING CENTER
	


	Reason for visit:
   Asked by Medicine team to see this 88 yo woman who presents with UGIB 9 d after inferior STEMI/BMS PCI to PLV/RCA


	Interval History:
   Ms. Ulrich is a 88 yo w/ h/o CAD, DM2, and dyslipidemia, who was admitted 10 d ago with an inferior STEMI in the setting of nauseau and CP, who subsequently received BMS stents to the RPLV and mid RCA.  Plavix was reloaded for 1 week in this setting.  She was discharged to a rehab facility in pauls valley 8/10/96 for PT/OT.  At the rehab facility she developed hematemesis and was admitted to the medicine service last night for UGIB.  She denies CP/SOB/N at present.  She does not have memory of the hematemesis episodes overnight.  She required some reorientation to the situation leading to her readmission.


	Past medical history:
   1. CAD:
-s/p PCI of PDA 2089 for 99% lesion in setting of ACS, s/p PCI of 99% LAD lesion in 2090 also in setting of ACS, residual LV function normal w/o focal WMA in 2091.  Inferior STEMI 7/96 due to near occlusion of PLV resulting in BMS to PLV and mid RCA.
2. HTN/Hypertensive heart disease: rather difficult to control HTN, needing multiple agents to achieve near normal to high normal pressures.  Had a good bp response to thiazides but caused unacceptable degree of hyponatremia.  BP also related to the degree of chronic low back pain, and was substantially better for 6 months after localized treatment.  Hypertensive HD manifest primarily as peripheral edema, worsened by norvasc, improved on diuretic.
3. Dyslipidemia
4. DMII
5. Postherpetic neuralgia  
6. Depression  
7. Hemorrhoids  
8. Osteoarthritis  
9. h/o DVT /PE
10. Breast CA  96 T2N1MO ER/PR+ Her2 neg breast CA s/p L radical mastectomy, XRT, and tamoxifen x 10 years  
11. Recurrent UTI  
12. Urinary incontinence 
13. History of HIT AB Positive 2090


	Family history:
   There is a history of non-premature cardiovascular and cerebrovascular disease:  Her father died of a stroke in his 80s, her mother had congestive heart failure, and a brother had an MI.  Her other siblings have lived into their 80s.


	Social history:
   She has not smoked, and uses alcohol only rarely.  She lives at home with her youngest daughter, Vaccaro.  Another daughter, Tiffany, has been also very involved in her mother's care.


	Review of systems:
   As above, otherwise negative in detail. 

Physical examination:
	
-Pulse: 58  
-resp. rate:  16  
-Abdomen:   soft NT and ND, no hepatosplenomegaly, no pulsatile masses.
-Neuro:   a + oriented to self, needs orientation to location and context
-Extremities:   trace lower extremity edema, 1+ bilat PT pulses, 2+ radial pulses
-Chest:   cleart to auscultation anteriorly without crackles or wheezes
-Neck:   JVP not elevated, no HJR, no carotid bruits
-HEENT:   NC/AT, with mild ptosis of left eyelid from post herpetic changes
-General appearance:   A WD, WN elderly woman in no acute distress. Answering questions propriately, but requiring reorientation.
-BP: 155/60  


	EKG:
   NSR, CRO old IMI, NSSTTWAs, no significant change


	Impression:
   88 yo woman with extensive CAD history, HTN and DM2 recently started on oral agents, now presents with UGIB in setting of plavix extended reload of 150 QD x 1 week.

Agree with reducing plavix to 75 QD for now in combination with low dose ASA.  Despite low level cardiac marker elevation there is little suggest an intercurrent coronary syndrome currently complicating the UGIB.  Would try to continue antiplatelet therapy for a minimum of 30 days, and preferably for 90 days in the setting of recently placed bare metal stents, if tolerable from a hemodynamic and hemostatic perspective.  Agree with switching to short term beta blocker, and holding lasix for now given apparent volume depletion.  Continue high dose statin, ARB, and low dose CCB for BP control.

If UGIB continues to stabilize would prefer to maintain on H2 blocker rather than PPI to limit interference with antiplatelet therapy with plavix.  

Will follow with you.

	
Geary A. Camacho, MD
Document Status: Preliminary



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>