<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2080-05-17

                     WMH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
JOHNSON,PEPPER E.   537-18-74-8                   VISIT DATE: 05/17/80
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 50-year-old male that 
presents to Wausau Memorial Hospital Department of Emergency 
Medicine with complaints of noticing a small amount of blood on his 
underwear this a.m. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  He also noted a similar effect at 
1400 hours today while at work.  He denies any fevers, chills, he 
denies any burning or urgency on urination, he denies having a new 
sexual partner.  He denies of having a past medical history of this 
problem. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes since 2068. 
MEDICATIONS:  Insulin for diabetes. 
ALLERGIES:  None known. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils: 
Equal, round, reactive.  Fundi positive for AV nicking.  Neck was 
supple, no JVD.  Chest was clear to auscultation and percussion, no 
rales, wheeze, or rhonchi.  Heart:  Normal S1, S2, no S3, S4, no 
murmur.  Abdomen was soft, benign, nontender without masses, 
guarding, rebound, or organomegaly.  Extremities:  Grossly within 
normal limits.  The patient was noted to have negative flank pain. 
Examination of the penis noted a circumcised male, there were no 
abrasions, erosions, or penile discharge noted.  There was no 
tenderness noted.  There was no blood noted at the meatus. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The patient had a UA done in the ED.  The 
UA was noted to be negative.  However, it was positive for 2+ 
glucose but it was negative for blood.  The patient also had a set 
of electrolytes done to monitor kidney function and he was found to 
have a glucose of 176, BUN 11, creatinine of 0.9, sodium of 140, 
potassium 4.2, chloride 102, and a CO2 of 27. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Gross hematuria, resolved. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The plan is to 
discharge the patient home, to place him on Bactrim 1 tab p.o. 
b.i.d. and have him followed up by his PMD.  Condition on discharge 
is satisfactory. 
___________________________________                    MQ775/2509 
H. U. HEBERT, M.D.  UH02                            D:05/17/80 
                                                       T:05/19/80 
Dictated by:  H. U. HEBERT, M.D.  UH02 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-02-17

                     WMH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
JOHNSON,PEPPER E.   537-18-74-8                   VISIT DATE: 02/17/81
Patient seen and evaluated with Dr. Collins.  I agree with Dr. Collins's 
note. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 51 year old male 
with a history of a fever over the last two days.  He has had some 
URI symptoms and increasing glucose requiring increased insulin. 
Fever of 102 today.  He has had a cough productive of some 
yellowish sputum but no real shortness of breath, no dysuria, no 
urgency, no frequency, no diarrhea, no melena, no bright red blood 
per rectum, no nausea or vomiting. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes. 
MEDICATIONS:  Per the resident's note. 
ALLERGIES:  Per the resident's note. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Per the resident's note. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Well nourished, well developed male, 
slightly tachycardic initially, in no acute distress.  Skin:  Warm 
and dry without rash.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic, 
oropharynx clear.  Neck:  Supple, full range of motion.  Lungs: 
Clear.  Heart:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Abdomen:  Soft. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Chest x-ray clear. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Bronchitis, viral syndrome. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Plan is 
Albuterol and Erythromycin, followup with PMD.  Condition on 
discharge is stable. 
___________________________________                    TP009/2221 
OWEN URE, M.D.  OU98                       D:02/17/81 
                                                       T:02/18/81 
Dictated by:  OWEN URE, M.D.  OU98 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-12-23

                     WMH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
JOHNSON,PEPPER E.   537-18-74-8                   VISIT DATE: 12/23/81
The patient was seen by me and examined.  Briefly, the history is 
as follows. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 52 year-old 
black male with multiple cardiac risk factors including insulin 
dependent diabetes, hypertension, and hypercholesterolemia, who now 
presents for evaluation of chest pain.  The patient states he 
developed substernal chest pressure this a.m. at approximately 9 
o'clock, associated with nausea, shortness of breath, diaphoresis, 
and generalized weakness.  He states the discomfort was a 
substernal tightness without radiation.  At the present time he 
states the pain is approximately 4/10 in intensity.  Of note, the 
patient had a stress test done on December 6, 2081, standard Bruce, 
for which he exercised 7 minutes, 30 seconds and stopped secondary 
to fatigue.  He went 74 percent of predicted and developed no 
symptoms.  The test revealed no evidence of ischemia. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As noted above. 
MEDICATIONS:  Lopressor, amoxicillin, aspirin, insulin, 
nitroglycerin p.r.n., Claritin, lisinopril, and Zocor. 
ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  The patient denies smoking. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Well-developed, well-nourished, 
pleasant male in no acute distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 97, 
blood pressure 108/62, pulse 80, respiratory rate 18, O2 saturation 
97 percent on room air.  HEENT:  Mucous membranes were moist 
without lesions.  NECK:  Supple without jugular venous distension. 
LUNGS:  Clear to auscultation.  HEART:  Regular rate and rhythm 
without murmurs, rubs or gallops.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, non-tender and 
non-distended.  EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  No 
calf tenderness.  Negative Homan's sign.  NEUROLOGIC:  Awake, alert 
and oriented times three, non-focal. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  CBC:  White count 8.9, hematocrit 40.8, 
platelets 323,000.  CPK was 1213, MB 10.5.  SMA-7 was within normal 
limits.  Cardiac troponin was 0.04.  EKG showed normal sinus rhythm 
with nonspecific T-wave changes.  There was a flipped T-wave in 
leads 1 and aVL, which is unchanged compared with prior tracing 
dated December 6, 2081. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was treated in the 
emergency department with O2, two liters via nasal cannula, 
nitroglycerin 1/150 sublingual times three, Lopressor 25 mg p.o., 
and aspirin 325 mg p.o.  The patient became pain-free and remained 
hemodynamically stable. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain, rule out myocardial infarction. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 
be admitted to the medical service for further evaluation and 
management, including usual rule out myocardial infarction 
protocol.  He was admitted in stable condition. 
___________________________________                    BW018/5369 
URIEL ERVIN, M.D.       UE24                        D:12/23/81 
                                                       T:12/24/81 
Dictated by:  URIEL ERVIN, M.D.       UE24 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-06-13

EDVISIT^53718748^Johnson, Pepper^06/13/85^UMANA, BRUCE

The patient was seen by me along with Dr. Abbott on 06/13/2085. 

The history is documented by Dr. Abbott, was reviewed by me with

the patient, found to be accurate and complete.  The physical

exam was confirmed by my examination.  Evaluation and management

was also concurred with.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  In brief, this is a 56-year-old male

who enters with a history of after sitting playing a piano,

developed shortness of breath, had decreased ability to breathe. 

Says he had some diaphoresis this morning, dyspnea on exertion

which he has noted that he has been having repeated exertional

dyspnea over the past several days, worsening today when he had

diaphoresis accompanying with no chest pain but felt confused and

did not know where he is supposed to be going in the building until

he was overhead paged to report to specific room, when he looked

up 25 minutes had gone by and he was unaware of what had happened

during that time.  He has had some mild upper respiratory tract

infection about a week ago.  No nausea, no vomiting, no

dizziness, no abdominal pain, and the patient states that he is

feeling much better while he was being given some oxygen but just

feels like he has no energy.  The patient had a cardiac

catheterization in December of 2081 and had a luminal

irregularities and 30% stenosis and echocardiogram revealed 55%

ejection fraction.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  The patient has history of coronary

disease, MI, and hypercholesterolemia.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Smoked in the past for 30 years.  He is a

Senior Manager of Broadcasting by occupation.  Lives with his family.

Review of systems, allergies, and medications are as documented

in the chart.  Please see Dr. Abbott' notes for details.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Awake, alert, well-developed,

well-nourished male in mild distress.  Temperature 96.6, pulse

100, respirations 20, blood pressure 164/86.  Lungs clear. 

Cardiovascular:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Abdomen is flat,

nondistended, bowel sounds normoactive, nontender, no pedal

edema.

LABORATORY DATA:  White count 7.9, electrolytes are normal,

hematocrit 36.  CK was elevated at 657, troponin was negative. 

The patient's D-dimer was 211 and an EKG showed T-wave inversions

in aVL, V5 and V6 which ________ from previous chest x-ray was

negative.

DIAGNOSIS:  Acute coronary syndrome, rule out myocardial

infarction.

As such was admitted to Medicine on 06/13/2085.

______________________________

UMANA, BRUCE M.D.

D: 06/13/85

T: 06/13/85

Dictated By: UMANA, BRUCE

eScription document:9-2130535 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>