<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2086-10-19

                                              10-19-86
 
 
 
This patient was seen with Dr. Nabor Jacoby.
 
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 29 year old woman with diabetes and 
obesity.  Her problems are as follows:
 
1.   Diabetes.  She was sent to me from OB/GYN because of her high glucose 
     and she was put on insulin by me.  Xitlali Xia followed her in 
     order to get her on a good dose but then she was lost to follow up as 
     she did not come to her appointments and did not return phone calls.  
     She finally comes back and I am relieved, but she has not brought any 
     list of her blood sugars.  She says she does take them about twice a 
     day and she did write them down but her daughter ripped them up and 
     threw them away.  She says that they never go higher than 200; that 
     they usually are about 110.  It was 101 this morning before 
     breakfast, she says.  She says it does get as low as 19 and five or 
     six times it has been below 50.  She does say she eats three regular 
     meals but then later in the morning when I asked her if she had eaten 
     breakfast she said no.  She is seeing a nutritionist this morning.
 
     I will check a hemoglobin A1C today.  I expressed to her again how 
     important it is that she eat three regular meals, but not sweets.  
     She had been eating a lot of chocolate.  She says she has gotten off 
     of a lot of this although she does have cravings for it and eats it 
     then.  She is going to a nutritionist today and I hope that she will 
     help her with her diet.  If her diet does get better, maybe we can 
     wean her off the insulin and try Micronase.  I explained to her, too, 
     that if she both had a good diet and lost some weight that we might 
     be able to get her off the insulin.  This seemed to be something that 
     she would like to do.  Hopefully the nutritionist can help.  I also 
     told her that in order to find out what was going on that I need her 
     to take her blood sugar before breakfast, lunch, dinner and sleep, 
     and then come back in a week and a half so that we can see what was 
     really going on and whether they are getting too low.  She denies any 
     kind of symptoms with even as low a blood sugar as 19.  I am 
     wondering if she is remembering all these blood sugars correctly.  
     She had no shakiness, no loss of consciousness, no dizziness, no 
     nothing.  She felt totally normal.  So hopefully she will really 
     record these and we will get a better idea.  She said this always 
     happens in the morning.  She kept contradicting herself and had no 
     documentation.  I went over with her the symptoms of hypoglycemia.  
     Once she had a low blood sugar by fingerstick.  She does drink juice, 
     but I went over the symptoms again with her.  She will call me if she 
     does have any.
                                              10-19-86
 
 
 
2.   Left ankle pain.  I sent her to the orthopedist as she requested.  
     She said that she may do some surgery on her.
 
3.   Dysuria.  She says this is totally resolved after giving her the 
     Bactrim.
 
4.   Yeast infection.  She said this has also resolved.
 
5.   She complains of headache.  She says these have been going on for two 
     or three months; that light and noise bother her when she has some.  
     She has had nausea and vomited once.  This happened pretty much every 
     day and it can be at any time of the day.  Tylenol and Advil did not 
     help.  She knows she is going to have a headache because it starts in 
     the back of her left ear very faintly and then it spreads from there.  
     But she has no further prodrome.  She says it is a banging kind of 
     pain that is rhythmic.  She also says she does see stars in front of 
     her eyes when it happens.  I asked her if she had any hearing loss, 
     and she said that she hears voices but people are not there 
     sometimes.  It has been happening for a couple of weeks.  I discussed 
     this with Dr. Jacoby and we both agreed that these do sound like 
     migraines.  I will not image her head now as there is no evidence 
     that this would be something to do with brain tumor.  Her neuro exam 
     was totally normal.  Cranial nerves II-XII were checked and intact.  
     Her gait was normal.  Light touch was touched.  Her toes were 
     downgoing.  Her reflexes were symmetric bilaterally.  Her disks were 
     sharp.  EOMI, PERRL.  I gave her a prescription for Motrin, 600 mg PO 
     t.i.d. and told her to take one the minute she got the pain behind 
     her left ear.  I will see her in a week and a half to reassess this.
 
6.   Health maintenance.  I thought that since she is diabetic and obese 
     that she might benefit from a flu shot.  She has no interest in this 
     at all.  Her blood pressure was 110/70 in the left arm with a thigh 
     cuff.  Her pulse was 96.  Her blood sugar was 151 and her weight was 
     285.
 
 
 
 
_________________________
Xitlali Crane, M.D.
 
CCL:FG:1879
DD:10-19-86
DT:10-21-86
DV:10-19-86
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-10-19

LOVELAND INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Youngman, Cody
                                              06386371
                                              10-19-87
 
 
 
HPI:  Ms. Youngman is a 30-year-old woman with diabetes who comes in for a 
regular follow-up.
 
Assessment and Plan:
1.   Diabetes.  She said she has been doing well, sticking to her diet, 
     has had no hypoglycemic episodes, and that her fingersticks have been 
     ranging between 120 and 160, never above and never below.  This is 
     borne out by her last hemoglobin A1C on 6-04-87 which was 4.9.  She 
     definitely does have good control, and she is working hard as her weight 
     is down to 236 lb from 238.75 on 6-29-87.  She had a recent hemoglobin A1C 
     and urine dip.  She, however, is due for an eye exam as she has no had one 
     for over a year and is willing to go, so I referred her.  She also needs 
     to see a Podiatrist as she has not seen one; she will go.
 
2.   Health maintenance.  Patient does not want a flu shot.  Otherwise, 
     she is up to date except for a Pap smear, but she had her daughter 
     with her so asked if she could have her Pap smear on her next visit.  
     We will do so.
 
3.   Migraine headaches.  She said she has had one every day recently.  
     This is worse than her usual.  The Motrin was not helping.  I 
     therefore prescribed Midrin and explained to her expressly how to 
     use.  Should this not help, she will page me as she knows how to do.  
     I will see her back soon to make sure this is getting better.
 
4.   Ankle pain.  Patient has chronic ankle pain.  She went to an 
     Orthopedist who told her a while back to lose weight and see if it 
     got better.  She has been slowly losing weight with no improvement 
     and would like to go back to the Orthopedist.  I therefore referred 
     her at her request.
 
 
 
_________________________
Xitlali Crane, M.D. 
 
FS:XI:4842
DD:10-19-87
DT:10-20-87
DV:10-19-87
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-09-14

LOVELAND INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Youngman, Cody
                                              06386371
                                              9-14-88
 
 
 
HPI:  Ms. Youngman is a 31 year old woman with a history of morbid obesity, 
complicated by diabetes, who was a former patient of Dr. Xitlali Crane.  
She comes in today for routine follow-up.  Patient's diabetes was 
initially diagnosed during gestation with her daughter.  Patient was 
formerly controlled by insulin but has lost 61 pounds over the last 16 
months and is now off all medications and states her finger sticks have 
been excellent with a peak of about 150, with most well below that.  
Patient also has a history of        in situ which was treated with laser 
treatment to the cervix.  She is a hemophiliac carrier.  Has a history of 
migraines and currently is being treated by Dr. Jacoby for depression.  
Since her last visit with Dr. Crane, patient apparently attempted suicide 
in July.  It is unclear how serious the attempt was although she did cut 
her left upper extremity.  Since then she states that she has been feeling 
a lot better and feels that she has really made progress with Dr. Jacoby.  
Her mood seems fine today in clinic.  Patient denies any medical symptoms 
at this time.
 
Patient's cardiac risk factors include smoking 5-6 cigarettes a day.  A 
positive family history of coronary artery disease including a mother who 
just died of a heart attack in May at age 53 and had had a previous MI at 
age 40 and a CABG at age 43.  Patient does not have hypercholesterolemia 
or hypertension but does have the diabetes history as noted above.
 
SOCIAL HISTORY:  Notable for tobacco use as noted above and she drinks 
about one beer per day when she is distraught that she continues to do.  
She says that she should not be drinking with her medications.
 
PHYSICAL EXAM:  Moderately obese Hispanic woman in no acute distress.  
Blood pressure: 120/70.  HEENT: unremarkable.  Neck: no JVD, carotids were 
2+ bilaterally without bruits.  Chest: clear.  Cardiac: within normal 
limits.  Abdomen: benign.  Extremities: without edema.
 
ASSESSMENT/PLAN:
1.   Weight control:  Patient has had excellent weight loss over the last 
     16 months.  I told her how impressed I was with this.  She, in fact, 
     does not require any oral hypoglycemics for good sugar control at 
     this time.  I will let her continue this dietary control for the next 
     six months and check her hemoglobin A1C at that time to assess her 
     control.  However, in the past, she has been very straight forward 
     with Dr. Crane according to her notes.
2.   Depression:  Patient continues to be actively depressed.  Is 
     currently on trazodone, Klonopin, Paxil and Motrin.  She will 
     continue to follow-up with Dr. Jacoby with whom she seems to be very 
     happy.
LOVELAND INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Youngman, Cody
Page 2                                        06386371
                                              9-14-88
 
 
 
3.   General health care:  Patient will need a pelvic exam in six months 
     time.  Patient currently has an intrauterine device which was placed 
     in June.  She does not take oral contraceptives because of her 
     history of diabetes and history of heart disease.  She was instructed 
     that she should go to Gynecological Clinic if any symptoms related to 
     the IUD occur.
4.   Diabetes:  Patient's blood sugars have had peaks of about 150 as 
     mentioned above.  I will check her hemoglobin A1C in six months time.  
     Patient feels good with no polydipsia, no urinary frequency and no 
     headache.  I elected, therefore, not to treat it at this time.  
     Patient was given prescriptions for fingersticks and lancets.
 
 
 
_________________________
Raymond Castaneda, M.D.
 
NW:ZR:8898
DD:9-14-88
DT:9-15-88
DV:9-14-88
 Attending Physician: YOCOM,GARY ZACHARY,M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-11-30



LOVELAND MEMEORIAL HOSPITAL
LOVELAND Internal Medicine Associates
23  Colgate Road                             Youngman, Cody
Cincinnati, WA  33699                             06386371
                                              11-30-93 



IDENTIFICATION:  Ms. Youngman is a 36 year old woman with the following 
medical problems: 

1.   Type II diabetes mellitus.
2.   CAD.
3.   History of CIN2 status post laser treatment to the cervix.
4.   Depression.
5.   History of substance abuse.
6.   GERD.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Enteric-coated aspirin 325mg PO q.d., atenolol 
25mg PO q.d., glyburide 5mg PO q.d., Lipitor 10mg PO q.h.s., Celexa 20mg 
PO q.d., Zantac 150mg PO q.h.s., Prevacid 30mg PO q.d., trazodone 150mg 
PO q.h.s.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Youngman returns to clinic today to 
follow up regarding her diabetes, coronary artery disease, and 
depression.  Since I last saw her, she presented to Urgent Care 
complaining of some epigastric discomfort and was referred to 
Gastroenterology where apparently she was started on Prevacid at 30mg a 
day in addition to maintenance with q.h.s. Zantac and scheduled for a 
upper GI series with a small bowel follow-through with a plan to add a 
pro-motility agent if there was no structural abnormalities on her GI 
study.  She is scheduled later this month.  She has no new complaints, 
although she recently stopped taking her glyburide and has not refilled 
it over the past two days.  She denies any increasing polyuria, 
polydipsia, polyphagia.  Says until yesterday, she had been taking all 
of her medications regularly, although mostly at night rather than in 
the morning.  I pressed her about this because she has a history of 
being noncompliant with her medicines in the past, but she does maintain 
that she has been taking them.  It is not entirely clear to me whether 
this is true or not.  

Regarding her depression, she denies any suicidal ideation.  She says 
she is feeling a little bit better.  She was recently started on 
risperidone in addition to her Celexa, apparently by a psychiatrist at 
the Connerstone Regional Hospital by the name of Dr. Lehman whom she sees once 
a month.  She is also seeing a counselor there weekly.  She says overall 
she is doing a little bit better, although still intermittently binge 
drinking and occasionally smoking marijuana.  We again discussed the 
importance of AA; she says she is not interested in that.  

Regarding her coronary disease, she continues to have exertional angina 
after approximately 14 steps which has not increased in intensity or 
frequency.  She denies any PND or orthopnea, denies any chest pain at 
rest.  


LOVELAND MEMEORIAL HOSPITAL
LOVELAND Internal Medicine Associates
57  Colgate Road                             Youngman, Cody
Cincinnati, WA  33699                             06386371
                                              11-30-93 
Page 2


PHYSICAL EXAM:  She is a morbidly obese woman in no acute distress.  Her 
pulse is 80 and regular, blood pressure 134/74.  Her weight today is 
249lb.  Her sclera are nonicteric.  Her JVP is not visible at 90 
degrees.  There are no carotid bruits.  Her lungs are clear to 
auscultation bilaterally, and her cardiac exam reveals a regular rhythm, 
positive S1, S2.  No murmurs, rubs, or gallops appreciated.  Her 
extremities are warm and without significant edema.  Her finger stick 
blood sugar in the office today was 331.

ASSESSMENT/PLAN:  Thirty six year old woman with multiple medical 
problems, including a history of noncompliance and substance abuse.

1.   Diabetes.  Her last hemoglobin A1C was approximately 9.3, 
     essentially unchanged from six months prior.  Finger stick in the 
     office is 331 today, confirming her recent noncompliance and would 
     now describe that she has not been taking her medicine regularly 
     over the past couple of months.  In any event, she most likely need 
     a higher dose of sulphonurea.  We will check a hemoglobin A1C 
     today, and if it remains in the 9 range or higher, will increase 
     her glyburide to 10mg daily, and I talked to her about the plan.  
     Her last urine microalbumin was negative.

2.   Hypercholesterolemia.  When she returns to clinic in three months, 
     we will recheck a lipid profile by which time she will have been on 
     Lipitor for approximately six months.

3.   Coronary disease.  She is still having exertional chest pain.  
     Increased her atenolol to 50mg PO q.d. as she did have room to go 
     with her pulse and blood pressure.

4.   Depression.  I again encouraged her to continue following up with 
     her psychiatrist and her counselor.  Again, reinforced the 
     importance of trying to remain substance free and recommended AA 
     again as I have in the past.

5.   GERD.  She will follow up with Gastroenterology and continue on her 
     PPI and H2 blocker for now.  I told her she should take the 
     Prevacid in the morning and the Zantac at night only.

6.   Health maintenance.  She received a flu shot and she will return to 
     clinic in three months to follow up on her diabetes, 
     hypercholesterolemia, and coronary disease.  Additionally, I 
     referred her to Nutrition for further counseling regarding weight 
     loss and a heart-healthy diabetic diet.  I also stressed the 
     
LOVELAND MEMEORIAL HOSPITAL
LOVELAND Internal Medicine Associates
06  Colgate Road                             Youngman, Cody
Cincinnati, WA  33699                             06386371
                                              11-30-93 
Page 3


     importance of her seeing the eye doctor.  She says she is scheduled 
     to see the eye doctor this month given that she is at risk for 
     diabetic retinopathy.



_________________________
Jeffrey Koehler, M.D.

LX:ZK:3809; DD:11-30-93; DT:12-3-93; DV:11-30-93 


========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================

Case discussed with Dr Koehler.  DM: glucose in the 300s.  Ran out of meds.  Compliance a problem.  We are restarting glyburide today.  MIBI was positive, but we are trying medical management.  Increasing atenolol to 50mg.  Cont. Lipitor for lipids.  close f/u planned.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-11-24







LOVELAND MEMEORIAL HOSPITAL

LOVELAND Internal Medicine Associates

83  Colgate Road

Cincinnati, WA  33699



Youngman, Codi 

06386371

11/24/94





PROBLEMS:  Ms. Youngman is a 37-year-old woman with the following 

medical problems:

1.	Diabetes.

2.	History of polysubstance abuse.

3.	Recent bilateral pyelonephritis.

4.	History of CIN 2 and laser to cervix.

5.	Depression.

6.	CAD with ischemia on MIBI in October 2093.

7.	Gallstones.

8.	Status post appendectomy in July 2093.

9.	GERD.



CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Include glyburide 15 mg p.o. q.d., Prevacid 

30 mg p.o. q.d., atenolol 50 mg p.o. q.d., Lipitor 10 mg p.o. 

q.d., enteric coated aspirin 325 mg p.o. q.d., Celexa 20 mg p.o. 

q.d., and trazodone 150 mg p.o. q.h.s.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Youngman returns to clinic today 

for follow up regarding her diabetes.  Since I last saw her, she 

has been hospitalized with bilateral pyelonephritis in mid 

October.  Since discharge, she has been feeling well, and a 

repeat urinalysis and urine culture on October 27, 2094, were 

essentially within normal limits.  She denies any recurrent flank 

pain, fevers, chills, or dysuria.  Says overall she is feeling 

relatively well.  She is taking all of her medications as 

prescribed.  She denies any polyuria, polydipsia, polyphagia, 

fatigue, or blurry vision.  She continues to smoke.  She has not 

been exercising.  She also continues to have intermittent chest 

pain of unclear etiology.  Several days ago, she had an episode 

that lasted a minute or two at rest.  She described it as a 

tightness, and it was not associated with shortness of breath, 

nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis, or neck or arm symptoms.  She has 

no recurrent symptoms since then, and has had no exertional 

symptoms in the past few days.  She has not been taking her blood 

sugars at home as her machine is broken.  Also, she self-

discontinued her lisinopril.  She thought it gave her a headache.







Youngman, Codi 

06386371

11/24/94

Page 2





PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is an obese young woman in no 

distress.  Pulse 68 and regular.  Blood pressure 134/84 and 

weight 226.  Fingerstick today 198.  Neck veins are non-elevated.  

No carotid bruits.  Oropharynx is clear.  Lungs are clear to 

auscultation bilaterally.  Cardiac exam is regular rhythm.  

Normal S1 and S2.  No murmurs.  Extremities are warm and without 

edema.  Feet are without ulcerations and sensation is intact to 

vibration and light touch.



LABORATORY DATA:  Her EKG today reveals a normal sinus rhythm, 

normal axis, normal intervals, normal ST segments, and normal T-

waves.  Hematocrit and troponin are pending.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN: A 37-year-old woman with multiple medical 

problems as follows:

1.	Type 2 diabetes.  Her hemoglobin A1c has continued to run in 

the 9.0.  She is poorly controlled and remains unwilling to 

try Glucophage again due to the diarrhea.  At this point, it 

is prudent to consider switching her over to an insulin 

regimen starting with b.i.d. NPH, and we will refer her to the 

diabetic teaching nurse, and see her back in about a month 

with a plan to transition her at that time.  Her urine 

microalbumin was negative a few months ago.  We will recheck 

her hemoglobin A1c today.  She has been to the ophthalmologist 

recently, and does not need to see the podiatrist as of yet.

2.	Regarding her chest pain, her persistent intermittent chest 

pain is somewhat concerning.  She does have coronary disease 

as per her MIBI just over a year ago.  She is taking an 

aspirin and a beta-blocker.  Her EKG today is normal, and she 

has been symptom free for at least the past 2-3 days even with 

exertion.  Given this, I advised her should she have recurrent 

pain at rest or with minimal exertion to call me and come to 

the emergency room, otherwise, to continue taking her aspirin 

and beta-blocker.  I will repeat her stress test to see if her 

ischemic burden has increased in which case we will consider 

referring her to Cardiology.





	

	Youngman, Codi 

	06386371

	11/24/94

	Page 3

	

	

3.	Regarding her hypertension, given her diabetes, we would 

prefer better blood pressure control.  She agreed to try the 

lisinopril again at a small dose, and will let me know if she 

thinks it disagrees with her.  I told her I felt the headache 

was probably unrelated to the lisinopril.

4.	Regarding health maintenance, when I see her back in a month, 

I will do a Pap smear and give her a flu shot, as she left 

today without receiving one.  

5.	I will see her back in clinic in one month.







_______________________________

Jeffrey Koehler, M.D.



JK/JW4

502491.do

c

DD:  

11/24/2094

DT:  

11/25/2094

DV:  

11/24/2094







========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



===========================Preceptor Notes====================================





Dr. Koehler and I jointly interviewed and examined this  37  year old patient who presents for f/u of diabetes, depression, pyelonephritis. See resident's note for details. PMH/FH/SH significant for GERD , substance abuse. ROS remarkable for headache. 



On exam, we found pulse 68, neck  veins flat, chest clear. See Resident's note for further detail. Of note is .

normal podiatry exam.

Impression and Plan reviewed and I agree with the resident's assessment of  mult med problems and diagnosis of diabetes,depression  . We agree on the plan to  switch to bid NPH, restart lisinopril, f/u appt with diabetic teaching nurse. 











______________________________                              



Rahasia Pauline Vuong, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>