<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2063-12-31

UHER,OLGA
258-16-49-2
12/31/63
 
                     CARDIOLOGY OFFICE NOTE
 
NOTE
     Ms. Uher returns after a 4  year hiatus.  She is now 52 and
has long-standing insulin dependant diabetes with a h/o retinopathy
OS, possible peripheral neuropathy but not known nephropathy.  She
had a maximal negative exercise test in 2059 and has felt generally
well since that time.  Over the past year she has not been as
careful as previously with her diet and has not been checking her
sugars regularly.  A random cholesterol w/i the past year was over
300.
     She has intermittently had sharp, brief discomforts of the
anterior chest lasting only seconds and not accompanied by dyspnea,
diaphoresis or light-headedness.  There has not been any reduction
in her physical capacity, in fact, she feels stronger than a year
ago and is working full-time.  There has been no orthopnea, PND or
peripheral edema.  She is interested in increasing her physical
activity program.
     Cardiac risk factors include remote smoking, stopped by age
20, hypercholesterolemia and family history in that her father
developed coronary disease possibly in his 50's.  She is
perimenopausal and has discussed later estrogen usage with her
gynecologist Dr. Bradley Brandt.
     Her only medication is lente insulin taken twice per day.
 
EXAM
     She is comfortable at rest.  BP 110/76, HR 80 and reg.  No
JVD.  Carotids full w/o bruits.  Chest clr.  Cardiac exam shows
normal heart sounds w/o gallop or murmur.  Abd. soft w/o
organomegaly.  No peripheral edema.
     Resting EKG shows sinus rhythm with normal intervals and axis
and is a normal tracing.
     For further evaluation of her chest discomforts and to help
gauge her exercise program an exercise treadmill test was performed
using the standard bruce protocol.  She exercised for 9 minutes, 8
seconds and stopped because of knee discomfort but not because of
chest pain or inordinate dyspnea.  Peak heart rate was 143 (85%
maximal predicted) with an appropriate rise in systolic pressure. 
There were no diagnostic changes of ischemia at this good work
load.  Compared to the test of 9/15/59 she exercised 1 minute, 4
seconds longer.
 
IMPRESSION
     1.  No evidence of clinical coronary disease at this time. 
She has major risk factors of insulin dependant diabetes,
hypercholesterolemia, family h/o coronary disease and a
perimenopausal state.  She will be seeing Dr. David Yun as
her primary care provider, and would urge that a fasting lipid
profile be obtained and that dietary/pharmacologic therapy be 
PAGE 2
UHER,OLGA
12/31/63
 
 
instituted to achieve an LDL cholesterol <130.  From a cardiac
standpoint, post-menopausal estrogen therapy would be desired.  Low
dose aspirin therapy could also be considered.
     I would be happy to see Ms. Uher for additional cardiac
evaluation as needed in the future.
 
REFERRING MD
cc:  David Yun, M.D.
 
 
 
Ivan M. Ing, M.D.
 
DD: 12/31/63
DT: 01/01/64
DV: 12/31/63
 
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-04-20

                             OFFICE NOTE
 
Uher, Olga
258-16-49-2
04/20/64
 
She returns to clinic for follow up. Unfortunately she missed her
entire appointment and did not bring her blood glucose log with
her. She reports that at 4 a.m. last Thursday she woke up and felt
disoriented with sweats. She checked her blood glucose, it was 50,
and she treated herself by eating. This led to resolution of her
symptoms, although she said that she overshoots. She has developed
a foot infection, has been seen by a podiatrist and started on
antibiotics. She has also been taking a thyroid hormone but she
still feels that it is making her tired. She just in general has
not been feeling as well as she had been previously.
 
Past Medical History:
 
1.   IDDM.
 
Medications: See previous notes.
 
Allergies:  Same.
 
Physical Examination:  Not performed. The patient had a  special
orthopedic shoe on, her foot was wrapped.
 
Impression:  Patient with IDDM with usual blood glucoses in the
200's and an elevated A1C. Discussed the need for consistent meals
and exercise and need for more control. Will increase day time
insulin to 17 units of Lente and evening will stay at 10. She will
follow up in one month. Will check a TSH today.
 
 
 
Phyllis Jacobson, M.D.
 
/lott
 
DD: 04/20/64
DT: 04/22/64
DV: 04/20/64
 
 
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-11-04

Neurology EW Resident Consult



ID/CC: 59 RHF decreasing visual acuity





HPI: Ms Uher was doing well until 8/70 when she she was noted to have several "staring spells." At the same time she had increased gait instability leading to admission to SLMC. A head MRI was reportedly normal. She improved and was discharged without treatment or diagnosis. At that time she also noticed subtle decline in visual acuity and eye exam confirmed this. She was told that this was caused by her diabetes. Her vision continued to worsen and she was treated with laser OS. Over the past month her balance has worsened nad her vision has continued to deteriorate. She reports severe HA in 8/70 but none recently. She was seen by ophtalmology at SGAH and noted to have optic disc swelling, cotton wool spots and hemorrhages. She was sent to CCH EW for evaluation.





ROS:She c/o painful dysesthesia and weakness BLE (lonstanding). She denies HA, tinnitus, vertigo, numbness, fever, chills, cough, nausea, vomiting, chest pain, palpitations, shortness of breath, heartburn, constipation, diarrhea, dysuria, incontinence, or rash.





PMH:

ear infection spring 2069 requiring IV abx (?mastoiditis)

type 1 DM x 38 year {retinopathy, nephropathy, neuropathy

arthritis, tendonitis, capsulitis

hypothyroidism

hypercholesterolemia



MED:

Insulin NPH 12U qam and 9U qpm

Insulin Reg SS

levothyroxine 200 mcg qd

Epogen 3x/wk



ALL: NKDA





SH: Retired, lives alone in Cape Cod, denies tobacco and alcohol





FH: type 1 DM





VS: T 98.8  HR 86  BP 157/94  RR 16





PE:  Genl 	WD WN WF mildly agitated NAD

HEENT 	AT/NC, MMM no lesions

Neck 	Supple, no thyromegaly, no LAN, no bruits

Chest 	CTA B

CVS 	RRR no MGR

ABD 	ND, +BS, NT, no masses, no hepatosplenomegaly

EXT 	b/l olecranon nodules, swollen fingers, no edema, distal pulses full, no rashes or petechiae

Rectal 	deferred

       Neuro

  MS:	disorganized thought (s/p ativan), speech fluent, flat affect

  CN: 	I--not tested; II,III--pupils pharmacologically dilated right sluggishly reactive and left non-reactive, VFF by confrontation, b/l optic disc swelling with small hemorrhages and cotton wool spots; III,IV,VI--EOMI, no ptosis; V--sensation intact to LT/PP, masseters strong symmetrically; VII--face symmetric without weakness; VIII--hears finger rub; IX,X--voice normal, palate elevates symmetrically; XI--SCM/trapezii 5/5; XII--tongue protrudes midline, no atrophy or fasciculations

  Motor:	normal bulk and tone, no tremor, rigidity or bradykinesia, no pronator drift.strength:

                  Sh abd


****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2071-06-26


Long Prairie Memorial Hospital
94 Aspen Court                                        Uher, Olga
Chilton, IN 26297                                      25816492
(606) 846-1043                                           06/26/71


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient has a
new apartment.  She is actually in the process of moving. 
She recognizes that she is improving, and is very excited
about the fact that, during the course of the week, she went
out to Sel de la Terre, and also went through a movie with her
friend.  

Her sugars are still not well controlled.  She has been
liberalizing her diet, which I thought was appropriate.  I
did increase her morning insulin to 20 units of 30/70, and
suggested that she change from five units of NPH at bedtime
to 8 units of 30-70, taken with her supper, to try to give
her a little better coverage for her evening meal.  I wrote
a note to the nurse to actuate this change.  They actually
called me later in the evening, on page, and I discussed
this with them, at length, at that time, including the
rationale for this change.

She is not having any exertional or other chest pain.  No
orthopnea, PND or peripheral edema.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Blood pressure is 135/80.  Heart rate
68 and regular.  Respirations 14.  Venous pressure 3.  Clear
chest.  S4, no S3.  No retrosternal dullness or rub.  She
has only a trace of ankle edema.

IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  Her verbal skills have improved.  She
got very nervous when I tried to test her cognitive skills,
and was able to give me the days of the week forward, but
not backwards.  I did not push her beyond that.  I did tell
her that we would need to check her TSH in a couple weeks'
time, to see if last increment had returned her to a
euthyroid state.


______________________________
Sean Ugalde, M.D.


eScription document:7-829452 STeScription

DD: 06/27/71
DT: 06/27/71
DV: 06/26/71



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-10-16

EDVISIT^25816492^Uher, Olga^10/16/73^BALL, MILDRED

The patient was seen in conjunction with resident Dr. Sharp. 

The resident's note reviewed.  The patient was seen and examined

by me.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, this is a 62-year-old woman

who has had decrease in mental status and activity since 3 days

ago.  She has had some fevers off and on.  Temperature ranging

between 100 and 101.3.  Her blood sugar has been 300-500.  She

reports a decrease in energy.  She has end-stage renal disease on

hemodialysis Sunday, Tuesday, and Thursday.  She had her dialysis

today but has much less energy than usual.  She has a cough, no

nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea, has constipation, takes lactulose,

and has a normal bowel movement.  Last BM was Thursday evening. 

This is a normal spacing of her usual bowel movements.  According

to her visiting nurse, the urine looks dark.  Blood pressure is

running in the low 100 in the last month.  Change in mental

status for 5 days means that she is not as talkative as usually

is.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY, SOCIAL HISTORY, AND REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: 

Reviewed, confirmed, and notable for history of high cholesterol,

arthritis, insulin-dependent diabetes, retinopathy, renal

failure, foot ulcers, and hypothyroidism.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She was in an acute care facility as a nurse

coming regularly.  The patient arrives to the hospital with a

DNR/DNH order, which near the end of her visit once the family

arrived, we got the information that this order has been and

rescinded by the family in the past.  This is noted nowhere in

her chart.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative except as noted above.

MEDICATIONS:  The patient takes methylphenidate, Ambien,

Prilosec, Ultram, verapamil, PhosLo, Coumadin, Renax, Colace, and

olanzapine.

ALLERGIES:  She is allergic to NSAIDs.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She has a fever of 100.3, pulse of 95,

respirations 24, blood pressure 85/53, and saturating 90% on room

air and 100% on 3 liters.  She has facial asymmetry which nurse

believes is baseline.  Neck is supple and nontender.  She has no

elevated JVP.  Respirations are bilateral basilar crackles with

full inspiration effort.  Cardiovascular exam is regular rate and

rhythm, tachycardic.  Abdomen exam is soft, nontender, no

distention, and no organomegaly.  Skin is warm, dry, and intact. 

No lesions or rashes.  She does have contractures on both lower

extremities.  Neurologically, she is not oriented at all and

cranial nerves II through XII are grossly intact.  There is no

motor or sensory deficits.

LABORATORY DATA:  Reveal white count of 6.8 and hematocrit of

28.8.  Chemistry shows sodium 146, potassium 4.4, chloride 105,

bicarbonate 29, BUN 36, creatinine 3.5, glucose 263, CK 281,

CK-MB 7.5, and troponin 142.  Platelets is 17.6.  PNI 37.7 and

INR 1.4.

EKG, what is concerning is she has ST elevations approximately 2

mm in leads II, III, and F, and V3 through V5.  There is no

R-wave progression.  Chest x-ray showed mild pulmonary edema.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Fever.

SECONDARY DIAGNOSIS:  Possible sepsis.

DISPOSITION:  She is admitted to the hospital having received

ceftriaxone, vancomycin, and levofloxacin in the Emergency

Department empirically.  She is admitted to the ward in stable

condition.

______________________________

BALL, MILDRED M.D.

D: 10/17/73

T: 10/17/73

Dictated By: BALL, MILDRED

eScription document:8-2575360 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>