<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2070-10-08

















October 8, 2070





Thomas You, M.D.

743 Gilson Road

Vernon, ME 27525



RE:  		Jaquante Xuereb

SRI: 		134-43-51



Dear Dr. You:



Thank you for asking me to consult in the care of this complex patient.  Mr. Xuereb is a 55-year-old white male who presents with an ischemic right foot.  He has a longstanding history of lower extremity occlusive disease and has worked as a high school principle.  He has undergone previous right SFA angioplasty in 2059, previous left SFA angioplasty and stent placement in 2062, previous right fem-pop above-knee bypass grafting in February 2070, previous left leg fem-pop bypass grafting with saphenous vein in April 2070 and a redo right fem below-knee popliteal bypass graft with a bifid saphenous vein performed in September 2070.  After this last procedure, the patient at the time of follow-up office visit was noted to have a nonfunctioning graft with an ischemic right lower extremity.  He denies any history of trauma.  He is a former smoker.  He denies any history of hypercoagulable states or history of significant coronary disease.  He does have longstanding non-insulin dependent diabetes mellitus as well as hypertension and COPD.



Past surgical history is as above.



Medications include Glucophage, Lopid, Prilosec, Norvasc, hydrochlorothiazide, Lipitor, Effexor, Plavix 75 mg q.d., aspirin, albuterol, Serevent, Nasacort and Pulmicort.



No known drug allergies.



Review of systems is positive for diabetes, asthma and hypertension.  All other review of systems is negative as per H&P sheet.



Habits, he is a former tobacco smoker.  He denies alcohol use.



Family history is positive for MI, stroke and cancer.



On physical exam, the patient is a well-developed and well-nourished male in moderate discomfort.  Respiratory rate is 12-14.  Pulse is 60-70 and regular.  Weight is 172 pounds.  Blood pressure is 170/90 in the right arm, 150/90 in the left.  No jugular venous distention.  Normal respiratory effort.  Lungs are clear to auscultation.  Heart, regular rate and rhythm.  No murmur or bruit.  He has no palpable abdominal aortic aneurysm.  He has normal carotid, brachial, radial and femoral pulses bilaterally.  Absent pedal pulses on the right with Doppler signals, which are monophasic.  On the left side, he has adequately perfused foot with normal capillary refill and Doppler signals.  He has moderate edema in the right lower extremity.  No varicosities.  He does have dependent rubor, cyanosis of the right forefoot and purplish discoloration of the tips of the right second to fifth toes.  The right great toe is blanched.  He has no abdominal masses, tenderness or hepatosplenomegaly.  He has grossly intact musculoskeletal tone and strength with no dermatitis, ulcers or sores.  He is alert and oriented to person, place and time with slightly depressed affect.



Assessment and Plan:  



1. Ischemic right lower extremity consistent with thrombosed bypass graft.  We will plan to admit the patient for treatment with intravenous heparin and plan to schedule him for an urgent arteriogram within the next 24 hours.  We will attempt to identify any possible way to re-establish flow  with either thrombolysis and/or angioplasty and stenting.  If this is unsuccessful, he will ultimately require redo fem-pop bypass graft.

2. Tobacco abuse:  The patient needs to continue to remain abstinent from smoking.

3. Hypertension:  Moderately controlled on current medications.  His previous angiogram did not reveal any evidence of any hemodynamically significant renal artery stenosis.  We will adjust him as appropriate from a medical standpoint.  

4. Non-insulin dependent diabetes mellitus.  The patient's blood sugars are currently under good control on Glucophage, which we will need to hold post arteriogram.  I will keep you informed as to the status of this very nice patient.  



Thank you for allowing me to participate in his management.  If I can be of any further assistance and management of this or any of your patients with cerebrovascular, aortic, renovascular or low peripheral vascular disease, particularly those in need of a minimally invasive vascular procedure, please feel free to contact me directly.  



Sincerely,







Shane R. Herring, M.D.





cc:	Dirk O. Reece, M.D., PCP, Pune, ME



SRH/valdovinos	19-35905660.doc





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-12-03













December 3, 2070





Thomas You, M.D.

239 Gilson Road

Vernon, ME 27525





RE:  		Jaquante Xuereb

SRI: 		134-43-51



Dear Dr. You:



I had the pleasure of seeing our mutual patient, Mr. Jaquante Xuereb, in follow up evaluation in our vascular surgery clinic here at the Santa Rosa Infirmary today.  As you remember, he recently underwent a revision of his lower extremity bypass graft with thrombectomy of the fem-pop bypass graft and subsequent jump graft to the below-knee popliteal artery.  He returns today for follow up evaluation. 



He has a warm, well-perfused foot with a palpable dorsalis pedis pulse.  Unfortunately, over the last ten days he has developed increased erythema and tenderness on the medial aspect of his left knee with superficial skin breakdown consistent with either a staph or a strep cellulitis.  He had been on a course of p.o. antibiotics over a week ago for treatment of strep throat as well.  The patient has been increased his activity and prior to this time had been extremely active with no erythema, tenderness or drainage from his leg.  My concern is that he has increased warmth with blanching and erythema on the medial aspect of his knee consistent with a superficial cellulitis and I believe that he would benefit from hospital admission with a course of IV antibiotics, bedrest and elevate.  We will tentatively plan to admit him for localized wound care measures, treatment with IV Nafcillin on a q.4 hour basis.  In addition, he has intact femoral pulses on the left side.  He does report when he was ambulating he was having increased difficulty with claudication in the distal left lower extremity and calf region.  Most recent vascular lab studies dated November 29, 2070 reveal an ABI of 0.96 on the right, 0.56 on the left.  



I will keep you informed as to the status of Mr. Xuereb.  My concern is that if he does infect this PTFE graft we do not have any suitable autogenous conduit to perform an additional reconstruction and he would stand a very high chance of losing his limb at the knee level.  If I can be of any further assistance in the management of this or any of your other patients with vascular disease, particularly those in need of a minimally invasive vascular procedure, please feel free to contact me directly.





Sincerely,





Shane R. Herring, M.D.



cc:	Dirk O. Reece, M.D., 9 Church Street, Pune, ME 99597



SH/truitt		89-05167655.doc





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2071-04-14

Patient Name: XUEREB, JAQUANTE;  MRN: 1344351

Dictated on: 04/27/2071 by LILLIAN STEELE, N.P., PH.D. 



 

Mr. Xuereb returns to clinic for evaluation and management of recurrent ulcerations on the hypertrophic scar tissue along the medial aspect of the right lower extremity.  

 

Today, on physical examination, the wound bed measured 1 cm x 0.7 cm.  The wound bed was covered with yellow biofilm, which was debrided.  The underlying wound bed contained moist red tissue with a few drops of bloody drainage.  The margin was clear.  

 

IMPRESSION:  There has been epithelialization of the wound along the medial aspect of the right knee.  There has been no further disruption of the epithelium overlying the hypertrophic scar tissue.   



PLAN:  We will continue with dressing changes every two to three days per the following protocol: spray the wound with AllClenz wound cleanser followed by irrigation with normal saline 30 cc x 3; apply skin protectant to the periwound margin, Panafil paste 1/8" thick to the wound bed, gauze dampened with normal saline (cut-to-fit), covered with DuoDerm secured with Medipore tape.  

 

Mr. Xuereb will return to clinic in two weeks.  

 

__________________________ 

Lillian Steele, N.P., Ph.D.  

 

DD:04/27/2071 

DT:04/28/2071 

FJ:801734    :77 

 





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-12-03

 



CCU JAR ADMIT NOTE



Name:   Xuereb, Jaquante D

MRN:   1344351

Date of Admission:   12/03/73

Admitting Physician:   Dr. Burke

Code Status: Full

Source of Hx:   Chart, patient



ID/CC:   Chest pressure, pulmonary edema. 



HPI:   58 year old man with PMH HTN , Hypercholesterolemia, smoking. And PVD. S/P LE bypass was admitted to Vascular service with 1-2 day history of RLE pain, discoloration. Found to have occluded fem-pop bypass. Underwent unsuccesfull attmp by IR to open vessel and was awainting sheath pull on the vascular floor when he developed shortness of breath and b/l chest pressure in the setting of FFP transfusion. Did have a troponin 0.6 and some anterior ST changes. He was diruesed and placed on CPAP when he began to increasing respiratory effort and evidence of tiring. He was then intubated and transferred to the CCU. On arrival in the CCU pt became hypotensive with MAPS in the 40's. He was startered on peripheral  dopamine with good respone. No EKG chages associated with these symptoms.  





.



PMH/Old Data

PVD

Hyperlipidemia

HTN

Smoking





Allergies/Adverse Reactions

NKDA



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for diabetes, hypertension, high

cholesterol and depression.

     

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Significant for bilateral knee arthroscopies and

multiple bypass grafts and revascularizations of his lower extremities.

     

MEDICATIONS:  Include Glucophage, Actos, gemfibrozil, Lipitor, lisinopril, Norvasc, hydrochlorothiazide, Effexor, warfarin, and aspirin.

     

ALLERGIES:  He has no known drug allergies.

     

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is an ex-smoker.  He quit two years prior to this

admission.  He was a social drinker and is a  school administrator.







PE          

VS: 	T  afebrile , MAPS 40-80 , HR 50's-60's , O2 Sat 97 % on 100%fiO2 PC.  

Gen: 	Intubated and sedated. 

HEENT:  JVP 8-10cm

Lungs: 	CTAB - ant

Cor: 	RRR, no m/r/g 

Abd: 	Abdomen soft, NT 

Extr: 	Warm, PPP . Left arterial sheath. 

Pulses:	pulse with Doppler on L , none on R. 





Labs





Plasma Sodium                    137                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.0                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  99               L        (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            26.0                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Calcium                          8.6                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       5.5              H        (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.7                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             11                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.0                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Plasma Glucose                   405              H        (70-110)       mg/dl

Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       3.7                       (0.0-6.9)      ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                                       (0.0-3.5)      

Troponin-T                       0.65             H        (0.00-0.09)    ng/ml

Creatine Kinase                  94                        (60-400)       U/L





FIO2/Flow                        UNSPEC.                                  FIO2/L

Temp                             37.0                                     deg C

Unspecified pH                   7.29             L        (7.32-7.45)

Unspecified PCO2                 53               H        (35-50)        mm/Hg

Unspecified PO2                  204              H        (40-90)        mm/Hg

Potassium                        4.2                       (3.5-5.0)      mmol/L

Glucose                          439              H        (70-110)       mg/dL







WBC                              13.5             H        (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              37.3             L        (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              12.8             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              4.29             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              324                       (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              87                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              29.9                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             34.3                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              14.3                      (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               20.7             H        (11.3-13.3)    sec

PT-INR                           2.9

APTT                             27.7                      (22.1-34.0)    sec

     





  



Studies

EKG-NSR, dynamic t-wave changes anterior, ~1mm ST elevation worse than prior v4-v5

CXR:  Vascular congestion. 







Impression and Plan:  58 year old man with PVD, likely CAD but no available ischemic work-up. Resp decompensation likely secondary to pulmonary edema in the setting of volume load. There is some question as to what to do about EKG changes and mild troponin elevations. No definite ST elevations, but elevation in troponin does seem to be too soon to be directly attributable to flash pulmonary edema and resultant demand. Follow enzymes,  heparinize both for ?ischemia and for PVD with sheath in place. As not lilely ACS, not emergent indication for cath, but he was scheduled for elective cath 12/08 and likely would benefit from expedited diagnosis. 



Pump - intubated, diruesis as allowed by pressure (JVP up, some edema of CXR). Started on peripheral dopa, but this is at least partially related to sedation. 



Rhythm - Bradycardia, no acute issues



Iscenmia - Demand ischemia vs NSTEMI. Follow markers. Likely to cath today where it is propble he will have 3vd and require CT surg consult.  Have request FMC records. 



Heme - FFP + lasix prior to cath. Heparin, 



Resp -  Wean vent post cath/OP





Prophy - Heparin/nexium/peridex while vented. 





Code: Full



______________

S. Stanley Oberg, MD, PhD

Medicine PGY-2

Pager 86807      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-12-05

      

 



CCU JAR TRANSFER NOTE



Name:   Xuereb, Jaquante D

MRN:   1344351

Date of Admission:   12/03/73

Date of Transfer:  12/05/73

Admitting Physician:   Dr. Burke

Code Status: Full

Source of Hx:   Chart, patient



ID/CC:   Chest pressure, pulmonary edema. 



HPI:   58 year old man with PMH significant for HTN , Hypercholesterolemia, smoking and PVD. S/P LE bypass.  Admitted to Vascular service with 1-2 day history of RLE pain, discoloration. Found to have occluded fem-pop bypass. Underwent unsuccesfull attmp by IR to open vessel and was awaiting sheath pull on the vascular floor when he developed shortness of breath and b/l chest pressure in the setting of FFP transfusion. Did have a troponin bump to 0.6 and some anterior ST changes. He was diuresed and placed on CPAP when he began to have increasing respiratory effort and evidence of tiring.  He was then intubated and transferred to the CCU.  On arrival in the CCU, pt became hypotensive with MAPS in the 40's. He was startered on peripheral dopamine with good respone. No EKG chages associated with these symptoms.



PMH/Old Data

PVD

Hyperlipidemia

HTN

Smoking

B knee arthroscopies and multiple bypass grafts and revascularizations of his LE



Allergies/Adverse Reactions

	NKDA



Social Hx:

	Ex-smoker, quit 2 yrs PTA

	school administrator



Home Meds:

	Glucophage, Actos, Gemfibrozil, Lipitor, Lisinopril, Norvasc, HCTZ, Effexor, Coumadin, ASA.

  

Please see admission H&P for initial exam and today's progress note for current exam.



Labs/Studies

Admission EKG-NSR, dynamic t-wave changes anterior, ~1mm ST elevation worse than prior

Admission CXR:  Vascular congestion.

12/05/73:

Chem7 WNL, Cr 1.0, Glu 200-265, Mag 1.8

Peak Trop 0.65 (trending down)

WBC 8.8    16.2, Hct 33.2, Plt 283

INR 2.7, PTT 61.5





CCU Course/Plan:  



Ischemia:  Patient was taken to cath lab on 12/03/73 and found to have 3-V CAD (70% prox LAD, 60% LCx, occluded RCA).  He was transferred to the CCU (intubated) but with diuresis he was weaned and extubated on 12/04/73.  He continued to be medically managed with ASA/Plavix (on hold now for anticipated surgery), Statin (lipitor 80 mg po qhs), BB (lopressor 50 mg po q6h), and ACE-I (captopril 6.25 mg po tid started on 12/05/73).  He is awaiting CABG but does not have good conduits as expected given his extensive PVD.  Plastic surgery is evaluating patient for potential grafts.  CNI pending pre-op.



Pump: Patient was quickly weaned off all pressors.  TTE was obtained on 12/05/73.  EF was 38%, mild MR, LA dilatation, LV is dilated and fxn is moderately impaired (inf/post/lat dysfunction).  There were echodensities noted in the LV apex which may be trabeculations, however, thrombus cannot be excluded.  He has received prn doses of lasix (responds to 80 IV) and we are continuing his BB and ACE-I.  Goal TBB is ~-1.0 L.



Rhythm: Stable, continuing BB, Telemetry.



Resp: Stable, s/p extubation.  On NC with sats > 95%.  Continue diuresis and f/u CXRs.



PVD/LE: Unsuccessful attempt at percutaneous revascularization of his RLE.  Limb is currently not threatened and he has dopplerable pulses.  No plans now for interventions in LE.



ID/WBC: WBC elevated on 12/05/73 but no fevers.  May be due to steroids (was receiving Dex while cort-stim was in process).  This was discontinued.  Cultures all show no growth to date.  Continue to trend WBCs.



Proph: Heparin gtt, Nexium.



FULL CODE



John Yeatts, MD

CCU JAR, Pager 09171











****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>