<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2068-02-04

ASSOCIATED ARTHRITIS SPECIALISTS CENTER            Quijano, Baylee
                                              2-03-68
 
 
 
Identification:  Patient is a 53-year old markedly obese female 
complaining of bilateral weight knee pain.  She denies any morning 
stiffness, any jelling phenomena.  She has had no trauma or effusions in 
the knee.  She had noted on x-ray many years ago that she had had a 
chipped bone in the right knee and some mild osteoarthritis but it has 
bothered her only intermittently until this year.  Last year she did go 
to Briggs Stratton and dropped to 270 lb. at which point her knees felt 
better, but currently she is back up to over 300 lb. and at her height 
of 5 ft. 1 in., she is in pain.  She has not visited a physician.  She 
has no internist who currently checks on her general medical health, but 
she does report that the occasional Advil she takes does produce some 
dyspepsia.  She has no history of gout, no history of psoriasis, no 
history of pseudogout or any rash, alopecia, headaches, shoulder or hip 
discomfort.  She does not complain of back pain but does have difficult 
walking 50 yards because of the knee pain.
 
Allergies:  None.
 
Medications:  Occasional Advil.
 
Past Surgical History:  Cholecystectomy 2064.  Two c-sections.
 
Past Medical History:  Negative for hypertension, diabetes, cancer, 
stroke, tuberculosis, hepatitis, asthma, heart disease.
 
Family History:  Mother is alive and well with no medical problems.  
Father is alive and well with no medical problems.  She has 12 siblings.  
One sibling died of pneumonia at a young age.  Another sibling has 
asthma.
 
Physical Examination;  She is a markedly obese female, no apparent 
distress.  She is 5 ft. 1 in. and weighs 304 lb.  Examination of joints:  
No evidence of active synovitis or pain in her DIPs, PIPs, MCPs, wrists, 
elbows, shoulders.  Bilateral hips are limited in internal external 
rotation but not because of pain-- due to obesity, bilateral knees have 
crepitus, but no warmth or swelling.  There is some pain at extremes of 
flexion on the left of 110 degrees.  Ankles and toes within normal 
limits.  Please note above in the clinical history that she does not 
complain of back pain but does have difficult walking 50 yards because 
of the knee pain.  The blood pressure could not be taken secondary to 
the fact that the large blood pressure 
cuff did not fit around her right arm. 
 
Impression:  
 
1.   Probable bilateral osteoarthritis.  I will obtain plain films and 
     have prescribed Disalcid 3 gm. a day p.r.n.   GI and renal side 
     effects explained.
                                              2-03-68
 
 
 
2.   We discussed seriously the need for weight loss.  She will be 
     referred to the nutritionist to get on a weight loss program.  She 
     will seriously entertain a weight loss program.  Patient will 
     return in a few months unless she has any further problems.
 
3.   I have referred her to an Internal Medicine doctor for health maintenance since 
     she does not have one as yet.
 
 
 
 
_________________________
Ada R. Kruger, M.D.
 
FK:SK:3696
DD:2-03-68
DT:2-05-68
DV:2-03-68




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-01-22

                     AASC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
QUIJANO,BAYLEE   853-62-51-4                    VISIT DATE: 01/22/74
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a very pleasant 50 
year old woman with a history of hypertension, on atenolol, 
hydrochlorothiazide, triamterene who presents to the Emergency 
Department complaining of subjective fevers, myalgias and cough. 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative for headache, neck pain, chest pain, 
shortness of breath, dyspnea on exertion, abdominal pain, fevers or 
chills. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Afebrile.  Vital signs are normal. 
Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Neck:  Supple.  JVD to approximately 7 
cm.  Chest has bibasilar faint crackles that do not clear with 
cough.  Abdomen is soft, obese.  Heart:  Regular rate and rhythm. 
Extremities:  1+ non-pitting edema versus obesity. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Chest x-ray with bilateral inferior lobe 
infiltrates with cephalization consistent with mild to moderate 
CHF, no effusions.  EKG with LVH, no ST elevations, T wave 
inversions or evidence of acute ischemia. 
ASSESSMENT/PLAN:  New onset CHF, setting in a probable URI. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  I will admit to 
Medical Service for workup of CHF, rule out MI, echocardiogram. 
The patient is admitted in good condition. 
___________________________________                    ZW011/0863 
DAVID ZHU, M.D.  DZ0                                D:01/22/74 
                                                       T:01/22/74 
Dictated by:  DAVID ZHU, M.D.  DZ0 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-01-15

                     AASC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
QUIJANO,BAYLEE   853-62-51-4                    VISIT DATE: 01/15/75
The patient was worked up in the emergency department by myself and 
the resident, and I concur with her work up and evaluation in the 
emergency department. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:    Chest pain, shortness of breath, 
productive cough. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 60-year-old 
female that presents to the emergency department at Associated Arthritis with complaints of chest pain, shortness of breath 
and a cough productive of white sputum.  The patient denies fever 
or chills.  She denies any other acute complaints. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Morbid obesity, congestive heart failure, 
hypertension, rheumatoid arthritis. 
MEDICATIONS:  Zestril, a water pill most likely Lasix, Motrin and 
Tylenol. 
ALLERGIES:  No known allergies. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 99, pulse 85, 
respiratory rate 16, blood pressure 214/117.  Oxygen saturation 92% 
on two liters.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils equal, 
round, reactive.  Positive AV nicking.  NECK:  Positive for jugular 
venous distension.  CHEST:  Rales audible bilaterally.  HEART: 
Normal S1/S2.  No S3/S4.  No murmur.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender. 
EXTREMITIES:  Positive for 2-3+ pitting edema.  NEURO:  She was 
awake, alert, and able to follow commands. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  CK 84.  White count 10, hemoglobin 12, 
hematocrit 42, platelet count 329.  Urinalysis noted 1+ blood in 
her urine, however, overall, her urinalysis was negative.  Chest 
x-ray which noted cardiomegaly with findings consistent with 
congestive heart failure.  EKG noted no acute changes. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was given 40 mg of 
Lasix IV initially.  For her chest pain, she was given sublingual 
nitroglycerin.  She was also given one aspirin.  She had a 
nitroglycerin patch placed in the emergency department. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS: 
1. Congestive failure. 
2. Chest pain, no evidence of an acute myocardial infarction. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 
be admitted to the medicine service for further work up and 
evaluation.  The patient is in stable condition. 
___________________________________                    CY313/62627 
O. DE OTIS, M.D.       DO36                       D:01/18/75 
                                                       T:01/18/75 
Dictated by:  O. DE OTIS, M.D.       DO36 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-07-20

                                                       Patient Name: QUIJANO,BAYLEE [ MRN: 85362514MARY ]                                                         Date of Visit: 07/20/2076Chief Complaint	

Ms. Quijano is a 61 yo morbidly obese woman with CAD, OA, and CHF who is in for follow-up of these problems.  



History of Present Illness	

She is working every day and feels much better than she did last year.  She has had multiple admissions in the past for CHF and for ischemia.  Recent echo shows septal and apical hypokinesis.  



She has had no chest pain.  She does not complain of SOB.  She does cough, but this is because of the air conditioning and postnasal drip, she believes.  



She also complains of severe knee pain, with the right worse than the left.  She can walk a little, but standing is very painful.  



In addition, she complains of some food intolerance.  She has a hard time eating breakfast because she gets abdominal cramps.  After eating orange juice, she gets terrible cramping and has to run to the bathroom to have a bowel movement.  She has changed her milk to lactaid, which she says helps.  Certain types of salad dressing also cause this reaction.  



Problems	  

MORBID OBESITY	      

KNEE OA	      

ANSERINE BURSITIS, BILAT	      

S/P 2 C-SECTIONS	      

HTN	      

CAD	      

CHF	      

ASTHMA	      



Medications	  

VENTOLIN	 2PUFFS INH QID

AZMACORT	 4PUFFS INH BID

ECASA	 1  PO QD

ATROVENT	 2PUFFS INH QID

TNG 0.4 MG	    SL 

SEREVENT	 2PUFFS INH BID

FLOVENT	 220MCG INH BID

COZAAR	 100MG PO QD

LOPRESSOR	 25MG PO TID

LASIX	 60MG PO BID

ZANTAC	 150MG PO BID

NORVASC	 10MG PO QD

ISOSORBIDE DINITRATE	 20MG 1 Tablet(s) PO TID



Allergies	  

LISINOPRIL	 COUGH



Social History	

Employment:  Works in commercial diving.  

Marital/Relationship:  She is married.  Her husband is retired. She has 3 children, and 3 grandchildren, and 2 great grand children!  Recently went down to Mississippi to celebrate her father's 81st birthday.  They drove down in a van because she is afraid of flying.  





Family History	

Father:  Alive, and very healthy.  

Mother:  Mother died at age 80 in Apr, 2075, of MI.  

Siblings:  She has 12 siblings--she is the oldest.  None of them have weight problem.  Her two daughters have obesity.  Her grandson is also overweight at 12 years old.  



Habits	

Tobacco:  Never.  

EtOH:  None

Drugs:  None

Seatbelts:  Yes

Domestic violence: None

Sleep:  She tends to sleep a little less than before.  She is tired during the day.  No daytime somnolence.  She wakes herself up with snoring.  

Exercise:  None.  

Emotional history:  No depression.  

Diet:  She is not really on a regimen.  She admits to lots of snacking.  



Review of Systems	

No headaches, lightheadedness, vision changes.  No chest pain, SOB, DOE, palpitations.  No  abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, constipation, diarrhea.  No change in bowel habits, BPBPR, melena. No dysuria, dypareunia.  No numbness, tingling, weakness, myalgias. No fever, chills, change in appetite, weight loss. Remainder of systems reviewed and negative.





Vital Signs	  

Blood Pressure:	 178/80   

Pulse:	 88   

Height:	 62   Inches

Weight:	 332   Pounds



Physical Exam	

General Appearance: Morbidly obese, very pleasant woman in no acute distress.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  PERRLA, EOMI.  Neck:  No thyromegaly.  No JVD, carotid bruits, lymphadenopathy.  Neck is supple with full ROM.  Chest:  Clear to P and A.  No wheezes, rales, rhonchi.  Cardiac:  Normal S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops. Breasts:  Symmetric, no masses, tenderness or nipple discharge.  Abdomen:  Normal bowel sounds, no HSM or tenderness.  Extremities: Crepitance in both knees.  4+ pretibial edema.   



Assessment	

1.  Hypertension:



Increased lasix to 80 mg po bid.  Increased lopressor to 50 mg po bid (she hadn't been taking this).  RTC one month to see me for f/u.  



2.  Hypercholesterolemia:



For some reason, she had stopped taking her zocor.  I restarted her on lipitor 20 mg po qd, given her very high dLDL on 5/26/76--171.  Checked AST today.  She will come in tomorrow for fasting cholesterol levels.  



3.  Obesity:



She is making no progress in this area, and in fact is getting worse.  Her daughter had the gastric bypass operation and has lost 100 lbs.  She is receptive to the idea of going for a consultation.  She had gone to Weight Clinic before for the liquid diet, but she could no longer afford to go.  



Plan:  

Referral to Dr. Bobby Davison.

Checked TSH



4.  Polyuria, polydypsia:



She has had one random BS of 170, and another of 136.  We will have her come back for a FBS tomorrow.  Also checked Cre, K.  









______________________________                              



Xanthopoulos, Kelly Willie, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-02-05

                     AASC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

QUIJANO,BAYLEE   853-62-51-4

Ms. Quijano is a 62-year-old female who was seen by the resident and 

seen and examined by me.

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Nausea, vomiting and diarrhea.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Patient is a 62-year-old female 

with history of asthma and CHF with coronary artery disease, 

presents now with multiple episodes of vomiting and diarrhea and 

"feeling sick".  Has no history of fevers.  Mildly tachycardic with 

a pulse rate of 100.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Stated that recently was feeling sick.  Had a 

chest x-ray recently and was negative.  Treated with Amoxicillin, 

but still continued to have some mild cough and wheezes.  That 

brought her to the Emergency Department, but no complaints of any 

new shortness of breath, but has this persistent cough that has not 

gone away despite being treated with antibiotics.  Denies fever or 

chills.  Denies shortness of breath.  Denies dyspnea on exertion.  

Denies PND.   Review of systems otherwise unremarkable.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  History of hypertension, CHF, asthma, status 

post cholecystectomy.  History of coronary artery disease.  Status 

post C-section times two.  

MEDICATIONS:  On multiple medicines including Ventolin, Lasix, 

Lopressor and Zantac as well as Lipitor.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  HEENT:  Normal.  NECK:  Supple.  LUNGS:  

Some mild wheezes bilaterally.  No rales however.  No respiratory 

distress.  Some course rhonchi heard throughout lung fields.  

CARDIAC EXAM:  Regular rate and rhythm.  No murmurs.  ABDOMEN:  

Soft, nontender without any masses.  MUSCULOSKELETAL:  Shows trace 

edema greatest in the lower extremities, but good pulses, normal.  

Capillary refill and neurological is intact.

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Full laboratory studies were done including 

chest x-ray.  EKG showed sinus rhythm with T-wave inversion in A, V 

and L.  This is not new based on old cardiograms.  Chest x-ray 

shows some cardiomegaly and a fluffy chest x-ray indicating CHF.  

Electrolytes, BUN and creatinine normal.  Hematocrit of 45 and a 

normal white count.   

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Initially systolic blood pressure 

was over 200 and diastolic over 91 and patient also received some 

Diltiazem for blood pressure control.  

Assessment:  This is a 62-year-old woman who has vomiting, 

diarrhea, and "feeling sick" and she has a chronic cough despite 

recent treatment with antibiotics, but no shortness of breath, now 

found to be in CHF on chest x-ray.  Patient has been diuresed.  PCP 

is aware.  She is going to be admitted. 

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Primary care physician.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Cough with congestive heart failure.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted to the hospital in stable condition.

___________________________________                    UZ272/3146

FRANK ISON, M.D.       FI65                           D:02/05/77 

                                                       T:02/05/77 

Dictated by:  FRANK ISON, M.D.       FI65 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>