<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2083-05-18

























May 18, 2083



Yesenia Olive, M.D.

26 Jeremy Place

Antioch, KY  71287



RE:  Gerald, Marion 

MRN: 48967301 

DOV: 05/18/83



Dear Dr. Olive,



Thanks for asking me to see Marion Gerald who I saw on May 18.  She is 

referred for either fibromyalgia or polymyalgia.  The patient states she is 

currently 60 but was in her usual state of good health until 2065 when she 

developed diffuse chest wall pain and tingling.  This continued to bother her 

and she eventually was treated with steroids.  I am not sure she had a 

diagnosis of PMR or fibromyalgia.  She then was switched to ibuprofen which 

did not work particularly well.  Over this time, she would have intermittent 

episodes with nocturnal discomfort and most recently has increasing pain in 

her palms, back, neck, low back, legs, and into her arms.  She was seen by 

Dr. Zink at Barr Clinic, and no blood studies were obtained, but she states 

she had "25 shots" of steroids.  She denies any hot or swollen joints.  She 

has had occasional arm swelling but this has resolved.  Extensive ROS reveals 

no photosensitivity but she does have some oral ulcers and Raynaud's.  She 

has urgency regarding her bladder and has been evaluated but not particularly 

well.  She has continued to be concerned about that.  She has had fevers or 

chills but no temperature elevation.  She has intermittent abdominal pain but 

has had a colonoscopy two years ago and was evaluated for this.  She has 

morning stiffness of about an hour and nocturnal pain through the night.



Family history is otherwise remarkable for diabetes in her father.  Mother is 

85.  Two sons alive and well.  Two siblings alive and well except for 

hypertension and hypercholesterolemia.



Past medical history is pertinent for above.  She has had a partial 

hysterectomy, cholecystectomy, and fracture of her wrist.  Medications 

include for hypertension, diabetes, and hypercholesterolemia, the following: 

metformin 500 b.i.d., verapamil 240 b.i.d., Avapro 150 q.d., Pravachol 20 mg 

q.d., Bumex 20 q.d., cyclobenzaprine 10 q.d., Prilosec 20 q.d., and Allegra.  

No smoking or drinking history.  No allergies.  No other medical problems.



Social history is pertinent in that she lives in Elizabethtown.  She works as a 

midwife and director of Iowa Birth Clinic.  Her husband is 

a Broadcast Technician.  They have traveled quite a bit because of this.







Yesenia Olive, M.D.

RE:  Gerald, Marion 

MRN: 48967301 

Page 2





Physical reveals a very pleasant woman in no distress.  Weight 152.  BP 

120/80.  She had a respiratory rate of 16.  She had full range of motion of 

all of her joints with tenderness in epicondyles, greater trochanters, and 

cervical and lumbar area.  Otherwise, no active synovitis or skin lesions.  

No oral ulcerations.  Good salivary pool.  No lymphadenopathy, thyromegaly, 

or axillary adenopathy.  Chest: clear to A&P.  No carotid bruits.  Vascular 

exam: normal.  Cardiac exam: quiet precordium without murmur or gallop.  

Abdominal exam: nontender without hepatosplenomegaly.  Extremities: without 

edema.



I suspect she has fibromyalgia.  I do not really know the place of steroids 

in this setting.  I will obtain chemistry profile including CPK, LFTs, TSH, 

CBC, ESR, as well as a urine, ANA, CRP, and RF.  I will see her back in four 

to six weeks.  She will get old records for me to review.  We will talk about 

what therapeutic interventions we may take at that time, but I really need to 

have more information because at this point her symptoms are rather benign.  

I will be in touch with her regarding these results as they come in.



Sincerely yours,







_______________________________ 

Miguel H. Ames, M.D. 



cc:	Gerald Yan, M.D., PROMPTCARE

 

DD: 05/18/83 

DT: 05/21/83 

DV: 05/18/83 

/maldonado



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-06-29



Fairview Lakes Regional Medical Center

64 Tara Boulevard

ASB II, 9st Xloor                                         GERALD, MARION

Cedar Hill Lakes, KY 99249                                      48967301

(290) 680-0790                                           06/29/83





Xochil Higgins, M.D.

091 Keith Street
Antioch, KY 71287



Dear Dr. Higgins,



Marion Gerald will be seeing you sometime in September for primary

care.  I was seeing her for various rheumatologic issues.  She

comes in today with ongoing pain in the left side of her face. 

Actually, upon exam, she clearly simply has left TMJ.  She has

been told this by ENT and I reinforced to her that that is what

she has and she will go ahead with a dental visit that she had

planned.  However, she has other medical problems which I will

deal with until she sees you.  At her last visit, there was a

question of PMR and she had "25 shots" of steroids but I have not

given her steroids and she has done reasonably well.  However,

she does have a history of a recent mild anemia but has diabetes,

hypertension and hypercholesterolemia and medications include

metformin, verapamil 250 b.i.d., Avapro 150 q.d., Pravachol 20

q.d., Bumex, Bentyl, Prilosec and Allegra.



Physical examination today reveals left TMJ pain which reproduces

her pain.  She had had no lymphadenopathy or thyromegaly.  HEENT

was otherwise unremarkable.  I obtained blood studies which

revealed a blood sugar of 208, abnormal LFTs with an AST of 62

and ALT of 58, normal ferritin B12 and folic acid, TSH of 8.8

with thyroid antibodies pending, urine microalbumin/creatinine of

14.5 and a CBC which had anemia with a hematocrit of 32.9.  A1c

pending.  A protein electrophoresis is pending and urinalysis did

not reveal proteinuria or sediment.  HBsAG and HCV are pending as

well.



I will be in touch with her regarding these results.  I was

wondering if you could see her sooner than September because of

these abnormalities outlined.  Thanks for letting me participate

in her care.



Sincerely yours,



Dictated By: Miguel Ames











______________________________

Miguel Ames, M.D.





eScription document:6-0391514 ZB







DD: 06/30/83

DT: 07/01/83

DV: 06/30/83



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-10-01



Westwing Place Nursing Home

356 Chablis Court                                    GERALD, MARION

Doha, KY 63216                            48967301

(638) 074-1457                                           10/01/83

(449) 515-0294





REASON FOR VISIT:  Follow up cholesterol and new problem of chest

pain.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Gerald is a 61-year-old patient

with history of diabetes, hypertension, elevated lipids,

hypothyroidism and I now have available old records from previous

doctor, Yesenia Olive.  The following issues addressed:

1.  Diabetes:  She is currently feeling well and denies any

symptoms of polyuria and polydipsia.  Maintained on Glucophage

1000 mg b.i.d.  Blood sugar testing at home once or twice a day

is around 120.  We will be obtaining glycohemoglobin level today.

 Has ophthalmological exam scheduled.

2.  Elevated cholesterol:  With her diabetes, her target LDL will

be less than a 100.  She is maintained on Pravachol 40 mg a day

and LDL from 09/15/83 was 154 with a total cholesterol of 256. 

We will initiate Zetia to add to the Pravachol.

3.  Hypothyroidism:  Maintained on Levoxyl and TSH level is

acceptable at 3.93 with a T4 of 8.5.

4.  Hypertension:  Maintained on Avapro and verapamil and blood

pressure is currently acceptable.

5.  Question of rheumatological disease, elevated sedimentation

rate, diagnosis of polymyalgia rheumatica has been considered in

the past.  No new symptoms of muscle aches, but now report a

history of recent chest pain.

6.  Exercise-induced chest pain.  The patient has noted over the

past month that she gets a pressure sensation in her mid chest

when she is walking after about 20 minutes of exertion.  This

subsides when she stops and rests for a while.  This has been

reproduced for the last three times she has taken a walk with her

husband.  Review of records from Dr. Olive show that she had

thallium stress test 12/26/79 achieving 85% of maximum predicted

heart rate with a workload of 10.1 minutes.  EKG showed 1 mm ST

depression in leads II and V4 through 6.  The thallium scan

showed slight apical ischemia and mild ischemia in the anterior

walls suggesting minimal ischemia in the left anterior descending

artery distribution.  She does not recall having symptoms at that

time.  Denies palpitations, sweats or shortness of breath with

chest discomfort.  There are some radiation into both shoulders

and neck.  Multiple cardiac risk factors include elevated lipids,

diabetes, hypertension and postmenopausal.



CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Levoxyl 50 mcg q.d., Pravachol 40 mg h.s.,

Prilosec 20 mg q.d., Flexeril 10 mg q.d., Bumex 2 mg q.d., Avapro

150 mg q.d., Verapamil of 240 mg b.i.d. and Glucophage 500 mg two

tabs b.i.d.



DRUG ALLERGIES:  None.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  director/midwife for Iowa Clinic in Temescal Valley.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Denies abdominal pain, change in bowel

habits, fevers, sweats chills, weight loss; otherwise, as above.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She appears in no distress.  Temperature

of 97.8 degrees, BP 130/70 and pulse is 70.  Pupils are equal,

round and reactive.  Conjunctivae clear. Sclerae anicteric. 

Oropharynx benign.  Neck is supple.  No neck vein distention. 

Thyroid is not palpable.  Chest is clear to percussion and

auscultation.  Heart:  Regular rhythm, S1, S2 and no murmur, rub,

thrill or gallop.  Abdomen:  Soft, nontender, active bowel sounds

and no organomegaly.  Extremities:  No clubbing, cyanosis or

edema.  Neurophysiologic:  EKG shows normal sinus rhythm.  No

abnormal complex.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:

1.  Diabetes.  We will check her glycohemoglobin and assure she

has had an ophthalmologic follow up.  Maintain Glucophage.

2.  Elevated cholesterol.  Add Zetia 10 mg q.d.

3.  Chest pain.  Symptoms certainly suggest ischemia.  I have

contacted Dr. Ng in Cardiology and he is arranging for an

ETT MIBI and a cardiology consult.  I prescribed nitroglycerin

1/150 to use sublingual q.5minutes. x 3 for chest

discomfort and she will limit exercise until ETT is accomplished.

 Suspect she might need catheterization and hesitant to add

beta-blocker because of high-dose verapamil and risk of inducing

heart block.

4.  Hypothyroidism:  Adequate replacement dose on current

Levoxyl.  The patient will see me back in four weeks' time and

cardiac workup to be arranged for early next week.











______________________________

E Xochil Higgins, M.D.





Dictated By: E Xochil Higgins





eScription document:8-7850722 EMSSten Tel







DD: 10/02/83

DT: 10/02/83

DV: 10/02/83



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-11-01



Westwing Place Nursing Home

144 Chablis Court                                    GERALD, MARION

Doha, KY 63216                            48967301

(638) 074-1457                                           11/01/83

(449) 515-0294



REASON FOR VISIT:  Follow up coronary disease and diabetes.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:

1.  The patient underwent an angioplasty on 10/07/83 and comes in

today having just had a stress test.  Stress test showed that she

was able to do a standard Bruce protocol for 7 minutes 34 seconds

achieving maximal heart rate of 116, peak blood pressure 122/60,

stopped for fatigue.  Immediately after exercise, she did have

some substernal chest pain, resolved 3 minutes into recovery. 

There were no EKG changes.  The patient reports that she has been

walking and has resumed her normal pre-hospitalization exercise

level and does not have any chest discomfort with walk, which had

precipitated the hospitalization initially.  She is looking into

cardiac rehab program but is not sure that she needs to do this. 

She feels very comfortable with her current exercise regimen. 

She has been careful with her eating and feels she is living a

healthy lifestyle.  She has returned to work.  She has follow up

scheduled with Dr. Schaefer in two days' time.

2.  Diabetes:  At last visit, I had added glyburide 5 mg to her

Glucophage 2000 mg a day.  She monitors blood sugars but only in

the morning.  Evening blood sugars are mostly in 90s to low 100s.

 However, at times during the day, she feels hypoglycemically

sweating and abdominal discomfort.  She has never actually

checked her blood sugar during these episodes as they tend to

occur at work.  She has not had any fainting or dizziness.

3.  Elevated cholesterol, is tolerating Zetia.

4.  Hypertension.  At last visit, we decreased her Avapro dose

because her blood pressure was quite low at 100/64, and

currently, she feels somewhat less fatigued.



CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Glyburide 5 mg q.d., Plavix 75 mg q.d.,

atenolol 50 mg q.d., Zetia 10 mg q.d., levoxyl 50 mcg q.d.,

Prilosec 20 mg q.d., Flexeril 10 mg q.d., Bumex 2 mg q.d.,

Pravachol 20 mg two tablets q.h.s., Avapro 75 mg q.d., Glucophage

500 mg two tablets b.i.d., and enteric-coated aspirin.



DRUG ALLERGIES:  None.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She denies chest pain, palpitation, shortness

of breath, abdominal pain, or joint pain.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She appears in excellent health and in

good spirits.  Weight is 145, blood pressure 120/68, and pulse is

70 and regular.  Conjunctivae are clear.  Sclerae are anicteric. 

Neck is supple.  No neck vein distention.  Chest is clear to

percussion and auscultation.  Heart: Regular rhythm.  S1 and S2. 

No murmur, rub, thrill, or gallop.  Extremities are without

clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:

1.  Coronary disease, doing well, status post recent angioplasty

with stenting.  Maintaining current medications of Dr. Schaefer. 

At this point, I am not sure that she actually does need cardiac

rehab, and we will defer that decision to him.

2.  Diabetes, seems as though her control is 

impressive, perhaps with recent change in her diet.  We will

discontinue the glyburide and follow up in 4 weeks.

3.  Elevated cholesterol.  We will check on lipid status in four

weeks' time.  On current medications with target of LDL less than

100.

4.  Hypertension.  Blood pressure acceptable on current medical

regimen.











______________________________

E Xochil Higgins, M.D.





Dictated By: E Xochil Higgins





eScription document:4-4587137 EMSSten Tel







DD: 11/01/83

DT: 11/01/83

DV: 11/01/83



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-01-10



Chief Complaint

f/u DM, CAD



History of Present Illness

Marion reports feeling quite well.  Saw Dr. Schaefer in mid December c/o dizziness - he lowered doses of Bumex and Avapro, finding her hypotensive.  She has actually continued to take Bumex QD, because she feels her hands get swollen when she doesn't take it.  However, she is no longer feeling dizzy.  Denies chest pain. Physically active: 25" treadmill daily, 10"yoga, 10" aerobics.  Was dancing New Year's Eve.  Has some slight pain L knee.

Monitors blood sugars in am - 120-130 range.  Has decreased glyburide to 2.5 mg qd.  Watching diet. Denies poly sx or hypoglycemia.



Problems

      Diabetes mellitus

      S/P hysterectomy

      Polymyalgia rheumatica

      Coronary artery disease

      Anemia

      Temperomandibular joint disease

      Hypothyroidism

      Hypertension

      Hyperlipidemia

      Gastroesophageal reflux disease

      Fibromyalgia

      Abnormal liver function tests

      S/P cholecystectomy

      Trigger finger



Medications

      Bumex (BUMETANIDE)    1MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Allegra (FEXOFENADINE Hcl)    60MG,  1 Capsule(s)  PO BID

      Nitroglycerin 1/150 (0.4 Mg)    1 TAB SL 

      Glucophage (METFORMIN)    500MG,  2 Tablet(s)  PO BID

      Avapro (IRBESARTAN)    75MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Flexeril (CYCLOBENZAPRINE Hcl)    10MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO qd

      Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE)    20MG,  1 Capsule(s)  PO QD

      Levoxyl (LEVOTHYROXINE Sodium)    50MCG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Zetia (EZETIMIBE)    10MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      ATENOLOL   50MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)

      Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL)    75 MG PO QD x 90 day(s)

      GLYBURIDE   2.5MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN)    40MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Ecotrin (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated)    81MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD



Allergies

      NKDA



Review of Systems

No h/a, dizziness, CP, SOB, palpitations, n/v, abd pain, change in bowels, LE edema.



S/P: Continues working.  Would like to take a dance class if Dr. Schaefer agrees.



Physical Exam

Delightful woman, appears nad  Wt 141  BP 100/62  P 80

C and S clear

No nvd

Chest clear P and A

Cor no m,r,t,g

Abd soft, nt active bs no masses, organomegaly

Ext no c,c,e



Imp:

1.  CAD - No symptoms, quite active. Remains slt hypotensive - rec taking Bumex .5 mg qd since can't tolerate no diuretic for a day.

2.  DM - doing well by home monitoring

3.  Hyperlipidemia - will check FLP in 4 wks, on Zetia

4.  Polypharmacy - reviewed meds w her and she is reluctant to cut back.  I suggested we might stop Flexeril but she is afraid her joint pains would flare.

f/u 3 mos, sooner as needed.





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>