<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2082-10-30

COLIN RAMEY

CHH Unit No:  433-88-47



MISSOURI PACIFIC HOSPITAL



ADULT MEDICINE





Date:  October 30, 2082



78-year-old male who comes in for follow-up of his high blood pressure.  He denies having any chest pain, any shortness of breath, or any difficulty sleeping at night.  His brother-in-law lives with him.  He reports no change in Mr. Ramey at all and no concerns. 



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  



(1)	Mental retardation.

(2)	Hypertension.

(3)	A history of anemia.

(4)	BPH.

(5)	History of peptic ulcer disease diagnosed by upper endoscopy in 2069.



MEDICATIONS:  Hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg q.d. and atenolol 25 mg q.d. 



ALLERGIES TO MEDICATION: None.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  He doesn't smoke.



PHYSICAL EXAM:  Weight 147, unchanged.  Blood pressure 140/70.  Pulse 72.  Lungs clear.  No crackles or wheezing.  Cardiac - Regular rate and rhythm.  S1, S2.  His abdomen is soft, nontender.  Extremities - trace edema at the ankles.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



(1)	Hypertension, which appears to be stable. Continue present regimen.  Will check a potassium, BUN and creatinine.

(2)	History of normocytic anemia.  His last hematocrit in 2080 was at 38, normal MCV.  At his next visit he will need a recheck of this as well as of B12 level. 

(3)	History of borderline sugars, although his glucose today is 105.  

(4)	Routine health maintenance.  Flu vaccine given to his left deltoid IM.  He will need Hemoccult cards at his next visit.  Follow up in 6 months or sooner as needed.





Xavier Combs, M.D.

XC/olivas/finn





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-01-30

COLIN RAMEY

CHH Unit No:  433-88-47



MISSOURI PACIFIC HOSPITAL



ADULT MEDICINE





Date:  January 30, 2083

78-year-old male for follow-up of blood pressure. He continues to live at the home of his sister-in-law's brother who reports complaints of knee discomfort that do affect his ability to walk. He is not using his cane. Regarding his inguinal hernia, Mr. Ramey reports that it is only slightly bothersome infrequently. No chest pain, shortness of breath, or abdominal discomfort. He may have at time some difficulty starting to urinate but does not have nocturia on a regular basis. 



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  

(1)	Mental retardation.

(2)	Hypertension. 

(3)	Anemia.

(4)	BPH. 

(5)	History of peptic ulcer disease diagnosed by upper endoscopy in 2069.



MEDICATIONS:  Hydrochlorothiazide 25 q.d., atenolol 25 q.d. 



ALLERGIES TO MEDICATIONS: None.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  Not smoking.



PHYSICAL EXAM:  Weight is 145, down 2 lb. Blood pressure today is 148/70. Pulse is 76. Lungs are clear. Cardiac - Regular rate and rhythm, S1, S2. Abdomen - Soft, nontender. Inguinal examination reveals a left inguinal hernia reducible, nontender today. Rectal - Prostate symmetrically enlarged 1+ but no specific nodules or masses. Extremities - Knees - There is some tenderness in the medial joint line bilaterally, but no evidence of any effusion or erythema. No ankle edema. 



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  

(1)	Hypertension, stable. Continue present regimen. Will check a potassium level.

(2)	History of anemia. Will recheck CBC as well as a B12 level as his MCV was slightly up at 97. TSH done in November was normal. 

(3)	Osteoarthritis. Advised use of Tylenol 2 tablets Extra-Strength q6 hours as needed. Will get Sissonville VNA to come and see him regarding physical therapy evaluation. He will otherwise follow up in 6 months. 



Xavier Combs, M.D.

XC/olivas/quijano





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-10-14

79 YO  male for f/u of blood pressure.  Patient is now living in Newton House in Blacksburg with Wllie Falk as his coordinator(856 241 8283). Mr. ramey enjoys living there and enjoys the meals.

his only complaint is of left inguinal discomfort which is worse at night. doesn't lift objects but still it is bothersome.





--------------Problems----------



Mental retardation  

Hypertension  

Anemia  

Benign prostatic hypertrophy  

H/O peptic ulcer disease  DX. BY UPPER ENDOSCOPY IN 2069.





--------------Medications----------

ATENOLOL   25MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD  







--------------Allergies----------



HCTZ (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)   HYPONATREMIA





--------------Vital Signs----------

bp 160/80 pulse 60

lungs: clear

cor:RRRs1s2

abd: soft and nontender

left ingunal region there is a bulge about 5 cm.

ext: no edema



a/p

probably inguinal hernia that is symptomatic.  will therefore refer to dr. nunley from surgery for eval.  discussed this with his coordinator.



htn:  add lisinopril 5 mg qd and recheck in three months.





--------------Health Maint----------



Influenza Vaccine   10/14/2083  GIVEN IM TO LEFT DELTOID       

Rectal exam   01/29/2083         

Pneumovax   01/29/2083      Done   

UA-Protein   02/28/80   1+      

HBA1C   10/31/2082   6.00      



_______________________________________

Xavier U. Combs, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-05-05

82 yo male for bp follow up.  no complaints. 

underwent successful turp last month. 

ros: neg for chest pain, cough or shortness of breath.  he does have mild swelling of ankles. 

PROBLEMS



Mental retardation  

Hypertension  

Anemia  

H/O peptic ulcer disease  DX. BY UPPER ENDOSCOPY IN 2069.

Benign prostatic hypertrophy  s/p turp 4/84

Coronary artery disease  ett 12/83: The ECG response to pharmacological stress was  nondiagnostic for ischemia. The myocardial perfusion scans show a moderate size, severe, fixed inferior and inferolateral defect indicative of prior infarct with little if any residual ischemia.





MEDICATIONS



VIOXX (ROFECOXIB)   25MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

PROSCAR (FINASTERIDE)   5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

LISINOPRIL   20MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  





ALLERGIES



HCTZ (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)  HYPONATREMIA  



exam: weight 146

140/60

76

lungs;clear

cor:RRRs1s2 with no gallops

ext; trace ankle edema



a/p:

htn: stable.  check lytes.



cad with mild ankle edema.  will send for cardiac echo to assess ef.  consider adding lasix.   will follow.  otherwise no angina or failure. 



follow up in four months.





____________________________

Xavier U. Combs, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-06-16

83 yo male for f/u of  heart  disease and bp.

he states he is fine and denies any chest pressure, dyspnea or abd pain.  denies any bleeding from stools.

Problems

Mental retardation 

Hypertension 

Anemia 

Benign prostatic hypertrophy : s/p turp 4/84

H/O peptic ulcer disease : DX. BY UPPER ENDOSCOPY IN 2069.

Coronary artery disease : ett 12/83: The ECG response to pharmacological stress was nondiagnostic for ischemia. The myocardial perfusion scans show a moderate size, severe, fixed inferior and inferolateral defect indicative of prior infarct with little if any residual ischemia.

Sick sinus syndrome 





Medications

Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 81MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Imdur (ISOSORBIDE MONONIT.(SR)) 30MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Zocor (SIMVASTATIN) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS

LISINOPRIL 30MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 40MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD

Percocet (OXYCODONE Apap) 325-5, 1 Tablet(s) PO Q8H : one half tab to one tab po q8 hours as needed for pain

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 





Allergies

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) - HYPONATREMIA 





weight:145(up five lbs)

bp:110/50

pulse64

appears well

cor:RRRs1s2

lungs: clear

abd: soft and nontender

ext:  trace edema



a/p:

cad:  no angina or failure but perhaps slightly fluid overload with edema, trace in ankles and   weight up. will increase lasix to 20 mg po bid.   check lytes.  continue all other meds,.



h/o pud:  cont with  nexium.  check cbc.



anemia;  due to gi bleed.  recheck.



htn:  stable. 



bph: stable. nocturia x2



f/u three months. 

Health maintenance

Influenza Vaccine 11/04/2084 

Cholesterol 09/01/2084 155 DESIRABLE: less then 200

Rectal exam 01/29/2083 

Pneumovax 01/29/2083 

Smoking status 01/20/2085 Never a smoker 

UA-Protein 09/23/2084 1+ 

HBA1C 10/31/2082 6.00 

Triglycerides 09/01/2084 77 

Cholesterol-LDL 09/01/2084 95 DESIRABLE: less then 130

Hct (Hematocrit) 01/20/2085 36.3 

Cholesterol-HDL 09/01/2084 45 

Hgb (Hemoglobin) 01/20/2085 11.5 









_____________________________________________

Xavier U. Combs, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>