<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-09-21

MICHAEL NOLAND

FWH Unit No:  233-87-20



MINERAL SPRINGS CLINIC



ADULT MEDICINE





Date:  September 21, 2074



46-year-old male presenting for follow up of his blood pressure. Since his last visit a month ago, he has been exercising, going out for walks every other day, compliant with medications. No new complaints for today. 



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:



(1)	Obesity.

(2)	Hypertension.

(3)	History of glucose intolerance.

(4)	Mild hyperlipidemia.



MEDICATIONS: Lisinopril 40 mg q.d., Procardia XL 90 mg q.d. 



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: Blood pressure today initially 190/108. Subsequently, 170/110. Rest of exam was deferred as he had an exam a month ago. 



ASSESSMENT & PLAN: 



(1)	Hypertension. Outpatient readings support today's reading as the patient as an automatic blood pressure machine. Will add hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg q.d. and come back in 4 days. A recent urinalysis showed 1+ protein. He will come back to check an early AM urinalysis to reassess for presence of protein. Follow up at next visit.

(2)	History of glucose intolerance. However, he had a normal fasting sugar of 104 and a hemoglobin A1C of 6.20. Mean glucose of 121. 

(3)	History of mild hyperlipidemia. However, cholesterol now of 186, HDL 46, LDL 105. Cardiac risk ratio 4.0. Continue with weight loss. 



Quince Ezell, M.D.



QE/mcclain/newsom





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-09-28

Nutrition Clinic Initial Assessment 9/28/76

Problems:  HTN, type 2 DM, class III obesity





Wt: 278#

Ht: 5'6"

BMI: 44.5

Weight History: long Hx obesity  highest bw 285#



Activity Level: ADL's     just began walking per report q other d

Maintenance Calorie Needs: 2,400kcals/d

wt. loss kcals: 1,900kcals/d



Diet History:    

Calories -  

% Protein - 

% Fat - 

% CHO - 



% Sat Fat - 

mg Chol- 

mg Na - 





Labs: HbAIC 8.10% 8/76 

SMBG qd 120-140mg

Assessment: 48 yo class III obese m. w/ HTN, type 2 DM interested in improving bp and wt. Notes w/ past diets difficult to be on b/c some high in Na (atkins he tried) and others not good for DM.  Requests 2,000kcal diet which will comply w/ his med needs.  Also on the road often for work and eats most lunches out.  Recall reveals, he is careful w/ label reading yet some inconsistencies in cho intake and high fat , high Na choices when eating out which is qd.  Reviewed all basics today including meal plan w/ consistent CHO intake, fiber, and lean pro @ each meal



Treatment Plan:

5 small meals/d

consistent CHO intake @ each meal

lean pro w/ each meal

increase fiber goal 20-35g/d

label reading <250 mg Na

<2,400mg/d Na goal

portion control

sat fat <7% kcals

healthful eating out guidelines

regular exercise

Recommended Additional visits:

prn

Educational materials provided:

handouts, written guidelines

Pt Response:                                                                   

Receptive

RTC:

5wks w/ food record

Sampson, MS,RD,LDN





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-06-18

 



NEUROLOGY JUNIOR ADMIT/CONSULT NOTE



CC   slurred speech, L hand tingling



HPI

50 yo RHM  presents after episode of L hand tingling and slurred speech. He was in his usual state of health when he woke up at 8 am. At around 10 am he told his son that he was not feeling well and went to bed. He reports that his speech was normal at that time. At 11:30 his wife called him and his speech was slurred. He was able to say real words but they were slurred and almost unintelligible. He also had L hand tingling. The slurred speech and tingling resolved at 12:15 pm. He denies weakness, diplopia, difficulty swallowing, headache, vertigo, chest pain, palpitations.



One week ago, while he was on vacation in Chincoteague, he had a transient episode of slurred speech. He reports that as he was walking to the bathroom, he suddenly felt lightheaded and fell. He had slurred speech and difficulty standing up but no focal weakness. The episode lasted minutes.



PMH

HTN

hypercholesterolemia

DM

sleep apnea

s/p cholecystectomy

TTE 11/77 - mildly dilated LA, mod LVH, EF 66%



MEDS

ASA 325

Zestril 40

HCTZ 25

Atenolol 100

Hytrin 2 bid

glucophage 1000 

Norvasc 10

Atrovent



ALL	nkda



FAM HX

Parents with hypertension, father with strokes



SOCIAL HX

Married. No smoking.

	

PE

VITALS  P70	BP150/80	O2 sat 98% 2L

GENERAL NAD

HEENT MMM

NECK no bruits

CHEST CTAB

CV RRR no mrg

ABDO soft ND NT

EXT no edema

NEURO

MS:  Alert, oriented. Speech fluent without paraphasic errors. Can name, repeat and follow commands. 



CN:

Pupils equal, round, reactive to light 

Visual fields full to double simultaneous quadrantic visual confrontation.

EOMI s nystagmus

Facial sensation in V1-V3 intact bilaterally to light touch and pin.

Face movement symmetrical.

Hearing intact to fingerrub

No dysphonia. Palate elevates symmetrically.

Tongue and palate midline, no fasciculations.

Shoulder shrug equal bilaterally 5/5.



Motor:	normal bulk and tone, no tremor,  no drift, leads with L arm on orbiting

	Del	Bic	Tri	WE	WF      FE	FF	  IO        HF	 HE	KF	 KE	DF	PF			

L	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	

R	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	

Coord:	normal finger to nose, heel to shin

Sens:	normal light touch, pinprick, vibration

Reflexes: 2+ c downgoing toes

     



LABS

NA        	135       	          	          	          	          

K         	3.1(L)    	          	          	          	          

CL        	99(L)     	          	          	          	          

CO2       	27.5      	          	          	          	          

BUN       	27(H)     	          	          	          	          

CRE       	1.4       	          	          	          	          

GLU       	368(H)    	          	          	          	          



WBC       	11.5(H)   	          	          	          	          

HCT       	42.2      	          	          	          	          

MCV       	84        	          	          	          	          

PLT       	226       	

          	          	          	          

PT        	12.9      	          	          	          	          

PTT       	21.8(L)   	          	          	          	          



STUDIES

Head CT/CTA prelim read negative

MRI prelim read - L insular infarct



A/P

50 yo RHM with 45 minute episode of dysarthria and L hand tingling, now asymptomatic with normal neurologic exam.



1) Neuro

- admit to RDA neurology

- continue ASA

- TTE, Holter

- continue HCTZ, atenolol, Norvasc



2) Renal 

- has Cr 1.4, was on glucophage, received contrast --> will need IVF



3) DM

- SSI, hold glucophage



4) Pulm 

- prn nebs



5) Proph

- nexium, fragmin







Davine Malone, MD 5-4328

Pioneer Neurology Resident





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-09-15



	CARDIOLOGY

	

	FORT WASHINGTON HOSPITAL

	



	Reason for visit:

   consulted by Dr Dunham for continuity of care s/p cabg



	Interval History:

   This 53 yo male was referred with DM and CAD who today underwent CABG and CEA with Dr Dunham. Specifically he had: CABG x 3;  LIMA: Pedicle (IMA) to LAD-Mid Saphenous Vein: Ascending Aorta to Diagonal-2nd Saphenous Vein: Ascending Aorta to Diagonal-3rd; Coronary Endarterectomy.



He was in his USOH until several months ago when he first noticed lower extremity edema and activity intolerance. Symptoms waxed and waned, but eventually progressed so he was experiencing daily SOB and fatigue with usual daily activities such as walking or working around his home, and worsening LE edema up to his knees. He sought evaluation from his PCP 3 weeks ago was and found to have severe cardiomyopathy with LVEF of 25% on stress-MIBI. There was global hypokinesis. Perfusion images suggest a small distal anteroapical scar and moderately dilated LV (both new since 2076). There was no definite evidence of ischemia, although it is noted the patient was unable to achieve 85% MPHR due to poor activity tolerance. 



He was started on Coreg, as well as Lasix which has been uptitrated from 20 to 60mg qd, with subsequent 12-14 lbs weight loss. His lower extremity edema is markedly improved, and activity tolerance is moderately improved. He can perform basic ADLs such as dressing and bathing without difficulty. Walking, especially inclines, climbing stairs, and carrying parcels will cause SOB. He still feels fatigued throughout the day. He has no orthopnea, PND, abdominal distension, early satiety, abdominal pain or anorexia. He reports BPs are much improved with the addition of Coreg, even as they are running 130-150s/80-100. 



	Past medical history:

   1. DCM, diagnosed 7/81. 

2. HTN, long standing, poorly controlled. 

3. DM, onset ~2074. became insulin dependent several months ago. 

a. Retinopathy and cotton wool spot. 

b. No peripheral neuropathy. 

4. Renal insufficiency, creatinine 1.6. 

5. S/P CVA, L putamen, ? cocaine related. 

6. History of cocaine abuse, last reported use 2078. 

7. Obesity. 

8. Sleep apnea, untreated. 

9. Hyperlipidemia. On low dose statin. 



	Family history:

   Father had HTN, stroke age 45. 

Mother had HTN. 

No known coronary artery disease, arrhythmias, SCD, heart failure, cardiomyopathy in immediate family members.



	Social history:

   He is married, with 3 young adult children who are A+W. He was formerly self-employed as a CPA and would often travel worldwide. He stopped doing so after 2075 so has no recent travel out of the country. He is now employed by Applied Industrial Technologies as an accountant. 



Habits: Denies any history of tobacco use. Although he denied illicit drug use, his chart review revealed above noted history of cocaine abuse. He subsequently admitted to prior use, i.e. at parties while traveling. He denies related excessive ETOH use, use of other illicit drugs, or high risk sexual behaviors. He admits to 3 drinks per week currently. 



	Review of systems:

   As detailed in HPI. He has never had chest pain or pressure, palpitations, irregular heartbeat, presyncope, or syncope. He denies having had fever, chills, or acute viral illness preceding onset of symptoms, recent travel out of the country or history of tick bites, hepatitis, or TB. He has no known thyroid problems. Remaining ROS noncontributory. 



Physical examination:

	

-General:   Obese WM, somewhat anxious appearing in NAD. Intubated/sedated

-Skin:   No rashes, nonicteric.

-HEENT:   NC.  No scleral icterus.  MMM.

-Neck:   Short neck.  Carotids +2 bilaterally, no bruits.  JVP assessment difficult due to body habitus, ~ 8-9cm H20. 

-Chest:   Clear to percussion and ausculation. median sternotomy bandaged.

-Cardiac:   RRR; no rub

-Abdomen:   Obese, soft, NTND, no fluid wave.  Unable to appreciate liver edge.  No palpable masses.

-Extremities:   Somewhat cool distal to lower shins, with trace pretibial edema bilaterally. Good femoral pulses, no bruit.  PT pulses intact.  

-Neuro:   sedated



	Assessment and plan:

   53 yom with DM and CAD now immediatey s/p CABG.



At this point routing CABG post-op care; will follow with you. 



As he weans off support would resume his usual regimen of meds. 

	

Sherrill Gaines, MD pager #36466

	

Signed electronically by  Sherrill Gaines, MD

Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>