<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2146-11-02

S: 1. c/o congestion, sinus pressure, green nasal d/c x 1 wk, h/o sinus probs 

    2. c/o nocturia x 3-4 , some daytime polyuria x 2 wks, no h/o DM

     

non smoker, in good health



O: afeb, no resp distress

R frontal and max  sinus tenderness

oro-benign

no adenopathy

chest clear



U/A 2+ glucose , o/w neg

WBG 264

  

A/P:1.sinusitis

           amox 500 TID x 10d :fluids, steam, acetaminophen

      2. new dx NIDDM

           handout given, to call PCP 11/4 





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2147-05-03

S:  66 yo man comes to clinic c/o laryngitis x 2days.  Hurts his L ear when he swallows.  Feels pain along R side of his neck when turning his head.   No cough, chills, sweats.    No wheeze, SOB, chest tightness. No HA, facial pain, earache, sore throat. Throat feels dry.  No fatigue or appetite changes. Non smoker.



Problems

Diabetes mellitus 





Medications



O: Temp 98.6

bp 140/70

HEENT:  PERRL, sclera, TM's w/clr fluid bilat, sinuses nt,  no rhinorrhea, O/P benign: no erythema or exudate, no lad.

Lungs: clr.  RR 16

Heart: reg S1S2, no m/r/g

A/P: URI, prob viral.  Gargles, lozenges, decongestants prn. RTC if sx exacerbate.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2149-01-11

 
MS III Admission Note

Patient:  Eubanks, Larry
MRN:  7744323
DOB:    10/03/2080
Admit Date:  01/10/49
PCP:  Talbert, Nicholas	(783)508-2821
Sources:  Patient, wife, reliable; past medical records from Pennsylvania Hospital

CC:  chest pain

HPI:
Mr. Eubanks is a 68 year-old man with hypertension, mild diabetes mellitus type II, and gout who presents with 2 hours of burning chest pain prominent in the left anterior chest and radiating to both arms and to the center of the back.  

In addition to HTN and DM, Mr. Eubanks    cardiac risk factors include a family history of CAD (brother, sister) and prior history of mild, spontaneously resolving chest pain in early 2147.  He received a cardiac workup for the chest pain including baseline EKG, exercise tolerance test, and Myoview study.  Baseline EKG was unremarkable with normal sinus rhythm but the ETT was positive with inverted T waves, ST segment downsloping depressions in the anterolateral and inferior leads, and PVC   s in recovery.  The patient had no chest pain and good exercise capacity during the ETT, which was terminated after 9 minutes because of leg fatigue.  On the Myoview study, a small area of ischemia with possibly minimal scaring was noted in the inferior wall although wall motion was normal.  Estimated left ventricular ejection fraction was 62%.  A subsequent exercise echo was normal.  Baseline blood pressures at the time of the workup measured 160/68 with systolic pressures noted as high as 180.  His blood pressure has been since controlled on atenolol and was measured per patient account to be around 148/80 at his most recent visit to his PCP in August.  Hemoglobin A1C in 2147 was 6.2 and diabetes has been managed with only diet.   He was previously using daily aspirin but stopped in October 2148 for a dermatologic surgery and did not restart.  

Mr. Eubanks was in his usual state of health until 3 days prior to admission when he developed two episodes of low grade chest pain, once in the morning and once in the evening.  These episodes lasted only 1-2 minutes, and seemed to him to be related to his ongoing issues with gout.  The chest pain was not associated with shortness of breath and seemed to improve with indomethacin, which he typically takes for acute exacerbations of gout.  His course over the next two days was unremarkable and he went to bed comfortable the night prior to admission.  He was awakened near 3 am by 8/10 burning chest pain and pressure in the left anterior chest and radiating to both arms and to the center of his back but not to the neck or jaw.  Associated with the chest pain were chills and a feeling of increased heart rate although the patient denies shortness of breath, sweating, nausea or vomiting, headache, lightheadedness, fever, or vision changes.  The pain persisted for 2 hours without improvement or alleviating factors, prompting the patient to have his wife drive him to BBH ED from his Cheney home.  

Review of systems was positive for polyuria, increased thirst, mild non-productive cough, post-nasal drip, and intermittent mild diarrhea in past months.  The patient denies recent or past history of edema, GERD, claudication, clots, hemoptysis, hematemesis, dyspnea on exertion, orthopnea, paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea, wheezing, fatigue, appetite or weight changes, or night sweats.  

In the emergency department, the patient was given aspirin, lopressor, sublingual nitroglycerin, and 2L O2 by nasal cannula, and chest pain subsequently resolved.  EKG on presentation showed a poor baseline in sinus rhythm with ventricular ectopy.  Subsequent EKG   s revealed continued PVC   s and PAC   s with biphasic T-waves in V4-5.  A chest x-ray was negative for pneumonia or acute CHF and showed no evidence of widened mediastinum.  CT scans with and without contrast which were negative for aortic dissection.  Cardiac enzymes x 2 sets were negative, but D-dimer was elevated at 816.  Stool sample was guiac positive, although CBC was stable with HCT 44.6.  




PMH:  

Hypertension, treated with atenolol
Diabetes mellitus type II, managed with diet
Gout, treated with colchicine and indomethacin
Basal cell carcinoma on right ear, s/p excision in Oct 2148
Recurrent sinusitis

PSH:
Basal cell carcinoma excision, Oct 2148
Nasal septum repair

Meds (on admission):
Atenolol (dose unknown)
Colchicine 5 mg qday
Indomethacin 50 mg prn gout exacerbation

Allergies:  
Allopurinol    hives
Hay fever

FH:  
Patient has relatively poor recollection of his family history.  
Mother:  died at 89 yo, h/o heart disease requiring pacemaker, osteoporosis
Father:  died young of brain tumor
Brother:  died of cardiac arrest March 2147; h/o catheterization with stent
Sister:  probable heart disease
Grandparents:  grandmother lived into 80s

SH:
Non smoker
Occupational exposures (i.e. mold) through work as an economic policy analyst
Social drinker, very mild
Denies IV or other drug use
Denies sick contacts, remarkable travel history
Lives at home with wife; has two children 18, 25
Happy, does not have problems with mood

ROS:  As above in HPI.  Also hearing changes, dizziness, sore throat, neck stiffness, palpitations, dysphagia, diarrhea, constipation, melena, hematachezia, dysuria, hematuria, weakness, leg swelling, easy bruising, bleeding from gums, epistaxis, heat/cold intolerance, changes in mood or sleep habits.

PE:
VS:  		Tm , Tc , HR , BP , RR , O2 Sat 
General:		NAD, lying in bed
Derm:		Small, red, macular spots diffusely on back,  non-tender 
HEENT:	Conjunctivae clear, sclerae anicteric, mucous membranes moist, oropharynx benign, no ptosis.  
	Pupils equal, round, and reactive to light.  Extra-ocular movements intact.  
Oral:	Dentition intact.  Tongue midline.
Neck:	Supple, full range-of-motion, no thyroid enlargement or masses, trachea midline, no lymphadenopathy, carotid pulses 2+ bilaterally and no bruits
Breasts:		No gynecomastia
Chest/Back:	Chest wall  non-tender, Spine non-tender w/o deformity.  No costovertebral-angle tenderness.
Lungs:	Respirations unlabored without accessory muscle use.  Symmetrical bilateral diaphragmatic excursions. Clear to auscultation bilaterally.  
CV:	Regular rate and rhythm with distant S1 and S2.  Physiologically split S2.  Multiple PVC   s detectable.  No murmurs, gallops or rubs.  No heaves, thrusts or thrills.  2+ Carotid pulses. JVP flat.  
Abdomen:	+ bowel sounds, soft, non-tender, non-distended, no rebound or guarding, no hepatosplenomegaly.
Rectal Exam:	Guaiac + stools in ED.  
Extremities:	No cyanosis, clubbing or edema, warm and well-perfused.  No cords or tenderness to palpation.  Negative Homans sign.  2+ radial, femoral, PT and DP pulses bilaterally.  5/5 strength bilaterally in upper and lower extremities.  
Genital:		Deferred.
Musc/skel:	Joints non-focal, full range-of-motion, minimal swelling and erythema in left big toe.  
Neuro:	AOX3 and grossly non-focal.  CN II-XII intact.  Motor and sensory exams unremarkable.  2+ patellar DTR   s.  Negative Babinski.


Labs:
Chemistry (01/10/49 05:39):  Na 141, K 3.7, Cl 103, HCO3 27.3, BUN 19, Cr1.1, 
Glu 159, Ca 9.4, Mg 1.4, PO4 3.5
Hematology (01/10/49 05:39):  WBC 6.2 (59% poly, 30% lymphs), Hct 44.6, Plt 174, MCV 85, RDW 13.5, PT 12.7, PTT 28.1, INR 1.1, D-Dimer 816
U/A (01/10/49 06:54):  pH 5.0, sp grav 1.010, neg WBC, 1+ bld, 1+ prot, neg nitrite. 

Cardiac Enzymes (01/10/49)

          		01/11/49  	01/10/49  	01/10/49  	01/10/49  	01/10/49  
          		00:03     		15:16    	 	08:27     		05:39     		05:36     

NT-BNP    	          		          	    	      		440(T)    	          
CK        	          	          				53(L)     	          	          
CK-MB     	          		Negative  		          	          		Negative  
TROP-I    	          		Negative  		          	          		Negative  
TROP-T    	0.04      	          			0.01      	          	          


Diagnostic Studies:
EKG (01/10/49):    Serial studies.  Normal sinus rhythm with multiple PVC   s, evolving to TWI in V4-V5
CXR (01/10/49):	   No acute CHF or pneumonia.  Subsegmental atelectasis involving the right lower lung.
CT (01/10/49):  With and without contrast.   No evidence of aortic dissection.  5 mm left lower lobe pulmonary nodule, for which three month follow up chest CT is recommended to exclude malignancy.  Choelithiasis without cholecystitis.  Punctate calcification in the left kidney, without evidence for hydroureteralnephrosis, likely vascular, though renal calculus is possible.

Assessment:

Mr. Eubanks is a 68 year-old man with HTN, DM II, and gout, who presents with 2 hours of severe chest pain.  The differential for chest pain is broad and includes cardiac ischemia, myocardial infarction, aortic dissection, pneumothorax, pulmonary embolus, bronchitis, pleurisy, GERD/esophageal spasm, musculoskeletal/chest wall pain, and anxiety.  The sudden onset of severe chest pain, awaking him from sleep, raises the probability of an acute cardiac or pulmonary event such as MI, aortic dissection, or PE.  The patient has elevated D-Dimer but otherwise lacks physical exam findings (dyspnea, pleuritic chest pain, cough, hemoptysis, tachypnea, signs of DVT) or CT/CTA imaging features consistent with pulmonary embolism.  The patient   s HTN is a risk factor for aortic dissection, but this diagnosis can be ruled out by negative CXR and CTA scans, which have 80     95% sensitivity.  In addition, he lacks a number of other clinical manifestations of dissection, including syncope, pulse deficits, and new murmur.  The distribution of the pain is anginal in distribution and is relieved by nitroglycerin + aspirin.  Moreover, the patient has had two similar but less severe attacks a few days ago, and has multiple cardiac risk factors.  This makes unstable angina or myocardial infarction the most likely diagnosis.  
EKG changes lacked ST segment elevation, although T-wave inversions were present in some leads.   The patient   s cardiac enzymes were negative from the ED x 2 sets with a third troponin negative on the floor.  The patient may have either a non-ST elevation MI or unstable angina.  The plan will be to continue monitoring closely for chest pain and EKG changes, with the next step likely to involve stress test or catheterization in the morning tomorrow.  Cardiology is following closely and has provided recommendations that are incorporated into the plan.  


Plan:  

1.  Chest pain
Telemetry, cardiac monitor
Troponin, CK, CK-MB q8h x 3
LDH on next draw
EKG if chest pain reemerges or in AM if no chest pain flare
ASA 325 mg po qd
Metoprolol 37.5 mg PO q8h
Nitroglycerin 0.3 mg 1 tablet prn chest pain
If chest pain continues, enzymes positive, EKG changes    add IV heparin
If chest pain flare, enzymes positive, or EKG changes, consider catheterization.  Otherwise exercise-MIBI in AM.  
NPO except MEDS after midnight; diabetic diet before midnight
Hold AM B-Blocker dose for exercise MIBI
Check in AM for fasting lipids, A1C 

2.  Ventricular Ectopy
Replete K, Mg to meet goals (K = 4.0, Mg = 2.0)

3.  GI bleed
Guiac positive stools
HCT stable 
AM labs:  CBC (HCT),Diff,Lytes,Glucose,BUN/Creatinine,Calcium,Phosphorus,Magnesium

4.  Diabetes
Stable, controlled by diet at home
Blood glucose fingersticks AC + HS
HgA1C in AM
Urinalysis in AM (proteinuria per prior notes)

5. Prophylaxis 
Sennosides
Docusate sodium 

6.  Code Status:  Full Code




The assessment and plan were discussed with the senior teaching resident.



Robert Rich
MS III 
Pager:  #81852

Intern Addendum: I have interviewed and examined the pt with the medical student. In brief, the pt is a 67M w HTN gout and DM who woke up at 3am today with chest pressure and pain that radiated to both arms. He did feel slightly SOB but there was no N, V, diaphoresis or lightheadedness at this time. The episode lasted less than one minute and he felt better after he took indomethacin. Upon further questioning, he thinks he had two similar episodes last week. He has not had any DOE, PND, or LE edema. He does recall having chest pressure and chest pain in Feb 2147 when he had a    cardiac evaluation    at the Pennsylvania Hospital. He does not know the details of the workup. Of note the pt does not smoke, is not on ASA, and has several family members with CAD but no men <55 or women<65. He is on atenolol     but unsure of the dose. 
In the ED, he did have some chest pain but it was relieved after 1 nitro. HR was 85 and BP 135/82. He was given ASA and a BB. Initially, his EKG was read as normal but later the T waves became biphasic in leads V4-6. Repeat EKGs when he was chest pain free, showed flipped Ts in V4-6. There were no old EKGs available for comparison. He was seen by cardiology who recommended holding off on heparin bolus as he was found to be guaiac + (Hct 44). A dissection protocol CT was performed and was neg for dissection and for a central PE. (the ddimer was elevated). His first two sets of cardiac enzymes were negative and he was sent to the floor for further evaluation. On exam, he was in NAD and was CP free. Heart was RRR, lungs CTAB and he had no lower extremity edema. ASA and BB were cont. The third set of cardiac enzymes came back negative and the pt was scheduled for a stress test. However, the patient did experience some chest discomfort this morning and therefore cardiology felt it was best to take him to cath instead. This is planned for this morning. Please note this pt is allergic to Allopurinol. 

V. A. Nunes MD 32043
Internal Medicine Intern



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2149-03-18



	CARDIOLOGY

	

	BETHANY BRETHREN HOSPITAL

	



	Reason for visit:

   Mr. Eubanks is a 68 yo man w/ recently diagnosed CAD s/p LAD stent.



	Interval History:

   Mr Eubanks presents for hospital followup after presenting to BBH in January 2149 w/ after he developed 2 episodes of chest pain lasting 1-2 minutes each and not associated with any symptoms.  On the morning of admission, patient developed more severe chest pain and pressure radiating to both arms and back.  Pain persisted for 2 hours, prompting the patient to present to the BBH ED for further care. In the ED, patient was treated with ASA, metoprolol, sl NTG, and chest pain resolved. EKGs showed biphasic T-waves in V4-5.  CT scan was negative for aortic dissection or other acute pathology.  Cardiac markers were negative.  Patient was admitted to the Internal Medicine service for further management. Of note, at Pennsylvania Hospital, patient had a positive ETTMIBI showing fixed + mild reversible defect in the inferoapical region in 2/47, followed up with normal exercise echo in 5/47.



On first night of admission, patient developed recurrent chest pain when going to the bathroom.  Because of his risk factors for disease, the decision was made to proceed directly to cardiac catheterization. In the cath lab, patient was found to have multivessel CAD with an LAD culprit.  He received 3xCypher stents to the mid and distal LAD with residual flow limitation.  RCA with moderate disease.  LCx with distal disease.  

Patient was transferred to the SDU for further care.He was started on beta-blockers and ace-inhibition, and tolerated these medications well.  He was evaluated for cardiac rehab. Of note, patient was informed of the pulmonary nodule located on CT scan and the need for follow-up CT in 3 months.







	Past medical history:

   CAD as above

HTN

Hyperlipidemia

Gout

DM type 2

GERD

Pulmonary nodule



	Medications (Confirmed):

	

ASA  325 mg po qd

atenolol 

Indocin  50 mg po bid PRN gout flares

Lipitor  80mg po qd

lisinopril 

omeprazole 

Plavix 



Allergies:

	

Drug allergy   Allopurinol led to hives.



	Family history:

   Mother died at 89, had heart disease. Father died young of a brain tumor, Brother with CAD in 40s,Sister with CAD





	Social history:

   Lives in Cheney with wife.  economic assessor. Tobacco - none, Alcohol - occasional, Drugs - none





	Review of systems:

   Otherwise negative in detail



Physical examination:

	

-BMI: 24.2  Normal, low risk

-Pulse: 68  

-resp. rate: 18  

-height: 71  in.

-weight: 173  lbs.

-General:   No acute distress.

-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.

-HEENT:   Unremarkable

-Neck:   Carotids 2+ without bruits. JVP no jugular venous distention.

-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.

-Cardiac:   Left ventricular impulse discrete and nondisplaced. Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2, with no S3 or S4. There were no murmurs, clicks or rubs.

-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.

-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. 2+ femoral pulses without bruits. 2+ pedal pulses.



	EKG:

   NSR 68 w/ occas PVC. PRWP and NSSTTWA.



Selected recent labs:

	 Metabolic

Date     NA       K        CL       CO2      BUN      CRE      GLU      CA       PHOS     MG       

01/12/49 139      3.8      103      26.0     17       1.2      151                        1.6      

01/11/49                                                                9.1      3.4               



Lipid/Thyroid

Date     CHOL     TRIG     HDL      LDL      

01/11/49 139      131      36       77       



Hematology

Date     HCT      WBC      PLT      

01/12/49 40.0     7.9      185      



Urinalysis

Date     UA-GLUC  UA-SPGR  UA-BLD   UA-PH    UA-PROT  UA-NIT   

01/10/49 NEGATIVE 1.010    1+       5.0      1+       NEGATIVE 



Immunology

Date     HGBA1C   

01/11/49 6.60     



other

Date     MEAN-GLU 

01/11/49 134      





	



	Assessment and plan:

   Mr. Eubanks has CAD and had a recent UAP w/o MI admission. He has moderate multivessel CAD and was treated w/ Cypher stent x 3 to the severe stenoses in his mid and distal LAD.  His followup stress test was negative for ischemia and he has an appt at cardiac rehab on 3/29.



Problems:

	



Diabetes mellitus (adult onset).



Hyperlipidemia.



Pulmonary nodule.



Hypertension.



Coronary artery disease.



Changes to Medications this visit

	

lisinopril 10 mg  po qd QTY:30 Refills:11

atenolol 50mg  po qd QTY:30 Refills:11

Lipitor 80mg  po qd End: 03/18/2149 DC reason: Other - Inactivated

Plavix 75mg  po qd QTY:30 Refills:11

omeprazole 20mg  po qd QTY:30 Refills:11

colchicine 0.6 mg  po qd Start: 03/18/2149

ASA 325 mg  po qd

Indocin 50 mg  po bid PRN gout flares Start: 03/18/2149

simvastatin 40mg  po qpm QTY:30 Refills:11 Start: 03/18/2149

	

-Mae S. Naylor, MD pager #76228

Document Status: Preliminary



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2150-09-28

Urology 
Admission Note
 
As per Dr. Nesmith&#8217;s note, detailed below, Mr. Eubanks is a 69 year-old male with nephrolithiasis. He underwent cystoscopy, selective cytologies, bilateral retrograde pyeloureterogram, left ureteroscopy, laser lithotripsy, stone extraction, stent, and bladder biopsies on 9/27/50. Post-operatively he experienced urinary retention and a catheter was placed without difficulty. He was advised he could safely return home, but he was sleepy and his wife expressed distress over looking after the catheter. He was therefore admitted.



History of Present Illness:   69 yo male noted to have a 10mm distal left UVJ stone during an evaluation for gross hematuria.  No history of urinary tract infections and previous stones.



Past Medical History:  CAD - cardiac stents x 3, gout, HTN, hyperlipidemia, GERD, right ear surgery




Medications:  atenolol 50 mg, avapro 300mg, plavix 75 mg,ASA 325 mg, omeprazole 20 mg, colchicine 0.6 mg, simvastatin 20 mg



Allergies: NKDA



Social History:

Married with 2 children

Does not smoke

No alcohol use

Employed in policy making



Family History: 

No history of stones

Mother - died of old age

Father - died of brain tumor

No siblings with cancer



Review of Systems: 

No shortness of breadth

No dizziness

No visual changes

No palpitations

+ Sinusitis

No Seasonal Allergies

No COPD

No Asthma

No Pneumonia

No MI

No MVP or heart valve problems

No peptic ulcer disease

No gastroesophageal reflux

No anemia

No bleeding disorder

No diabetes

No Thyroid problems

No stroke or neurological problems



Genitourinary Review of Systems

+ Kidney stones

No Urinary tract infections



Physical Examination:



Vital Signs:

Well nourished, well-developed

General Examination:

Neck supple

lungs CTAB

Cardiovascular exam RRR

Back/Flank Exam: No costovertebral angle tenderness

Abdomen: soft, NT

Extremities: No calf tenderness or edema

Neurological: walks without assistance 

Skin: Normal Turgor

GU: Catheter in place with fruit punch colored urine.





31-May-2150

Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units

Chemistry Comments               Fasting

Plasma Sodium                    144                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.9              H        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  105                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            29.6                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 9                         (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          9.3                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             23                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.34                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             56                                       mL/min/1.73m2

     Abnormal if &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2. If patient is African-American, multiply the

     result by 1.21.     

Plasma Glucose                   131              H        (70-110)       mg/dl




6/5/2150 PSA 4.29



AbdCTw&amp;w/oConPelCTw&amp;w/oContrst 18-Jun-2150 

REPORT:

     TECHNIQUE:

     CT of the abdomen and pelvis WITH AND WITHOUT intravenous

     contrast.

     

     Scans were continued into the pelvis to evaluate the ureters.

     

     COMPARISON: CT chest dated 7/8/49, CT scan dated 1/10/49

     

     FINDINGS:

     LOWER THORAX: There is a 4 mm subpleural nodule involving the

     lateral segment right middle lobe (series 4, image 3), stable.

     There is a 7-mm nodule involving the periphery of the left lower

     lobe (series 4, image 23), stable.  There is a 6-mm subpleural

     nodule involving the posterior basal segment right lower lobe

     (series 4 and image 49), new from the prior study, but which may

     represent atelectatic changes.  Mild bibasilar dependent changes.

     

     HEPATOBILIARY: The liver demonstrates mildly cirrhotic morphology.

     No focal hepatic lesions.  No biliary ductal dilatation.

     SPLEEN: Mild splenomegaly at 14.6 cm.

     PANCREAS: No focal masses or ductal dilatation.

     

     ADRENALS: No adrenal nodules.

     KIDNEYS/URETERS: No hydronephrosis.  There is a punctate

     nonobstructing intrarenal calculus involving the lower pole of the

     left kidney. There is a 10 x 5 mm ovoid calcification in the

     region of the left distal ureter at the ureterovesicular junction,

     stable since 1/10/49, and consistent with a nonobstructing distal

     ureteral calculus.

     

     There is a 6 mm hypodensity involving the interpolar region of the

     left kidney which is too small characterize.  There is a

     subcentimeter hyperdense focus involving the lower pole the right

     kidney of apparent (series 2, image 32), stable and possibly

     representing a proteinaceous/hemorrhagic cyst.  There is cortical

     scarring involving the upper pole of left kidney and lower pole

     right kidney.

     PELVIC ORGANS/BLADDER: The prostate gland is enlarged.

     

     PERITONEUM / RETROPERITONEUM: No free air or fluid.

     LYMPH NODES: No lymphadenopathy.

     VESSELS: There is mild atherosclerotic calcification involving the

     aorta and its branches.

     

     GI TRACT: No distention or wall thickening.  Scattered sigmoid

     diverticula without evidence of diverticulitis.

     

     BONES AND SOFT TISSUES: There are degenerative changes involving

     the visualized spine.  There are no suspicious lytic or blastic

     lesions.

     

     IMPRESSION:

     Nonobstructing 10 mm distal left ureteral calculus at the

     ureterovesicular junction, unchanged since 1/10/49.  Punctate

     nonobstructing intrarenal calculus involving the lower pole the

     left kidney.

     

     Bilateral pulmonary nodules measuring up to 7 mm, including a 6 mm

     right lower lobe nodule new from the prior study, but which may

     represent atelectatic changes.  A follow-up CT scan chest is

     recommended in 3 months.

     




Impression:   69 yo male s/p cystoscopy, laser lithotripsy, stone removal, and stents with post-op urinary retention.
-         Continue Foley
-         Flomax
-         D/C home


Warda Graham MD, PGY1
Pager 62030




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>