<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2062-02-10

RANKIN GENERAL HOSPITAL
Arthritis Center
39 Autumn Glen Circle                             Rivers, Ida
Brazzaville, UT  33953                             71701456
403-5583                                      2-10-62
 
 
 
1.   Sjogren's.
2.   Diabetes.
 
CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Insulin, estrogens, Tears.
 
HPI:  Is noting a dry cough.  Has noted it over the last couple of 
months.  It has been intermittent.  No fever.
 
Using artificial tears.  Not using Saliva.  Diabetes, she reports, under 
excellent control.  However, is beginning to lose weight.
 
No extraglandular symptoms now.
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Weight 138.  Oral cavity dry.  Neck: supple 
without adenopathy.  Lungs: clear.  Cardiac exam: no murmurs.  Abdomen: 
soft, nontender, without spleen tip.  Joints: no active synovitis.  
Proximal muscle strength normal.
 
ASSESSMENT:
1.   Primary Sjogren's, stable.
2.   Diabetes.
 
PLAN:
1.   Tears and Saliva.
2.   Dietary intake encouraged.
3.   Bone density because she is at risk for osteoporosis.
4.   Calcium and estrogens.
5.   If cough persists, see Primary Physician for chest x-ray.
6.   Follow-up 6 months, but she will call me after bone density to 
     review results.
 
 
 
______________________________
Richard F. Vidal, M.D.                                              
 
VD:IP:7913                                                              
DD:2-10-62                                                              
DT:2-11-62                                                              
DV:2-10-62                                                              
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-06-19











Arthritis Center 				(581) 730-4429
Richard F. Vidal, M.D.


June 19, 2064

Frank Ito, M.D.
Jewish Hospital
61 Church Street
Murfreesboro, UT  97331

RE:  Rivers, Ida 
MRN: 71701456 
DOV: 06/19/64

Dear Dr. Ito,

Ida was seen back today for evaluation of Sjogren's as well as left wrist 
pain.  Her Sjogren's has been reasonably stable.  She still remains with 
difficulty in controlling her blood sugar.  She has continued difficulty with 
her oral cavity.  She has had no extraglandular symptoms -- specifically, 
polyneuropathy, myopathy, or purpura.

She uses artificial tears and saliva.  She remains on insulin and estrogens.

She has a one-week history of pain and swelling of her left wrist.  She was 
seen at the Graduate Hospital Emergency Room several days ago.  Radiographs of the 
wrist show chondrocalcinosis.  She was started on Motrin with some response 
but still has active symptoms.  She is wearing a splint.

Today on exam, she is afebrile.  There was OA involving the DIP joints.  PIPs 
and MCPs were nontender.  The left wrist showed swelling and heat with 
diminished motion.  Right wrist showed full range of motion.  Elbows, 
shoulders, hips, knees, ankles, and feet did not show active synovitis.  
There was no adenopathy and lungs were clear.

I aspirated the left wrist under sterile technique.  No fluid was obtained.  
I injected it with 40 mg of Depo-Medrol.

Clinically, I think she has had pseudogout.  She has chondrocalcinosis on 
radiograph and has a clinical picture consistent with crystal disease.  In 
addition, she has primary Sjogren's.  The two diseases are unrelated.

In addition to injection of her wrist, I switched her from Motrin to Celebrex 
200 mg twice a day due to side effect profile issues.  She should probably 
take that for about five to seven days.  Side effects were reviewed.

I would like to see her back in four months.  She will be returning to you 
for further care in the interim.



Frank Ito, M.D.
RE:  Rivers, Ida 
MRN: 71701456 
Page 2


ADDENDUM:  At her next visit, I will want her to check her calcium and 
thyroid status since that can be associated with CPPD disease.

With best wishes,


 
_______________________________ 
Richard F. Vidal, M.D. 
 
DD: 06/19/64 
DT: 06/22/64 
DV: 06/19/64
/turpin


 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2066-05-20





RANKIN GENERAL HOSPITAL
Arthritis Center
49 Autumn Glen Circle 					Rivers, Ida
Brazzaville, UT  33953 					71701456
(963) 403-5583						05/20/66


1.	Sjogren's.
2.	Diabetes.

HPI:  Is now getting her diabetes care through the HMC.  Very impressed by 
their detail.  Is getting better control for blood sugar.

Is getting physical therapy for her knee where she has internal derangement.  
Is wearing a brace which appears to help her instability.

Noting some discomfort involving her feet.  Has a history of arterial 
insufficiency.

Remains on colchicine 0.6 per day for pseudogout and has had no recurrent 
episodes.

Sjogren's the same, no change in symptoms.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  OA of DIP and PIP joints and thumbs.  No active 
synovitis of MCP joints, wrists, elbows, shoulders, or hips.  Right knee: 
small cool effusion, instability noted, quadriceps laxity noted.  Left knee: 
full motion.  Ankles and feet nontender.  Proximal muscle strength normal.  
Peripheral pulses diminished, particularly left foot, intact right.

ASSESSMENT:  
1.	Sjogren's.
2.	Chondrocalcinosis with probable pseudogout.
3.	Diabetes.
4.	Internal derangement.
5.	Vascular insufficiency.

PLAN:  
1.	Baby aspirin.
2.	Needs Primary Care Doctor.
3.	Quadriceps-strengthening exercises.
4.	Colchicine to block further episodes of pseudogout.
5.	Follow-up six months.



_______________________________
Richard F. Vidal, M.D.

DD: 05/20/66
DT: 05/21/66
DV: 05/20/66
/turpin






****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2066-06-17

SDU JAR Admit Note



Name:	Rivers, Ida	

MR: 468 48 69	

Date of Admission: 06/17/66



Cardiologist: Valdivia



CC: 73 yo woman with h/o Sjogren's syndrome, Diabetes (?Type I), vascular insufficiency who now presents with syncopal episode.

		

HPI:  Ms Rivers was in her USOH until the morning of admission, when she went into the city to buy some buttons and pay a bill at ViewSonic.  She noted that she was not feeling well throughout the morning, and she felt as if she may need to eat something.  However, because she did not have her insulin and blood sugar monitoring equipment, she decided not to eat.  She continued to feel poorly (she is somewhat vague on symptoms but reports feeling that her chest was congested and that she may have had some palpitations and felt chilled).  She saw a police cruiser, and walked over to it with the intention of getting help.  When she arrived, there was no one in the car, and she leaned forward to rest her head on the front of the car.  This is the last thing she remembered; when she awoke, she was surrounded by people.  She was told that she had falled backwards and hit the back of her head.  When EMS found her, she was confused, making repetitive statements, and stating that she had pain in her occiput that radiated down her neck.  When she arrived at the FMH ED, her blood pressure was 213/97 HR 84 RR20 O2 sat 99% RA Temp 97.3.  She received Labetolol 20 iv, Toradol 30 mg iv, ASA 325 mg and Tylenol 1000 mg po x 1.  Her mental status cleared somewhat, and her blood pressure came down to 130s/80s.  She did have one episode of emesis, during which her HR was noted to transiently dip to the 40s (not captured on the monitor); spontaneously recovered to the 60s.

She had a C-spine series and head CT which were negative for acute process, and a CXR which was negative except for R shoulder not well-visualized on CXR.  She was noted to have some superficial bleeding of her posterior scalp, but no obvious laceration.  She was admitted to the SDU because of the episode of bradycardia.



PMH/PSH 

-Diabetes Type I (by her report) followed at Hometown Medical

-Sjogren's disease, followed by Dr Vidal at RGH

-Pseudogout

-s/p benign breast mass resection 11 yrs ago.

-? Peripheral vascular disease?



Meds:  

Insulin: Lantus 9-10 U qhs, Humalog sliding scale.

ASA prn

Colchicine prn



All: 

PCN



SH:  

Lives alone in Las Vegas with her cat.  Her daughter lives in Cheboygan.  Remote h/o smoking, no EtOH or drugs.



FH:	

Unable to obtain



Exam:  	VS:   BP 152/76  HR 77 O2 sat 99-100% RA

	HEENT: posterior occiput with areas of oozing, no laceration or active bleeding, R pupil surgical, L reactive, nonicteric.  EOMI.  OP w/ dry mms, w/o exudates.

	Neck:  	supple, NT, full ROM, no LAD, JVP at 8 cm

	Lungs:  	CTA B

	Cor:  	Regular nml  S1S2, soft 2/6 SEM.

	Abd:  	soft, non-tender, with BS

	Extr:  	wwwp, no c/c, 2+ PP UE/LE, no edema.  R shoulder minimally tender, ROM preserved.

	Neuro: 	AAOX3, MS nl, CN II-XII grossly intact, Motor 5/5 UE/LE, Sensory gross intact. No nystagmus.



	

DATA:	



Sodium (Stat Lab)      139                       135-145        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)   3.9                       3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)    108                       100-108        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)         25.5                      23.0-31.9      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)         17                        8-25           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)  0.8                       0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)     155        H              70-110         mg/dl



Calcium                10.6       H              8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus             2.4        L              2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium              1.6                       1.4-2.0        meq/L

Total Protein          8.1                       6.0-8.3        g/dl

Albumin                3.7                       3.3-5.0        g/dl

Globulin               4.4        H              2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin       0.2                       0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin        0.5                       0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase   125        H              30-100         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT      24                        7-30           U/L

Amylase                58                        3-100          units/L

Lipase                 2.3                       1.3-6.0        U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT      28                        9-32           U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz NEGATIVE                  NEG

Troponin-I             NEGATIVE                  NEG



WBC                    5.2                       4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                    39.5                      36.0-46.0      %

HGB                    12.1                      12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                    5.44       H              4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                    138        L              150-350        th/cumm

MCV                    73         L              80-100         fl

MCH                    22.2       L              26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                   30.5       L              31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                    13.8                      11.5-14.5      %

Superstat PT           11.9                      11.1-13.1      sec

Superstat PT-INR       0.9

  Result Text:

     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.

Superstat APTT         21.1       L              22.1-35.1      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST   RECEIVED

Diff Method            Manual

Poly                   43                        40-70          %

Bands                  3                         0-10           %

Lymphs                 47         H              22-44          %

Monos                  5                         4-11           %

EOS                    1                         0-8            %

Basos                  1                         0-3            %



UA-Specific Gravity    1.010                     1.001-1.035

UA-pH                  7.0                       5.0-9.0

UA-WBC Screen          NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Nitrite             NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Albumin             NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Glucose             2+                        NEG

UA-Ketones             NEGATIVE                  NEG

UA-Occult Blood                                  NEG

 

CXR:  

IMPRESSION:

	1.  No active disease seen in the chest.

	2. Mild degenerative change of the right acromioclavicular joint

	is noted.   Limited evaluation of the shoulder demonstrates no

	other significant abnormality. Dedicated shoulder imaging is

	recommended as clinically indicated.



C-spine films:

IMPRESSION:

	NO EVIDENCE FOR CERVICAL SPINE FRACTURE OR DISLOCATION.

	MULTILEVEL DEGENERATIVE CHANGES, MOST SEVERE AT C5-6 AND C6-7.

	

Head CT:

IMPRESSION:

	No evidence of an acute intracranial process.  Ventricular

	dilatation that may be mildly out of proportion to sulcal

	enlargement.



EKG: 

NSR rate 74, J-point elevation V2

____________________________________________



Impression: 

73 yo woman with h/o Sjogren's disease, ?Type I DM now admitted with syncopal event.  DDx includes hypoglycemia, seizure (unlikely), vasovagal episode, arrythmia or ischemia.



Plan: 	

1.Cardiac

Ischemia: Continue ASA, B blocker as tolerated for elevated BP.  Cycle enzymes, monitor EKG for new changes.

Pump: Echo today to assess function, r/o valvular disease or outflow obstruction.

Rhythm: In NSR, continue on monitor to assess for arrythmia.



2. Respiratory: ED CXR shows no significant pulmonary disease.  



3. Endocrine: will continue her home Lantus and use CZI Regular.  Will need to contact HMC re: her care. If she is Type I diabetic, will need basal insulin.  No evidence of DKA on urine or labs.  Check TSH, Hgbaic.



4.  Rheum: h/o Sjogrens, extent of her disease unclear.  Will contact her rheumatologist at RGH.  Consider dedicated R shoulder xray once rules out to assess for possible fx, particularly if pain persists.



5.  Neuro: imaging negative.  She is slow in her responses; monitor closely for evolving neuro sx.

  

6.  GU: Follow urine output.



7.  ID: Afebrile. Normal WBC



8. Hem: HCT stable.  Follow closely



9. F/E/N: replete magnesium, K prn.



10. Prophylaxis: nexium.







_________________________________

Rose Anaya, MD

Pager #76979









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-01-24





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

FREEPORT MEMORIAL HOSPITAL



History of present illness   Ms Rivers was hospitalized 1/22-1/24/67 after presenting to ER with left shoulder pain that evolved to an ache radiating to her chest and forearm, associated with nausea, diaphoresis, dizziness.  In the ER, the pain was characterized as mechanical, but was also relieved by SLNTG (which however precipitated hypotension, brady to 30s). EKG showed only ? slight exaggeration of baseline 1mm ST elevation in V2, V3.  She was heparinized and admitted to SDU.  R/O by serial markers.  Cardiac cath on the day after admission showed a tight RCA (with unclear relationship to anterior ischemia seen on prior stress). She is now s/p Cypher stent, with plans for at least three months of Plavix.



Other issues:

- HgbA1c drawn during office visit was 11.3.

- UTI, pan-sensitive E. coli



Medications added at discharge included levofloxacin x 3 d, Plavix and MVI.  Med list has been updated to reflect discharge orders below.



AMLODIPINE (NORVASC )  10 MG PO  QD  

COLCHICINE  0.6 MG PO  QD  

ATORVASTATIN (LIPITOR )  10 MG PO  QD  

MULTIVITAMINS (MVI )  1 TAB PO  QD  

ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED (ASA ENTERIC COATED )  325 MG PO  QD  

CLOPIDOGREL (PLAVIX )  75 MG PO  QD  

ATENOLOL  25 MG PO  QD  

LISINOPRIL  40 MG PO  QD  

LEVOFLOXACIN  500 MG PO  QD   x  3 DAYS  

INSULIN GLARGINE (LANTUS )  14 UNITS SC  QHS  <DI>  



Major Problems

Diabetes mellitus

A:

- Per patient, history of type I diabetes - Followed at the Hometown Medical Center, Dr. Abernathy (beginning 4/2066) - On Lantus and a humalog sliding scale (checks her blood sugars at home QID) - Has a podiatrist and an opthalmologist and is followed regularly.  Has dilated eye exam scheduled for 2/67 

- last Hgb A1C 9/66 still elevated 9.70 - last urine microalbumin screen 10/66 negative 

A: - 1/21/67: Pt reports that her AM sugars have been running high.  Her Lantus has been increased by the HMC staff from 9 U to 12 U to 14 U (as of several days ago) 

- 1/23/67 HgbA1c 11.3

P: -1/21/67: q3 month HgbA1c while not meeting treatment goals; remains on Lantus 14 U qHS

- 1/23/67: Pt has f/u appointment at HMC on 1/27.  Will also offer referral to FMH diabetes center for consolidated f/u.

Hypertension

A:

- 7/11/66: Hypertensive on atenolol 25 qd and lisinopril 20 qd when seen by Dr. Olszewski. He recommended the Omron HEM 711 model for home bp monitoring. Has kept a log of blood pressures, and based on the data, her lisinopril was increased to 40 mg qd and HCTZ 12.5 mg qd was added by Dr. Olszewski. - 8/21/66: Most recent measurements showed typical bp's 130-150/70s, HR 60s-70s. 160/90 in office. Didn't want to increase HCTZ until d/w cardiologist - 9/05: electrolytes wnl on HCTZ; HCTZ increased by Dr. Olszewski - 10/17/66: HCTZ d/c'd, amlodipine started at 5 mg given exacerbation of hypercalcemia - 12/12/67: Remained hypertensive.  D/w Dr. Olszewski and increased amlodipine to 10 mg QD - 1/21/67: BP 130/80 with HR 60 today.  Per Dr. Olszewski clinic note from 1/07/67, SBPs at home 129-135 with HR 60s 

- 1/23/67: No significant RAS seen on abdominal aortogram

P: -1/21/67: c/w current regimen: lisinopril 40, norvasc 10, atenolol 25

- 1/24/67: Pt was instructed to schedule post discharge bp check in office

Coronary artery disease

A:

- Risk factors include diabetes mellitus, HTN, remote tobacco, postmenopausal - Adenosine-MIBI 6/08/2066:    ECG response to pharmacological stress was  positive for ischemia. The perfusion images are suggestive of a small area of mild anterior ischemia. - TTE 6/2066: dilated LA, mild to moderate MR, borderline symmetric LVH, no SWMA, EF 71%, moderate TR, RVSP 42 mmHg    -1/21/67: No chest pain or SOB 

- Admitted with left shoulder pain 1/22/67. R/o by markers.  Cath 1/23 showed calcified subtotally occluded RCA which was PCI'd with a CYPHER stent (the vessel was on the smaller side and was co-dominant) as well as OM2 and OM3 disease not intervened on because small territory.  

P: 

- 1/23/67:  Plavix x 3 months added to current regimen of ASA, lipitor, atenolol, lisinopril, amlodipine.  Patient also enrolled in HIT Cath study and will need repeat HIT antibody and platelet draw on d3 and d7 post cath.



Other Problems

Syncope

A; Reports occasional fainting spells since youth.  Had an extensive w/u at SVRHC per patient.  ? diabetic nephropathy versus vasovagal faints.  Has not had recurrence since her last clinic visit in July. - 1/05/67:  Seen by neuro; etiology remains unclear. No significant vascular lesion on 6/66 CTA.  Old CVA suspected based on exam, including diffuse hyperreflexia and facial asymmetry. Lp(a) and homocysteine wnl. - 1/21/67: No further syncope/presyncope, but still concerned about having sustained head injury 

P: Dischaged from FMH with plans for a loop recorder - received a letter from Dr.K. Ivan Olszewski of the Cardiac Unit who saw Ms. Rivers on 7/11/66.  He reports that results of her event monitor revealed no arrhythmias.  He concurs that her episodes sound like they may be related to vagal episodes. 

- 1/05/67:  f/u brain MRI and EEG scheduled by neuro 

- 1/24/67:  Called patient and reviewed that she will need to reschedule her MRI given her new stent (~8 weeks)

Anemia

A:  Appears to have had Hct ~ 35, MCV ~ 73-74 for > 10 years.  Per patient, has thalassemia trait.  Per pt, has had negative colonoscopy. -1/21/67: B12 was wnl 9/66, but iron studies were omitted   

- 1/24/67: Normal iron studies.  MCV 76. Hct~ 34 at d/c from baseline ~ 39.

P:

-1/24/67: f/u repeat labs from HIT study. 

Thrombocytopenia RULE OUT

A:

-1/24/67: Baseline plt count runs low ~120-130 K.  D/c count 102, nadir 97 during admission, which included brief heparinization.

P:

- 1/24/67: F/u results from HIT study

Urinary tract infection STATUS POST

A:

- 1/25/67: > 100,000 pan-sensitive E. coli from 1/23 urine.  U/a from that date with 3-5 WBC, positive nitrite, many bacteria, few squam

P:

- 1/25/67: completing 3-day course of levofloxacin



Active Medications



multivitamins 1 tab po qd QTY:30 Refills:0

levofloxacin 500 mg po qd x3d QTY:3 Refills:0

Plavix 75mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:0

insulin glargine (rdna origin) injection 14 u SC QHS prescribed by hmc

lisinopril 40 mg po qd

atenolol 25 mg po qd

aspirin 81 mg po qd

atorvastatin 10 mg po qd

amlodipine besylate 10mg po qd

colchicine 0.6 mg po qd originally prescribed by dr. vidal, rheumatology



Change in therapies and Renewals

multivitamins 1 tab po qd QTY:30 Refills:0 Start: 1/26/2067

levofloxacin 500 mg po qd x3d QTY:3 Refills:0 Start: 1/26/2067

Plavix 75mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:0 Start: 1/26/2067



Procedures

Percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty STATUS POST Critical proximal RCA stenosis.  1.5x9 mm OpenSail, then 2.0 mm Maverick baloon, then 2.5x23 mm Cypher stent.  TIMI-3 flow achieved.



Selected recent labs     01/24/67 Triglycerides 90, 01/24/67 High Density Lipoprotein 83, 01/24/67 Low Density Lipoprotein 73, 01/22/67 Iron 108, 01/22/67 Iron Binding Capacity 261, 01/22/67 Ferritin 76, 01/24/67 UA-Nitrite NEGATIVE, 01/24/67 UA-SED-WBC >100, 01/24/67 UA-SED-Bacteria Many, 01/23/67 Hemoglobin A1C 11.30 H, 01/24/67 Homocysteine Total 7.9



Signed electronically by   Debra Y Xin MD, PhD  on  Jan 26, 2067     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>