<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-02-22

 
Gregg, Lloyd
2-22-74
 
                             OFFICE NOTE
 
Address:  26 Burrit St, Marlborough, WI 21145
 
First visit for this 51-year-old white male.
 
1.  Gout.  This has been present for 7 years.  Evaluated at Mary by
Dr. Farrar.  Treated with Colchicine.  He cut down the amount of
organ meats and red meat that he had been eating at the time.  He has
not had any alcohol for 11 years.  Strong family history in his father
and all his brothers.  Continues to have 4 or 5 relatively mild flares
a year which are frequently attributable to forgetting to take the
Colchicine.
 
PMH:  Tonsillectomy.  Cervical radiculitis.  He is a recovering
alcoholic.  No alcohol for 11 years.  Hypertension when he was
drinking.  Hidradenitis.  
 
Meds:  Colchicine 0.6 mg q.d.  
 
ALL:  None.
 
FH:  Father died at 57 from an MI.  Mother at 60 in her sleep. 
Brothers have gout, one has hypertension.
 
SH:  Married for the second time.  His wife is Emily Ippolito another
patient of mine.  They will have been married for one year in May. 
He works as a Patternmaker for McCall in Enid.  He averages 1 1/2
packs of cigarettes a day for the last 35 years.  No alcohol.  No drugs
or HIV exposure.
 
ROS:  Bifocals. Slightly decreased hearing in the left ear.  No chest
pain.  Has a chronic AM cough bringing up 1/4 cup of phlegm daily.  He
occasionally plays tennis and bicycles.  He believes his cholesterol
was 170.  Does like high cholesterol food but has cut back because his
wife has a problem.  He uses seat belts.
 
On physical examination he is a very pleasant large white male.  His
weight is 222 lbs., blood pressure 128/88, heart rate 72.  HEENT -
EOMI, PERL, fundi negative.  Cerumen impacted against the TM's.  Benign
oral cavity examination.  No lymphadenopathy or thyromegaly.  Lungs
clear.  No murmurs or gallops.  No hepatosplenomegaly.  No testicular
masses or hernias.  Normal prostate, guaiac negative stool.   Absent
distal pulses.  2+ femoral pulses without any bruits.  1+ reflexes.  No
swelling or tenderness over the first MTP's.  Neurologic exam shows
hearing decreased to watch tick bilaterally.  Air conduction is greater
than bone.  Weber is not lateralized.  
 
Impressions and plans:  1.  Gout.  It sounds like this is really not
much of a problem when he remembers to take the Colchicine.  I
encouraged him to make this a regular habit.  We will check a random
uric acid level.
 
2.  Cardiac risk factors.  He is a male with a very positive family
history who is a smoker.  He has significant cardiac risk factors.  We
spent a long time talking about smoking today.  At his request I gave
him a prescription for Nicoderm patches.  He will start at 21 mg for
six weeks and then move to 14 mg for 2 weeks and 7 mg for 2 weeks.  We
will check a cholesterol and he should be less than 200 given his risk
factors.  I pointed out to him his evidence by history of chronic
bronchitis and of peripheral vascular disease.  I think he found this
sobering.
 
3.  General health.  We discussed exercise, cholesterol and seat belts.
We also discussed the use of Q-Tips which I think may also be a
significant contributing factor to his decreased hearing and the
impaction of cerumen.  I recommended ear drops.  We can have him tested
formally when he becomes interested in intervention.
 
 
 
 
Xzavior C. Welch, M.D.
 
DD: 2-22-74
DT: 02/26/74
DV: 2-22-74
      
XCW/erwin




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-06-13

                           OFFICE NOTE
 
Gregg, Lloyd
MR #657-72-75-7
06/14/80
 
A follow up visit of a 57-year-old white male.  Unfortunately, he
arrived 24 hours late.  
 
He is gradually recovering from a recent flare of his COPD.  This
started with an upper respiratory infection.  He called over the
weekend and was started on prednisone.  He continued to have a
stuttering course over the course of that following week and came
to urgent care the following weekend.  There he was treated with
nebulizers.  He reports that today he was finally able to blow 350
on his peak flow meter.  He is still bringing up lots of junk.  His
gout has been quiescent.  
 
Medications:  Albuterol.  Azmacort.  Colchicine.  Enalapril.  
 
Allergies:  None.
 
Social History:  Married.  His adoption of a 10-year-old girl named
Xiao has been finalized.  He is employed as a sales representative and that
requires a lot of lifting and carrying.  He quit smoking three and
a half years ago.  He drinks no alcohol.
 
Physical Examination:  Looks well.  His weight is 222 pounds.  His
blood pressure is 124/82.  Pulse 76.  HEENT:  EOMI.  No scleral
icterus.  No lymphadenopathy.  His lungs are completely clear
posteriorly and anteriorly.  Distant heart sounds without any
audible murmurs.  Benign abdomen without any hepatomegaly.  No
rectal masses.  Normal prostate.  Guaiac negative stool.  No pedal
edema.  
 
Oxygen saturation on room air is 97 percent.  Peak flow is 320. 
 
Impression: 
1.  COPD.  We discussed this at length.  I think the crucial
component to his treatment will be to anticipate when he is going
to have a flare and responding quickly in a preventative fashion. 
We will have him check his peak flows at the same time every day. 
When he is feeling well his peak flows are always in the 350 range
and he reports that they never go to 300.  When it hits 300 he
should call me or if it is the weekend, he should start immediately
on prednisone 40 mg a day.  
2.  Gout.  Doing well on colchicine.  
3.  Hypertension.  Well controlled.  I will check a creatinine.
4.  General health.  We will check a cholesterol.  His cholesterols
have been good in the past but he has a slightly low HDL.
 
 
 
Gregg, Lloyd
MR #657-72-75-7
06/14/80
page 2
 
Xzavior C. Welch, M.D.
 
 
 
 
DD: 06/14/80
DT: 06/16/80
DV: 06/14/80
 
/ignacio
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-11-29

 

 

 

November 29, 2083

 

Dr. Xzavior Welch

Internal Medicine 

Southside Medical Center

73 Wood St

Palmetto, WI 88933

 

RE: Lloyd Gregg 

    MR#65772757

 

Dear Xzavior, 

 

I had the pleasure of seeing Lloyd Gregg for follow

up of his emphysema.

 

The patient reports that he continues to lead a very

active lifestyle working as a sales representative roughly 10 hours

a day, frequently lifting 60 pound boxes.  When he

returns home from work he cooks dinner and this

combined with his work schedule and picking up his

daughter from school and walking the dog has prohibited

him from a regular exercise program.  Needless to say,

he has remained active.  He is not limited in these

activities by his respiratory function with the

exception of some periodic exacerbation of dyspnea with

heavy lifting.  He uses albuterol during these

instances anywhere between 0 and 2 to 3 times per day. 

His usual peak expiratory flow rate is roughly 300-350

liters per minute.  He knows that when his PEFR falls

to below 250 for 3 days in a row to contact you for

advice as well as burst of prednisone and he has had 1

burst of prednisone since our last visit in April.

 

His medical regimen is notable for Flovent 220

micrograms per puffs, 2 puffs twice a day, Serevent MDI

2 puffs twice a day, Allopurinol, colchicine, Vasotec

and the albuterol as mentioned above. 

 

RE: Lloyd Gregg            -2-  November 29,2083 

    MR#65772757

 

The patient's review of systems is notable for the absence of

fevers, chills, sweats, chest discomfort, symptoms of GERD,

change in his bowel or bladder habits or weight.  He does

continue to have nearly continuous post nasal drip which leads to

frequent clearing of his throat and occasional cough.  There is

no hemoptysis or significant sputum production.

 

On physical exam, he appears well, is in no respiratory distress. 

NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, AS, pink conjunctiva.  TM's are clear with

normal light reflexes bilaterally.  His nasal mucosa is notable

for mild erythema bilaterally with a clear nasal discharge.  No

significant LAN in the cervical or supraclavicular axillary

chains.  Chest exam reveals an increased AP diameter and

prolongation of his expiratory phase.  He has an occasional

expiratory wheeze.  There are no focal findings of consolidation

and air movement is moderate.  No significant JVD and he has a

regular rate and rhythm with an S4, S1, a normally split S2 and

there are no murmurs, rubs or S3.  Abdomen is benign without HSM,

focal tenderness or masses.  His extremities are without

clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  His weight is 223 pounds. 

Temperature 97.1 degrees, pulse 86 per minute, BP 142/82 and his

respiratory rate is 20 with a room air resting oxygen saturation

of 97 percent.

 

My impression is that the patient's severe airflow obstruction

secondary to emphysema is stable on his current medical regimen. 

I once again encouraged him to continue to lead robust and active

life.  We agreed that the current action plan for a burst of

prednisone is appropriate and I also have provided him my contact

information in the event that he cannot reach you in the midst of

a flare.  I have refilled all of his current prescriptions.  To

try and prevent him from requiring these frequent bursts of

prednisone through the winter months, we have also begun

Combivent 2 puffs 4 times a day as well as Nasonex nasal spray to

be used 2 puffs in each nostril once a day.  We talked about

vaccinations and he reported that he has recently received the

influenza vaccine and he has previously received the pneumonia

vaccine.

 

Thank you for allowing me to participate in Mr. Gregg's care. 

He will follow up with us on a routine basis in 6 month's time

but will contact us sooner should he develop more symptoms of a

flare of his COPD.  

RE: Lloyd Gregg            -3-            November 29, 2083 

    MR#65772757

 

With best regards, 

 

 

Thomas Iyer, M.D.

/felder

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-08-25

61 yo man with CAD and PVD referred by Dr. Short for pre-operative evaluation prior to vascular surgery.



He has a long hx of ischemic ulcer of the second toe of the right foot. He was admitted to the vascular service on 8/09 and had an arteriogram that showed complete occlusion of the SFA with reconstitution of the popliteal and single vessel run off. His pre-operative EKG raised the possibility of old ASMI although it was unchanged for a number of years. He underwent dobutamine MIBI which showed a moderate area of severe ischemia in the LAD territory. His LV was normal with EF of 59%. He underwent cath which showed complete occlusion of the LAD with collaterals from a fairly large diagonal that also had a tight stenosis. There were lower grade occlusions in the RCA territory and the LCX. He had been asymptomatic. The LAD lesion was long and totalled and not felt to be amenable to angioplasty. There were no indications to have him undergo CABG so the decision was made to PTCA the diagonal lesion to improve flow to the anterior wall. He tolerated this well. Returns today feeling well and has been active painting his fence and going up and down stairs without any chest pains or unusual SOB. Has had a hematoma in the groin.



MEDICATIONS:  Serevent.  Flovent.  Enalapril.  Colchicine. Alopurinol.

Albuterol.  Viagra.

 

ALLERGIES:  None. 

 

FAMILY HISTORY:  Father died at 57 after his 8th MI.  He had his

first one at age 48.  Mother had a stroke in her early 50s.  His brother, Shields,

died a miserable death with recurrent, inoperable laryngeal cancer.

 

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Married.  Continues to work as a sales representative.  He

has an adopted child, Xiao who is now 14 and doing very well in school. Quit smoking and drinking a number of years ago.

 



ROS: No chest pains. Chronic shortness of breath. No bowel problems. No bladder problems. Does not exercise. Last cholesterol was  175/42.     The rest of the review of systems was negative. 



PE: General: Looks well.

================ Vital signs ================

Blood Pressure:   150/80 142/80   130/78

Pulse:   84   [Regular, Radial]

Weight:   222   [Pounds]

Skin: Chronic ischemic ulcer on the medial aspect of his second toe of the right foot.

HEENT: EOMI. PEERL. No scleral icterus. Bilateral cataracts. Benign pharynx.

Neck: No lymphadenopathy. No thyromegaly. No cartotid bruits.

Lungs: Decreased breath sounds. Wheezes.

Cor: JVP is normal. PMI is not displaced. Heart sounds barely audible No murmurs. No gallops.

Abd: Normal bowel sounds. No hepatomegaly. No splenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness.

He has a small echymosis of the left inguinal area. Bilateral femoral bruits. 1+ right femoral pulse. I cannot palpate the left pulse.

Extremities: No pedal edema. Ulcer as above.



EKG done in the office shows NSR at 74. Axis 90. Normal intervals. He has Q's in V1-V2 c/w possible OASMI. He has low volts in the precordial leads c/w chronic pulmonary disease. No changes from previous.



================ Problems ================

PRE-OP EVALUATION   He has rest ischemia of the toe. He has three vessel coronary disease that is asymptomatic. There are no indications at this time to push for CABG. He underwent angioplasty to try to improve flow to the anterior wall. His EKG suggests OASMI but his ventriculogram is normal without evidence of MI and EF of 59%. There are studies showing increased risk of in-stent thrombosis, MI, death in patients who have had Plavix stopped for non-cardiac surgery within two weeks of stent. He will be beyond the two week period and Dr. Short is willing to operate on him while continuing Plavix and aspirin. I believe he is an acceptable risk for surgery.



PVD   Will need surgery for ischemic ulcer.



COPD   Doing well and is stable. Instructed to use his inhalers faithfully in the preop period.

       

GOUT    No flares this year.

      

HYPERTENSION    Better when rechecked. He gets nervous with the initial measurements.

      

IMPOTENCE         Discussed the fact that, now that he has documented CAD, there is increased risk with Viagra use. He understands that but indicates that he feels that for him personally the benefits outweigh the risks.





______________________________                              



Welch, Xzavior Charles, M.D.



cc: Dr. Farris Short

     Vascular Surgery





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2086-07-11

Yearly visit 63 yo man with PVD and COPD.



If he has to walk a long distance gets an aching pain in the left calf. ABI is .78 on that side. Has been coughing for a month. Yellow sputum. Has not gone on steroids. Every year this happens once. Viagra is working sometimes at 50 sometimes at 100. Apparently bone packing did not have the desired result of his cystic lesion but he tolerates this.



PMH:

He has a long hx of ischemic ulcer of the second toe of the right foot. He was admitted to the vascular service on 8/09/84 and had an arteriogram that showed complete occlusion of the SFA with reconstitution of the popliteal and single vessel run off. His pre-operative EKG raised the possibility of old ASMI although it was unchanged for a number of years. He underwent dobutamine MIBI which showed a moderate area of severe ischemia in the LAD territory. His LV was normal with EF of 59%. He underwent cath which showed complete occlusion of the LAD with collaterals from a fairly large diagonal that also had a tight stenosis. There were lower grade occlusions in the RCA territory and the LCX. He had been asymptomatic. The LAD lesion was long and totalled and not felt to be amenable to angioplasty. There were no indications to have him undergo CABG so the decision was made to PTCA the diagonal lesion to improve flow to the anterior wall. He tolerated this well. 



MEDICATIONS:  Serevent.  Flovent.  Enalapril.  Colchicine. Alopurinol.

Albuterol.  Viagra. Aspirin. 

 

ALLERGIES:  None. 

 

FAMILY HISTORY:  Father died at 57 after his 8th MI.  He had his

first one at age 48.  Mother had a stroke in her early 50s.  His brother, Shields,

died a miserable death with recurrent, inoperable laryngeal cancer.

 

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Married.  Continues to work as a sales prepresentative.  He

has an adopted child, Xiao who is now 15 and doing very well as an honor student. She is going to the Summer Institute for the Gifted. He quit smoking and drinking a number of years ago.

 

ROS: No chest pains. Chronic shortness of breath. No bowel problems. No bladder problems. Off exercise since fracture.  The rest of the review of systems was negative. 



PE: General: Looks well.



================ Vital signs ================

Blood Pressure:   130/70   [Left Arm, Sitting]

Pulse:   78   [Regular, Radial]

Weight:   215   [Pounds]

Skin: No break down.

HEENT: EOMI. PEERL. No retinopathy. No scleral icterus. Benign pharynx.

Neck: No lymphadenopathy. No thyromegaly. No cartotid bruits.

Lungs: Decreased breath sounds. No wheezes.

Cor: JVP is normal. PMI is not displaced. Heart sounds barely audible except in epigastrium. No murmurs. No gallops.

Abd: Normal bowel sounds. No hepatomegaly. No splenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness.

Extremities: No pedal edema. Bounding right femoral pulse. Unable to palpate on the left.

No rectal masses. No prostate nodules. Guaic negative stool.







================ Problems ================

PVD  Stable. F/u with Dr. Tam.



BONE LESION    Stable.



COPD   Coughing x 1 month. Yellow sputum. Put him on levofloxacin.

       

GOUT    No major flares.



HYPERTENSION    Excellent.

      

IMPOTENCE      Better on the Viagra at 100 mg.



GENERAL   Had flex sig in 2082. Colonoscopy in 2087. Check cholesterol and HDL. Check PSA. 

______________________________                              



Welch, Xzavior Charles, M.D.









****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>