<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2091-03-15









CHIEF COMPLAINT:

Cough and followup of diabetes.



SUBJECTIVE:

The patient is a 63-year-old woman with 2-1/2 weeks of dry cough.  It is 

occurring in spasms.  No phlegm.  Her daughter had a bad cold.



Her diabetes has been managed with insulin and oral hypoglycemics.  She takes 

20 units of Humulin, she is not sure what kind in the morning, and she also has 

been taking Glucovance once or twice a day 5/500 mg.  She states that values 

recently have gone around the 200 level at home.



OBJECTIVE:

Unremarkable pharynx.  Normal TMs.  Lungs:  Clear.  Normal heart sounds.  

Benign abdomen.



ASSESSMENT:

1.	Cough, possibly viral syndrome.

2.	Diabetes.



PLAN:

1.	Chest x-ray if not better in 48 hours.

2.	Robitussin A-C, 4 ounces take 5 cc p.o. q.6h. p.r.n..

3.	Refills to be called in for her insulin and Glucovance.









William K. Joslin, M.D., M.P.H.





WKJ/edge

FI:  23755

DD:  03/15/2091

DT:  03/16/2091





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-02-14




Name:  Jennifer Neill
MRN:  4634248


CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Followup of diabetes.

SUBJECTIVE:  Jennifer states that at home her blood sugars by fingerstick 
typically went around 170.  She feels well.  She is not having any chest pains or 
palpitations.  She is followed by cardiology at PMC, Dr. Samantha Noland.  Her 
current medications include atenolol 25 mg p.o. q.d. and Zestril 20 mg p.o. q.d. 
along with Glucovance.  She feels that the atenolol is causing some side effects.

OBJECTIVE:  Appears healthy.  Blood pressure 132/68.  No acute distress.  
Normal JVP.  Lungs clear.  Unremarkable heart sounds.  No peripheral edema.

ASSESSMENT:
1.	Diabetes with suboptimal control.
2.	Hypertension with good control.
3.	Possible side effects on atenolol.

PLAN:
1.	Discontinue atenolol.
2.	Begin Lopressor 25 mg extended release 1 p.o. q.d.
3.	Check glucose and glycohemoglobin and adjust medications as needed.




William K. Joslin, M.D., M.P.H.

WKJ/3454
FI:  813458
DD:  02/14/92
DT:  02/15/92




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-07-22

CARDIOLOGY

PERHAM MERITCARE CLINIC



Reason for visit:

   Ms. Neill came into the emergency room even though she was feeling fine because she insists that she wanted to see me today even though it is not an office day.  She was instructed to come to the office and I was able to see her in between catheterization cases



Interval History:

   Ms. Neill was recently evaluated at Janesville Clinic for her dyspnea.  She was concerned that her dyspnea was related to her lungs and I believe self referred to Janesville for further evaluation.  



She was found by cardiac echo there to have significant decrease in her ejection fraction to 15%.  Previously here last fall her ejection fraction measured 43%.  She had global hypokinesis.



She was hospitalized at Janesville and had an abnormal set of pulmonary function tests showing moderate restrictive disease.  She had some air trapping and was noted to have room air saturation 97% at rest, 94% with exertion.  Lower extremity ultrasound negative for DVT.  d dimer 400 rnage.  BNP elevated at 500.  VQ scan showed possible perfusion defect in the left lower lobe.  Previous CTA in the emergency room had been negative for pulmonary embolus.  Because of continued suspicion about PE she underwent pulmonary arterogram which was unremarkable.  A repeat VQ scan after a normal PA gram showed some persistence in the left lower lobe defect and ultimately it was felt that she did not have evidence of any thromboembolic pulmonary vascular disease.  Of note pulmonary artery pressure was approximately 50 at the time of PA gram.



The patient was commenced on Lasix 20mg.  Her Atenolol was changed to Toprol.



Unfortunately she does not bring with her a complete list of her medications today although she relates that she is taking:

Lasix 20mg

Toprol XL 50mg

ASA 325mg

Zestril 20mg

Lantus 10 units hs

Glucovance 2.5/500mg

Multivitamin



She relates that her dyspnea is better



She is extremely reluctant to undergo Cardiac catheterization at this time despite recommendation on my part.  She would much prefer cardiac echo and if there is improvement, continued medical therapy.





Past medical history:

   1. Diabetes

2. Hypertension

3. Hyperlipidemia

4. Sick Sinus syndrome requiring permanant pacemaker

5. cardiomypathy

6. Minimal CAD by cath 2090



Family history:

   No significant cardiac disease



Social history:

   She and her husband are doing well.  She has retired. Daughter is finished with college and Quarry Worker in the Bristow area.



Review of systems:

   Patinet is improved with regard to exertional tolerance as noted.  Denies edema, PND, orthopnea.  Still has dyspnea with walking flat ground but not until 1-2 blocks.



Physical examination:

-BP: 130/80  

-General appearance:   No acute distress.

-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.

-Heent:   Unremarkable

-Neck:   CVP 8.  No carotid bruits

-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.

-Cardiac:   S1 S2.   No significant murmurs.  PMI normal.

-Abdomen:   Obese, soft, no hepatosplenomegly

-Extremities:   Good pulses, no edema

-Neuro:   Non-focal

-Pulse: 89  



EKG:

   Atrial triggered ventricular pacing with borderline first degree AV block.



Impression:

   Ms. Neill is very reluctant regarding angiography despite a drop in her ejection fraction.



Her evaluation at Janesville Clinic for thromboembolic pulmonary disease was unremarkable.



She was found to have a markedly positive ANA at 1-1280 with a speckled pattern and single stranded DNA postive.  Further markers etc are not available to me at this time.



At this point, repeat cardiac echo at our institution will be obtained.



Depending upon the results I will again approach the patient regarding considering Cardiac catheterization although in truth her pattern in LV dysfunction is more suggestive of recurrent myocarditis/undetermined cardiomyopathy than coronary disease.



In addition, the patient relates that she stopped Lipitor due to myalgia and that she is taking a differrent cholesterol tablet at this time although once again she unable to name the medication.  She relates that she will call our office.



Signed electronically by   Samantha G Noland MD  on  Jul 27, 2094     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-12-11


















 




Neurology Resident ED Consult Note 




Patient Name: Neill, Jennifer K

MRN: 4634248



PCP: Dr William Joslin



Date/Time/Place of Exam/Initial Assessment:   12/11/98, 8 PM, PMC ED.



Reason for Consult: Abnormal speech



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: This is a 71 year-old right-handed woman with multiple medical problems who presents with subacute speech abnormality.  



She was well before going to bed on 12/09/98.  In the morning of 12/10, her husband noticed that she was repeating the same word &#8220;lawyer&#8221; and the rest of her speech was garbled.  Patient subsequently states that she had word-finding difficulties, but denies comprehension problem.  There was no other neurologic complaint per husband.  Of note, she has similar presentation a few years ago.  Over the course of today, her speech has improved but still not back to normal.    



Witnessed onset: No (time last seen normal: before bed on 12/09)

Mode of arrival: walk-in 

Clinical course: improving 

Pre-morbid neurological status: no disability 





There have been no changes in vision or hearing, headaches, neck pain, tinnitus, vertigo, loss of consciousness, weakness, numbness, difficulty with comprehension, speaking, language, swallowing, eating, balance or gait. General review of systems was negative for fevers, chills, rashes, change in weight, energy level or appetite, chest pain, palpitations, shortness of breath, cough, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, bleeding diathesis, and change in bowel or bladder habits (i.e incontinence).





PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: 

-- Diabetes- since 2084

-- Hypertension

-- Hyperlipidemia

-- Peripheral vascular disease

-- AV block requiring permanent pacemaker  

-- cardiomyopathy with BiV ICD
: low EF


MEDICATIONS: 


Amlodipine 5mg QD
 
ASA 81mg QD
 
Lisinopril 20mg BID
 
Simvastatin 20mg QHS
 
Glucovance 2.5/500 2 tab BID
 
Flovent





ALLERGIES: NKDA



SOCIAL HISTORY: The patient lives with husband, has three children, and is a retired interpreter. There is no history of smoking, excessive ETOH intake or illicit drug use.



FAMILY HISTORY: 

Father: died at age 89- "old age"

Mother: died at age 87- Alzeimhers disease

Siblings: 2 siblings with DM



EXAMINATION:



General: Comfortable, in not acute distress, pleasant  



MS:        Alert and fully oriented, attentive, following 2-step cross body command, fluency decreased, naming impaired for low-frequency, calculation intact, reading intact, repetition intact, and praxis intact, no left and right confusion



CN:         VFF, PERRL 5-&gt;2mm, EOM intact without nystagmus, no ptosis, face and palate elevation and shoulder elevation symmetric, notable dysarthria, tongue midline



Motor:   Normal bulk and tone.  No tremor, rigidity, or bradykinesia. No pronator drift.  Full strength throughout



Coord:   Finger-to-nose, and heel-to-shin movements intact..



Reflex:   DTR symmetric throughout.  Toes are down bilaterally



Sens:      Light touch and temperature are decreased below the knees; joint position intact. No evidence of extinction.  



Gait:       Deferred







Labs/Studies:

See LMR



                                                                

Head CT (): 


     CT BRAIN: No definite evidence for acute intracranial pathology.  No 

     hemorrhage, mass lesion or evidence for acute territorial infarction.

      

     Stable chronic infarct involving the left frontal lobe.

      

     CTA HEAD: Occlusion of the distal right intradural vertebral artery 

     after the takeoff of the right PICA.  Normal appearance to the left 

     vertebral artery which courses to become the basal artery without 

     evidence of occlusion or significant stenosis.  The other 

     intracranial arteries demonstrate no evidence of significant stenosis 

     or occluded segment.  No aneurysm is visualized.  

      

     CTA NECK: Moderate stenosis of the proximal right cervical vertebral 

     artery secondary to atherosclerotic disease. The other cervical 

     vessels demonstrate no significant stenosis or dissection.





ASSESSMENT / PLAN:

This 71 year-old right-handed woman with multiple medical problems who presents with subacute impaired speech fluency.  



CT confirms infarct in left frontal lobe, age-undetermined.   The distal right intradural vertebral artery occlusion is likely chronic and incidental finding.  
MRI is contraindicated due to pacemaker



-          Out of the window for acute thrombolytics

-          Hold off on oral intake until swallow evaluation
; D5NS in the meantime
-          Repeat TTE: EF 20-25% in 3/98

-          Consider starting anticoagulation if EF remains poor (pending CMF team decision); continue with ASA for now

-          Rest of the stroke evaluation per CMF team







________________________________

Zyan Conrad, M.D., Ph.D

Neurology (34318)










****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>