<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2085-04-22

 
This patient wants to transfer his care from the McCook Erie Clinic to me. He 
got 
my name from a nurse who works in the hospital.  HE is a 58 year old white 
male retired Transportation Manager with a number of issues.  
1)  He had a cyst or a mass enlarge in his R submental region which was 
excised 
at the McCook Erie Clinic.  Note from his surgeon there said the path showed 
nonkaziating granuloma.  I hope cultures are pending.  The patient does 
volunteer at a homeless shelter so could  certainly be exposed to TB or 
atypical mycobacteria.  
2)  The patient has know mitral valve prolapse, mitral regurgitation followed 
at the MEC by a cardiologist. He had a stress test in the last year that was 
benign. Never had CHF or endocarditis.  
3)  Social situation.  The patient is a sober alcoholic and sober for the 
last 
2 years however he went through divorce probably because of his alcoholism 
10 years ago and took early retirement from Brookdale Metro Systems because 
of his alcoholism. He stays sober by going to meetings and also 
volunteering at the McCook Clinic. He lives with a woman. He has good 
relations with his grown children and his grand children.  His woman friend 
is very supportive and the patient is now feeling good enough about himself 
that he is ready to try and get work full time.  Previous attempts to do so 
have resulted in failure because of his Hx of alcoholism and his premature 
retirement.
 
Family Hx. Father died at age 79 of Altzheimers and some kind of cancer ? 
throat cancer.  His mother had diabetes and coronary artery disease and she 
died of colon cancer. The patient himself had a colonoscopy within the last 
year and it was normal.  One brother and 2 sisters, one of the sisters also 
has mitral valve disease. 
 
Past medical Hx the alcoholism and he was stabbed in the L hand I think in 
2059 and that was repaired. He also had a TNA in childhood. 
 
He has no known allergies to medications.
 
The only medication he takes is Lisinopril 5 mg for blood pressure. He was 
only started on this in the last year. He also takes a vitamin a day.
 
His other significant medical complaint is erectile dysfunction.  He has 
normal libido and good sexual drive however he tends to lose erection after 
he 
has gone for a few minutes.  He can achieve vaginal penetration.  His live in 
lover has been supportive but she would like him to have better performance 
and so would he. He does wake up in the morning frequently with erections. He 
has no known Hx of diabetes.  No prolonged hypertension or vascular disease.  
 
Social Hx.  The patient eats fairly well. He walks usually a mile or so a 
day.  
He does not do any aerobic activity. He does smoke  to a pack a day and has 
for many, many years.  He does wear seat belts when he drives and does not do 
any elicit drugs.  On system review:  Weight stable.  No change in skin. He 
always had a very gravelly voice.  He has had no change in his vision. He is 
very deaf in the L ear.  He has a morning cough no hemoptysis.  Cough is 
about 
a teaspoon of white/gray sputum. He has no dyspnea on exertion.  He has no 
angina.  No palpitations.  No presyncope or syncope.  NO claudication. He has 
no dysphagia. He has no epigastric discomfort.  No change in his bowel 
movements and no rectal bleeding.  He has no claudication.  No edema and no 
joint pains. No headaches and no low back pain.  No long bone pain.  He has 
no 
heat or cold intolerance.  He has no easy bruisability.  
 
PE: shows him to 5'7".  155 lbs.  Skin benign.  Nails do show some early 
clubbing. No cyanosis.  Normal no AV knicking.  Flat disks. Pupils equally 
round and reactive to light and accommodation at 3 mm. Nares normal.  TMs 
normal. Hearing is markedly diminished in the L ear. Head is normal cephalic. 
Thyroid not enlarged.  There is the scar at the site of his excision under 
the 
mandible. No associated adenopathy on either R or L neck or axilla or the 
supraclavicular region.  He is hyperesonant to percussion.  He has distant 
breath sounds. No rales, rhonchi or wheezes. He has normal S1.  Normal S2 and 
holosystolic blowing 2-3/6 mid systolic murmur radiates best to the axilla. 
No 
radiation to the clavicles. No carotid bruits.  Jugular venous pulsation to 7 
sonometers. Abdomen is soft and non tender. There is no enlargement of the 
liver. No adeventitious masses. There is a L inguinal weakness without frank 
hernia.  Phallus uncircumsized. Testes normal. Prostate is a little difficult 
feel because he has a band around the anal sphincter which makes it difficult 
for me to get beyond but I felt probably half of his prostate and it was 
normal and smooth. Stool was guac negative. Reflexes 3+ and equal throughout 
and normal vibratory sense and touch. Normal gait and station.
 
Assessment and Plan:
 
1)  Recent rapidly growing mass under the R mandible showing nonkaziating 
granuloma.  Culture is pending and we will plant a PPD and control early 
next week. I will have him tracked down the report of this from the MEC and 
get culture reports and will get chest x-ray today both for his COPD to 
rule out a cavitary lesion.  
2)  Alcoholism now sober.
3)  Erectile dysfunction try Viagra. He was given appropriate warnings and 
instructions.  I gave him 100 mg # 7.  
4)  Mitral valve prolapse by auscultation followed by cardiologist at the MEC.
5)  We spent a long time talking about smoking cessation.  He has some 
Wellbutrin at home from when he was depressed while getting sober and I 
encouraged him to take 150 b.i.d. and we made a plan for him to try and 
quit.   I will see patient again next week to plant a PPD and then see him 
again in about a month to see how he is doing.  We will certainly check the 
chest x-ray to make sure he did not have active cavitary disease.
 
Leroy X. Oshea, M.D.
 
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-05-27

 
Mr. Ostrander is here for follow-up of his thyroid situation, however due to 
scheduling difficulties he is only having his thyroid uptake and scan 
currently.  He took the tracer and he had his first scan now and the 
testing wont be done until tomorrow.  Thyroid function tests were 
completely normal.  His chest x-ray is completely normal except for 
tracheal deviation I believe which is due to his goida.  I talked to him 
that if the nodule were cold we will need a fine needle aspirate.  I also 
said to him that he made need to see a thyroid specialist.  Though 
slightly anxious he is agreeable to this.
 
He did not bring with him the pathology final report of his lymph node 
biopsy but he was told it was a reaction to an infection and no further 
follow-up or treatment was necessary.
We then talked about smoking cessation and he and his live-in have picked 
a date namely Jun 8th to quit .I tried to give him as much encouragement 
for that as I could.
 
Leroy X. Oshea, M.D.
 
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-02-15


















 
Internal Medicine Admission Note



PATIENT:  Ostrander 


MRN:  7226152

ADMIT DATE:  2/15/2094

ATTENDING:  Justus 

ADMITTING INTERN: Barron

Code status: Full



CC:  SOB

  

HPI:  67 yo m w/ past medical history of mitral valve prolapse, alcoholism, and smoking presents w/ 2 weeks progressive shortness of breath on exertion, PND, lower extremity edema, and orthopnea.  Over the past two weeks, he can no longer walk more than a block, whereas in the past he could walk &gt; 100 yards (and per his daughter, as far as he wanted).  He states that at night he wakes up short of breath and has to dangle his feet off the side of the bed, when he noticed they were quite swollen.  Additionally, he has trouble lying on his back, and has to either lay on his side or prop himself up, which is new.  He does not report any chest pain, or history of MI.  He has had a cough x 1-2 weeks as well.  



In the ED his intial vitals were AF 114/92 117 18 99% RA and he received Tylenol, albuterol, atrovent, a one liter bolus, and furosemide 20 IV x 2, 125 mg IV solumedrol, and his BNP returned at 10,765.  He had a CXR showing cardiomegally and pulmonary edema.   



ROS:  +restless legs x 3-4 days.  



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:  

None



MEDICAL HISTORY: 

+mitral valve prolapse x 35 years

Echo MH 2092 showing dilated LV, mod to severe MR, and EF 65%

ETOH abuse.

Hypertension.

Iron deficiency anemia.

Thyroid nodule.

Pulmonary nodule.

      

SURGICAL HISTORY: 

open reduction and internal fixation of the distal radius and right second metacarpophalangeal joint fracture



ALLERGIES:  NKDA



FAMILY HISTORY: non-contributory



SOCIAL HISTORY: smokes one PPD, 3-4+ 5x per week, last drink 5 days ago 



PHYSICAL EXAM: 

VITALS: 99% 100 142/78 96% 2L       

GEN&#8217;L:      NAD, non-toxic

HEENT:      MMM, no scleral icterus 


NECK:       supple, no LAD. JVP 12 cm w/ hepatojugular reflux no carotid bruits 

HEART:      RRR, normal S1, S2, 4/6 systolic murmur radiating to the axilla

LUNG:       Crackles &#189; way up, lll wheeze



ABD:        Soft, non-tender, non-distended, NABS. No HSM. No masses, rebound.

EXT: 
      wwp, no edema

NEURO:      AO x 3; CN II-XII grossly intact; Motor: 5/5 B UE/LE; sensation grossly intact to light touch, Finger/nose intact,



&#183; Chemistries:   



Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units



Plasma Sodium                    131              L        (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.3                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  95               L        (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            25.2                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 11                        (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          9.0                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       3.9                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        2.2              H        (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             21                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.17                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             &gt;60                                      mL/min/1.73m2

     Abnormal if &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2. If patient is African-American, multiply the

     result by 1.21.

     

Plasma Glucose                   354              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



&#183; Cardiac Enzymes:  



Test Name     MH           MH           MH           MH           MH       

              02/14/94      02/14/94      02/14/94      02/14/94      02/14/94  

              22:38         08:37         08:27         02:06         01:37     



NT-BNP                                                                10765(HT) 

CK            254           237                                                 

CK-MB         6.4           7.1(H)        see detail    Negative                

CKMBRI        2.5           3.0                                                 

TROP-I                                    Negative      Negative                

TROP-T        &lt;0.01         &lt;0.01                                               



&#183; Hematology:  



Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units



WBC                              5.5                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              41.2                      (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              14.2                      (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              4.79                      (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              205                       (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              86                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              29.7                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             34.5                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              14.1                      (11.5-14.5)    %

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED

Diff Method                      Auto

Poly                             87               H        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           10               L        (22-44)        %

Monos                            2                L        (4-11)         %

EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %

Absolute Neuts                   4.77                      (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  0.59             L        (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   0.12             L        (0.2-1.2)      th/mm3

Absolute EOS                     0.04             L        (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.02                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm

Aniso                            None                      (None)

Hypo                             1+               H        (None)

Macrocytes                       None                      (None)

Microcytes                       None                      (None)



&#183; Coags:  



Test Name     MH           MH           FSH           FSH           FSH           FSH       

              02/14/94      02/14/94      04/26/92      11/12/89      11/11/89      11/10/89  

              08:18         01:37         21:57         09:35         07:46         16:30     



PT            16.1(H)       REFUSED(T)    13.3          14.6(*)       15.3(*)       14.1      

PT-INR        1.5           REFUSED(T)    1.0           1.1           1.2(*)        1.1       

PTT           33.1                        30.6(#)       37.1(*)       36.8(*)       34.9      



&#183; Urinalysis:  negative



&#183; Radiology: CXR:  IMPRESSION:

     Mild interstitial pulmonary edema.  Cardiomegaly. 

       

&#183; EKG: Regular rate, sinus rhythm, indeterminate versus right axis. Frequent PVCs, Anterior Q waves, prolonged QT



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN: 66 yo m w/ likely new onset CHF.  Given his exam, I would favor systolic heart failure &gt; diastolic heart failure, although he has features going for both.  Features going for systolic are his widely displaced PMI and the fact that he had a mildly dilated LV on an echo in 2092.



I think he most likely has dilated cardiomyopathy 2/2 mitral regurgitation, which was moderate to severe in 2092.  His murmur is quite impressive.  Another possibility is alcoholic cardiomyopathy.  Ischemia is not out of the question given his age and risk factors. He is also a smoker.  



Another possibility is diastolic failure given his hypertension and likely diabetes.



1.        CHF &#8211; Still quite volume overloaded on exam.  Will give another dose of lasix 40 IV tonight.  Start captopril 6.25 q8 to also control BP.  Repeat echo in the am.  Strict I/Os, fluid restriction, low fat, low salt diet.  If EF is depressed, will start beta blocker, consider aldactone.

2.        Substance abuse &#8211; Will obtain Johnson Rehab consult for alcohol and cigarettes.

3.        HTN &#8211; Poorly controlled, captopril

4.        Elevated blood sugar &#8211; Will obtain fasting BSs and right for sliding scale insulin.  Will obtain HgbA1C

5.        Hyperlipidemia &#8211; LDL 128 in 2090.  Will start statin and check fasting lipid panel in am.

6.        Restless leg syndrome &#8211; Likely 2/2 iron deficiency anemia.  Will replete till ferritin &gt; 50 before treating

7.        Iron deficiency anemia &#8211; Will start iron sulfate, recheck ferritin.



F/E/N:  low salt, low fat/cholesterol diet



PROPHYLAXIS:    GI: none   DVT: fragmin    BOWEL: colace/senna   CODE:  FULL  









____________________

Ivory Barron MD 

PGY-1  Pager # 60809






****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-04-22

EDVISIT^93295529^OSTRANDER, BILL^04/22/95^OXENDINE, LAWRENCE

Seen and evaluated with resident, Dr. Castro.  I have reviewed

her note and assessment and plan, and I agree.  I have seen and

evaluated the patient myself.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 68-year-old

gentleman with past medical history of alcoholism, as well as

depression.  He has had a small-bowel obstruction in the past as

well as CABG x2, PTSD, and high cholesterol, now presenting to

the Emergency Room in the setting of having been separated from

his girlfriend of 15 years secondary to his excessive alcohol use

and drinking very heavily over the last week.  He was found in a

bar intoxicated, and upon EMS arrival stated that he wanted help

with his drinking problem as well as the fact that he was

depressed without any SI or HI.  He is also stating that he has

not taken any food in the last week, just alcohol.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  He is denying any chest pain, shortness of

breath, any nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, any headache or blurred

vision or any fall or trauma.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As above.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  As above.

MEDICATIONS:  He is on unknown medications.

ALLERGIES:  No known allergies.

ALLERGIES:  Current heavy alcohol use.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Does smoke cigarettes, but does not use illicit

drugs.  He is a retired transporation manager, and he was previously

living with his girlfriend, but has now been living alone for the

last week.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  When he presented, he had a heart rate of

65, respiratory rate of 16, BP of 150/79, and saturating 99% on

room air.  He was afebrile at 96.7.  He was alert, interactive,

appropriate, somewhat slurred speech, but gave a good history of

signs and symptoms.  HEENT exam:  He is nonicteric with dry

mucous membranes.  Heart was regular rhythm, no murmurs.  Lungs

were clear to auscultation bilaterally.  Abdomen was soft and

minimally diffusely tender.  He had no evidence of trauma and

pain to palpation in his extremities.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  This is a patient with severe alcohol

abuse, now presenting in the setting of an alcohol binge with no

p.o. food intake.  We did send laboratory studies notable for an

elevated white count of 9 as well as hyponatremia at 124, down

from 135 previously.  Please see the resident note for full

details.  His alcohol level was 277.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  We did treat the patient with IV

fluid as well as D5.  We did give him a p.o. diet here in the

Emergency Department and we monitored him for withdrawal signs. 

In addition, we contacted social work for help with his alcohol

dependence/abuse, and he will be admitted to the Ochsner for

further management of his hyponatremia as well as his alcohol

abuse.  We also treated him with multivitamins.

DIAGNOSES:

1.  Alcohol intoxication

2.  Alcohol dependence

3.  Depression.

4.  Hyponatremia.

______________________________

OXENDINE, LAWRENCE MD

D: 04/22/95

T: 04/22/95

Dictated By: OXENDINE, LAWRENCE

eScription document:1-81539559 HFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>