<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2070-09-14

9/14/70

Ito #1524720



HPI:	

64yo F RH presents with traumatic brain injury s/p being struck by car.  +struck head. +LOC, now recovered.  The patient denies any associated history of weakness, parasthesias, diplopia/blurry vision, loss of visual field, hearing loss/tinnitus, vertigo, nausea/vomiting.  

	

PMH: 	denies

All:	NKDA

Meds: 	denies



Exam: 

Gen: WDWN woman in NAD

HEENT: NC/AT, MMM, OP clear

Neck: Supple, FROM

Neuro:

Alert, responsive.  Oriented to person, place, time. Behavior perseverative, with obvious short-term memory loss, repetitive questions.

Speech fluent, spontaneous.  Comprehension, naming, repetition normal. 



Cranial Nerves: VFFTC, PERL, EOMI, ?mild left NL flattening, TML

Motor: normal bulk and tone, no atrophy, fasciculations, tremor

Moves upper extremities to command, full strength. No drift.

Moves lower extremities to command, full strength

Reflex:	Bi	BR	Knee	Ankle	Babinski

	C5	C6	L3/4	S1	

R	2	2	2	1	down

L	2	2	2	1	down

Sensory: Bilateral upper, lower extremities intact to light touch.



Labs: 	wbc 11.5, hct 42.7, plts 367, coags 12.5/22.8, u/a 3+glu, lytes notable for glu 341, ucg neg 

CT(I-):	4mm left subdural with adjacent SAH



Impression: 64yo female with non-operative traumatic brain injury. Exam consistent with post-concussive symptoms. 



1)	Continue to monitor neurologic exam - CT scan immediately if mental status or neurologic exam changes

2)     Plan for repeat CT scan in AM.

3)	Dilantin load 1g x 1 dose IV, then 100mg PO TID. Continue for 30 days.

4)	Upon discharge, the patient should follow up with Missouri River Manor by calling 418-875-8781 for an appointment in one month with a repeat head CT.

5)	The Hospital De Distrito will follow during this admission.



Case discussed with Dr. Michael Glenn. Thank you for this consult.









____________________

Paul T. Quinby, MD, PhD

NGH Neurosurgery

x13650





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-05-12

Physical exam:



CC:





HPI:  NO SHOW previous times.

66 y/o female with left breast CA, severe Left carotid stenosis, DM, HTM, right foot ulcer, etc. etc., here for follow up.  Has not been seen in a few months. Still smoking "a few cigarretes per day".  States she will quit next week. Scheduled for surgery 5/17/72 for left CEA. coughing a lot especially in AM. No fever.



Denies weight loss or gain, change in appetite, problems sleeping, night sweats, fevers, headaches, visual changes, dysphagia, shortness of breath, orthopnea, PND, chest pain, lower extremity edema, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, blood in stool, black stool, dysuria, nocturia, urinary or fecal incontinence, rashes, change in moles, joint pain, or depressed mood. no vaginal discharge, no pelvic pain, no dyspareunia.  





Problems

Diabetes mellitus type 2 : Not on any meds.

Depression 

Anxiety : Given lorazepam in ER.

sleep disturbance : Insomnia

Smoking : started 40 years ago.

Hypertension 

traumatic brain injury s/p MVA : 9/2070.

Hyperlipidemia 

diabetic foot ulcer on right big toe : Urgent referral to podiatry and put on Keflex.

Proteinuria 

left upper lobe lung nodule : 3 month follow up CT scan scheduled for 2/4/72. 





Medications

Gentamicin SULFATE 1 APPLICATION TRANSDERMAL BID , gentamicin cream, apply to big toe BID 

Panafil OINTMENT (PAPAIN/UREA/CHLOROPHYLLIN COPPER COMPLEX SOD) OINT.(GM) TOP BID , apply to toe bid as directed

Keflex (CEPHALEXIN) 500 MG (500MG CAPSULE take 1) PO BID , #20 BID 

Metformin 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO BID , For diabetes. One pill every 12 hrs.

Lisinopril 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , For high blood pressure. One pill every day in the morning.

Fluoxetine HCL 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , Take one pill per day for two weeks. Thereafter, take two pills per day. 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS , Para el colesterol alto. Tome una pastilla diaria por la noche.

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , Una pastilla diaria con comida. 

Calcium CARBONATE (500 MG ELEMENTAL CA++) 1250 MG PO TID , For osteoporosis. 1 pill with meals 3 times/day.

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 12.5 MG (12.5MG CAPSULE take 1) PO QD , Para la presi  n alta- si se siente muy mareado deje de tomarla y av  sele a su m  dico immediatamente.

Glucotrol (GLIPIZIDE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO BID , For diabetes. One pill twice per day.

Lorazepam 1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1) PO Q12H , One pill every 12 hrs. as needed. 





Allergies

NKA 



FAMILY HX:

No changes.



SOCIAL HX:

No tobacco, alcohol, or drug use.  Denies domestic violence.  Uses seat belts. Lives by herself. Works one day per week at sterling ledet associates.



PE:Vital Signs

Wt 128 lb



BP: 120/70   P-72



GEN: Pleasant female smoker in NAD.

HEENT:  PERRL, no icterus or scleral injection

OP: clear, no erythema or exudate

Neck: supple, no lymph nodes, no thyromegaly, no thyroid nodules, no masses

Lungs: CTA bilaterally

LNs: no cervical lymphadenopathy.

Heart: RRR, no MRG.  Carotids, radial, DP pulses 2+.  + III/VI left carotid bruit. No abdominal bruits.

Abdomen: soft, non-tender, non-distended, BS present, no Masses

Extremities: No C/C/E

Skin: Rigth toe ulcer well healed. + onychomycosis. no rashes, no irregular moles

Neuro: EOMI, CN II-XII intact, UE and LE reflexes 2+ and symmetrical.  FNF, RAM, and walk are normal.  



Labs:

Results

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            

04/28/2072        140            4.3            102            30.7           

                  (135-145)      (3.4-4.8)      (100-108)      (23.0-31.9)    



Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            

04/28/2072        12             0.7            211 (H)        

                  (8-25)         (0.6-1.5)      (70-110)       

01/17/2072                                      190 (H)        

                                                (70-110)       



Date/Time         CA             

04/28/2072        9.3            

                  (8.5-10.5)     



Date/Time         AST/SGOT       ALKP           

04/28/2072        17             81             

                  (9-32)         (30-100)       



Date/Time         HGBA1C         MEAN-GLU       

01/17/2072        9.30 (H)       224            

                  (3.80-6.40)                   



Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            

04/28/2072        8.5            4.42           13.1           40.2           

                  (4.5-11.0)     (4.00-5.20)    (12.0-16.0)    (36.0-46.0)    

01/17/2072        8.1            5.10           15.0           46.1 (H)       

                  (4.5-11.0)     (4.00-5.20)    (12.0-16.0)    (36.0-46.0)    



Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            

04/28/2072        91             29.6           32.6           304            

                  (80-100)       (26.0-34.0)    (31.0-37.0)    (150-350)      

01/17/2072        90             29.4           32.5           319            

                  (80-100)       (26.0-34.0)    (31.0-37.0)    (150-350)      



Date/Time         RDW            

04/28/2072        12.3           

                  (11.5-14.5)    

01/17/2072        11.9           

                  (11.5-14.5)    



Date/Time         METHOD         %NEUT          %LYMPH         %MONO          

01/17/2072        Auto Diff      67             25             3 (L)          

                                 (40-70)        (22-44)        (4-11)         



Date/Time         %EOS           %BASO          

01/17/2072        4              1              

                  (0-8)          (0-3)          



Date/Time         ANEUT          ALYMP          AMONS          AEOSN          

01/17/2072        5.39           2.01           0.28           0.34 (H)       

                  (1.8-7.7)      (1.0-4.8)      (0.2-0.4)      (0.1-0.3)      



Date/Time         ABASOP         

01/17/2072        0.07           

                  (0.0-0.3)      



Date/Time         ANISO          HYPO           MACRO          MICRO          

01/17/2072        None           None           None           None           

                                                                              



Date/Time         ESR            

01/17/2072        20             

                  (1-20)         


Impression and Plan:



1) Ductal Breast CA: Surgery put on hold because of 5/17/72 left CEA.



2) Severe Left carotid stenosis: As above.



3) DM: Uncontrolled in past. Check HbA1c next time.  Would advise tight control while in hospital.  cont. present regimen for now as she does not provide me with any data for BG control.  she did not bring any of her meds or glucometer/log book. She states she will next time.



4) HTN: Controlled. Cont. present regimen.



5) Smoking: Urged cessation again.  Risks and options discussed.



6) PAD: Some evidence of "leg tightening" after walking.  Will refer to vascular lab for work up of PAD in LE.



7) Anxiety: Lorazepam refilled.



8) COPD: Stable.  Advise aggressive pulmonary toilet/support, inhaers perioperatively. 



9) Paperwork for Comcast/utilities filled out and given to pt.



Encounter 45 min. more than 1/2 of it in face to face review of records, education, counseling, coordination of care.

_____________________________________________

Noah K. Quintin-Malone, M.D.











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-04-19

Physical exam:

CC:


HPI:Here for f/u. Doiing "well". 
No hypoglycemic episodes reported. Compliant with tx. Admits to indiscretions with diet.
Not exercising at all. Still smoking.
Recent visit to breast cancer center with Dr. Mitchell.

Denies weight loss, change in appetite, problems sleeping, night sweats, fevers, headaches, visual changes, dysphagia, shortness of breath, orthopnea, PND, cough, chest pain, lower extremity edema, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, blood in stool, black stool, dysuria, nocturia, urinary or fecal incontinence, rashes, change in moles, joint pain, or depressed mood.  no vaginal discharge, no pelvic pain, no dyspareunia.  


Problems
Diabetes mellitus type 2 : Not on any meds.
Depression 
Anxiety : Given lorazepam in ER.
sleep disturbance : Insomnia
Smoking : started 40 years ago.
Hypertension 
traumatic brain injury s/p MVA : 9/2070.
Hyperlipidemia 
diabetic foot ulcer on right big toe : Urgent referral to podiatry and put on Keflex.
Proteinuria 
left upper lobe lung nodule : 3 month follow up CT scan scheduled for 2/4/72.
Noncompliance 
H/O breast cancer : s/p radiation tx, chemotherapy.Left breast T2 N0 MX invasive ductal carcinoma, LVI-, margins -, ER+PR+, HER 2/neu- s/p lumpectomy and SLN mapping.
s/p left carotid endarderectomy 
Onychomycosis 
 

Medications
Panafil OINTMENT (PAPAIN/UREA/CHLOROPHYLLIN COPPER COMPLEX SOD) OINT.(GM) TOP BID , apply to toe bid as directed
Radiagel RADIAGEL TOP TID x 20 days, apply thin layer of gel to treatment area 2-3 times per day
Lorazepam 1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , BC 3025235 One pill every 12 hrs.
Lisinopril 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , For high blood pressure. One pill every day in the morning.
Fluoxetine HCL 20MG TABLET PO two pills QD , take two pills per day. 
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS , Para el colesterol alto. Tome una pastilla diaria por la noche.
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , Una pastilla diaria con comida. 
Glucotrol (GLIPIZIDE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO BID , For diabetes. One pill twice per day.
Calcium CARBONATE (500 MG ELEMENTAL CA++) 1250 MG PO TID , For osteoporosis. 1 pill with meals 3 times/day.
Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 12.5 MG (12.5MG CAPSULE take 1) PO QD , Para la presi  n alta- si se siente muy mareado deje de tomarla y av  sele a su m  dico immediatamente.
Metformin 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO TID , For diabetes. 
Fosamax (ALENDRONATE) 70MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK , Para la osteoporosis. One pill once per week. Must remain upright for at least 30 min. after taking it. If problems swallowing, pain, stomach pain, please let your doctor know.
Arimidex (ANASTROZOLE) 1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 30 days 

Allergies
NKA 


SOCIAL HX:
+ tobacco. No alcohol, or drug use.  Denies domestic violence.  Uses seat belts. 

PE:
Vital Signs
 
BP: 152/80    P-94



GEN: NAD.
HEENT:  no icterus 
Lungs: CTA bilaterally
CV: RRR
Abdomen: soft, non-tender
Extremities: No C/C/E
Skin: no rashes
Neuro: Unchanged. Grossly nonfocal.

Labs:

Results
Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            
03/02/2073        135            4.7            98 (L)         28.2           
                  (135-145)      (3.4-4.8)      (100-108)      (23.0-31.9)    

Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            
03/02/2073        12             0.9            444 (H)        
                  (8-25)         (0.6-1.5)      (70-110)       

Date/Time         CA             TBILI          TP             ALB            
03/02/2073        9.1            0.1            6.5            2.9 (L)        
                  (8.5-10.5)     (0.0-1.0)      (6.0-8.3)      (3.3-5.0)      

Date/Time         GLOB           
03/02/2073        3.6            
                  (2.6-4.1)      

Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          
03/02/2073        46 (H)         51 (H)         90             0.1            
                  (7-30)         (9-32)         (30-100)       (0.0-1.0)      

Date/Time         HGBA1C         MEAN-GLU       
03/02/2073        12.90 (H)      344            
                  (3.80-6.40)                   





Radiology

Exam Number:  0913426                        Report Status:  Final
Type:  MammoBilDigScr
Date/Time:  03/19/2073 11:09
Exam Code:  LLGKRS
Ordering Provider:  NEWTON, QUEEN

HISTORY:  
     routine screening

REPORT
     BILATERAL MAMMOGRAM
     The present study is compared to previous films.
     There are scattered fibroglandular densities.
     There is architectural distortion and skin and trabecular
     thickening involving the left breast that are consistent with post
     treatment changes.  There is no evidence of new or recurrent
     disease.
     No suspicious mass, calcifications or architectural distortion are
     identified in the right breast.  A clip and calcifications are
     noted in the upper outer quadrant from prior benign percutaneous
     biopsy.
     There is no mammographic evidence of malignancy in the right
     breast.
     

IMPRESSION
     Post treatment changes involving the left breast with no evidence
     of new or recurrent disease.
     No mammographic evidence of malignancy in the right breast.
     BI-RADS Category 2 Benign Finding
     
     
RADIOLOGISTS:                           SIGNATURES:
     XI, KATHERINE I                              XI, KATHERINE I
 


Impression and Plan:

1) Uncontrolled DM: A bit improved. Now with premeal values mostly in low 200s. Will increase to 1000 mg qpm since her AM values seem to be higest. Eventually will need to be on maximal doses of metformin (2550 mg qd). Hypoglycemic event management reviewed.
Still with frequent dietary indiscretions, such as eating candy and pizza on regular basis.

2) Diet modification reviewed.

3) HTN/proteinuria: Not optimally controlled. WIll add atenolol for now. Rationale for this reviewed with pt. Cont. ACEI and adjust next time based on microalbumin. Previously referred to renal for eval.

4) Osteoporosis: Stable. Cont. Fosamax. Reviewd proper use-drinking of water and staying upright for at least 30 minutes after taking pill.

5) Smoking: 5 cigs per day per pt. Risks and options discussed. Urged cessation. 

6) H/o breast cancer: Stable. F/u with Queen Newton 9/73 and Dr.Mitchell 12/73.

7) abnormal LFTs: recheck in a couple of months.

8) H/o noncompliance: reviewed in detail with pt. "busy schedule of appts". Urged compliance.

Encounter 40 min. more than 1/2 of it in face to face review of meds, education/counseling about DM management, rationale for medical regimen, HTN, compliance issues, smoking cessation and above.


_____________________________________________
Noah K. Quintin-Malone, M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-01-22



Internal Medicine Intern Admission Note


PATIENT:  ITO, WENDY
MRN:  152 47 20                   
ADMIT DATE:  1/21/2075             TIME:  6pm
ATTENDING: Dr Gerry Baldwin and Dr. Grace Jewell
PCP:  Dr. Noah Quintin-Mcclure   Poinciana, 030-624-6793       
CONTACT:  Verner Ito, (215)638-3640 or (365)775-4811  Son  Gilberto Ito 877-274-0509, Son
Code status: Full Code (discussed with patient and family)
Source: Patient, patient record


CC:  HTN and SOB


HPI: 
Ms. Iot is a 69-year-old female with a history of CHF (EF 40%, no home O2), DM type 2, HTN, nephrotic syndrome, and 1/8/2075 R humerus ORIF presenting from Crest Nursing Home with SOB and HTN. She was discharged from NGH to rehab on 1/8/2075 after ORIF of a right humeral fracture. She feels that she has been doing fairly at rehab. On the evening prior to admission, however, she had some anxiety that resolved after receiving Ativan from her nurse. She then was able to fall asleep but woke-up at 2AM with diaphoresis and SOB. She denied chest pain. She was attended to and her BP was 220/117. She was given 2 SL NTG, O2, and Lasix, after which her SOB somewhat improved but her HTN continued. She also complains of a chronic cough that is productive of white/yellow sputum. She denies missed medications, changes in diet, adding salt to meals (although she is at rehab and her diet order is unclear). At this time, she denies CP, SOB. 


ED COURSE:  
Vitals upon arrival to the ED were T 98.9   HR 114  BP 225/125 RR 32  02 Sat  84% RA. Exam was notable for tachycardia, rales at the apices, use of accessory muscles, and LE edema. Labs were notable for elevated WBC and BNP, non-infected U/A, and evidence of pulmonary edema on CXR. She received Lasix 40mg IV X2, nitoglycerin,  Nitropaste,ASA 81mg, Metformin 500, Simvastatin 40, Losartan 50, Lisinopril 40, Prozac 20, Calcium carbonate, and Lopressor 25.  She produced 700 cc urine. Upon d/c from the ED, BP was 157/72 and O2 sat was 100% on 2L. LENIs were pending.


ROS
General: Positive for diaphoresis and fatigue. no weight loss or gain; no fevers, chills, syncope
HEENT: no visual changes, no hearing changes; no neck pain
Pulmonary: no wheezing, no hemoptysis
Cardiac: Positive for orthopnea. Uses 2 pillow. no chest pain, no palpitations. No PND.
Gastrointestinal: Positive for constipation.  no nausea, vomiting, diarrhea; no jaundice; no abd pain, no GIB
Genitourinary: Positive for inc urinary freq (chronic) but no dysuria, hesitancy, no incontinence; no hematuria
Extremity: lower extremity edema
Neurology: no HA, no photophobia, no changes in strength/sensation; no numbness or tingling; no seizure activity


MEDICAL HISTORY 
1. Diabetes mellitus type 2: Last a1c was 7.90 (10/2074), Last Urine Microalb 283.0 (10/2074)
- C/b renal failure, h/o diabetic foot ulcer
2. Hypertension
3. Hyperlipidemia
4. Ischemic CMP
       -- TTE (3/74) showed EF 40%, LV wall dysfunction
       -- Adenosine MIBI (3/74): fixed anterior/inferior defects and no reversible ischemia or EKG changes
5. Renal failure/Proteinuria: longstanding nephrotic range proteinuria has persisted despite ACE/ARB. Raised concerns about alternate process in addition to DN. Was biopsied on 11/27--biopsy showed nodular diabetid glomerulosclerosis  
              -- Baseline Cr 0.7 to 0.9
6. Traumatic brain injury s/p MV in 9/2070.
7. H/O L Breast cancer: 00664-- T2 N0 MX invasive ductal carcinoma s/p lumpectomy, wide excision,  postop XRT
-- LVI-, margins -, ER+PR+, HER 2/neu- 
8. Left carotid endarderectomy 
9. Left upper lobe lung nodule  
10. Comminuted impacted R humerus surgical neck fx s/p mechanical fall on 12/19
11. Depression
12. Anxiety 
13. Insomnia
14. Onychomycosis


MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:
  1. Acetaminophen W/Codeine 30mg (Tylenol #3 )  1 TAB PO Q6H prn
  2. Magnesium Hydroxide (Milk Of Magnesia)  30 ML PO QD prn constipation
  3. Bisacodyl  5 MG PO QD prn constipation
  4. Multivitamins (Mvi)  1 TAB PO QD
  5. Docusate Sodium (Colace)  200 mg PO QD prn constipation
  6. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Asa)  81 MG PO QD
  7. Anastrozole (Arimidex)   1 MG PO QD
  8. Atenololl   50 MG PO QD
  9. Calcium Carbonate 1250 Mg (500 Mg Elem Ca)   2 TAB PO TID
10. Fluoxetine Hcl  40 MG PO QD
11. Fosamax (Alendronate)   PO QWEEK
12. Hydrochlorothiazide (Hctz)  25 MG PO QD
13. Lisinoprill  40 MG PO QD
14. Losartan  50 MG PO BID
15. Metformin  500 MG PO one tab qAM, 1 qNOON, 2 tabs in evening.
16. Simvastatin  40 MG PO QHS
17. Glipizide (Glucotrol)   5 MG PO BID BEFORE BREAKFAST AND BEFORE SUPPER
18. Acetaminophen  650 MG PO Q4H prn
19. Lorazepam  1 MG PO Q12H


ALLERGIES:  NKDA


FAMILY HISTORY 
Mother: CHF
Father: Prostate and colon cancer
Siblings: none


SOCIAL HISTORY
The patient lives in Poinciana alone but has been in rehab for her humeral fracture. She plans to return home. 5 sons. Retired Electrical Contractor
Tobacco: Quit 1/8/2075. 1PPD since teens
Alcohol: None
Illicit drugs: The patient denies past and present use of illicit drugs.


PHYSICAL EXAM
VITALS:  Tcurrent: 97.3    HR:   62      BP: 155/67      RR:  16      O2Sat: 92% 4L NC
GEN&#8217;L        NAD, Non-toxic appearing, AO x 3
HEENT      NCAT. PEERLA. EOMI. 
NECK         Supple, no thyromegaly or LAD. Carotids are 2+ bilaterally without bruits.  JVP 10cm
HEART     RRR. Normal S1, S2. No m/r/g
LUNG       Rhonchi and crackles at bases bilat. No wheeze. 
BACK        Normal spine curvature. No paraspinal tenderness. No CVA tenderness.
ABD:           Soft, non-tender, non-distended. Active BS.
EXT           WWP distally. 2+ pitting edema to thighs.  
NEURO:    Alert. Oriented to person, place, time. CN II-XII grossly intact.  Sensation grossly intact to light touch and vibration. 
 
CHEMISTRIES
21-Jan-2075 03:59  
Plasma Sodium                    136                       
Plasma Potassium                 4.3                       
Plasma Chloride                  98               L        
Plasma Carbon Dioxide            32.4             H        
Calcium                          9.4                       
Phosphorus                       3.9                       
Magnesium                        2.2              H        
Plasma Urea Nitrogen             20                        
Plasma Creatinine                0.9                       
Plasma Glucose                   297              H        
NT-proBNP                        8924             H   3900 in 3/2074   
 
CARDIAC ENZYMES
21-Jan-2075 04:33  and 11:00 AM
Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       NEGATIVE   x2 at 4AM and 11AM
Troponin-I                       NEGATIVE   X2 at 4AM and 11AM
HEMATOLOGY
21-Jan-2075 03:59  
WBC                              21.3            H        
HCT                              41.9                      
HGB                              13.0                      
RBC                              4.36                      
PLT                              659              H        
MCV                              96                        
MCH                              29.9                      
MCHC                             31.1                      
RDW                              12.6                      
Superstat PT                     11.7                      
Superstat PT-INR                 1.0
Superstat APTT                   24.4                      
Diff Method                      Auto
Poly                             80               H        
Lymphs                           13               L        
Monos                            4                         
EOS                              2                         
Basos                            1                         
Absolute Neuts                   16.96            H        
Absolute Lymphs                  2.83                      
Absolute Monos                   0.89             H        
Absolute EOS                     0.48             H        
Absolute Basos                   0.12                      
Aniso                            None                      
Hypo                             1+               H        
Macrocytes                       None                      
Microcytes                       None                      


URINALYSIS
21-Jan-2075 05:37  
UA-Color                         Yellow                   
UA-Turbidity                     Clear                    
UA-Specific Gravity              1.020                    
UA-pH                            7.0                     
UA-WBC Screen                    NEGATIVE                 
UA-Nitrite                       NEGATIVE                 
UA-Glucose                       Trace                    
UA-Ketones                       NEGATIVE                 
Urobilinogen                     NEGATIVE                 
Bili                             NEGATIVE                 
UA-Occult Blood                  2+                       
UA-SED-RBC                       20-50                     
UA-SED-WBC                       0-2                       
UA-SED-Bacteria                  NEGATIVE                  
Hyaline Cast                     3-5                       
Squamous Cells                   NEGATIVE                  
UA-Albumin                       3+                        


MICROBIOLOGY: None


RADIOLOGY
1. CXR: Lungs:  The lungs are satisfactorily inflated. There is increasing
prominence of the interstitium and peribronchial cuffing when compared to the prior study consistent with interval development of CHF.  Surgical clips are again noted projected over the left lower hemithorax.  No definite focal consolidation is demonstrated. Pleura:  There is no pneumothorax. The hemidiaphragms are very slightly less distinct than on the comparison study.  This could be related to the onset of parenchymal changes of CHF, but could also be related to a small amount of pleural fluid. IMPRESSION: Findings consistent with CHF.


2. Bilateral LENIs: NO EVIDENCE OF FEMORAL OR POPLITEAL DEEP VENOUS THROMBOSIS OF
EITHER LEG.


EKG: Normal sinus rhythm at 95. Normal axis. Normal PR, QRS, QT intervals. No ST elevations or depressions.  ? Q waves in v1, v2, v3 but also may be upslopes before the downslops. However new since 12/12/2074




ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN


Mrs. Ito is a 69F with a history of CHF (EF 40%, no home O2), DM type 2, HTN, nephritic syndrome, and 1/15/2075 R humerus ORIF presenting from Crest Nursing Home with SOB and HTN. Her exam and imaging is consistent with pulmonary edema, as she has had in the past. The precipitant of her flash pulmonary edema is less clear, however. She describes waking up acutely short of breath and was found to be profoundly hypertensive. It is possible that HTN 2/2 a change in her diet or fluid intake at rehab, ischemia, increases renin-aldo, or other cause led to flash pulmonary edema.  Conversely, however, CHF may have precipitated her HTN.
 
1. Shortness of breath/CHF: Evidence of volume overload by exam and imaging. PE also on the differential but seems less likely given improvement of resp status, negative LENIs. 
-- Lasix 40mg IV now 
-- Strict I+O
-- Daily weights
-- F/up PA/Lat
-- Continuous O2 sat monitor;Telemetry, cardiac monitor
-- f/up cardiac enzymes
-- ASA 325 qd
-- Will give Lopressor 25 Q8 and Captopril 50 Q8 for now but may need to reconsider the BB if CHF less compensated. 
-- Albuterol and atrovent for possible COPD component given tobacco history
-- Consider TTE in AM
-- Consider PFTs


2. Leukocytosis: Infection vs stress response. Patient presents with elevated WBC with 80% polys. Infectious work-up has included U/A that is negative for infection. CXR does not show evidence of focal consolidation, however may be obscured by pulmonary edema. Mental status at baseline. I am suspicious for PNA given her report of productive cough howeve do not feel pressed to treat at this time as she is afeb. 
-- Cont to follow fever curve and WBC
-- F/up PA/Lat
-- Consider addition of abx for HAP if fever, PA/lat concerning
-- F/up Blood cultures and sputum cultures
-- F/up c diff


3. Hypertension: Home HTN regimen is Atenolol 50mg QD, HCTZ 25 qday, Lisinopril 40 qday, Losartan 50 BID
-- Start Captoril 50 mg Q8 and Lopressor 25 q8 and titrate up as needed fo tight BP control 
-- Cardiac monitor


4. DM type 2: Home regimen is Metformin/Glucotrol. 
-- D/c oral agents and start Insulin SS w BID BS


5. Hematuria/Proteinuria on U/A: Consisent with prior U/A


6. Breast CA: Cont Arimidex (hormone tx)


7. HL: Cont statin


8. Depression: Cont Prozac


9. Tobacco use: Cont Chantix 0.5 mg PO QDay


10. Anxiety: Ativan PRN at home. 
 
11. FEN:  Low chol, low sat fat, ADA diet with no added salt. Cont Vit D/ Calcium
 
12. PROPHYLAXIS:
GI:  Not indicated    DVT: Heparin 5000 Units SC BID    BOWEL:  Colace/Senna PRN


13. CODE STATUS:   Full Code       (Discussed with patient)


__________________________________
Jocelyn T Issa MD, Mphil
Pager #61158



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-10-04


Referring Physician: Dr. Vernell-Paul
Surgical Oncologist: Dr. George Fletcher
Radiation Oncologist: Dr. Leonard Uranga


Cell Son George 877-274-0509 


ID:  T2 N 0 M X, ER/PR + Her 2 Neu negative left invasive ductal carcinoma


Reason for visit: Monitoring of adjuvant endocrine therapy for breast cancer


Initial Oncologic History:  
Ms. Ito first palpated a left breast lump in 2070. Two years later she was seen by her PCP and referred to surgery. In March '72 a mammogram showed a 1.6 cm left breast mass at 12 o'clock, also evident on ultrasonography. An additional group of indeterminate microcalcifications was noted in the upper outer quadrant of the right breast. 
On 3/22/72 a biopsy of the left breast mass confirmed invasive ductal carcinoma. Stereotactic core biopsy of the upper outer quadrant calcifications showed only fibrocystic changes. On 5/31/72 she underwent a L lumpectomy with sentinel node biopsy.  Pathology revealed a 2.0 x 2.5 x 2.3cm invasive ductal carcinoma, grade 3,  with negative margins, ER+PR+Her2neu-, sentinel node negative. She was then referred to multidisciplinary clinic and received a recommendation for whole breast irradiation and adjuvant endocrine therapy.


INTERVAL HISTORY:  
Returns to see us for regular 6 month follow up. She had follow up chest imaging with her PCP which did not show evidence of pna. She is happy to hear this. She reports she is doing well at home. Son agrees. He is in the process of remodeling her home so it is handicap accessible. She can dress herself and wash herself. No new breast symptoms, pain or other concerns today.
Mammogram due this month, this is booked. She takes the arimidex daily and has noted no untoward effects.


FAMILY HISTORY:  
Negative for breast and ovarian cancer


OB-GYN: 
She is a G6, P6 who underwent menopause at age 42.


PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  
Diabetes mellitus type 2 
Depression/Anxiety
Sleep disturbance 
Hypertension 
Traumatic brain injury s/p MVA : 9/2070.
Hyperlipidemia 
Diabetic foot ulcer on right big toe 
Renal failure-Proteinuria 
Congestive heart failure : EF 40 % 3/74
renal failure 11/2074 bx showed nodular diabetic glomerulosclerosis

LUL nodule

Osteoporosis


Pneumonia 11/76


PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:s/p left carotid endarderectomy 
S/p lumpectomy and SNB
 S/p appendectomy
S/P Tonsillectomy
R humerus  displaced fx, treated with  ORIF 1/8/2075


Medications
Amlodipine 5 MG (5MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD
Arimidex (ANASTROZOLE) 1 MG (1MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD
Atenolol 50 MG (25MG TABLET Take 2) PO QD
Atrovent Nasal 0.03% (IPRATROPIUM Nasal 0.03%) 2 SPRAY NAS BID PRN 
Calcium 600mg + Vitamin D(400IU) 1 TAB PO tid
Fluoxetine Hcl 40 MG (20MG CAPSULE Take 2) PO two pills QD
Fosamax (ALENDRONATE) 70MG TABLET Take 1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK
Furosemide 80 MG (40MG TABLET Take 2) PO QD
Glucotrol (GLIPIZIDE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID
Lisinopril 40 MG (40MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD
Lorazepam 1 MG (1MG TABLET Take 1) PO as directed PRN 
Metformin 500 MG (500MG TABLET Take 1) PO one tab qAM, 1 qNOON, 2 tabs in evening.
Multivitamins 1 TAB PO QD
Omeprazole 20 MG (20 MG TABLET DR Take 1) PO QD
Simvastatin 40 MG (40MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS
Tylenol Extra Strength (ACETAMINOPHEN Extra Strength) 500 MG (500MG TABLET Take 1) PO Q8H PRN pain




ALLERGIES: NKDA.  
  
SOCIAL HISTORY:  
The patient is widowed and lives in Poinciana alone. She had a child with a brain tumor who underwent radiotherapy at the North Greenville Hospital and subsequently died.  Her husband died . She has 5 living children.  She quit smoking cigarettes in November of 2076 and denies regular alcohol use.   


ROS: difficult giving patient's cognitive limitations

Weight gain.
No fever or chills.
No new lumps.No breast pain, lump, discharge or hardness.
No abdominal pain. 
No GU/GYN discharge or bleeding
No joint symptoms.
No edema.


PHYSICAL EXAM:
Vital Signs
BP 127/64 L Arm, RR 16, Temp 97.6 F, Wt 134 lb
HT. 59.75 in
PULSE SITTING 66
PAIN LEVEL (0-10) 0
FATIGUE (0-10) 0




Gen--WD, WN, NAD
HEENT:   EOMI, sclerae anicteric, pink conjunctivae
Neck:  supple, no LAD. 
Pulm:   CTAB, no W/R/R
Breasts:  Right breast has no dominant mass, axilla neg. The left breast is smaller and has a well healed incision, axilla is negative. No dominant mass, firmer in lower quadrant. No suspicious skin lesions.
CV:   RRR, S1, S2, no M/G/R
Back:  no spinal or CVA tenderness
Abd:  Soft, nt, nd, normoactive BS, no HSM appreciated 
Ext:  DP 2+; no C/C/E
Skin:  warm, dry, no rashes or lesions



    


IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  
Stage II endocrine sensitive breast cancer, on adjuvant endocrine therapy with anastrazole.

Reviewed her follow up schedule : needs MD visit/mammogram in six months.Further chest imaging/treatment per Dr. Vernell-Paul if needed.
Patient and her son know to call in the interim with any additional questions or concerns. 








****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>