<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2067-12-09

Patient Name: LAGNSTON, SHERMAN I.;  MRN: 7223692
Dictated at: 12/09/67 by GARY J. HUGHES, MD 

 
FOLLOW UP NOTE 
 
DIAGNOSIS:  Renal cell carcinoma, presumably metastatic to T1.  Interval since conformal radiation therapy to vertebra T1 to a dose of 50.4 gray:  Three months.  
 
TUMOR STATUS:  Not available.  
 
NORMAL TISSUE STATUS:  No difficulty.  
 
INTERVAL HISTORY:  Mr. Lagnston is generally doing well with no deterioration and some improvement in his symptomatology.  He now has occasionally tingling in his feet and hands, which is possibly similar to before or less so.  He also has some posterior neck tingling, probably related to some position or activity and with lifting weight.  He has no weakness in any extremities.  His nocturia has decreased from three to one.  His hands feel a little "fuzzy."  The trembles, which he has had for some time are possibly better or the same, still a little worse on the left hand than the right.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On physical examination he looks well.  His weight is up to 230 pounds.  He has no percussible bony tenderness throughout.  His abdomen is entirely negative, so is his incision.  
 
IMPRESSION:  Clinically possibly slightly improved, certainly no evidence of progression.  
 
PLAN:  I will obtain a repeat chest and thoracic spine CT, as well as a bone scan.  Assuming that these are not indicative of further progression, I plan to see him in routine follow up in four to six months.  Dr. Levine would like some blood tests drawn on him, which I will happy to arrange when I hear exactly what they are.  Dr. Sweet is still seeing him frequently and giving him Norvasc and Atenolol for his blood pressure.  
 
_______________________________ 
GARY J. HUGHES, MD 
 
 
cc: IZEYAH SWEET, MD 
    HUNTUR IVERSON, MD 
    THOMAS EARL, MD 
    Isaac Ortega, M.D.  
    KYLE LEVINE, MD 
 
DD:12/09/67 
DT:12/10/67 
GW:1014      :04 
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-01-30

Medicine Junior Admit Note (Choi 00576)

Name Sherman Langston

MR# 722-36-92

Date of Admission: January 29, 2070

Cardiologist: Calvin Null

PCP: Kyle Eads



CC:  61 yo male former smoker, hyperlipidemia with increasing frequency of chest pain over the past 4-5 days.



HPI:   	 

61 yo male (CRF:former smoker, HTN, obesity) present with 4-5 days of increasing chest pain.  



Patient reports that he began having pain at the R sternal border, no radiation 4-5 days ago.  Patient unsure when pain initially began.  Patient describes suprasternal pain, sharp pain that felt like  gas pain.   Initially lasting for minutes.  Pain came and went without any correlation with activity.  Episodes increased in frequency and intensity over the days.  Exercise did not worsen his pain and was able to climb 2-3 flights of stairs without exacerbation of symptoms.  



Pain has been increasing in intensity over the past 4-5 days.  Pain became unbearable and patient finally presented to BRA. Pt did not have any clear STE's,  given IV nitro, heparin, and ASA.  Evaluated by BRA Cardiologist and transferred to CCH CCU for further workup. 



Pt had similar pain past summer and 1 year ago while walking up steep hill

2061 ETT 12 METs, 37000 PDP,  no perfusion defects



PMH:

Metastatic renal cell cancer, s/p L nephrectomy, T1 radiation right kidney ca, hypertension, no DM, low HDL, s/p L ankle tendon surgery



Meds:  	

Norvasc 30mg QD

Atenolol 12.5mg QD



All:  	NKDA



SH:  	lives on his own, used to be avid bicyclist, 60 pack year history quit 18 years ago, retired, not married, no drugs, or ETOH



FH:	 mother and father died of MI's at age 84 and 70 both their first



Physical  Exam:



Vitals:  T  99.2      BP   126/ 60      HR  61       RR 18         Sat    95% on RA

Gen: NAD

HEENT: NC/AT,  PERRL, nonicteric.  EOMI. No strabismus, OP w/ MMM

Neck:  	supple, NT, full ROM, JVP normal

Lungs:  	CTA bilat

Cor:  	reg, S1S2, no m/r/g 

Abd:  	soft, non-tender, BS+

G/R: 	normal rectal tone, no stool in vault

Extr:  	no c/c/e 2+ DP's bilat

Neuro: 	AAOX3, MS nl

	

Chemistry:	

Plasma Sodium            139                         (135-145)        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium         3.9                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride          108                         (100-108)        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide    19.6               L        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

Calcium                  8.8                         (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus               3.6                         (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                1.6                         (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen     35                 H        (8-25)           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine        2.3                H        (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose           107                         (70-110)         mg/dl

Amylase                  106                H        (3-100)          units/L

Lipase                   3.4                         (1.3-6.0)        U/dl

Creatine Kinase Isoenz   219.1              H        (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index     16.5               H        (0.0-3.5)        %

Troponin-T               4.32               H        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase          1327               H        (60-400)         U/L



Heme:	



WBC                      10.3                        (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                      36.5               L        (41.0-53.0)      %

HGB                      12.8               L        (13.5-17.5)      gm/dl

RBC                      4.28               L        (4.50-5.90)      mil/cmm

PLT                      190                         (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                      85                          (80-100)         fl

MCH                      29.8                        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                     35.0                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                      13.6                        (11.5-14.5)      %

Superstat PT             13.3               H        (11.1-13.1)      sec

Superstat PT-INR         1.2

     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.

Superstat APTT           29.0                        (22.1-35.1)      sec



CXR:	wet read -normal heart size, mild increase vascular markings otherwise clear xray 



EKG:	

Old EKG 2067 NSR 84 BPM normal axis, normal intervals, LAE, Q in III, biphasic T waves V3-V6 old in V4-V6, I AVL, PVC



EKG at BRA: 2/3 66BPM NSR, LAE, normal intervals, 2mm STD in V5 V6, Q's in V2, V3



On admission to CCU: NSR 66 BPM, LAE, normal axis, normal intervals, q's in V2 V3, new 1mm STD in I, AVL, II, AVF, V4; new 2mm STD in V5 V6; new 1.5mm STE in AVR, R sided leads no elevations in V3 V4



Impr:	

61 yo male with (CRF:former smoker, HTN) presents with NSTEMI with likely diffuse disease, concerning given crescendo nature of symptoms



Plan: 	



1.	Ischemia -  patient pain free right now

a.	Heparin, ASA, titrate betablocker, statin, holding ACEI given CRI, s/p double bolus of initegrillin per Dr. Null

b.	Cycle enzymes, high troponin and CK's, troponin combination of renal failure and clear cardiac event over the past few days

c.	Check fasting lipids, HgA1C

d.	Plan to go to cath lab tomorrow, NPO past MN



2.	Pump	

a.	Attempt to get AM echo before cath per Dr. Null

b.	May have mild pulm edema on CXR however, clinically appears euvolemic without signs of failure



3.	CRI -- S/p L nephrectomy and R renal radiation therapy, and radiation to T1

a.	Mucomyst, IV hydration





_________________________________

Terry Choi M.D. pg 00576





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-10-27

 

CLERMONT COUNTY HOSPITAL

ERVING, VERMONT



GI CONSULT NOTE 								10/27/2070



Patient: Langston, Sherman

Unit #: 7223692

Location: Ol 11

Referring Attending: Null



Reason for consult:  BRBPR



HPI: The patient is a 62 year old male with history of CAD s/p stents of LAD lesion in February 2070 readmit with chest pain.  At the time of this stenting, he had total occlusion of his midRCA and mid circumflex with collaterals.  He presented with recurrent CP in May, and he underwent a second cath that revealed patent LAD with stent.  This admission he had a 10-15 minute episode of chest and jaw pain with tachycardia and hypertension by home monitoring.  The pain resolved with two sublingual nitroglycerins.  He went to Butte Ridge Associates where he was placed on heparin.  In the setting of heparin bolus with PPT >150, he had one episode, moderate volume of painless rectal bleeding.  Since transfer, still on heparin, he had no further bleeding, nor guiac positive stool until today.   This morning he passed a large brown bowel movement which was guiac negative.  Following this, after returning to bed, he had a small amount of oozing of blood from his rectum.  He had no abdominal pain.  No further bleeding since this morning.  He has never had rectal bleeding previously on aspirin and plavix.  His colonoscopy in 2066 revealed diverticulosis.  He is currently on aspirin, plavix, heparin with therapeutic PTT.



PMH:

CAD

Hypertension

Hypercholesterolemia

CRI

Bilateral RCC - s/p L nephrectomy,  R RFA, XRT.  Per renal note also has pulmonary nodules, which are presumably metastatic RCC, but patient states prior eval not consistent with met disease. 



MEDS:

ASA 325

Plavix

Heparin gtt

Toprol

Protonix

Lipitor

HCTZ

Diovan

MVI





ALL: NKDA

SH: works as an archivist.  

FH: no pertinent FH.



PE:

VS:  97.7    65  120/75   99 % RA

General: appears well, NAD

Neck:  no LN

Heent: OP dry, conjunc nl

Chest:  CTA B

Cardiac:  RRR, nl s1, s2, no murmurs, rubs or gallops

Abdomen: NT, ND, nl BS.  No hepatomegaly.  No epigastric discomfort

Rectal: small external hemorrhoids, nontender, blood around anus

Extremities: no edema, normal pulses

Skin:  No jaundice, no rashes



LABS:

Plasma Sodium                    137                       (135-145)        mmo

Plasma Potassium                 4.0                       (3.4-4.8)        mmol

Plasma Chloride                  102                       (100-108)        mmol

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            26.9                      (23.0-31.9)      mmol

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             38               H        (8-25)           mg/

Plasma Creatinine                2.6              H        (0.6-1.5)        mg/



WBC                              6.2                       (4.5-11.0)       th/

HCT                              37.2             L        (41.0-53.0)      %

HGB                              12.7             L        (13.5-17.5)      gm/

RBC                              4.18             L        (4.50-5.90)      mil/

PLT                              169                       (150-350)        th/c

MCV                              89                        (80-100)         fl

MCH                              30.3                      (26.0-34.0)      pg/

MCHC                             34.0                      (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                              13.9                      (11.5-14.5)      %

PT                               15.3             H        (11.3-13.3)      sec

PT-INR                           1.5              C

Superstat APTT                   72.0             H        (22.1-35.1)      sec



          10/27/70  10/26/70  10/25/70  	10/24/70  10/24/70  10/23/70  10/23/70           	          		<5        	<5        

HCT       37.2(L)   38.4(L)   35.5(L)   	33.3(L)   31.8(L)   33.3(L)   37.0(L)   

No transfusions while in the hospital



        09/22/70  	 

FE        47        		          	          

TIBC     278       	      	          	          

FER      134      



Colonoscopy June 2066 - large mouthed diverticulosis in the sigmoid.   	      	          	          

No prior EGD - had an ENT exam at Ridge Family Practice



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN: 

62 year old male with CAD with chest pain to be evaluated by cardiac cath with painless BRBPR following a large bowel movement today in the setting of heparin, aspirin and plavix.  This bleeding was minimal and self-limited, most likely of hemorrhoidal origin, rather than diverticular.  He does have some risk of recurrent rectal bleeding on these blood thinners, but the bleeding is likely to continue to be limited.  There is no contraindication to cardiac catherization or continuing these important medications.  There is also no intervention we could do now to adjust the risk.  Would recommend proceeding to cardiac catherization.  No alteration in medications required.  



Opal Larson, M.D. 

GI Fellow - Page 09744

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-01-13





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

CLERMONT COUNTY HOSPITAL



Personal data and overall health

			

  This is a 63-year-old man status post renal cell CA and coronary artery disease.



Reason for visit

			

  Followup multiple medical problems.



Major Problems





Coronary artery disease

The patient had recatheterization in May demonstrating 30% stenosis at the stent on the LAD.  He has diffuse disease, otherwise with good collateralization.  His exercise tolerance test in May showed excellent exercise tolerance, but positive images and positive tracings for ischemia.  His Duke ETT score was -10, but his perfusion images showed moderate reversibility in the inferior myocardium with fixed defect anteriorly.  He had infero-apical hypokinesis with an EF of 45%.  It is also noted that his blood pressure fell, but normalized during exercise.  The patient has been stable until last several weeks when he has noted some lower jaw symptoms anteriorly.  He has no chest squeezing, neck squeezing, or jaw pain, but there is an odd sensation under the front teeth.  He correlates this with exercise, but not consistently.  He also occasionally feels this at rest.  He is able to walk uphill and generate a pulse of 90.  He is working doing heavy labor in the garden, moving, and digging.  It is not clear that this represents angina, but we will let Dr. Null know.  He is seeing Dr. Null in three to four weeks.     01/13/2072: .  The patient has been improving steadily since his last admission for CABG in November 2070.  He states his exercise tolerance is steadily improving and he is able to walk 2 miles at a rate of 17 minutes per mile without dyspnea or fatigue.  He has no chest pain or palpitations.  He does worry about bradycardia and states his metoprolol of 50 mg BID may be too much.  He has been withholding half to full dose in the evenings when he finds his pulses about 50.  He has no symptoms of forgetfulness, dizziness, or loss of consciousness.  He does have cold extremities.  There is no weight gain, weight loss, or orthopnea.  He remains on beta blocker, lipitor, Diovan, hydrochlorothiazide, digoxin, and warfarin.  He is no longer on Plavix.  He has no nitrate.  On exam, he is somewhat hypertensive, but lungs are good and there is no elevated JVP.  His EKG shows first-degree AV block and I have asked him to bring that to Dr.  Null's office today.  

A: Stable. 

P: Continue medicines as they are because of borderline blood pressure today.  We would not escalate



Elevated blood pressure

The patient is on Diovan, hydrochlorothiazide, and metoprolol.  He states his blood pressure at home is usually quite good and he feels it is responsive to external stressors.  I have asked him to think hard about removing those stressors from his life in order to maintain health.



Hyperlipidemia

The patient remains on 40 mg of lipitor.  It has been a year since we have checked his excellent results and we will check today.  He has been fasting for 12 hours.



Iron deficiency anemia

We will recheck his indices today.  He is not fatigued or pale.



Renal carcinoma

The patient had repeat MRI and CT in January at the Healthwin Hospital.  These were read as stable and he needs no intervention other than continued monitoring at six-month intervals.  He is quite reassured by this.



Seborrheic keratosis

The patient is ready for evaluation by Dermatology.  He has several atypical-looking keratoses as well as poorly rounded lesions consistent with BCCs.  I have referred him to Dermatology today.



Sinus congestion

/ 5/10/64=&gt;/and stuffiness, no ear ache, no sore throat, no shaking, chills (saw Dr.  I have reinforced the wisdom of taking some nasal steroid at HS.



Anticoagulation

The patient is fully anticoagulated indefinitely.



Active Medications



aspirin 81 mg po qd

digoxin 0.125 mg po qd

Diovan HCT 160mg/25mg po qd

ferrous sulfate 325 mg PO TID with ascorbic acid

Foltx 2.2 mg

Lipitor 40 mg

metoprolol 50 mg bid  

Nasacort aq 55mcg/spray nasal qd 1-2 sprays/nostril; discontinue after 3wks if no improvement

nystatin powder 100,000u/g top bid-tid apply to affected area(s)

warfarin 5 mg 5 mg 5 days and 7.5  2 days qwk



Change in therapies and Renewals



warfarin 5 mg   5 mg 5 days and 7.5  2 days qwk Start: 2/13/2070

metoprolol 50 mg  bid   Start: 3/3/2070

Lipitor 40 mg   Start: 3/3/2070

Plavix 75 mg 1 tab po QD Start: 3/3/2070 End: 01/13/2072 - Inactivated

ranitidine hcl 150 mg 1 tab po QD Start: 3/3/2070 End: 01/13/2072 - Inactivated

aspirin 81 mg po qd Start: 3/3/2070

valsartan 80 mg  QD Start: 4/24/2070 End: 01/13/2072 - Inactivated

Foltx 2.2 mg   QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 5/09/2070

hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 mg 1 tab po QD Start: 6/12/2070 End: 01/13/2072 - Inactivated

isosorbide mononitrate 60 mg  QAM and 1 half qpm Start: 6/12/2070 End: 01/13/2072 - Inactivated

Nasacort aq 55mcg/spray nasal qd 1-2 sprays/nostril; discontinue after 3wks if no improvement QTY:3 bottles Refills:3 Start: 8/07/2070

digoxin 0.125 mg po qd Start: 01/13/2072

Diovan HCT 160mg/25mg po qd Start: 01/13/2072



Social history

			

  The patient remains at home and has continued to nurture his digital archiving business.  He continues to interest himself in equities trading.  He states he is not as active as prior to his CABG.  He denies depression.



Procedures and Immunizations 

Influenza vaccine 

 right deltoid.  Lot #82201, expires 06/25/2072.



Review of systems

			

  No chest pain, palpitations, shortness of breath with dyspnea on exertion, or orthopnea.  Stools are normal.  No blood or black stools.  Urination is fine without dysuria or frequency.  He has some right ankle and knee pain but is tolerable.  He has had developed some strabismus and is being followed by Dr.  Benjamin Shepherd at Ridge Family Practice Center.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 140/84    , repeated by me 140/90

Weight   206 pounds

Height   70.1 inches

General appearance   Well developed and well nourished in no apparent distress

Skin   Multiple seborrheic keratoses over the chest and back.  There are several atypical keratoses as well as some rounded, smooth papules over the chest.  He has skin tags on the neck and larger pigmented nevi on the forehead

Heent   Oropharynx, normal.  No lesions.  Hearing intact.  EOMI.  PERRL

Neck   Supple.  Carotids 2+.  No bruits.  Thyroid normal

Chest   Clear to PandA

Cor   S1 and S2.  No murmur, gallops, or rubs

Abdomen   Bowel sounds positive.  Soft and nontender.  No hepatosplenomegaly

Rectal exam   Guaiac negative brown stool.  Prostate is small, flat, and only partial exam is possible with the examining finger

Genitalia   Genital, normal circumcised phallus.  Normal testes without discrete nodule or mass.  No inguinal hernia detected

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  No DP or PT pulses detected.  Toes well perfused but cool.  DTRs 2+ at the patella, 0 at the calcaneus.  Toes bilaterally downgoing.  Gait is normal



Selected recent labs

			

  EKG reviewed.  There is first-degree AV block, IMI, and lateral T-wave changes that are chronic.  Rate was 50.



Assessment and plan

			

  Generally stable cardiac.  Renal cell cancer without progression.  Renal function to be evaluated today.  Unilateral kidney.  Anticoagulation stable.  We will send INR today.  Blood pressure could be better controlled.



Note transcribed by outside service

			

  Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Eads, Kyle on Jan 29, 2072     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>