<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2083-07-18

 
 
July 18, 2083
 
 
Vincent Ventura, M.D.
4971 Edmatteric Drive
Cheney, TX 37523
 
RE:  Peggy Tinsley
     MR #236-67-03-3
 
Dear Dr. Ventura:
 
Peggy Tinsley was seen in the renal clinic today.  This patient
with end stage renal disease secondary to diabetes was initiated
on hemodialysis 2 weeks ago in MH.  She has been doing well
except for the complaint of fevers and rigors intermittently for
the past week.  There is no history of cough, dyspnea, or chest
pain.  She denies any dysuria, urgency, or frequency.  Her blood
sugars at home have been between 120 and 180.  
 
Her current medications include Tums 5 to 6 tabs with meals,
Erythropoietin, Premarin and Provera, Nephrox 150 mg tid, insulin
NPH 10 units qam.
 
On July 17, after hemodialysis, Ms. Tinsley was given a partial
dose of Vancomycin and developed pruritus.  CBC at the time
revealed a white count of 6.2 with a hematocrit of 25.2.  Blood
cultures were sent.
 
On examination today this lady appeared well with a BP of 110/60
and a pulse of 88.  She was afebrile.  Head and neck examination
was unremarkable and chest was clear to IPPA.  On cardiovascular
examination JVP was at the sternal angle and there was no
peripheral edema.  Heart sounds were normal.
 
Urinalysis did not reveal and white cells and contained 3+
protein and 2+ glucose.
 
Miss Tinsley should be followed up at her dialysis center. 
There does not appear to be any evidence of a graft infection. 
She should also have a urine sent for culture to rule out urinary
tract infection.  Because of her early satiety she has been
eating poorly and we might suggest that she be started on a
gastroprokinetic agent such as Cisapride 10 mg qid.
Vincent Ventura, M.D.         -2-
RE:  Peggy Tinsley
     MR #236-67-03-3
 
 
Thank you for allowing us to be involved in the care of this
patient.
 
Yours sincerely,
 
 
 
Martin Y. Pruitt, M.D.
Renal Fellow
 
 
 
Y. Quinton Xanders, M.D.
Attending Physician
 
DD: 07/18/83
DT: 07/23/83
DV: 07/18/83
 
/bradford
 
cc:  Dr. Uriel Palmer
     Dr. Isaac Upson, Cheney, TX 37523
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-11-01

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
June 6, 2083
 
 
 
Vincent Ventura, M.D.
0758 Edmatteric Drive
Cheney, TX 37523
 
Re:  Peggy Tinsley
     MR#  236-67-03-3
 
Dear Dr. Ventura:
 
Peggy Tinsley was seen in the Renal Clinic today.  Her chief
symptomatic complaint is severe pruritus, which has not improved
much with Benadryl.  She has yet to fill the prescription for Sarna
lotion.  Her diarrhea has improved with Imodium, and she brought in
samples for cultures today.  Her appetite has improved somewhat.
She notes exertional fatigue and shortness of breath.  Medications
include Phoslo 1 tablet t.i.d., Lasix 160 mg b.i.d., Altase  2.5 mg
b.i.d., Lopressor 100 mg b.i.d., NPH 10 units q.d., iron t.i.d.
 
On examination, weight was 46.8 kilos, which is stable.  Heart rate
was 72, blood pressure 130/64.  JVP was clearly seen at 6 cm
greater than the sternal angle, and there was 1 plus peripheral
edema.  There was no S3.  Chest examination revealed bibasilar
inspiratory crackles.  Her left hand is no longer cold, but the
PTFE graft remains slightly edematous.
 
Blood work from May 30th showed a hematocrit of 23, potassium 5.2,
bicarbonate 15, BUN 91, creatinine 7.9, calcium 5.5., phosphate
5.2, albumin 3.4.
 
We will continue to hold off on dialysis until such time as Peggy's
PTFE graft is suitable.  This will save her the additional
morbidity of a semipermanent IJ catheter.  She is more hypervolemic
than last week, and I added Zaroxolyn 2.5 mg in the morning to her
diuretic regimen.  By oversight, she was not started on Rocaltrol,
and I have started her on Rocaltrol .25 mcg p.o. q.d., and
Nephrocaps 1 p.o. q.d.
 
Page 2
Vincent Ventura, M.D.
Re:  Peggy Tinsley
     MR#  236-67-03-3
June 6, 2083
 
A follow-up appointment was arranged in one week's time.
 
Yours sincerely,
 
 
 
Keith Quant, M.D.
Renal Fellow
 
 
 
Y. Quinton Xanders, M.D.
 
DD: 6-6-83
DT: 06/13/83
DV: 6-6-83
 
 
 
cc:
Ivan Tomlinson, M.D.
Surgery
FPM
 
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-09-02

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
                                             September 03, 2085
 
 
 
 
                                             
Bill X. Stafford, M.D.
Chief, Transplant Divistion
Department of Surgery
Family Practice Missoula
 
                                        Re:  Peggy Tinsley
                                             FPM#:  236-67-03-3
 
 
Dear Dr. Stafford:
 
     I was asked to provide a cardiologic evaluation on Mrs.
Tinsley with a concentration on her appropriateness to be listed
as a recipient for a cadaver renal transplant.  In summary, she is
a 46 year old woman who has been an insulin dependent diabetic
since the age of 29 and has been on hemodialysis since 2083.  By
report, her other complications for diabetes include retinopathy,
peripheral neuropathy, and peripheral vascular disease.  In viewing
her present history, she works in the Houghton Mifflin Harcourt learning technology department.  Her
three times a week hemodialyses are uncomplicated.  She does,
however,  experience occasional chest pressure with activities and
on rare occasions has had nocturnal angina.  These episodes are
relieved by nitroglycerin.  Mrs. Tinsley has also noted that with
walking she will occasionally get short of breath which is relieved
by slowing down.  
 
     In addition to diabetes and hypertension which was present
only pre-dialysis, she has been and continues to be a smoker.  Her
cholesterol by one report was 228 mg/dl.  I don't have
fractionations and her family history is unknown.  
 
     A report of an echocardiogram from April of 2083, shows mild
ventricular hypertrophy in the presence of mitral insufficiency,
preserved LV size and function.  She had an exercise tolerance test
in February of 2085.  On a modified protocol, she went for less
than 4 1/2 minutes.  This is equivalent to not even completing
stage 1 of the standard Bruce.  With that, she did develop chest
pain and had 2 mm of ST depression. That study was accompanied by
both fixed and reversible isotopic perfusion changes in the septum
consistent with prior non-transmural infarct with exercise induced
ischemia.  As was apparent to those involved, even the non-isotope
portion alone was worrisome for high grade coronary disease and led
to the recommendation for a cardiac catheterization.  
 
     That study was done in Macdonald Hospital and at this time, I
only have the report.  However, from this report, there was
preserved LV function with anterior lateral hypokinesis and trace
MR that is consistent with the echo and the thallium studies. 
Coronary angiography showed by report, diffuse involvement of
proximal mid-LAD without specific focal stenosis until an 80% mid-
LAD.  The circumflex was also diffusely diseased and there was a
discrete stenosis in the mid section of a large marginal.  The
right coronary artery was diffusely diseased with a discrete
stenosis.  At that time, the recommendation was to continue medical
therapy.  
 
     Her medical therapy at this time is estrogen replacement with
prempro 2.5 mg once a day, tenormin 25 mg qd, aspirin one every
other day in addition to her supplemental vitamins, iron and twice
daily insulin therapy.  
 
     In rounding out her medical history, her surgical procedures
have involved the hemodialysis access.  She has had one pregnancy
28 years ago without complications.  I also elicited a history of
some focal arm weakness and occasional slurring of speech.  This
was difficult to pin down, but is of some concern.
 
     On exam, her blood pressure was 150/80  mm Hg, pulse 90
regular, her weight 95 lbs.  Her hemodialysis shunt is on the left
arm.  There was a right carotid bruit, neck veins were not
distended.  Lungs were clear, PMI was displaced and sustained. 
There was an S4, no S3 and there was a holo systolic murmur at the
apex.  Abdomen was benign, femoral pulses were intact, extremities
were without edema.  The electrocardiogram showed sinus rhythm,
diffuse STT changes.  There were no pathologic Q waves.
 
     Although the focus of this evaluation was originally for
transplant candidacy, I am concerned about her current cardiac
status.  She is a young diabetic woman, symptomatic of both
shortness of breath and chest pain and on exercise test, has
limited functional capacity.  The coronary angiography reveals a
presence of multi-vessel disease.  Even without seeing the primary
data which I hope to do in the next week, it would be unlikely that
she would be an angioplasty candidate, given the poor results in diabetics.  
Therefore, coronary revascularization for her would be coronary artery 
bypass surgery. 
 
 
     Obviously, I would like to review the films first, and speak
with Dr. Upson regarding augmentation of her anti-anginals.  I
would also like to add pravastatin at this time, starting with only
10 mg and obtain non-invasive studies of the carotids.  As
indicated, although the focus of this evaluation was her
suitability for transplantation, the issue of controlling
symptomatic coronary artery disease in this young woman became more
pressing.
 
     I look forward to working with you and the other physicians in
her care.
 
 
                                   Sincerely,
 
 
 
                                   Quentin U. Johnson, M.D., Ph.D.
 
Quentin U. Johnson, M.D., Ph.D.
 
DD: 9/03/85
DT: 9/03/85
DV: 9/02/85
 
 
QUJ:jarrell
 
cc:  Verlon Ventura, M.D., 6593 Edmatteric Drive, Cheney, TX 
     37523
     Archie Oreilly, M.D., Family Practice Missoula
     Ivan Upson, M.D., Radford Community Hospital,
     0808 O’neil’s Court, Effingham, TX  38866
     Bill R. Joe, M.D., Macdonald Hospital, 726 Kehoe Avenue,
     Cheney, TX 37523
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-02-06

                     FPM EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
TINSLEY,PEGGY R   236-67-03-3                  VISIT DATE: 02/06/87
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 48-year-old female who has
had a kidney transplant as well as an extensive cardiac history who
comes in complaining of fatigue and shortness of breath.
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  She was seen primarily by Dr.
Robert Villasenor.  She also complains of pleuritic chest pain and a
cough.
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Are as documented in the written chart by
Dr. Villasenor.
MEDICATIONS:  Are as documented in the written chart by Dr.
Villasenor.
ALLERGIES:  Are as documented in the written chart by Dr. Villasenor.
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Are as documented in the
written chart by Dr. Villasenor.
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her temperature is 99.  Her other vital
signs are stable.  Her O2 sat is 96% on room air.  Her exam is as
noted in the written chart.  Of note, on her cardiovascular exam:
She has a regular rate and rhythm with a 2/6 systolic murmur.  The
lungs show left lower lobe crackles.
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Are notable for a white blood cell count of
12.5 and a hematocrit of 45.3.  Chest x-ray shows an infiltrate in
the superior segment of the left upper lobe.
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  This is a 48-year-old female status post a kidney
transplant who now has a left upper lobe pneumonia.
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The plan is to
admit the patient for IV antibiotics.  Condition on admission is
satisfactory.
___________________________________                    JD545/5915
SARINA BOOTH, M.D.  SB17                           D:02/06/87
                                                       T:02/07/87
Dictated by:  SARINA BOOTH, M.D.  SB17




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-03-01

                     FPM EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
TINSLEY,PEGGY R   236-67-03-3                  VISIT DATE: 03/01/88
The patient was seen in the emergency department with Dr. Singleton, 
history per Dr. Singleton. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Ear pain and rash. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 49 year old 
female with past medical history positive for recent transplant, 
hypertension, Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus, and coronary 
artery bypass grafting who presented to the emergency department 
with right ear pain for the last week now.  She now has a petechia 
rash in the periumbilical area.  She has no fevers, chills, cough, 
trauma, or other complaints. 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As documented by Dr. Singleton. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As documented by Dr. Singleton. 
MEDICATIONS:  As documented by Dr. Singleton. 
ALLERGIES:  As documented by Dr. Singleton. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  As documented by Dr. Singleton. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Her 
blood pressure is 220/80, pulse 80 and regular, respirations 16, 
the patient is afebrile with oxygen saturation 97% on room air. 
Examination of her right air shows positive cerumen impaction and 
question of otitis externa.  Otherwise her airway is patent.  Her 
neck is supple without jugular venous distension, nodes, or bruits. 
Her lungs are clear.  Her heart reveals a regular rate and rhythm 
without murmur.  Her abdomen is soft, positive petechial rash on 
the left aspect of the umbilicus, not raised, no hives or 
tenderness over the graft.  No rebound, guarding, or rigidity.  Her 
extremities have no deformities.  Neurologic examination is non 
focal.  The rest of the physical examination is unremarkable. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Complete blood count shows a white blood 
cell count of 5.8, hematocrit 35.8.  Electrolytes are within normal 
limits.  BUN is 16.9 with creatinine 2.8. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was seen in the 
emergency department by ENT and by the transplant service. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Cerumen impaction and otitis externa to the ear. 
Elevated BUN and creatinine. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 
admitted for further evaluation and treatment.  She was admitted in 
stable condition. 
___________________________________                    MA317/6938
                                                       D:03/01/88 
                                                       T:03/02/88 
Dictated by:  UNKNOWN Y. PARRA, M.D.  UP65 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>