<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-11-09

                     HEARTHSTONE EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
LEVINE,LYDIA   813-25-60-5                   VISIT DATE: 11/10/74
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 48 year old 
female who while working at home two days ago noticed pain and 
swelling of the left fifth finger.  The patient was also noted to 
complain of pain, erythema and a slight amount of pus of the fifth 
finger of the left hand.  She denies any other complaints.  There 
is no fever, no chills, no nausea or vomiting. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  She has a history of insulin dependent 
diabetes mellitus. 
MEDICATIONS:  Insulin for her diabetes. 
ALLERGIES:  No known allergies. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature of 99, pulse of 96, respiratory 
rate of 16, blood pressure is 165/96.  Examination of the fifth 
finger noted pus and erythema of the extensor surface of the fifth 
finger of the left hand.  She was noted to have full range of 
motion of the fifth finger of the left hand. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Pus was drained from the wound, 
approximately 1/2 cc of pus.  The patient was given Ancef 1 gram IV 
piggyback. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  She was 
discharged home on Keflex 250 mg p.o. q.i.d. x seven days.  She was 
also given a tetanus shot.  Condition on discharge stable. 
___________________________________                    JD134/2915 
D. EMON DUBOIS, M.D.  ED65                            D:11/10/74 
                                                       T:11/10/74 
Dictated by:  D. EMON DUBOIS, M.D.  ED65 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-03-20

                          OFFICE NOTE
                                
Lydia Levine
MR #813-25-60-5
March 20, 2076
 
Ms. Levine is a 50-year-old, perimenopausal woman with non-
insulin dependent diabetes, hypercholesterolemia, and a history
of tobacco use, who underwent a recent cardiac catheterization
for a positive stress test.  At catheterization she had a
proximal 60% lesion in her RCA as well as a mid 60-70% RCA
lesion, obtuse marginal lesion of 60%, and an LAD mid lesion of
60%.  At the time it was decided to continue medical therapy on
Ms. Levine.  Since her cardiac catheterization approximately two
weeks ago, she has had no recurrent symptoms of chest pain.  She
continues on her medicines including Lopid 500 mg b.i.d.,
atenolol, aspirin, and sublingual nitroglycerin as needed, as
well as her oral hypoglycemic medicines.
 
Physical Examination:  She is an obese, white female in no acute
distress.  Her vital signs are stable.  Lungs are clear to
auscultation.  Cardiac exam reveals regular rate and rhythm,
normal S1 and S2; no murmurs, rubs or gallops.  She has no
peripheral edema.
 
Electrocardiogram shows a normal sinus rhythm at a rate of 70,
axis of about 46, and there are no acute ST-T changes noted.
 
Impression/Plan:  We will continue Ms. Levine on her current
cardiac regimen.  She has three-vessel coronary artery disease,
non-obstructive in nature.  As long as she remains asymptomatic
on her current medical regimen, we will continue to follow her. 
She will return for a follow-up visit in approximately three
months.
 
 
 
Quinn Ivey, M.D.
 
DD: 03/20/76
DT: 03/22/76
DV: 03/20/76
 
/aponte
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-10-11


Hearthstone Cardiovascular Division
CVD R5
53 Peterborough Place                                      LEVINE, LYDIA
Hartsville, VA 84583                                           81325605
(201) 957-6458                                           10/11/80


This patient was seen in combination with Dr. Lance Camacho.  His note reflects our joint assessment and plan.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, Ms. Levin is a 54-year-old female with diabetes, hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, who has known coronary artery disease.  She had an exercise test in 2076 for some vague symptoms, which was positive, and led to cardiac catheterization.  This catheterization revealed 60% LAD lesion, 50% first marginal, 60% RCA, and a 70% diagonal lesion.  She was maintained on medical management with few symptoms.  She has been lost to followup from Cardiology Clinic.  She has within the last week developed increasing symptoms with minimal exertion.  She underwent a stress test in which she was able to exercise for 6 minutes and 9 seconds on the Bruce protocol.  She achieved 93% of age-predicted maximal heart rate.  At 4 minutes, she developed 2 mm ST segment depressions in the anterior leads associated with chest discomfort.  She is a vague historian, but has not had clear rest anginal symptoms.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On physical examination, she is mildly obese white female.  She has no jugular venous distention.  Her carotids are 2+.  Her heart shows normal S1 and S2.  There is a 2/6 holosystolic murmur at the apex.  Lungs are clear.  Abdomen is benign.  Extremities show no cyanosis or edema.  Electrocardiogram shows normal sinus rhythm, normal axis and intervals.  There is no evidence of ischemia or infarction.

ASSESSMENT:  Ms. Levin is a 55-year-old diabetic woman with progressive anginal symptoms with known moderate 3-vessel coronary artery disease from 4 years ago with at least moderate risk, positive stress test.  After discussion with Dr. Camacho, our plan will be continue her on aspirin, beta-blocker, and a low-dose ACE inhibitor through her regimen.  She refuses to take a cholesterol-lowering agent due to previous concerns with myalgias.  She will be referred for cardiac catheterization within the next several days with a goal to better define her coronary anatomy for the possibility of percutaneous coronary intervention versus cardiac bypass surgery.





______________________________
Clyde Roe, MD


Dictated By: Clyde Roe


eScription document:1-3896405 AFFocus



DD: 10/11/80
DT: 10/12/80
DV: 10/11/80



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-10-28



Vital Signs

BP 122/70, Temp 97.2 F, Wt 164 lb



AGE 54y10.7m 



54 year old female presents to follow-up recent hospitalization for coronary angiogram. denies chest pain, SOB, but is experiencing pain at the site of the catheter insertion for her angiogram and stent placement. the pain is so strong that she cannot stand and walk for longer than a few minutes. there is no discoloration at the site, but the pain is a burning pain - as if someone poured alcohol on the spot. pain travels down the right leg

occasionally feels discomfort in both calves when walking for a long distance

taking medications as directed but has not been able to get her insurance to pay for zetia.

taking lisinopril - no cough. (had a cough with captopril in the past)

VS as noted

NAD

carotids 2+ symmetrical

chest clear to ausc. RR 12

cardiac normal s1/s2 no m/s3/s4 HR 70 reg

extremities no peripheral edema DP and PT full bilaterally

sl tenderness at right femoral artery, scarred area corresponds to where the discomfort begins  no warmth, fluid collection, ecchymosis

reviewed all data from recent hospitalization

Assessment - cardiovascular status - stable

r/o peripheral artery disease

Plan influenza vaccine per RN

samples dispensed of zetia for 6 weeks. will check fasting lipids and ALT. if effective, will contact her insurance for prior authorization

non-invasive arterial studies of lower extremities

continue regimen per medication list

RV 12/05/80  

letter for work



J. Needham, MD      



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>