<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2092-11-16

 
 
 
 
 
 
November 16, 2092
 
 
 
Stuart J. Long, M.D.
Glenn Helen Medical Group
Glenn Helen Infirmary
Algoma, CO  71183
 
RE:  Roberta Vincent
     MR #380-18-32-2
 
Dear Dr. Long:
 
Thank you for referring Ms. Roberta Vincent to the Renal Services Clinic.  I had the pleasure of seeing her on November 16,
2092.  Please allow me to summarize her history for our records.
 
Ms. Vincent is a 56-year-old mother of eight with chronic renal
failure of unknown etiology.  She is six years status post
hysterectomy for endometriosis during which an occult
leiomyosarcoma was discovered.  She has an extensive history of
hidradenitis, obesity, and hypertension.  She had one stillborn
infant, one premature infant, and three spontaneous abortions. 
SFOC records are unavailable at this time.
 
Her medications include Premarin 0.625 qd, Diltiazem 240 qd,
furosemide 40 mg qd, Mevacor 20 mg qd, Calcitriol 0.25 mcg qd,
Niferex 300 mg qd, Vitamin E 400 units qd, fish oil qd, and Keflex
250 mg qid.
 
On physical examination Ms. Vincent is a 56-year-old woman in no
distress.  Her weight is 101.5 kilograms, or 223 lbs.  Temperature
is normal.  Pulse is 88 beats per minute.  Blood pressure is
178/96.  There is striking hirsutism and moon facies.  There is a
buffalo hump.  The lungs show scattered wheezing.  Cardiovascular
exam is normal.  There are discolorations of the skin across the
neck, upper extremities, and trunk which are hyperpigmented but not
raised.  The abdomen is obese without palpable masses.  There is a
ventral hernia deep in the lower part of the abdomen.  The
extremities show trace edema.  There are several areas of
superficial petechiae.
 
In summary, this 56-year-old woman has chronic renal failure of
unclear etiology.  She does report an episode of lower extremity
swelling in association with an episode of hidradenitis.  ThisRoberta Vincent
MR #380-18-32-2               -2-            November 16, 2092
 
 
raises the possibility of a post-infectious glomerulonephritis now
in a chronic phase.  Other diagnostic possibilities include other
forms of chronic glomerulonephritis including systemic lupus
erythematosus given the history of spontaneous abortions. 
Nevertheless, I agree that kidney biopsy is not indicated at this
time given the advanced nature of her disease and the increased
risk due to her body habitus.
 
I discussed several options in renal replacement therapy with Ms.
Vincent. Although she has no medical conditions which would
preclude living-related or cadaveric kidney transplantation, her
obesity and glucose intolerance along with the history of
hidradenitis make transplantation a less attractive option.  I have
encouraged Ms. Vincent to attempt a gradual weight loss program in
order to improve her fitness prior to either dialysis or
transplantation.  Nevertheless, her appearance is quite reminiscent
of Cushing's disease, and this should be worked up if it has not
been performed previously.
 
I have arranged an iothalamate GFR to more closely approximate her
kidney function and a follow-up appointment in two months' time to
meet with Helen Uren and consider creation of a native AV
fistula or placement of a graft.
 
Thank you once again for your kind referral.
 
Respectfully,
 
 
 
Elias Q. Mercado, M.D.
 
 
 
S. Quenton Jolley, M.D.
Glenn Helen Medical Group
80 Whitney St
Algoma, CO  71183
 
DD: 11/16/92
DT: 11/24/92
DV: 11/16/92
 
/joshi
 
cc:  Edward Xanthos, M.D.
     Saint Francis Outpatient Center
     784 Greatstone Drive
     Boulder, CO  72529




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-01-18

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
January 18, 2093
 
 
 
Edward Xanthos, M.D.
Saint Francis Outpatient Center
744 Greatstone Drive
Boulder, CO 72529
 
RE:  Roberta Vincent
     MR #380-18-32-2
 
Dear Dr. Xanthos,
 
We had the privilege of seeing your patient, Mrs. Roberta Vincent, in
the Renal Services Clinic on January 18, 2093.  We will
not repeat her history as you know it well. Over the past three
months Mrs. Vincent has complained of increasing fatigue,
occasionally sleeping more than 12 hours per night, forgetfulness
and tingling of the fingers and toes. She has maintained a
relatively good appetite and denies nausea, vomiting or shortness
of breath.  An Iothalamate GFR test obtained on December 14, 2092
revealed a glomerular infiltration rate of approximately 10 ml per
minute, suggesting profound loss of renal function.
 
On physical examination today her weight is 99.5 kilograms or 219
pounds.  Blood pressure is 150/90, pulse is 80 and regular.  The
lungs are clear. There is no peripheral edema. Again, there marked
cushingoid features. Despite overall weight loss, Mrs. Vincent
comments that she has gained facial and abdominal fat as well as
facial hair over the past several months.
 
In summary, Mrs. Vincent appears to be developing early symptoms of
uremia.  Given her advanced azotemia we believe that she should
undergo creation of an arteriovenous fistula so that she may start
dialysis within the next several months. We have arranged to
recheck her chemistries today.  We would also recommend that she
undergo repeat work up for her cushingoid features.  Although renal
failure may alter hormonal balance and may promote occasional
androgenic features in woman, this is beyond ordinary.
 
Thank you once again for allowing us to participate in her care.  
 
Edward Xanthos, M.D.
RE:  Roberta Vincent
MR #380-18-32-2
January 18, 2093
Page #2
 
 
Please do not hesitate to contact us if we can be of any further
assistance.
 
Sincerely,
 
 
 
 
Elias Q. Mercado, M.D.
 
 
 
S. Quenton Jolley, M.D.
 
DD: 01/18/93
DT: 01/24/93
DV: 01/18/93
/knox




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-04-10

                     GLENN HELEN EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
VINCENT,ROBERTA J.   380-18-32-2
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 59-year-old 
female who is status post renal transplant with history of 
hypertension and diabetes who presents complaining of recurrent 
shortness of breath.  She had a renal transplant in 2093 with 
history of chronic renal insufficiency.  She was last admitted here 
on February 23 for shortness of breath.  The patient has had sore 
throat and URI symptoms now for a few days.  No nausea and 
vomiting.  No sweating.  No chest pain or dizziness. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Complicated by hypertension, diabetes, pedal 
neuropathy, hernia, and hysterectomy. 
MEDICATIONS:  Premarin, insulin, Prilosec, prednisone, and sodium 
bicarbonate.  She is also on Lasix, hydralazine, and Talwin. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile.  Vital signs are normal. 
Oxygen saturation 97%.  Initial blood pressure is 214/118.  The 
second blood pressure is 188/100.  HEENT:  Normal.  Cardiac:  No 
murmurs or rubs.  Lungs:  Crackles bilaterally, but no wheezing. 
Abdomen:  Soft and nontender with good bowel sounds.  Extremities: 
Trace pedal edema 1+ throughout.  Neuro:  Intact. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrolytes here are normal.  Creatinine 
is pretty good.  She was 4.4 on February 26.  She is 3.3 now, so 
she has improved in creatinine.  White count is 12.9 and hematocrit 
of 36.  EKG showed sinus rhythm at 97, old left ventricular 
hypertrophy, and no acute changes.  Chest x-ray shows increased 
chronic pulmonary edema and old small right pleural fluid seen. 
CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  The Renal fellow is here.  The case 
has been discussed with the Renal fellow. 
ADMITTING DIAGNOSIS:  Congestive heart failure and hypertension. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 
going to be admitted to the Renal Service, admitted to Dr. Elias 
Mercado.  Admitted in stable condition. 
___________________________________                    VC341/8846 
DEXTER N. JOHNSON, M.D.  DJ50                             D:04/10/96 
                                                       T:04/10/96 
Dictated by:  DEXTER N. JOHNSON, M.D.  DJ50 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-05-27

                     GLENN HELEN EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
VINCENT,ROBERTA J.   380-18-32-2                    VISIT DATE: 05/27/96
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Shortness of breath. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 59 year old female who 
presents to us with shortness of breath tonight.  She has been 
developing shortness of breath now with nausea and vomiting today. 
There is no history of fevers, no chills, and no abdominal pain. 
She does complain of some mild flank pain but nothing significant. 
She has had chronic back pain for years. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  The patient has a significant past medical 
history.  History is significant for hypertension, diabetes, and 
congestive heart failure.  She is status post total abdominal 
hysterectomy and bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy and status post 
L5-S1 laminectomy. 
MEDICATIONS:  The patient is on multiple medications including 
Lasix, lisinopril, prednisone, Premarin, nifedipine. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Here the patient looked mildly 
uncomfortable.  Blood pressure was 151/58, oxygen saturation was 99 
percent, and heart rate was 98.  Blood pressure has remained stable 
since she has been here.  Heent examination was normal.  Pupils 
were reactive normally bilaterally.  Oropharynx was clear.  Neck 
was mildly obese with no jugular venous distention.  There were 
good carotid upstrokes, no bruit.  Lungs had some crackles 
two-thirds of the way up and some rales at the bases, one-half way 
up.  Cardiac examination revealed S1 and S2, somewhat tachycardic, 
with a 2/6 murmur.  Abdomen had multiple striae and was soft and 
non-tender, with good bowel sounds.  There were good pulses 
throughout.  Extremities were normal. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrolytes here were normal.  Blood sugar 
was normal.  White count was 14, hematocrit 34.  Initial CK was 
140, troponin 2.6.  Chest x-ray showed moderate effusion and a 
small left effusion.  Patient's last echocardiogram showed an 
ejection fraction of 60 percent.  This echocardiogram was done in 
February of 2096.  She also had a second echocardiogram in April of 
2096 which showed an ejection fraction of 55 percent, with moderate 
MR.  EKG here showed ST depression in V6 and some decreased T's in 
aVR and aVL.  Sinus rhythm on EKG rated about 100. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  In the Emergency Department the 
patient was heparinized.  She was placed on oxygen, given an 
aspirin, and placed on a Nitroglycerin drip.  She also received 
some Nitropaste here.  She also received a mg of Morphine.  SFOC 
Cardiology was aware of the patient's troponin of 2.6, indicating 
that she had a myocardial infarction or could still be evolving a 
myocardial infarction here.  She received IV Lasix 60 mg here and 
responded very well.  She was diuresing considerably and her 
shortness of breath appeared to be much better than when she 
arrived here in the Emergency Department. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Congestive heart failure with myocardial 
infarction, diuresing well and responding to medications. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 
admitted to the CCU.  SFOC is aware.  She remains in stable 
condition here and is going to be transferred up to CCU in a little 
while.  Condition at this time is satisfactory. 
___________________________________                    PF091/9353 
DEXTER N. JOHNSON, M.D.  DJ50                             D:05/27/96 
                                                       T:05/27/96 
Dictated by:  DEXTER N. JOHNSON, M.D.  DJ50 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-03-31

                     GLENN HELEN EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
VINCENT,ROBERTA J.   380-18-32-2                    VISIT DATE: 03/31/98
See primarily by Dr. Ulises Collier.  I also saw the patient and 
reviewed Dr. Collier's history. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This 62 year-old woman comes from 
dial where she developed substernal chest pain radiating to her 
left arm near the end of the run.  She also complains of shortness 
of breath.  She noted some nausea, but no vomiting.  She had no 
other related symptoms.  She has had no previous history of chest 
pain.  She was given Nitroglycerin x 3 and this eventually relieved 
her pain. 
PAST MEDICAL/SURGICAL HISTORY:  Includes end-stage renal disease, 
coronary artery disease with a bypass graft but without any chest 
pain at the time, and insulin dependent diabetes mellitus which may 
account for her previous cardiac history without chest pain. 
ALLERGIES:  PENICILLIN AND CODEINE 
MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin and Xanax. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Blood pressure 164/94, pulse 
94, respirations 24, oxygen saturation 96%.  GENERAL:  The patient 
is comfortable in no acute distress.  HEAD AND NECK: 
Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils equal and reactive. Pharynx 
benign.  Tongue is of normal shape and contour.  Neck is supple. 
No jugular venous distention.  LUNGS:  Are clear bilaterally. 
CARDIAC:  Regular rate and rhythm.  S1, S2, with no murmurs, rubs 
or gallops.  ABDOMEN:  Soft and non-tender with normal bowel 
sounds.  EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema or rash. 
NEUROLOGICAL:  Patient is alert and oriented x 3.  She moves all 
extremities.  Has symmetrical strength and all proximal and distal 
upper and lower motor bilaterally.  Normal sensation to light touch 
grossly. 
LABORATORY:  White blood cell count 9, hematocrit 41.  Glucose was 
high at 533.  However, she has bicarbonate of 24, so she is 
probably not in diabetic ketoacidosis.  BUN 31, creatinine 3.8. 
Troponin-I was 0.5.  Chest x-ray was negative.  Electrocardiogram 
shows normal sinus rhythm with left ventricular hypertrophy and 
non-specific ST/T wave changes.  Perhaps some ST depressions in II, 
III and AVF, and deep S waves in V1, 2, 3, and 4. 
TREATMENT RENDERED AND COURSE IN ED: In the hospital the patient 
did not have further chest pain here.  She was admitted for chest 
pain and for rule out myocardial infarction to the Medical Service. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Rule out myocardial infarction 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Admitted. 
___________________________________                    FD008/9052 
STEVE NUTT, M.D.       SN2                         D:03/31/98 
                                                       T:04/01/98 
Dictated by:  STEVE NUTT, M.D.       SN2 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>