<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2062-01-29

TRIBAL INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Hart, Matthew
                                              1-29-62
 
 
 
History of Present Illness: This was the first Internal Medicine clinic visit for 
this 38-year-old black male with a history of non-insulin dependent 
diabetes diagnosed a year ago, maintained on Diabeta 5 mg. q.d.  Also 
with a history of borderline hypertension previously on 
hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg. q.d. for the last year, which he discontinued 
last Sunday, who now comes in because over the last two to three weeks 
he has been having trouble with increased dizziness and headaches, and 
he is afraid that his sugar is up.  He states that over the last two or 
three weeks, he gets stars and floaters and sometimes halos of light 
followed by mild headaches.  He says that the visual changes are usually 
accompanied by the headache, and the headache is usually relieved with 
Excedrin in 5 minutes to an hour.  He does admit to a history of 
migraines but states that in the past his migraines have been much more 
severe than this, though the visual aura is very similar to his previous 
migraine aura.  
 
He states that he was seen in the emergency room on 1-12, at which time 
they did a finger stick which was about 180, and they told him to come 
to this appointment at this time.  He denies any fevers.  He does have a 
recent 25 lb weight gain and he admits to new nocturia of 2-3 times a 
night over the last three weeks.  He also has been complaining of 
diarrhea two or three times a week over the last two to three weeks, 
which is watery in nature without any blood.  He has no nausea or 
vomiting or any fever, and he has never had problems with diarrhea like 
this in the past.  His past medical history is otherwise benign.  
 
Habits:  He does have a history of cocaine abuse, and while he was free 
basing about one year ago, he came into the emergency room with chest 
pain and was told that this was secondary to lack of oxygen to his heart 
from the cocaine, since which time he has been using cocaine much less 
frequently.  He denies any tobacco use, and he drinks alcohol socially.  
He is currently unemployed and lives with his mother.  He is sexually 
active with one sexual partner and denies any other risk factors.
 
Family History:  His family history is notable for a grandmother with 
diabetes and hypertension, mother with heart disease and father with 
history of breast CA, who is currently getting radiation therapy here.  
His oldest brother died of street violence and his younger brother is 
alive and well without any medical problems. 
 
Physical Examination;  He is a mildly obese black male in no acute 
distress with weight of 270 lbs.  Blood pressure 138/88 in the right arm 
and 132/94 in the left arm.  Pulse regular at about 80.  HEENT was 
notable for normal fundi without any evidence of diabetic retinopathy or 
hypertensive retinopathy.  Oropharynx was clear.  He had no thyromegaly.  
His chest was clear.  His breasts showed no masses or discharge, and his 
                                              1-29-62
 
 
 
heart sounds were normal.  His abdomen was obese, soft, nontender, 
without any hepatosplenomegaly.  Genitalia: normal, with bilaterally 
descended testes, and his rectal exam was normal tone with brown trace 
heme positive stool.  Neurologic exam was intact. 
 
Assessment and Plan:  
 
1.   Non-insulin dependent diabetes with possible symptoms of increased 
     sugar at this time.  Will check a fasting blood sugar tomorrow 
     morning as well as a hemoglobin A1C, and may increase his Diabeta 
     to 10 mg. q.d.  He will be referred to a nutritionist for diet 
     control as well.  
2.   Hypertension: borderline hypertension at this time off meds.  I 
     will recheck his blood pressure in a week to two weeks, and if it 
     is still borderline at that time, will follow only with a low-salt 
     diet.  
3.   Trace heme positive stool: may be from his diarrhea.  I will get a 
     stool culture and O&P since the diarrhea is persistent for two to 
     three weeks, and follow it at this time.
4.   Patient requesting HIV test: and HIV counseling was given at this 
     point, and a test will be drawn, and I will give him the result 
     when it is back, though I feel that he is very low risk at this 
     time.  
 
 
_________________________
Cadence Barton, M.D. 
 
FL:RP:2786
DD:1-29-62
DT:1-30-62
DV:1-29-62




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2065-02-04

TRIBAL INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Hart, Matthew
                                              46103196
                                              2-4-65
 
 
 
HPI:  The patient is a 41 year old man with a history of non-insulin 
dependent diabetes, hypertension, obesity and substance abuse who I 
learned today was recently admitted for deep venous thrombosis and is 
presenting for follow up of his DVT.  The patient's current medical 
problems include:
1.   Recent DVT.  The patient was admitted between the days of 1-24 and 
     1-30 secondary to the development of a right lower extremity DVT.  
     The patient told me that he had been doing well and denied any 
     previous trauma to his leg or other predisposing factors such as long 
     car or airplane trips and he stated he had been as active as 
     previously over the recent few weeks.  The patient stated he awoke 
     in the morning of the 24th and noted tightness in his right 
     quadriceps and right calf.  He later developed progressive swelling 
     of the leg and therefore presented to the THD emergency 
     department.  He had lower extremity non-invasives performed which 
     confirmed the presence of a right lower extremity DVT.  He was 
     admitted and heparinized and then Coumadinized prior to discharge.  
     The patient disclosed a history that his daughter had a DVT at the 
     time of her pregnancy and therefore a hypercoagulability work-up was 
     sent off which was negative.  The patient currently returns to me 
     complaining of further right calf pain and swelling.  He states that 
     he was interested in physical therapy but states that that did not 
     occur during his hospital course.  The patient was also angry and 
     upset that I had not visited him during his hospital stay.  I 
     explained to him that I had not been notified of his admission or of 
     his emergency department visit.  I called all of the parties 
     responsible for his admission to clear the confusion that had 
     occurred.
 
2.   Hypertension.  The patient's previously been on anti-hypertensives 
     including lisinopril, unfortunately the patient has not tolerated ACE 
     inhibitors secondary to a severe cough and therefore these were 
     discontinued recently.  With a discontinuation of his drinking, the 
     patient's blood pressures have been under much better control.
 
3.   Adult onset diabetes mellitus.  I recently started the patient on 
     insulin.  He was scheduled for a follow up visit but unfortunately 
     did not make his visit.  His insulin dose was adjusted during his 
     recent hospitalization and his current dosage is 35 units of NPH in 
     the morning and 15 units of regular.  In the evening he takes 10 
     units of NPH and 10 units of regular.  The patient does not yet have 
     a home glucometer.  We will arrange for this.
 
THD INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Hart, Matthew
Page 2                                        46103196
                                              2-4-65
 
 
 
Physical Examination:  Vital signs showed a heart rate of 90.  Blood 
pressure: 135/92. Respiratory rate: 14 and unlabored.  HEENT: pupils 
equal, round and reactive to light, extraocular movements intact, 
oropharynx clear. Mucous membranes moist. Cardiac: regular rate and 
rhythm, normal S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  Lungs: clear to 
ausculation. Abdomen soft, nontender with active bowel sounds.  
Extremities:  There was notable edema of his right lower extremity with 
significant pain and a positive Homan's sign.  
 
Impression:
1)   DVT.  Given his current physical examination, and lack of recent PT 
     check since time of discharge on the 30th, I am sending a stat PT.  I 
     encouraged the patient to elevate the leg. My feeling is that the DVT 
     has not successfully been treated and that likely his PT is not 
     therapeutic at the present time.  I have arranged for the patient to 
     follow up with Aguilar, the Internal Medicine nurse, on Wednesday for a repeat 
     check of his PT.  I left instructions that I should be called 
     immediately upon receiving the PT value, I also arranged for the 
     patient to meet with the physical therapist for the provision of a 
     cane to help with ambulation. 
 
2)   Adult onset diabetes.  I will recheck a hemoglobin A1C value at his 
     next office visit.  A finger stick in the office approximately three 
     hours after eating is 253.  I feel this is still too elevated.  I 
     will therefore adjust his insulin dose when I see him next week.  I 
     will follow up with the patient next week and make any necessary 
     adjustments in his medications at that time.
 
 
 
_________________________
Michael Uecker, M.D. 
 
PD:UD:1698
DD:2-19-65
DT:2-22-65
DV:2-4-65




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-03-09

TRIBAL HEALTH DEPARTMENT
Tribal Internal Medicine Associates
32 Cambridge St                             Hart, Matthew
Lonaconing, CT  91197                             46103196
829-1293                                      3-09-67
 
 
 
HPI:  The patient is a 43 year old man with multiple medical problems 
who presents for routine follow up.
 
CURRENT ISSUES:
1.   Adult onset diabetes mellitus.  The patient had a hemoglobin A1C 
     approximately a month and a half ago, which was 9.5.  We discussed 
     this in the office today, with the general concept that someone who 
     is taking three injections of insulin a day should have much 
     tighter control.  He states he has been following his finger 
     sticks, though admits that occasionally forgets to do this. His 
     current regimen is 35 units of NPH in the morning with 20 units of 
     regular.  At bedtime, he is taking 35 units of NPH and 6 units of 
     regular at dinnertime.  He denies any symptoms of hypoglycemia.
2.   Hypercholesterolemia.  Of note, the patient recently experienced a 
     rash to his simvastatin.  This resolved on the discontinuation of 
     the simvastatin.  Of note, his most recent cholesterol was 314 in 
     January, 2067.  He has met with the dietician to discuss the 
     institution of a low-fat diet, and states that he tries to avoid 
     fats.
3.   Venous insufficiency secondary to deep venous thrombosis.  The 
     patient states he is doing better since the institution of a 
     Jobst stocking.  He still notes significant edema when he doesn't 
     wear this, but notes an improvement in ambulation when he is 
     compliant with the stocking.
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Blood pressure:  130/90.  Heart rate:  76.  
Respiratory rate:  12 and unlabored.  Cardiac exam:  Regular rate and 
rhythm, normal S1 and S2, no murmurs.  Lungs are clear to auscultation.  
Abdomen:  Soft, non-tender, obese, with active bowel sounds.  
Extremities show no clubbing or cyanosis.  There is 1+ pedal edema of 
the right lower extremity, which is covered with a Jobst stocking.  Foot 
care remains excellent.
 
IMPRESSION:                         
1.   Adult onset diabetes mellitus.  We will increase the patient's 
     morning NPH dose to 40 units.  He will once again try to become 
     more compliant with his diet.  He will be scheduled for a follow up 
     ophthalmologic examination.
2.   Hypercholesterolemia.  We will hold off re-starting therapy given 
     his recent rash to simvastin.  We will re-check a fasting lipid 
     profile as well as a set of LFT's.
TRIBAL HEALTH DEPARTMENT
Tribal Internal Medicine Associates
01 Cambridge St                             Hart, Matthew
Lonaconing, CT  91197                             46103196
829-1293                                      3-09-67
 
 
 
PAGE 2
 
3.   General health maintenance.  We will once again schedule a follow 
     up examination with the dietician as well as the ophthalmologist.  
     He will keep a log of his sugars and follow up with me in the 
     clinic in approximately one to two months.
 
 
 
_________________________
Michael Uecker, M.D.
 
GG:XO:4403
DD:3-27-67
DT:3-27-67
DV:3-09-67
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Preceptor HINES,ALEXANDER SAMMY,M.D. Note:
Pt seen with Dr. Uecker.  Rash resolved off simvastatin.  Blood sugar and BP
sub-optimally controlled.  Agree with plan to increase BP meds and moniotr
FSGs more closely.  Fasting lipid profile prior to restarting statin.
Alexander Hines, MD
 ******** Approved by Attending HINES,ALEXANDER SAMMY,M.D. ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-03-28

Other CARDIOLOGY F8 - INTERN ADMIT NOTE
Hosptial Room: 
Attending: Carroll (Cardiology)
PCP: Smith (Internal Medicine)
Speciailists: Carroll (Cardiology)Chief Complaint Abnormal stress testHistory of Present Illness 55yo M with a history of IDDM, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, ESRD (on HD), h/o DVT (positive lupus anticoagulant), osteoarthritis was scheduled for elective hip surgery 3/29/77. For his pre-operative work-up, the patient had a stress PET exam on 3/26 that was notable for a medium-sized defect of moderate intensity in the mid and basal inferior and inferolateral walls that was reversible. As a result, the patient was referred to Dr. Carroll who saw the patient in clinic on 3/27. Given the patient's risk factors and positive stress test, the patient was scheduled for right and left heart catheterization on the day of admission with the plan to delay his hip surgery if he requires a stent and subsequent Plavix therapy. On the evening prior to his catheterization, he had dialysis.
 
The patient went to the cath lab where he was found to have an 80% lesion of the mid-RCA so a bare-metal stent was placed. After cath, the patient was started on ASA 325mg PO daily and Plavix loaded with 600mg PO x 1 then 75mg PO daily thereafter. He was also given Warfarin 8mg PO x 1 for an INR of 1.6.Review of Systems negative except as abovePast Medical History 1. IDDM (A1c 6.9, neuropathy)
2. Hypertension
3. Hyperlipidemia
4. ESRD (on HD, s/p AVF)
5. h/o DVT x 2 &amp; PE x 1 (positive lupus anticoagulant)
6. Osteoarthritis
7. h/o bladder cancer treated by "scraping"
8. Obesity
9. GERD
10. s/p skin graft from hip to foot for burn
11. s/p amputation of two toes on R foot for infectionMedications ASA 81mg PO daily
Folic acid 1mg PO daily
Gemfibrozil 600mg PO BID
Insulin lantus 50u SC QPM
Lipitor 80mg PO QPM
Insulin Lispro 10-15u AC
Nephrocaps 1tab PO daily
Nifedipine ER 30mg PO daily
Phoslo 1334mg PO TID
Protonix 40mg PO daily
Soma 350mg PO QID PRN spasms
Viagra 100mg PO PRN
Zetia 10mg PO daily
Toprol XL 25mg PO daily
WarfarinAllergies Codeine, Cephalosporins, SimvastatinFamily History Is remarkable for father at 81 years of age who has had breast and prostate cancer more than 15 years ago and has chronic lung disease currently.  His mother died at 73 years of age after an operative intervention.  Two brothers have been killed by shooting, one by police, and one by an unknown assailant.  The patient reports having 10 children and 21 grandchildren, three of his children have diabetes.Social History Retired on disability and previously worked for West Liberty Foods.  He is not married but has been living with his common-law wife for 34 years.Habits Tob:
EtOH:
Illicits:Vital Signs T           HR              BP                 RR                O2 SAT                 WTPhysical Exam  General Appearance NAD, pleasant, obese   HEENT NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, arcus senilis, OP clear, MMMNeck supple, no LAD, no JVD, no bruits, 2+ carotids   Chest good inspiratory effort, CTAB, no crackles/wheezes   Cor/Cardiac RRR, S1 S2, no M/R/G, no thrills/lifts/heavesAbdomen +BS, S/NT/ND, no hepatomegaly, no splenomegaly   Genito-Urinary DeferredExtremity No C/C/E, 2+ radials, 2+ DP, 2+ PTNeurological A&amp;O x 3 (place, person, time), face symmetric, fluent speech, moving all extremities, sensation grossly intactSkin No gross abnormalities   Nodes/Lymphatic No LADResults 3/28
INR 1.6
 
3/27
141/5.3/94/31/80/11.17/192, Ca 9.0
ALT 13, AST 15, TBili 0.3, AlkP 109
CK 176
7.35&gt;36.3&lt;424
INR 1.5Diagnostic Testing EKG: NSR 87bpm, no ST-T changes (unchanged from prior)
 
Stress PET: The patient's PET-CT test results are abnormal and consistent with a medium sized region of moderate dipyridamole induced peprfusion defect in the distribution of an OM coronary artery.Assessment and Plan 55yo M with a history of obesity, diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia with a positive pre-operative stress test now s/p cardiac catheterization. 
 
# CV (I): The patient had an abnormal stress test and is now s/p cardiac cath.
- telemetry
- lipids and A1c in AM
- ASA, Plavix, statin, BB
- consider the addition of an ACEi especially given history of diabetes
 
# ESRD: On the evening prior to cath the patient had HD and will have HD tomorrow.
- renal aware
- continue phoslo, nephrocaps
 
# DM: Last A1c was 6.9.
- check A1c in AM
- Lantus 55u SC QPM, Aspart 10u SC AC, Aspart SS AC + HS
 
# Hypertension: 
- continue nifedipine and metoprolol
 
# Hyperlipidemia:
- check lipids in AM
- continue lipitor, zetia, gemofibrozil
 
# Osteoarthritis: Elective surgery now deferred since patient is s/p stent and on necessary Plavix
- percocet PRN
- carisoprodol PRN
 
# h/o DVT: Currently on Coumadin but subtherapeutic. The patient received 8mg PO x 1 in the cath lab.
- follow INR daily
- continue home Coumadin
 
# FEN: 
- renal/cardiac/diabetic diet
 
# PPX:
- coumadinContact Info Edith Vandiver (significant other) 216-669-9576Code Status FULL CODE



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-06-14

EDVISIT^46103196^HART, MATTHEW^06/14/79^NAPOLITANO, URSULA

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 56-year-old male

with a history of end-stage renal disease on hemodialysis,

history of coronary artery disease, diabetes, hypertension, and

DVT on Coumadin who comes in to the ER because he has recently

missed dialysis appointment and he feels increased abdominal

girth and shortness of breath.  He said that his father has been

sick, so he has been spending a significant amount of time

helping him and because of that had a short dialysis on Wednesday

and missed his Friday dialysis run.  Today is Sunday and he

generally gets dialysis on Sunday as well.  When I asked if he

has been having chest pain, he says he has not had chest pain,

but he did have a tickling in his chest that lasted seconds and

was not accompanying with any diaphoresis or radiation of the

pain.  Even he was ambulatory into the ED, he had no chest pain

when he was exerting himself.  He does feel slightly increased

shortness of breath and worse when he walks around, but he thinks

that because of increased fluids.  He has had no fevers or

chills, no lightheadedness, no nausea, vomiting and no diarrhea.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  End-stage renal disease on hemodialysis,

coronary artery disease, hyperlipidemia, osteoarthritis,

diabetes, DVT on Coumadin, hypertension, bladder cancer,

substance abuse and GERD.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  AV fistula in 01/2078.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  No tobacco, rare alcohol and occasional cocaine

use.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Breast cancer and prostate cancer.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As mentioned in HPI, otherwise negative.

MEDICATIONS:  Reviewed, please see the list.

ALLERGIES:  Include cephalosporin and simvastatin.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Temperature 97.3, heart rate 92,

respiratory rate 28, blood pressure 155/84 and O2 saturation 100%

on room air.  The patient is awake, alert, talking in complete

sentences, appears to be mildly uncomfortable.  ENT:  Atraumatic.

 Neck:  Normal to inspection, supple.  Chest:  Clear to

auscultation bilaterally, no rales.  Cardiovascular:  Regular

rate and rhythm, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  Abdomen:  Minimal

distention, soft.  No focal tenderness.  Skin is intact. 

Extremities:  No lower extremity swelling or edema, no calf

tenderness bilaterally.  Neuropsychiatric:  Oriented x3.  Cranial

nerves II through XII tested and intact.  No motor or sensory

deficits.  Gait is normal.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient received an EKG, which

showed normal sinus rhythm.  No significant ST or T

abnormalities, no significant peaked T waves are consistent with

his previous EKG.  PA lateral chest x-ray showed no evidence of

acute cardiopulmonary infiltrates.  Only labs which resulted

initially were CBC, which showed a hematocrit of 33.2, platelets

423,000 and white count of 6.74.  We made contact with the renal

fellow who recommended that we proceed dialysis while the

dialysis unit still open and we felt that it was safe for this

patient.  His potassium was not back at the time that he left the

department, however, he was well appearing and had no arrhythmias

on the monitor and we think that his tickling chest sensation is

very atypical for cardiac symptom, not being, so we will reassess

when he comes back and likely check a second troponin to be sure

that this is unlikely to be acute coronary syndrome.  After he

left the department, additional labs came back include INR of 2.1

and a Chem-7 showing a sodium of 142, a potassium of 6.4, a

chloride of 102, bicarbonate of 21, BUN of 106, creatinine 6.18,

glucose of 195, CK of 157, troponin of less than 0.04, calcium

8.6, phosphorus of 5.1, and magnesium of 2.3 and promptly called

the renal fellow who was aware of the elevated potassium and have

the patient on the monitor in the Dialysis Unit and agreed to

treat him there acutely.  Again after the dialysis, the patient

will return to the Emergency Department.  We will reassess if

symptoms and see how he feels, check a second cardiac enzymes. 

If he feels significantly improved and he continues to have no

chest pain, we feel that his symptoms are likely atypical for

acute coronary syndrome and we also called that this was not

acute coronary syndrome if two troponins are not elevated and he

will be able to follow up and resume his regular dialysis

schedule.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Volume overload.

SECONDARY DIAGNOSIS:  End-stage renal disease, on hemodialysis.

DISPOSITION:  Pending.

Please see ED note for further ED course.  This was a shared

visit with resident physician, Dr. Adam Mcclure.

______________________________

NAPOLITANO, URSULA M.D.

D: 06/14/79

T: 06/14/79

Dictated By: NAPOLITANO, URSULA

eScription document:4-65347834 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>