<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2126-01-29

Personal Data and Overall Health	

53 year old male scheduled for surgery on February 6th.



Chief Complaint	

The patient is scheduled for left total hip replacement.



History of Present Illness	

The patient complains of pain of left hip secondary to osteoarthritis.



Past Surgical History	

Prior surgery includes:  none



Family History	

There in no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.



Past Medical History	

Current medical problems include:  obesity



Social History	

Smoking: no

Alcohol use: 3-4beers/day

Substance abuse: none

Allergen Exposure within 3 Months (blood/pregnancy/surgery):  none



Review of Systems	

Medications: Celebrex, Vicodin

Allergies:  penicillin cause swelling and difficulty breathing

Cardiovascular:  no history of hypertension, no MI; denies CP, DOE, syncope, ankle edema

Respiratory: no history of asthma or chronic lung disease; denies unusual shortness of breath

Neurological: no history of neurological problems

Gastrointestinal: no history of PUD; denies reflux

Hepatobiliary: no history of liver disease; denies jaundice or hepatitis

Renal/Genitourinary: no history of renal failure; denies hematuria, dysuria, obstructive uropathy

Musculoskeletal: pain of left hip

Endocrine/metabolic: no history of diabetes, no endocrinopathy 

Heme/Onc:  no history of bleeding, blood diseases; no history of malignancy, chemotherapy, or radiation therapy

Psychiatric: no significant psychiatric problems





Exam	

SaO2:97

Ht:5'11"

Wt:312

BP:142/79

P:84



HEEN&T:  good range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat, no bruits

Airway:  Mallampatti Class II

Teeth:  in good repair

Lungs:  clear bilaterally

Heart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop

Abdomen:  not examined

Extremities:  not examined



Assessment	

ASA Physical Status:  II

Well prepared for surgery; no unusual concerns related to medical problems.



Plan	

Proposed Anesthetic: spinal or general anesthesia

Monitors:  standard

Pain Management:  IVPCA

Autologous blood:  none

Premedication:  none

Usual Medications:  take on day of surgery

Medications to be held on day of surgery:  none

Diabetic medications:  not applicable

NSAIDS:  avoid for 3 days before surgery

Aspirin:  avoid for 7 days before surgery

NPO: after midnight 



External Labs	

Not available



Attending Anesthesiologist Reassessment Note	

I have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with the following exceptions:







______________________________                              



Patton, Chong, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2132-10-03


10/03/2132
Greg Overman, MD
Brooksville Regional Hospital
55 Overlook Drive
Edgefield, WI 18421
RE: URQUHART, WENDELL Y
MRN: 5747359
DOB: 11/22/2072


Dear Dr. Overman: 
I had the pleasure of seeing your patient, Wendell Urquhart, in consultation today. The patient presents complaining of lower back pain with right lower extremity radiation. He develop symptoms gradually three months ago with no history of preceding trauma. The symptoms became progressively worse. The patient has a history of lower back injury 30 years ago in a motor vehicle accident - at that time he was diagnosed with disc rupture. Currently the pain is intermittent and occurs daily. He grades the intensity of the pain as up to 7 to 8 out of 10 on the numerical pain scale. He describes it as sharp shooting sensation in the lower back with radiation all the way down right lower extremity to the foot. The symptoms are worse with standing; better with sitting and lying down. There is no change in the intensity of symptoms with coughing or sneezing. The patient any recent fever or chills, no loss of bowel or bladder control. He describes occasional intermittent numbness in the right leg and foot. He denies any weakness. He lost 30 pounds through dieting over the past two months. The pain does not wake the patient up at night. 
Diagnostically, the patient denies any recent imaging studies of the lumbar spine. 


Therapeutically, the patient denies any recent physical therapy; no previous injections or surgical procedures of the lumbar spine. Currently he takes nabumetone 750 mg once in the morning with moderate relief of his symptoms. He also occasionally takes Naproxen at night with moderate relief. 
MEDICATIONS: 
1. Aspirin. 
2. Hydrochlorothiazide. 
3. Toprol. 
4. Caduet. 
5. Nabumetone as needed. 
6. Naproxen as needed. 
ALLERGIES: Penicillin. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: 
1. Coronary artery disease status post 2 stent placements. 
2. Hypertension. 
PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: 
1. Cardiac stent placement. 
2. Left total hip replacement. 
SOCIAL HISTORY: The patient works as a programmer for Dish Network. He is married with no children. He does not smoke, drinks alcohol socially, and denies illicit drug use. 
FAMILY HISTORY: There is no history of medical problems that run in the family. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: The complete review of systems was performed including constitutional, eyes, ENT, cardiovascular, respiratory, GI, GU, musculoskeletal, integument, neurological, psychiatric, endocrine, lymphatic, and immunologic. It is positive for musculoskeletal complains and medical problems as above.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is well-developed, moderately overweight man in no acute distress. He is alert and oriented to time, person and place. His mood and affect are stable. He demonstrates good attention and concentration. The patient ambulates without an assistive device with normal heel strike and toe off.  He is able to stand on his heels and toes. He is able to walk heel to toe in a straight line with intact balance. Vital signs are stable. Sclera is anicteric, no ptosis noted, no lymphadenopathy, unlabored respiration, abdomen is soft and non-tender, no skin rash.  


There is limited range of motion in the lumbar spine with flexion limited to 60 degrees, extension limited to 10 degrees. There is no tenderness to palpation over the spinous processes, paraspinal muscles, SI joints or greater trochanteric bursae bilaterally. There is full 5/5 strength in the lower extremities with intact sensation bilaterally.  1+ reflexes in the knees, absent reflexes in the ankles bilaterally. There is downgoing Babinski, no clonus, normal tone in the lower extremities. Straight leg raise test is negative bilaterally. There is no pain with hip internal and external rotation. 



Cervical range of motion is within normal limit. There is no tenderness to palpation over cervical spinous processes and paraspinal muscles. There is full 5/5 strength in the upper extremities with intact sensation bilaterally. Symmetrical reflexes in the biceps, brachioradialis and triceps bilaterally. Negative Hoffmans sign and Spurlings maneuver.  The range of motion in bilateral upper extremities is normal. 
IMAGING: During today's visit I reviewed x-ray study of the pelvis dated September 24 2132. it demonstrates lumbosacral spondylosis in the visualized lumbosacral spine. 
For complete description of the study, please see formal radiology report. 
IMPRESSION: 
1. Sub-acute lower back pain with right lower extremity radiation, non-focal neurological examination. 
2. Lumbar radiculitis. 
3. Degenerative disc disease. 
4. Lumbar spondylosis. 
RECOMMENDATIONS: 
1. MRI study of the lumbar spine will be obtained to further evaluate etiology of ongoing symptoms. The patient will discuss with radiologist if MRI study can not be performed due to cardiac stents. 
2. Upon review of the imaging studies, a lumbar epidural steroid injection would be considered to decrease the inflammatory component of his symptoms and to inhibit peripheral nociceptive transmission. 
3. The patient was encouraged to remain active and to participate in low-impact aerobic exercises to prevent deconditioning. He was encouraged to continue with weight loss program. 
4. The therapeutic plan was discussed with the patient. All of his questions were answered. He will be seen in follow-up after imaging study is completed in 1-2 weeks. 



Thank you for allowing me to participate in the care of your patient. Please do not hesitate to call my office for any further questions. 


Sincerely,






__________________________
Ubaldo R. Daugherty, MD 
cc: Dr. Tawn Johanson, 73 Elm Court, Rm. 54, Albertville, WI 63721
DD: 10/03/2132
TD: 10/04/2132 13:34:19
TR: 5315751
BackJob ID: 852182
VoiceJob ID: 45936320




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2133-06-25


Visit Note




Patient Name: URQUHART, WENDELL Y                                          MRN: 5747359



Dictated Date: 06/25/2133                                        Dictated By: Ubaldo Daugherty, MD
.



Date of Visit: 06/25/2133








CHIEF COMPLAINT: Right buttock pain with right lower extremity radiation. 




HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  I had the pleasure of seeing Wendell Urquhart in follow-up today. He underwent right piriformis injection under fluoroscopic guidance on 06/10/2133. The patient reports greater than 50% improvement in his symptoms after the procedure. Currently the pain is intermittent. He describes it as sore sensation in the right buttock. He grades intensity of pain as 2/10 on the numerical pain scale. The symptoms are worse with prolonged walking for more than 2 miles a day and completely alleviated with rest. There is no change in the intensity of symptoms with Valsalva maneuver. The patient denies any recent fever or chills, no loss of bowel or bladder control, no numbness, no weakness, no unexplained weight loss. 





REVIEW OF MEDICAL HISTORY: During today's visit, I have reviewed past medical, social and family history, medication list and allergies. There has been no interval change as compared to the previous visit. REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Positive for musculoskeletal complains as described above. No recent fever, no chills, no chest pain, no shortness of breath, no abdominal pain, no loss of bowel or bladder control, no unexplained weight loss. The rest of the systems were reviewed and are negative.



PHYSICAL EXAM: The patient is alert and oriented to time, person and place. His mood and affect are stable. He demonstrates good attention and concentration. He ambulates without an assistive device with normal heel strike and toe-off. He is able to stand on heels and toes. He is able to walk heel-to-toe in a straight line with intact balance. There is limited range of motion in the lumbar spine with flexion limited to 80 degrees, extension limited to 20 degrees. There is no tenderness to palpation over piriformis muscles, paraspinal muscles, spinous processes, SI joints, or greater trochanteric bursa bilaterally. There is full 5/5 strength in the lower extremities with intact sensation bilaterally. 1+ reflexes in the knees, absent reflexes in the ankles bilaterally. There is downgoing Babinski, no clonus, normal tone in the lower extremities. Straight leg raise and femoral stretch test are negative bilaterally. There is pain with right hip internal rotation. 




IMPRESSION:

1.  Piriformis syndrome.

2.  Lumbar spondylosis with degenerative disk disease.

3.  Right hip arthropathy.




RECOMMENDATIONS:

1.  I had lengthy discussion with the patient about his condition and further treatment options. The patient will continue with home exercise program that he learned in physical therapy.

2.  The patient was encouraged to remain active and to participate in low-impact aerobic exercises as along as it does not exacerbate his symptoms.

3.  The patient was counseled on the benefits of weight reduction. He was informed about Weight Center here at Brooksville Regional Hospital. He is trying to control his weight through a balanced diet and aerobic exercises. He will consider an evaluation at the Weight Center if those approaches are not successful.

4.  The therapeutic plan was discussed with the patient. All of his questions were answered. In fact greater than 50% of today&#8217;s 25 minute visit was spent on counseling and coordination of care. I asked the patient to follow-up with me as needed if his symptoms return. 




It was my pleasure to follow-up with him.







___________________________

Ubaldo Daugherty, MD
.




cc:






TD: 06/25/2133 09:13:37

TR: 7765393

BackJob ID:  780753

VoiceJob ID:  06100547







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2134-02-15

EDVISIT^72484104^URQUHART, WENDELL^02/15/34^MARQUEZ, RONALD

I evaluated this patient independently.  I concur with findings

as noted on the medical record, supervised the care as provided

by the resident in the Emergency Department.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  In brief, this is a 61-year-old male

with complaint of chest discomfort on exertion for the past six

weeks after climbing upstairs.  The patient noticed symptoms

again today.  He called his FLH physician who sent him to the

Emergency Department for probable admission.  The patient has had

a prior history of proximal RCA lesion and two stents placed in

06/2128 after similar episodes.  The patient has been doing well

since and recently has developed worsening symptoms.  He is

followed by Dr. Ure and contacted Dr. Ure's office who

sent him to the Emergency Department.  He denies chest pain at

rest.  He does not have abdominal pain.  No pain radiating to the

back.  No shortness of breath, dysuria, or additional symptoms.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension and coronary artery disease.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  As noted, past surgical history is stent

placement.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Past tobacco user.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Significant for that which is noted on the

HPI.  All other symptoms are negative as noted in the medical

record.

MEDICATIONS:  Please refer to the chart.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Vital signs are as noted in the medical

record.  I examined this patient and agree with physical exam

findings as noted on the record.  Please refer to the chart.  Of

note, the patient has no specific physical exam findings, a

benign physical examination.

LABORATORY DATA:  Pending.  EKG is normal sinus rhythm with

biphasic T waves in III, V6 but otherwise normal, no acute ST-T

wave changes.  The patient is currently pain free.

ASSESSMENT AND MEDICAL DECISION MAKING:  This is a 61-year-old

male with likely stable angina that is worsening in character. 

He will be admitted to Cardiology.  I discussed this case with

the cardiologist on call, Dr. Maxwell.  The patient will be

admitted for further workup and determination of catheterization

if necessary.

______________________________

MARQUEZ, RONALD M.D.

D: 02/15/34

T: 02/15/34

Dictated By: MARQUEZ, RONALD

eScription document:8-9594396 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>