<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2114-02-17

 
 
 
                                                          (391) 293-7888
PARK VIEW HOSPITAL
 
 
 
February 17, 2114
 
 
Dr. Nunes 
Oppintong or 
Lambertville
 
 
RE:  Craft, Lloyd                                                    
MRN: 26649180                                                           
  
Dear Dr. Nunes:
 
Thank you for asking me to see Mr. Craft. Patient says he was diagnosed 
as having neuropsychiatric lupus in 2103 at the Vermilion Hospital by Dr. Parker 
Xian and was treated with steroids at the time. It's not clear what CNS 
or neuropsychiatric manifestation he had at the time. Because of complex 
partial seizures he was seen by Dr. Arce at the Livingstone Homes who 
referred him to Dr. Hoffman at the Livingstone Homes who said that his 
estradiol level was in the 80s. His testosterone was up but available 
testosterone was down so he was put on Clomid and testolactone which he 
said turned off the lupus and turned off his seizures. Said he was doing 
fine until around 2 weeks ago when he felt that his lupus recurred. He 
said his neck felt full and warm. His head felt like it was going to 
explode. He had tinnitus, excess saliva, he felt that his lower jaw was 
vibrating and when he lay on his pillow his neck felt like it wasn't 
right. Also about the time he developed a cold with runny nose and 
postnasal drip. Lab work on February 8 showed a normal CBC, urine, and 
anti-DNA (in 2103 his ANA was positive at 1:1024 but I don't have any 
other results). He's had no fevers, no rashes other than a folliculitis 
on his legs. No new problem with head, ears, eyes, nose, throat, teeth 
or gum except that he has to wear his glasses. Recently had some teeth 
removed. Has a postnasal drip with a little bit of a cough. No other 
cardiorespiratory problems but takes Altace for mild hypertension. No GI 
problems. Has urinary frequency due to nocturia ever 2 hours, due to 
benign prostatic hypertrophy and recently had a TUR. Dr. Nunes 
RE:  Craft, Lloyd                             
MRN: 26649180                        
February 17, 2114
Page 2
 
 
A PSA has been normal. Past history of kidney stones. He's allergic to 
penicillin, Lozol, allopurinol and bee venom. Has a past history of 
diagnosis of gout versus pseudogout. Sleeps fine. No history of fractures. 
Only operation is a total knee replacement on the left for arthritis and 
appendectomy. Bruises easily, frequently has headaches. Has been diagnosed 
as being bipolar. Exercises.
 
Recent MRI consistent with a "vasculopathy."
 
Family history. Mother died of colon cancer at 62, smoked. Father died 
at 62 of heart attack, stroke and insulin dependent diabetes, also 
smoked. He is an only child.
 
Social history. Doesn't smoke. When he's depressed he becomes a binge 
drinker. Exercises when he's not depressed. He's retired since 2103. Was 
a stage manager.
 
Physical exam. Somewhat overweight gentleman. Blood pressure was 160/80. 
Pulse was 88 and regular. Skin, a hint of livedo reticularis on 
forearms, and a couple of infected hair follicles around his knees. One 
small node in the left side of his neck. Mouth and throat was clear. 
Bilateral nasal polyp more on the right than left. Ear drums fine. 
Hearing fine (tuning fork in the middle of the forehead was heard in the 
forehead). Chest clear. No CVA tenderness. Heart: No murmurs. Abdomen, 
no organs, masses, tenderness but obese. Extremity, joint exam fine. 
Neurological fine.
 
I do not think that his lupus has acted up but think most of his current 
symptoms could be explained by an upper respiratory tract infection. 
However, I suspect he might have the antiphospholipid antibody syndrome 
and therefore have tested him for that, and also for complement level to 
also exclude lupus and vasculitis. Basically I told him to take Flonase 
twice a day until his ringing in the ear cleared up and postnasal drip 
cleared up. 
 
In the meantime continue on the Lamictal 100 mg twice a day as a 
stabilizer, Risperdal 0.25 mg per day as a mood stabilizer, the 
testolactone 50 mg 4 times a day to increase the availability of 
testosterone, the Clomid (clomiphene citrate) 50 mg per day to decrease 
estradiol, Levoxyl 50 mcg twice a day, Altace 10 mg twice a day regarding 
hypertension, and ibuprofen 800 mg twice a day for low back pain. Patient 
also gave me 2 pages of notes similar to what he had including comments 
regarding increased appetite, decreased memory, 
Dr. Nunes 
RE:  Craft, Lloyd                             
MRN: 26649180                        
February 17, 2114
Page 3
 
 
decreased cognitive function, decreased balance, fatigue, decreased 
hearing, a history of carotid sinus, hypersensitivity, question of 
cholinergic transmission problems.
 
Also should be noted that a lot of his symptoms coincided with taking 
Aricept to improve his memory. Took it for 10 days and hasn't taken it 
for 2 weeks but his symptoms persisted. 
 
Thank you again for asking me to see him. Please let me know if I can be 
of further assistance. 
 
Sincerely yours,
 
 
 
Richard Aviles, M.D.
 
PS: If you could give me some information of what evidence there was 
that he had systemic lupus and neuropsychiatric lupus back in 2103 at 
the Vermilion Hospital, for instance the discharge summary from the Vermilion Hospital, that would be appreciated.
 
 
JP:BT:6157                                       
DD:2-17-2114                                     
DT:2-21-2114                                     




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2114-03-16

 
 
March 16, 2114
 
Brice Short, M.D.
671 Foundation Street
Lambertville, OK  66399
 
RE:Craft, Lloyd
MRN:26649180
 
Dear Dr. Short:
 
Today I had the delight of seeing your patient Mr. Craft for the 
possibility of central nervous system vasculitis.  As you know, he 
is a 64 year old, right-handed man with an extensive past medical 
history for a rheumatological disease.  His past medical history, 
briefly, is that he was diagnosed with lupus in 2103 and at that 
time he had a butterfly rash, he complained of chronic fatigue and 
he also had what was considered temporal lobe seizures which were 
characterized as complex partial type events, and elevated double-
stranded DNA of 1:80 and ANA of 1:512 with a homogenous pattern.  
All of these suggested that the patient did have lupus.  He was 
treated for approximately three years with prednisone and he notes 
that after medications were added by Dr. Taliyah Hoffman, his 
symptoms and seizures went away.  Since that time, he has had a 
recurrence of symptoms which includes fullness of his face and 
neck, pressure within his head.  He considers himself to have 
vascular headaches with facial weakness, ringing in his ears, 
numbness and tingling of his left hand and arm, excessive 
salivation and increased appetite. In describing his headache, he 
noted that it is primarily a headache which is there every day and 
has a combination of throbbing sensation as well as throbbing 
quality.  It is worse in the frontal temporal area and is not 
associated with nausea, vomiting or paraesthesias.  There is no 
family history of migraines as well.  Also during his headache 
events, he does not notice any decrease in his appetite or any 
nausea or vomiting.
 
Past medical history:  As per above.  Medicval issues include 
bipolar II with ____________ diagnosed in 2110, hypothalamic 
gonadism, hypothalamic hypothyroidism and questionable history of 
migraine headaches.  
 
His current medications include Lamictal, Risperdal, testolactone, 
chromisene, Levoxyl, Altace for hypertension, ibuprofen p.r.n. and 
prednisone p.r.n.  
 
He is allergic to penicillin, Lozol, bee stings and allopurinol.  
There is a questionable history to Aricept which he feels that the 
use of this medication made his current symptoms come out of 
remission.
 
 
Brice Short, M.D.
RE:Craft, Lloyd
MRN:26649180
3-16-14
Page 2
 
 
 
Family history is remarkable for insulin dependent diabetes 
mellitus in father and father also had heart disease.  
 
Social history:  He is a former stage manager.  
 
Neurological exam:  He was awake, alert, oriented x 3.  Attention 
was normal.  Speech was fluent, without dysarthria or paraphasic 
errors.  There is no memory deficit or agnosia.  The patient gave 
a very detailed history of events and no further detailed mental 
status testing was performed.  Cranial nerves:  Bilateral visual 
fields were full.  Disks were sharp.  Fundus was clear.  
Extraocular movements were intact.  There was no nystagmus.  He 
had normal facial sensation and symmetry.  Hearing was grossly 
normal.  Uvula, tongue and palate were midline.  Motor examination 
revealed normal tone and bulk with normal strength.  Deep tendon 
reflexes were symmetrical.  There was no upper motor neuron sign.  
Coordination and gait were normal.  
 
Overall impression:  64 year old, right-handed male with a history 
of lupus in the past.  His recent blood work shows that his 
double-stranded DNA was negative.  Taking into consideration his 
current constellation of symptoms and his MRI reports that I 
evaluated which were completely normal except for small vascular 
disease, at this time he does not fit with the diagnosis of 
central nervous system vasculitis.  He was told that he is at a 
high risk for having a stroke secondary to (1) having high blood 
pressure and (2) having an elevated cholesterol.  If it is 
possible to maintain his blood pressure in good control and start 
a cholesterol-lowering agent, he is to discuss this with you, and 
also consider starting aspirin 81mg PO q.d. for primary prevention 
of heart disease.  He was informed that it is possible that there 
is some element of his immune system fluctuations and possibly his 
hormonal therapies may be contributing to some of his 
symptomatology but the diagnosis or etiology of these symptoms is 
not clear.  
 
Thank you for letting me take part in your patient's healthcare.
 
Sincerely, 
 
 
 
Clarence K. Hart, M.D. 
 
 
Brice Short, M.D.
RE:Craft, Lloyd
MRN:26649180
3-16-14
Page 3
 
 
 
cc:
Mr. Lloyd Craft
009 Buchanan St
Opp, OK  21785
 
YF:LN:4843/DD:3-16-14/DT:3-22-14 
 
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2119-06-22

Vermillion Weight Center

57 King Street, 5th floor

Newberry, OK  62981

Tel.  895.376.3157
Fax.  320.821.2954

Initial Medical Consultation Follow-up



Referred by: Dr. Juan Yun, psychopharmacologist, (PCP is Xavier Hobbs, MC) for comprehensive evaluation of obesity and consideration of treatment options.  Patient is being evaluated concurrently by a nutritionist and a psychologist.



CC/ HPI:  Patient is a 69 year old male, with 

Weight:   227 (  231 )   lbs   Height:    68   Inches   BMI: about  35

and with obesity-related complications as listed below.  Main concerns about weight include: "I am overeating and can't stop".  Pt says he can't stop eating after 3-4 pm, gets enraged, aggressive, anxious, restless, (was given barbiturate and Ativan prn for this, and has improved somewhat ~40%) eats 1/2 gallon of ice cream per day, eats as aggressively as he feels, ongoing for 1.5 yrs.  Afraid he will do something aggressive, and uses entering a "food-coma" to help restrain himself.  Has bipolar, is in "mixed state" now, with characteristics of both depr and mania.  Has neurendoc MD, thinking his pattern related to "peak endocrine secretions".



Had binge drinking episodes till 2 yrs ago.  Drank for 2 days when switching into mania.  Learned to use substitution.  Learned to recognize mania coming on, prodrome, less need for sleep, euphoric speech, spending money.  Wife helped identify this.  Substituted going boating, listening to music, walking, talking to friends.



Wonders if substitution method can work for eating.  A potential method is to use 8 oz water or dietetic candy which have worked to satisfy his hunger.



Learned aggression is PTSD.  Rel to betrayal by mother at age 13.  Trapped, helpless, boxed in.  Medical ailments make him feel the same way.



Has has had talking therapy for ETOH, never for PTSD.



Thinks he may need therapy with wt loss program.



New hx:

Started Tramadol, thinks it's helping curb his hunger.  Will have ablation procedure for pain.



WEIGHT HISTORY:

Onset of obesity/overweight:  Birthwt 10'3.  Heavy till 17.       Highest weight:  220->255 (2103 dx'd with CNS lupus and given prednisone)  

Course, triggers and exacerbators of weight gain:  Genetics.  Lost wt in military, wrestled at 177#, this wt till 25yo.  Wt gain onset w/ marriage, pt cooked, both ate.  Lots of sports and activity over the years.  Less time for phys activity as got busier by his early 50s.  Gained 35# on Prednisone x 4 yrs.  Gained 20# over last 1.5 yrs w/ psych-induced eating as above.

  Family weight hx: F was built like pt, M 98# and could "outeat any man and never gained wt".

  Eating habits: Bingeing?     Night eating?   Excessive hunger?  No   Feels fullness? Yes   Eat past full?  YES   Full details per dietician note.

  Emotional factors/triggers of eating:  See HPI

  Exercise:  HS football westling, military wrestling, coll wrestling, 7 mi/d run, tennis for 20 yrs w/ wife.  Currently walks dog 4 miles a day, "not at aerobic speed".

  Prior medications promoting wt gain (diabetes, hormones, steroids, psychiatric):  Prednisone 4 years

Various psych (Lexapro, Effexor, Depakote, Prozac)- no wt gain attributed.



Attempts at weight loss:  "Will power and stepping up the exercise".  Yo-yo'd.  Details per dietician note.

  Weight loss medications:   Phen/Fen lost 20#.

  Dietician:  No.

 

PMH - obesity complications:

CAD, unstable angina 2 episodes, stents x 2 at LH 2117.  Has had workup at MeritCare Clinic  ASA 81.  



Diabetes type 2, 2112.  A1C 5.8.  Insulin 4.  Fastin BS 87.  Metformin 500.   Known microalbuminuria.  Today ratio is 139.5 (nl < 30).



HTN.  Accupril 20.



Sleep apnea, mild.  No specific Rx.  Also Restless Legs Syndrome, helped by Clonazepam.



Hypercholesterolemia.  Lipitor 10.



Hypogonadism 2103



Back pain.  Scoliosis, DDD 09, facet arthritis.  Cortisone injections at Pain Clinic, last 1-2 months.  May have radio freq ablation.



OA knees.   L TKR 2112.  



Kidney stones x 2.  Ca oxalate.  Lithotripsy.



Overactive bladder.  Detrol LA 4.



PMH/PSH - other:

Hypothyroidism 2108.  Levothyroxine 100.



Bipolar II.  Initially evolved from anxious depression onset with lupus, 2105.  Lamictal 300. Clonazepam .5 tid 



CNS lupus - presented with complex partial seizure of temporal lobe, dx 2103

  started to see Dr. Thomas Hoffman Neuroendoc, at LH in 08, given Teslactone (later replaced with Arimidex) (interferes    

  testo -> estradiol conv) which made lupus go into remission, szs stopped.  Arimidex 1 mg



Sjogren's 2112



h/o Atrial fibrilation 2116, 4 episodes, cardioverted.  Sotalol 80.



BPH.  s/p TURP x2 (12 17)



s/p Appendectomy 2065



T&A



MEDICATIONS:  MVI, Vit C

lamictal

arimidex

levothyroxin

sotalol

accupril

lipitor

metformin

detrol LA

clonazepam, 0.5mg po TID

ASA, 81mg po qD

acetaminophen500 8/d

Tramadol/acet 37.5/325 taking 3-6 per d



MED ALLERGIES:  pcn - hives



FAMILY HISTORY:  per paper chart



SOCIAL HISTORY:   No tobacco   In the past quart of vodka w/ onset of mania.  No recreational drugs     Lives with wife.  2 adult children.   Work:  had mechanic business until Lupus diagnosis.  student counsellor out of college.



REVIEW OF COMPLICATIONS OF OBESITY/ROS: 

DIABETES:  No polyuria, no polydipsia, no blurry vision.

CARDIOVASCULAR DISEASE:  No CP w/ exertion, no doe, no palpitations, no edema, no claudication.

PULMONARY:  No wheeze, no chronic cough.

GERD:  No heartburn, no regurgitation, no acidic taste, no epigastric pain.

GALLBLADDER:  No RUQ pain or non-GERD related discomfort after eating fatty foods.

LIVER DISEASE:  No history or risk factors other than obesity.

MUSCULOSKELETAL:  no hip pain

SKIN:  No rashes.  No cellulitis.

NEURO:  No HAs, no h/o head trauma correlated with obesity onset, no numbness/tingling, no fainting

CLOTTING RISKS:   ?  No h/o DVT/PE, no varicose veins

CANCER SCREENING?    Colon  ?



PHYSICAL EXAM: 

Vitals:  BP:  144/80   HR:  66   Neck circumference   

Pleasant.  Full range of affect.  Generalized mild obesity.  Anicteric.  Facies normal.  OP clear.  Voice not hoarse.  No neck bruits.  No buffalo hump.  No thyromegaly or nodules    RRR no mur/rub/gallop.  Lungs CTA bilat.   

No abd striae.  NT.  NABS.  No HSM.  R of midline vertical scar. No LE edema.  No swollen joints.  No rashes.  No acanthosis nigricans.  Neuro nonfocal.   Normal gait and speech.   



DATA: (selected labs and studies) 

HbA1C 5.8  Glu 87  Fasting insulin 4     microalbumin ratio 139.5 (nl < 30)



Assessment/Recommendations:

69 y.o. male with obesity, BMI = 35, with known complications as listed above. No new medical diagnoses identified. Causes of this patient's obesity include genetic predisposition, past medications (prednisone, antidepressants?), emotional/compulsive/binge-like eating related to manic phase of bipolar illness.   



Our evaluation team recommends a comprehensive program of individualized nutritional education addressing meal structuring, portion control, food choices, etc. and psychological counseling addressing emotional contributors to eating and weight gain.  Referring to Paul Edwards RD, and Allison Ng, PhD.



Pt will continue exercise (walks 4 mi/d).  May increase the aerobic component.  He also plans to start swimming, and may go to a back exercise group per the pain clinic.  He feels motivated to proceeed.



At a later time we can consider medication (in this case, orlistat).



Discussed prevention of ca oxalate stones.  Increase fluids, use plant protein instead of animal, calcium intake OK, decrease grapefruit juice.



F/U w/ me 2 - 2.5 mos.



>50% of the 30-minute visit was spent counseling the patient about the potential implications of obesity and obesity-related conditions, and the above treatment plan.  All questions answered.



Parker Quinby, MD



CC: Dr. Juan Yun (email)

PCP, Dr. Xavier Hobbs











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2119-09-01

Vermillion Weight Center

45 King Street, 3th floor

Newberry, OK  62981

Tel.  895.376.3157

Fax.  320.821.2954

Initial Medical Consultation Follow-up



Referred by: Dr. Juan Yun, psychopharmacologist, (PCP is Xavier Hobbs, MC) for comprehensive evaluation of obesity and consideration of treatment options.  Patient is being evaluated concurrently by a nutritionist and a psychologist.



CC/ HPI:  Patient is a 69 year old male, with 

Weight:  213  ( 227  231 )   lbs   Height:    68   Inches   BMI: about  35 -> 32/33

and with obesity-related complications as listed below.  Main concerns about weight include: "I am overeating and can't stop".  Pt says he can't stop eating after 3-4 pm, gets enraged, aggressive, anxious, restless, (was given barbiturate and Ativan prn for this, and has improved somewhat ~40%) eats 1/2 gallon of ice cream per day, eats as aggressively as he feels, ongoing for 1.5 yrs.  Afraid he will do something aggressive, and uses entering a "food-coma" to help restrain himself.  Has bipolar, is in "mixed state" now, with characteristics of both depr and mania.  Has neurendoc MD, thinking his pattern related to "peak endocrine secretions".



Had binge drinking episodes till 2 yrs ago.  Drank for 2 days when switching into mania.  Learned to use substitution.  Learned to recognize mania coming on, prodrome, less need for sleep, euphoric speech, spending money.  Wife helped identify this.  Substituted going boating, listening to music, walking, talking to friends.



Wonders if substitution method can work for eating.  A potential method is to use 8 oz water or dietetic candy which have worked to satisfy his hunger.



Learned aggression is PTSD.  Rel to betrayal by mother at age 13.  Trapped, helpless, boxed in.  Medical ailments make him feel the same way.



Has has had talking therapy for ETOH, never for PTSD.



Thinks he may need therapy with wt loss program.



New hx:

Doing well with indiv psych and nutrition (reviewed notes).



When depressed uses food for comfort.



Afternoon "warewolf" mode: every day 4-7 pm gets agitated, hostile, aggressive, hunger.  Hypothesized per neuroendocrine that cycles "out of sync".  Tried lorazepam, klonzepam.  Eats PB sandwich.  Would like something to reduce appetite during that time.  Has tried lots of water at the time, may work for him.



Recent radiowave ablation for lumbar back pain.  Expect proced to help for 1-3 yrs.  Felt "like a new man" afterwards.  Was told it is now OK to exercise, has started exercise at gym.  Treadmill.  In addit to walking dog (not aerobic) 2 miles twice a day.  Now 2 goal is 3 times a week.  Also swims.



[prior]

Started Tramadol, thinks it's helping curb his hunger.  Will have ablation procedure for pain.



WEIGHT HISTORY:

Onset of obesity/overweight:  Birthwt 10'3.  Heavy till 17.       Highest weight:  220->255 (2103 dx'd with CNS lupus and given prednisone)  

Course, triggers and exacerbators of weight gain:  Genetics.  Lost wt in military, wrestled at 177#, this wt till 25yo.  Wt gain onset w/ marriage, pt cooked, both ate.  Lots of sports and activity over the years.  Less time for phys activity as got busier by his early 50s.  Gained 35# on Prednisone x 4 yrs.  Gained 20# over last 1.5 yrs w/ psych-induced eating as above.

  Family weight hx: F was built like pt, M 98# and could "outeat any man and never gained wt".

  Eating habits: Bingeing?     Night eating?   Excessive hunger?  No   Feels fullness? Yes   Eat past full?  YES   Full details per dietician note.

  Emotional factors/triggers of eating:  See HPI

  Exercise:  HS football westling, military wrestling, coll wrestling, 7 mi/d run, tennis for 20 yrs w/ wife.  Currently walks dog 4 miles a day, "not at aerobic speed".

  Prior medications promoting wt gain (diabetes, hormones, steroids, psychiatric):  Prednisone 4 years

Various psych (Lexapro, Effexor, Depakote, Prozac)- no wt gain attributed.



Attempts at weight loss:  "Will power and stepping up the exercise".  Yo-yo'd.  Details per dietician note.

  Weight loss medications:   Phen/Fen lost 20#.

  Dietician:  No.

 

PMH - obesity complications:

CAD, unstable angina 2 episodes, stents x 2 at LH 2117.  Has had workup at MeritCare Clinic.  ASA 81.  



Diabetes type 2, 2112.  A1C 5.8.  Insulin 4.  Fastin BS 87.  Metformin 500.   Known microalbuminuria.  Today ratio is 139.5 (nl < 30).



HTN.  Accupril 20.



Sleep apnea, mild.  No specific Rx.  Also Restless Legs Syndrome, helped by Clonazepam.



Hypercholesterolemia.  Lipitor 10.



Hypogonadism 2103



Back pain.  Scoliosis, DDD 09, facet arthritis.  Cortisone injections at Pain Clinic, last 1-2 months.  Had radio freq ablation 7/19 which has had dramatic results - no back pain now.



OA knees.   L TKR 2112.  



Kidney stones x 2.  Ca oxalate.  Lithotripsy.  Still has 2-3.  Also cysts.



Overactive bladder. Stopped  Detrol LA 4.  Workup ongoing.



PMH/PSH - other:

Hypothyroidism 2108.  Levothyroxine 100.



Bipolar II.  Initially evolved from anxious depression onset with lupus, 2105.  Lamictal 300. Clonazepam .5 tid 



CNS lupus - presented with complex partial seizure of temporal lobe, dx 2103

  started to see Dr. Thomas Hoffman Neuroendoc, at LH in 08, given Teslactone (later replaced with Arimidex) (interferes    

  testo -> estradiol conv) which made lupus go into remission, szs stopped.  Arimidex 1 mg



Sjogren's 2112



h/o Atrial fibrilation 2116, 4 episodes, cardioverted.  Sotalol 80.



BPH.  s/p TURP x2 (12 17)



s/p Appendectomy 2065



T&A



MEDICATIONS:  MVI, Vit C

lamictal

arimidex

levothyroxin

sotalol

accupril

lipitor

metformin

stopped detrol LA

clonazepam, 0.5mg po TID

ASA, 81mg po qD

acetaminophen 500 8/d prn HA

stopped Tramadol/acet 37.5/325 taking 3-6 per d



MED ALLERGIES:  pcn - hives



FAMILY HISTORY:  per paper chart



SOCIAL HISTORY:   No tobacco   In the past quart of vodka w/ onset of mania.  No recreational drugs     Lives with wife.  2 adult children.   Work:  had mechanic business until Lupus diagnosis.  student counsellor out of college.



REVIEW OF COMPLICATIONS OF OBESITY/ROS: 

DIABETES:  No polyuria, no polydipsia, no blurry vision.

CARDIOVASCULAR DISEASE:  No CP w/ exertion, no doe, no palpitations, no edema, no claudication.

PULMONARY:  No wheeze, no chronic cough.

GERD:  No heartburn, no regurgitation, no acidic taste, no epigastric pain.

GALLBLADDER:  No RUQ pain or non-GERD related discomfort after eating fatty foods.

LIVER DISEASE:  No history or risk factors other than obesity.

MUSCULOSKELETAL:  no hip pain

SKIN:  No rashes.  No cellulitis.

NEURO:  No HAs, no h/o head trauma correlated with obesity onset, no numbness/tingling, no fainting

CLOTTING RISKS:   ?  No h/o DVT/PE, no varicose veins

CANCER SCREENING?    Colon  ?



PHYSICAL EXAM: 

Vitals:  BP:  170/90  (144/80)  (says higher in the mornings)  HR:  60 (66)   Neck circumference   

Pleasant.  Full range of affect.  Generalized mild obesity.  Anicteric.  Facies normal.  OP clear.  Voice not hoarse.  No neck bruits.  No buffalo hump.  No thyromegaly or nodules    RRR no mur/rub/gallop.  Lungs CTA bilat.   

No abd striae.  NT.  NABS.  No HSM.  R of midline vertical scar. No LE edema.  No swollen joints.  No rashes.  No acanthosis nigricans.  Neuro nonfocal.   Normal gait and speech.   



DATA: (selected labs and studies) 

[prior]

HbA1C 5.8  Glu 87  Fasting insulin 4     microalbumin ratio 139.5 (nl < 30)



Assessment/Recommendations:

69 y.o. male with obesity, BMI = 35 -> 32/33, with known complications as listed above.  Causes of this patient's obesity include genetic predisposition, past medications (prednisone, antidepressants?), emotional/compulsive/binge-like eating related to manic phase of bipolar illness.   



Pt continuing comprehensive program of individualized nutritional education addressing meal structuring, portion control, food choices, etc. and psychological counseling addressing emotional contributors to eating and weight gain.  Seeing Paul Edwards RD, and Allison Ng, PhD.  Lost 18# in 4 months (1 pound a week) so far with nutritional change, exercise.  Commended pt on success.



Pt will continue exercise (walks 4 mi/d, gym 2 (going to 3) times a week for an hour, swimming).



Because of the afternoon period he describes as being like a "Warewolf" (4-7 pm), I recommended he use this time for exercise rather than for his other, more sedentary, activities.



At a later time we can consider medication (in this case, orlistat).  Currently progress is excellent without needing it.



Discuss elevated BP with PCP, may need higher dose of ACEI.



F/U w/ me 2 - 2.5 mos.



>50% of the 30-minute visit was spent counseling the patient about the potential implications of obesity and obesity-related conditions, and the above treatment plan.  All questions answered.



Parker Quinby, MD



CC: Dr. Juan Yun (email)

PCP, Dr. Xavier Hobbs











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2122-07-08




 


Neurology Attending Staff:


July 8, 2122
Time of exam 1:05 PM
Patient: Lloyd Coleman
Reason for admission: headache, gait instability, mental slowness


I had the pleasure of meeting Mr. Craft who has been admitted to the Neurology service for evaluation and management.  Along with the Neurology Residents, I personally interviewed, examined, and counseled the patient, confirmed the history and findings, reviewed records and studies, and discussed the impression and recommendations.  For greater details of H/P/ROS/meds/exam/labs/studies, and assessment &amp; plan, please refer to the neurology resident admit note by Dr. Robert Neil (and below under my assessment). 


ROS performed across 10 systems are negative (as noted in neurology note) except as noted in Hx/Assessment and resident's note. 


Cognitive and Elemental neurologic exam as noted in neurology resident note. 
Of note, AFVSS, was asleep but awoke to voice and became alert, attentive to examiner, but had moderate psychomotor retardation. Was slowly conversant and followed simple multiple step commands across midline. 
Oriented to time/date/place. 
Great d/w simple attention (MOY backwards only to Nov, skipped Oct went to September and then went forwards again). 
Able to perform complex attention and working memory bihemispheric Newberry location alpha-numeric task after a second trial. 
Language: fluent w/o dysarthria. Farily Intact naming for high and low frequency items except clasp and had some mild retrieval d/w. 
Memory: gives good details of recent events including hospitalizations. 
Leprosarium name and address: 5/5 registration --&gt; 2/5 recall in 5 min --&gt; 1/3 recognition from a list
Presidential candidates = Xayarath and Golden
Calculations: # of quarters in $6.75 = 27
Moderate d/w Luria fist-side-palm that improved w/ verbal cuing but still poor L&gt;R. 
No EDSS, neglect, R-L confusion or apraxia. 
Mood: "low ... my daughter has cancer that spread to the bones"; Affect: congruent. 


CN's II-XII intact, good up and down gaze and w/o IV or VI CN palsy. 
No PND, abnl movements, tremor, asterixis, or UE ataxia. Slow but okay FFM, FNF, RAM. 
Full MS, nl DTR's and tone. Plantar responses flexor. 
Mildly diminished stocking distributaion of LT/Cold/VS both legs to mid-shins. HKS mild d/w. 
Unable to stand w/ feet together even w/ eyes open. Moderate retropulsion trying to stand and moderate to severe retropulsion w/o spontaneously recovery on pull-test. Narraw base, small step size w/ low steppage, cautious and w/ retropulsion, slow rate w/ 10 step en bloc turning w/ imbalance (backwards). 
No photo- or phono-phobia, no nuchal rigidity.


Labs/Studies: of note BUN 21, Cr 1.2, MCV 95, Hct 41.6, wbc 13.3


Neuroimaging: Personally reviewed HCT - mildly large vents, no s/o SDH or SAH or infarct/mass lx/hemorrhage. 


Assessment:: Likely Communicating Hydrocephalus with mild elevation of ICP in context of minor head trauma.  On exam shows psychomotor retardation, d/w concentration, retrieval (including memory and words), frontal fucntions including set-switching on Lurias, and working memory. He also has moderate retropulsion on exam worse on pull-test than spontaneously, and hypomimia. His vents are mildly dilated in context of general cerebral atrophy that is not o/w out-of-proportion for his advanced age. Onset of his sx's including bilateral headache described as constant 6-8/10 pressure at posterior vertex w/ occ. radiation foward made worse by lying down for some time (worse in the mornings) and better in the afternoons or after sitting or standing. No blurred vision but mild nausea w/o vomiting. No nuchal rigidity or photo-phonophobia. No f/c/ns/cp/sob/rash/weakness/changes in sensation. Describes very clear psychomotor retardation since first fall including d/w concentraion, memory and word retrieval, and extreme slowness in mental processing (including reading - used to be a speed reader and now reads one word at a time very slowly). He's had some urinary urgency but no incontinencey. Describes his d/w gait as not being able to get his legs to do what he wants them to do despite having good strength. Additionally, feels that he's always losing his balance backwards. No suggestion of meningoencephalitis, stroke or seizure. Had mild bilat tinnitus but no vertigo. Does ascribe rare very transient visual distortion and object movement (up/down). WBC mildly elevated but no fever and U/A and CXR are negative. 


Overall, there is a diad of gait apraxia and frontal cognitive dysfunction and psychomotor retardation (no urinary incontinence) in context of sx's of mildly elevated ICP and mildly enlarged vents. Has a mild small and large fiber distal symmetric polyneuropathy which exacerbates his gait difficulties. He is also at least mildly anxious and moderately anxious.  Had bradycardia in ED - now better but need to follow. 


Plan: 

- Optimize pain/headache control
- Neuro checks q4hrs
- Cardiac telemetry
- Elevated ICP (mild) precautions with HOB &gt; 45 degrees; and gentle hydration (he is dehydrated by labs)
- MRI of brain to better assess vents and possible transependymal flow, as well as to exclude much less likely brainstem and posterior fossa lesions. Also need to assess posterior circulation w/ MRA (had mild constant tinnutus), and assess for small SDH (b/o h/o head trauma). 
- check B12, homocysteine, TSH, ESR, hsCRP, ANA

- After Brain MRI is reviewed, need to assess fundi, gait and cognition (formally score and time) and then perform diagnostic LP for hydrocephalus -- measuring opening and closing pressure after removing ~ 20cc and sending for cell count, glucose, TP, and xanthochromia as well as keeping ~ 10 cc. 

- Hold sotalol, complete cardiac/MI r/o by enzymes. 
- Follow wbc and monitor for s/s infection. 


Discussed assessment and plan with pt and family who understand and agree. 






Tom Tejeda, M.D., Ph.D.











****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>