<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2066-03-05





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

OCHILTREE GENERAL HOSPITAL



History of present illness   The patient is a 53year-old male returns for diabetes and evaluation of swelling in his right testicle.  He was seen on 02/20/2066, given Levaquin for orchitis versus epididymis.  The patient took the medicine and was seen by Urology.  By the time, he saw Urology on 03/04/2066, the swelling had mostly resolved.  The patient has no pain nor urinary symptoms.  Urine culture was negative.  He feels fine at this time.  No polyuria or polydipsia.  No chest pain or shortness of breath.



Major Problems

Impotence



Degenerative arthritis



Hyperlipidemia



Diabetes mellitus (adult onset)





Change in therapies and Renewals

Viagra    PRN

Avandia 4 mg 1 tab  qd

Naprosyn 500 mg  bid PRN

Pravachol 20 mg  QD

aspirin 325 mg 1 tab  qd

Levaquin 500 mg po qd x10d QTY:10 Refills:0 Start: 2/20/2066 End: 3/05/2066 - Inactivated



Physical examination

Blood pressure 138/90  

Weight   209 pounds

General appearance   No acute distress

Chest   Lungs clear

Cor   Regular rhythm.  S1 and S2 normal.  No murmur, S3, or S4

Abdomen   Soft and nontender.  No masses

Genitalia   Testicles, normal sized bilaterally.  No pain or no swelling.  No hernia

Extrem   No edema



Assessment and plan   Epididymis.  Resolved.  Return if symptoms recur     Type 2 diabetes mellitus.  Check hemoglobin A1c.  Continue Avandia     Hyperlipidemia.  Continue Pravachol



Disposition

Return in three months.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by   Steven  Thomson   on  Mar 10, 2066     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-01-28





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

OCHILTREE GENERAL HOSPITAL



Reason for visit   URI



History of present illness   Pt has URI with cough for several weeks.  The majority of this 25 minute visit was spent in counseling about hid drinking.



Major Problems

Diabetes mellitus (adult onset)

No sx. HB A1c was good last month.

Hyperlipidemia

has started lipitor without problem about a month ago.  Not fasting today.



Other Problems

Cough

Pt had uri about a month ago. He has continued to have disturbing cough after acute symptoms resolved.  He describes cough worse in cold air, starting after he gets into the weather. No scarf. No history of asthma.  No supine sx. Exam neg. Offered alupent inhaler and instructed to use muffler for probable dx of cold induced asthma.

Depression

Subject came up re asking about drinking (potential relation to cough).  He drank heavily after Korea (field nurse) and had depression at that time.  He had SI about 18 months ago.  Now seeing Navarro (rx) and Lacey Frost (Tx) ans is on two drugs paxil and another.  States they reliably cause him to vomit if he drinks.  States drinks two rums and diet coke a night.  Thinks he should stop; discussed; needs to bring this up with his tx.  Not si now, states mood stable.



Change in therapies and Renewals

Proventil  two puffs inhaled qid QTY:1 cannister Refills:3 Start: 01/28/2067 prn



Habits

Alcohol use status: major  



Physical examination

Pulse 70   

Blood pressure 160/90  

Weight 210  216 pounds

General appearance   Well developed, well nourished, in no acute distress

Skin   Clear

Heent   Eyes, nonicteric.  Nose clear.  Pharynx normal.  Ears normal

Neck   No masses

Chest   Lungs are clear

Cor   Regular rhythm.  S1 and S2 normal.  No murmur, S3, or S4

temperature 98.0  



Disposition

return in two months; obtain fasting lipids before then.



Signed electronically by Miranda, James R on Jan 29, 2067     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-03-06





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

OCHILTREE GENERAL HOSPITAL



History of present illness   This is a 54-year-old white male here complaining persistent cough.  He has had a dry cough for about two months.  He was put on inhalers, but there was no improvement.  The cough is worse at night, but also he has it during the day.  He has no mucus production, no hemoptysis, no shortness of breath, and no wheezing.  He is a nonsmoker.  About a week ago, he was admitted to a local emergency room for chest pain.  He was rushed to Ochiltree General because of ST-T wave abnormalities on his EKG.  In retrospect, he has had these changes for many years, and anyway he had a cardiac catheterization, which showed mild obstruction of some of his coronary systems but no evidence of coronary artery syndrome.  He did have cardiomyopathy with the ejection fraction of 35%.  He was sent home on Toprol XL 50 mg QD, Lipitor 10 mg QD, lisinopril 10 mg, aspirin 325 mg once a day, and Avandia 2 mg once a day.  Since returning home, the patient feels no chest pain or shortness of breath.  No orthopnea or PND.  He still has a dry cough.



Change in therapies and Renewals

Viagra 50mg  PRN QTY:15 Refills:3 Start: 10/05/2063

Avandia 2 mg 1 tab   qd QTY:30 Refills:3 Start: 1/31/2065

aspirin 325 mg 1 tab   qd QTY:30 Refills:1 yr Start: 3/12/2065

lisinopril 10 mg   QD Start: 8/4/2066

Lipitor 10mg po qd Start: 12/17/2066

Proventil two puffs inhaled qid QTY:1 cannister Refills:3 Start: 1/28/2067 End: 3/06/2067 prn - Inactivated

Toprol XL 50 mg po qd Start: 03/06/2067

Prilosec 20mg po bid QTY:60 Refills:1 Start: 03/06/2067 take before meals



Physical examination

Blood pressure 110/80  

Weight   214 pounds

General appearance   Well-developed and well-nourished, no acute distress

Skin   Clear

Heent   Eyes, nonicteric.  Nose clear.  Pharynx normal

Neck   No masses.  Neck veins not distended

Chest   Lungs clear

Cor   Regular rhythm.  S1 and S2 normal.  No murmur, S3, or S4

Abdomen   Soft, nontender, and no masses.  No liver or spleen palpable

Extrem   No edema



Assessment and plan   Cardiomyopathy.  Continue present medications.  Complete abstention from alcohol advised.

Diabetes.  Check hemoglobin A1c.

Persistent cough.  Question GERD.  Plan:  A trial of Prilosec 20 mg twice a day.  Schedule upper GI.  Return in one month.  If cough persists, consider a role of lisinopril.  However, he was taking lisinopril long before his cough started.

Hyperlipidemia.  Continue Lipitor.  Check lipid profile.

Impotence.  Refill Viagra.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Thomson, Steven on Mar 09, 2067     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-11-30

CARDIOLOGY

OCHILTREE GENERAL HOSPITAL



Reason for visit:

   Follow-up appointment for cardiomyopathy



Interval History:

   Mr Lara reports no problems since the time of his last visit. He insistists that he has absolutely abstained from etoh since his last visit.



Denies fevers, chills. denies palpitations or syncope.



Under a fair amount of stress at home: his son is home after a head injury and neurological complications of an MVA and is fairly debilitated. He has had to give up his job to help take care of him. 



Past medical history:

   diabetes, cad, cardiomyopathy



Medications (Confirmed):



			

aspirin 325 mg 1 tab  qd

Avandia 2 mg 1 tab  qd

Levitra 10mg po qd PRN

Lipitor

lisinopril 10 mg  QD

Patanol 0.1% eye drops

Prilosec 20mg po bid

Synalar ointment  .025%    

Toprol XL



Social history:

   Currently not working out of the house; denies etoh..



Review of systems:

   see above. remainder negative in detail



Physical examination:

-BP: 160/90  

-Pulse: 73  bpm

-General:   No acute distress.

-Heent:   Unremarkable

-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.

-Cardiac:   Left ventricular impulse discrete and nondisplaced. Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2. There were no clicks or rubs. ? faint 1/6 systolic murmur at the apex.

-weight: 205  

-BMI:   

-Abdomen:   normal active bowel sounds.

-Extremities:   without clubbing or edema.

-Neuro:   A+Ox3



EKG:

   Sinus Rhythm with 2 pvcs. Q waves leads 1, AVL RPO high lateral infarction. Apical TWI. Q waves leads V5 and v6 rpo oapical MI. C 8/67, TWI more marked. 



Assessment and plan:

   55 yom with history of cardiomyopathy likely secondary to etoh use; at time of cath, he had mild-moderate CAD found. Also, hypetension

1) Patient missed his last echo appt. Will reschedule to check for interval improvement on treatment and off moonshine. Pt counseled to give up all etoh for ~ 6mos at least. He voices understanidng.

2) hypertension: not acceptable at this level given diabetes. I have asked Joe to increase his lisinopril to 40 mg 

3) diabetes: well controlled by Dr. Thomson

4) CAD: on a statin (DM is CAD equiv as well) 



Cardiac prescriptions written



Changes to Medications this visit

Avandia 2 mg 1 tab    qd QTY:30 Refills:3 Start: 1/31/2065

aspirin 325 mg 1 tab    qd QTY:30 Refills:1 yr Start: 3/12/2065

lisinopril 40 mg  po qd QTY:30 Refills:11 Start: 8/4/2066

Lipitor 10mg  po qd Start: 12/17/2066

Toprol XL 50 mg  po qd Start: 03/06/2067

Prilosec 20mg  po bid QTY:60 Refills:1 Start: 03/06/2067 take before meals

Levitra 10mg  po qd PRN QTY:10 Refills:3 Start: 06/26/2067 Max: one tab per day; take one hour prior to sexual activity

Synalar ointment  .025%      QTY: 45g Refills: 2 Start: 06/26/2067  apply bid

Patanol 0.1% eye drops     QTY:5cc Refills:1 Start: 10/10/2065 2gtt  bid



DX Tests Ordered:

   echocardiogram to eval LV function



Signed electronically by   Elon  Levine MD  on  Nov 30, 2067     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2069-10-10


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	OCHILTREE GENERAL HOSPITAL
	


	Reason for visit:
   The patient is a 61 yo Equadorian male admitted for cardiac cath after an episode of chest pain with? positive markers.


	Interval History:
   The  patient was  transferred to OGH in 3/2067 because of chest pain with positive markers and aaaanterolateral T wave changes.At which time he was diagnosed with possible ETOH myocarditis. His EF was 34%. He underwent cardiac cath which showed that the Left Main and LAD were patent, , a very distal LCX lesion. RCA was dominant and patent. The patient was discharged to home on a program of ace, BB, ASA and instructed to curtail his ETOH use. His EF improved to 66 %. He had repeat nuclear stress testing which showed small anterior infarct/small prior inferior infarct and was negative for ischemia in July 2068..
   Since then he has had a stable angina pattern with chest pain brought on when he has to move very heavy objects in his work as a packager . This is usually relieved with one TNG. Most recently, he was seen by his PC Dr. Thomson and treated with Augmentin/Robitussin AC for a URI. He had a productive cough  and some chest discomfort related to coughing. 
   Most recently, he was brought into police custody for public intoxication. While in his jail cell,"resting" he developed the sudden onset on midsternal sharp chest pain accompanied by heavy breathing. There was no radiation to the arms, but he noted bilateral hand numbness. He also had palpitations and sweating and felt nauseated. He received one sl TNG. An ambulance was called and he received 2 TNG sprays. His pain diminished. His BP was 176/100 at the time. He was brought to the Evanston Hospital ER and found to have "high lateral changes" on his EKG's. Troponins were slightly elevated at .13- considered a "gray zone" for the hospitals range  for MI. The patient was pain free after a dose of Morphine. While in the hospital, he was placed on suicide watch. He has a history of a suicide attempt 3 years ago and has previously had counseling and been on antidepressants. He has a son who is in a vegetative state after an MVA whom he helps care for and this is very stressful. His recent arrest made hiite despondent. At Evanston Hospital, he was started on a beta blocker and Lovenox. He had a suboptimal stress test which was stopped because of SSCP and nausea. He is now transferred to OGH for further evaluation.


	Past medical history:
   diabetes
Cardiomyopathy(?ETOH related)
CAD- 50 % LCX lesion 3/67
Depression with suicide attempt 3 years ago- was on antidepressants until 6 months ago
Obesity


	

	Changes to Allergies
	
No known allergies
No known drug allergy


	Medications (Confirmed):

	
aspirin  325 mg daily
Augmentin  500mg/125mg po q8h x 10 days
Levitra  20mg po daily PRN
Lipitor  10 mg daily
lisinopril  40 mg daily
metformin hydrochloride  500 mg daily
Patanol 0.1% eye drops 
Prilosec  20 mg daily
Robitussin ac  100mg/10mg/5ml po q4-6h PRN cough
Synalar ointment  0.025%
Voltaren  75 mg BID PRN


	Family history:
   non contributory


	Social history:
   working until recently- was "packaging manager for Johnson & Johnson"
 no smoking
 rare etoh- one glass red wine with evening meal
Lives with wife/2 daughters- has son in vegetative state after car accident whom family cares for


	Review of systems:
   see above. remainder negative in detail

Physical examination:
	
-BMI: 42.6  Obese, high risk
-Pulse: 62  bpm
-weight: 225  lbs.
-Neck:   jvp 6 cm without bruits
-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.
-Cardiac:   Left ventricular impulse discrete and nondisplaced. Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2. Split S2 There were no clicks or rubs.
-Abdomen:   normal active bowel sounds.No HSM
-Extremities:   without clubbing or edema.- Femoral pulse 2+ DP @+
-BP: 126/87  


	EKG:
   NSB 60 Q 1, L, TWI L, V5-6, c/w 10/14 ECG

Selected recent labs:

	 to be drawn upon admission
	


	Other Data:
   Cath: 3/67: patent LM/LAD, LCX 50% stenosis, RCA dominant
Last echo 12 /67  EF 63%  walls 12/8 mild MR, symmetrical LVH, trace PI, RVSP 41 borderline RVH
Nuclear cardiology 7/68: small prior ant infarct/inf. infarct- no ischemia, EF nl


	Assessment and plan:
   The patient is a 47 yo diabetic, with known CAD, improved EF after d/c of ETOH now admitted after episode of chest pain with ? EKG changes and  "intermediate"Troponins per local hospital assay.Case reviewed with Dr. Levine. Would continue ASA, beta Blocker and Lisinopril in addition to usual meds. He has previous CAD and is diabetic. Even though stess test was suboptimal, he has risk factors of diabetes, obesity and hypertension, and 50 % LCX lesion , so would proceed with cath tomorrow. NPO after midnight for cath lab. He is currently pain free so no heparin for now. Would check serial EKG;s, and troponins in addition to usual labs. Please obtain fasting cholesterol panel.

Will need psychiatric consult to aseess suicidality though he currently denies this.

Agree hold NSAIDs/Voltaren intil after cath.

	
Florene Kim, NP

	
Transcribed by: Florene Kim

	
Signed electronically by  Florene Kim, NP
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>