<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2090-07-07

Willow Gardens Care - Columbus  Barnesdale



Follow up htn and diabetes. Feels well. Occassional bilat hand numbness in am's or if leans on elbows watching TV. No motor deficits, no clumsy hand. No speech difficulty nor gait difficulty.



Tolerating meds below.



--------------Problems----------



actinic keratoses

Eczema

CAD

BPH

Tinea corporis

Hypertension

Diabetes

Hearing impairment





--------------Medications----------



ATENOLOL   25MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

LISINOPRIL   40MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

DYAZIDE 1 CAPSULE    PO QD 

METFORMIN   500MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

GLYBURIDE   5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

ASA (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)   81MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

CLOBETASOL 0.05% CREAM     TOP BID 





--------------Allergies----------



NKDA



--------------Vital Signs----------





120/68 HR 80

Neck: 1+ bilat carotid upstroke, no carotid bruits

CV: distant, RRR, no m/r/g

Chest: distant, cta

Ext: no foot ulcers, hands without Tinel sign, good grip strength

sensory intact

-------------Data----------------

K+ 5.4 last visit. Hasn't repeated since then

creat borderline high



-------------Assessment/Plan------



1. diabetes: fairly good control. HbA1C today and glucose sent. c/w current meds

2. htn: good control. c/w current meds. Check chem 7 today, may need to avoid bananas (averages 1/2 qday). Monitor creat.

3. hand numbness: most likely carpal tunnel. Explained that has some risk for carotid disease, but simultaneous bilat symptoms makes carotid disease less likely explanation for hand numbness. Advised wrist splints. Call office immediately if ever "clumsy hand" or if accompanies by speech/gait difficulty.

4. HM: Physical in 3 months. f/u optho Dr. Quon next week.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-07-19

Willow Gardens Care - Columbus Medicine

206 Barnesdale Lane



76 y.o. man here for f/u DM and HTN. Last night had some pain in R flank after salty soup. Pain subsided last night. Bowel movement yesterday. Woke this am ok. No chest pain or n/v/diaphoresis.



No hx of renal stones, no hematuria.



PROBLEMS



Eczema  right chestwall.  (Dr. Vanpelt, Berrien)

Tinea corporis  tinea cruris

Hypertension  140/100 5/88, 150/90 2/89, 158/80 3/89, 130/64 4/89, 140/80 8/89, 134/80 10/89

Hearing impairment  doesn't wear aids due to background noise.

actinic keratosis  nose derm consult 5/88, right eyelid lesion 8/89 reconsult derm

benign prostatic hypertrophy  denies voiding symptoms

obesity  

neuropathy  impotence;

peripheral vascular disease  ; carotid stenosis 10/90 without bruit

Diabetes  Type 2.  ? 2079, Resumed oral hypoglycemic agent 11/86.  Fasting glucose 140 12/86, HB Alc 11.38 (11/19/86), HgAlC 5.93 3/87, 7.1 9/88, 7.9 2/89, 5.6 5/89

nephropathy  



Medications

Clobetasol 0.05% CREAM TOP BID

ATENOLOL 25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

LISINOPRIL 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

GLYBURIDE 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

DYAZIDE 1 CAPSULE PO QD 





Allergies

NKDA 







Exam

BP 130/60 ,Wt 215 lb 

last visit BP 160/80 (last visit BP 162/90) both arms today, HR 60 regular

alert and oriented x 3 , slightly hoh, wife present for visit

Heent: OP clear, TM's clear, decreased hearing to finger rub at 3 feet

SKIN: no broken skin. No ulcers

CHEST: distant lungs sounds but clear to auscultation and percussion.

CV: distant heart sounds, RRR Normal S1 S2, No murmurs, rubs, gallops

AbD: soft, nt, nabs, no flank tenderness

EXTREM: 1+ distal pulses feet, poor femoral pulses, no bruits, no abd masses, no adenopathy, no cyanosis, clubbing, or edema. No foot ulcers



Data



UA-Protein 10/04/2089 NEGATIVE 



HBA1C  6.7 in Jan '92, 6.8 6/2092



creat 1.5 Jan '92, repeat creat 1.5 6/2092



Assessment/Plan



1. abd pain: resolved this am: possible diverticular disease acting up, gas pains, doubt renal stone. Pt declines colonoscopy at this time. Send stool cardsx 3. 



2. HTN: Excellent today since resumed Dyazide. Creat is stable.  Pt to increase po fluids.

recheck K+ and creat today. 



3. diabetes mellitus, type 2 with retinoapthy: fair control,  HbA1c rising slightly. wt loss and  exercise as tolerated.



4. renal insufficiency: likely was prerenal from dyazide in past. Resume dyazide, drink more fluids. Monitor creat.



5. claudication: pt prefers to avoid surgical intervention. c/w exercise as tolerated.

f/u 5/92, sooner if issues/concerns



6. will send for adenosine mibi given multiple cardiac risk factors including DM, HTN, PVD and older age

Denies symptoms. Send nonfasting lipids today. Was wnl '90.



____________________

Robert I. Harmon, M.D.















****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-04-19


Willow Gardens Care - Columbus 




80 y.o. man here for routine 3 months f/u for diabetes with retinopathy (has had laser therapy twice). Seen foot doctor every 3 mos.
Denies polyuria or polydipsia. Wife has been pushing the fluids given his elevated creat.
 
Vitamin B12 deficiency treated with injections.


Has  renal insufficiency and HTN. 
Home BP readings are normal.


Repeat chest CT scans shows stable nodules, prior asbestos.
No cough. Has been dieting to lose weight.


Incidental note of thyroid nodule. NO symptoms. TSH wnl 10/95. Thyroid u/s reassuring.


Walks  intermittently. Keeps active around the yard at home. 
Mows lawn and shovels snow himself. Denies chest pain.


Notes some DOE with walking from house to backyard.
Occasional burping after meals--better sometimes after TUMS and sitting down to relax. No associated lightheadedness or dizziness, no nausea.




Problems
actinic keratosis : nose derm consult 5/88, right eyelid lesion 8/89 reconsult derm
Eczema : right chestwall. (Dr. Vanpelt, Berrien)
benign prostatic hypertrophy : denies voiding symptoms
Tinea corporis : tinea cruris
Hypertension : 140/100 5/88, 150/90 2/89, 158/80 3/89, 130/64 4/89, 140/80 8/89, 134/80 10/89
Diabetes : Type 2. ? 2079, Resumed oral hypoglycemic agent 11/86. Fasting glucose 140 12/86, HB Alc 11.38 (11/19/86), HgAlC 5.93 3/87, 7.1 9/88, 7.9 2/89, 5.6 5/89
Hearing impairment : doesn't wear aids due to background noise.
obesity 
nephropathy 
neuropathy : impotence;
peripheral vascular disease 
Renal insufficiency : stopped HCTZ '93 due to creat 1.5, creat 1.6 '95 


Allergies
NKA 



Medications
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81MG TABLET CHEWABLE take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Atenolol 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Cyanocobalamin 200 MCG (100MCG/ML DISP SYRIN take 2 ML) IM see below , 200MCG QD x's 1 wk,then 200MCG Qwk x's 1 month,then 1000mcg Qmon x's 3mos then
Flex-a-min 1 PO AS DIRECTED , ONE TAB WITH MEALS UP TO THREE TIMES A DAY
Flexeril (CYCLOBENZAPRINE HCL) 10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID PRN muscle spasm x 5 days, do not drive if using this med
Glyburide 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Ketoconazole 2% SHAMPOO 1 APPLICATION (2% SHAMPOO ) TOP BIW x 30 days
Lisinopril 20MG TABLET PO QD 
Metrogel 1% (METRONIDAZOLE 1% GEL) 1 APPLICATION (1% GEL ) TOP QD 
Mucinex 600 MG PO Q 12 HR PRN , Swollow whole. Stop if rash, headache or breathing problems occur
Simvastatin 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 
Viagra (SILDENAFIL) 100MG TABLET take 0.5 Tablet(s) PO x1 , STOP USING IF YOU HAVE NAUSEA, INCREASED SWEATING, CHEST PAIN, DIZZINESS 
Zithromax (AZITHROMYCIN) 250MG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s) PO see below , 2 capsules po first day, then 1 capsule po qd until gone 




ROS: notes DOE this month.

No dyspnea today.


Exam:
Wt 210 lbs, BP 150/68 (home BP reading 130s/80s per pt), Wt 210 lbs, fingerstick glucose 153 mg/dl
last visit Wt 212 lbs, BP 160/80 (home readings are 110s/70s per pt however)


Heent: eomi
Neck: no carotid bruits
CV: rrr, no m/r/g
Chest: distant breath sounds, cta
Ext: no cce, resolution of 2 cm x 2cm soft tissue edema R upper arm, no bruising, no pulsatile masses appreciated, pulses symmetric at wrists.
Derm: no suspicious lesions


Data
1.2 2/2096


PSA 11/02/86 0.5 
Td Booster 04/07/2094 


Microalbumin 04/13/2095 5.6 


creat 1.7 1/2097


HbA1c 10/18/2096 6.80 =&gt; HbA1c 01/17/2097 7.20 
 
Triglycerides 01/17/2097 113 
Cholesterol-LDL 01/17/2097 59 DESIRABLE: &lt;130 
Microalbumin 01/17/2097 9.2 
Cholesterol-HDL 01/17/2097 32 



ct scan 5/2096
 IMPRESSION:     Stable pulmonary nodules.


thyroid u/s 4/2096 
Thyroid nodule as above.  No suspicious ultrasound features.


A/P


1. Diabetes Mellitus type2:  still has HbA1c above 7.0. No more hypoglycemic episodes.
c/w current meds. If the repeat Hba1c is still above 7, then will need additional medication;


2. Dyspnea on exertion: reviewed potential risk of cardiac ischemia. Recommend stress testing. Will obtain ecg today. To ED if symptoms progress or if chest pain.
Follow up after stress test 


3. vit B12 deficiency: repeat B12 level wnl last time. Continue with oral supplementation
due for UGI/SBFT but pt declines to have test.


4. chronic renal insufficiency: creat normalized 2/96  with fluids then rising in 1/2097.
Recheck again today



5
. cough: resolved.  Has pulmonary nodules. Due for surveillance ct scan in 5/2097


HM: Due for colonoscopy but pt declines.
Influenza Vaccine 10/20/2096 
Pneumovax 01/29/2089 
PSA 11/19/86 0.5 REF. RANGE: MALE AGE:&gt;39 0.0 - 4.0 
Td Booster 04/07/2094 


_____________________________________________
Robert I Harmon, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-04-30


	CARDIAC SURGERY
	

	WILLOW GARDENS CARE CENTER
	
Date of Service: 04/30/2097 16:19

Demographics
Race: Caucasian
Surgeon: Troyer, Timothy
Staff Cardiologist: Yelton, Ora-jordan

History of Presenting Illness
81 male with a long history of claudication and gas pressure.  He had been walking for five miles a day until about a year ago, when he began to experience more symptoms.  He is presently able to get symptoms with minimal exertion. He had an exercise stress test, which was positive.  He underwent a cardiac cath today, which demonstrated severe left main in addition to three vessel coronary artery disease.  He had an Intra-aortic balloon pump placed and cardiac surgery was consulted for Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting.

Indications
Coronary Artery Disease

Pre-operative risk factors
Weight (lb)
Height (in): 70
Smoker
Diabetes type: Diabetes Mellitus Type II
Diabetes Control: Oral
Dyslipidemia
Preop Creatinine: 1.64
Hypertension
Peripheral Vascular Disease
Peripheral Arterial Disease: Claudication

Prior CV Interventions

Other Past Medical/Surgical History
Hypercholesterolemia
Hypertension
Peripheral Vascular Disease (PVD)Left greater than right 2095 studies.
Pulmonary NoduleSerial Scans last being 4/23/97
Vitamin B12 Deficiency Anemia
CataractsOD
Asbestosis
Peptic Ulcer Disease
BPH
NeuropathyLegs/feet
Chronic Renal Insufficiency
Retinopathy

Allergies
NKA: No Known Allergies

Admission medications
None

Current Medications
Acetylcysteine 20%(200 mg/ml) 600 MG PO BID
Cefazolin sodium (ancef ) 1000 MG IV Q8H
Chlorhexidine(mouthwash) 0.12% (peridex m rinse ) 30 ML MOUTHWASH on call to OR
Heparin 1000 Units/Hr IV 
Heparin Sliding Scale IV BID
Metoprolol tartrate (lopressor ) 12.5 MG PO Q8H
Mupirocin (bactroban ) 1 APPLICATION TOP BID
Omeprazole 40 MG PO DAILY
Simvastatin 10 MG PO DAILY

Preop Cardiac Status

Preoperative Hemodynamics and Diagnostic Testing

Cath report
 Willow Gardens Care Center   left main severe; left anterior descending 70%; CX ostial disease; right coronary artery moderate to severe; PLV .80 to .90

Echo
Pending

Carotid Non-Invasive Study
 Pending

Social History
Other Notes: DC smoke 2062, Married, Retired for 20 years, no ETOH.

Family History

Review of Systems
General: Denies fevers, chills, recent weight gain or loss
HEENT: Denies headache , sore throat, rhinorrhea, difficulty swallowing
Cardiac: Per HPI
Pulmonary: Denies cough, hemoptysis
GI: Denies reflux, nausea, vomiting, constipation, diarrhea
GU: Denies dysuria, hematuria, incontinence
Neuro: Denies syncope, stroke, TIA, seizure.
M/S: Denies arthritis, arthralgia, myalgia, recent fractures
Hemat: Denies easy bruising, anemia, deep vein thrombosis.
Vascular: + claudication

Physical Exam
GENERAL: No acute distress, speaks in full sentences and able to lie supine. HOH with hearing aide.
TEETH: No active infection, edentulous.
NECK: Supple, no JVD
CV: Regular rhythm, no rub, no murmur, + Intra-aortic balloon pump sounds
PULM: Clear bilaterally with supine exam.
SKIN: No lesions or rashes
EXTREMETIES: Warm, no edema
ABD: Soft, non-tender, no organomegaly
RECTAL: Guaiac negative
NEURO: Alert and oriented.  EOMI, PERRLA
Saphenous Vein: Ok bilaterally on supine exam following IABP.
Pulse 1+ throughout.   
Bruits: none in abdomen or Carotids.


Chest X-ray
Pending

Most Recent Labs (since admission)
-- CBC --
2097/04/30 15:58 - WBC... 5.2 th/cmm
2097/04/30 15:58 - Hgb... 13.6 gm/dl
2097/04/30 15:58 - Hct... 36.5 % (L)
2097/04/30 15:58 - Plt... 151 th/cumm
-- BMP --
2097/04/30 16:04 - P Na... PEND mmol/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - P K... PEND mmol/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - P Cl... PEND mmol/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - P TCO2... PEND mmol/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - P BUN... PEND mg/dl
2097/04/30 16:04 - P Cre... PEND mg/dl
2097/04/30 16:04 - P Glu... PEND mg/dl
2097/04/30 16:04 - Phos... PEND mg/dl
2097/04/30 16:04 - Mg... PEND meq/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - TSH... PEND uU/ml
-- HFP --
2097/04/30 16:04 - SGOT... PEND U/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - SGPT... PEND U/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - Alk Phos... PEND U/L
2097/04/30 16:04 - TBili... PEND mg/dl
2097/04/30 16:04 - DBili... PEND mg/dl
2097/04/30 16:04 - Alb... PEND g/dl
-- CARDIAC --
2097/04/30 16:04 - CPK... PEND U/L
-- COAGS --
2097/04/30 16:12 - PT... 13.1 sec
2097/04/30 16:12 - PT-INR... 1.1 
2097/04/30 16:12 - APTT... 65.8 sec (H)

Problems and Plans
1: CAD Plan for Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting on IABP, tenative date for 5/01.   Echocardiogram pending to eval for valvular disease and EF.  If needs valve surgery, he is edentulous.  Have consented for both pending results.  + recent ASA.  On heparin. 
2: CNIS Pending.  Has Hx of RICA disease in 2095. 
3: Pulmonary H/O Asbestosis.   Serial CT's demonstrating nodules.  Discussed results with Dr Troyer.   Plan to proceed with surgery for now, and reeval post op. 
4: Renal CRI noted.  Perhaps secondary to Lisinopril or EF.
Pt and family aware of possible need for dialysis. 
5: Diabetes Mellitus Type II Presently oral control. 
6: Preop Issues - labs pending
- Cardiac surgery consent completed for Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting +/- valve surgery pending echocardiogram results. 

Signed by Mitchell Jaynes Pa  on 04/30/2097 16:19




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-06-10


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	WILLOW GARDEN CARE CENTER
	

	
	Note: There is an addendum for this note (6/10/2097)
		


	Reason for visit:
   Mr. Bell is an 81 year old male with recent CABG, now admitted via EW with progressive shortness of breath and hypoxia for further evaluation.


	Interval History:
   He has multiple cardiac risk factors and a history of CAD dating back to April 2097. At that point, he noted increasing chest pressure and dyspnea on minimal exertion. Following a positive stress test, he was admitted for cardiac catheterization. Coronary angiography revealed severe multi vessel CAD. He had an IABP placed and underwent cardiac surgical evaluation. Carotid non-invasive studies revealed a moderate right carotid lesion with mild left carotid disease. 

He underwent a 4 vessel CABG by Dr. Troyer. His graft anatomy includes a LIMA to the LAD, SVG to the PDA and PLV and a SVG to the OM branch. He required re-exploration for bleeding. He also had atrial fibrillation with a rapid ventricular response, treated with Amiodarone. His IABP was removed a few days post operatively. He developed new anterior ST changes, and an echocardiogram revealed a marked decline in his LV function from 66% to 19%. 

He was taken emergently to the cardiac catheterization lab. Coronary angiography revealed a widely patent SVG to OM, a 30% ostial lesion in the SVG to the PDA and PLV. The LIMA was patent, but there was no flow into the distal LAD. He underwent stenting of the LIMA anastomosis into the LAD with a 2.5mm x 18mm, 2.5mm x 12mm and 2.5mm x 12mm MiniVision stents. 

His post cardiac surgical course was further complicated by a Serratia pneumonia and a transient worsening renal function. He also required sternal rewiring for sternal instability. He was followed by Dr. Hardin. His HIT assay was borderline negative. He was also found to have a factor VII deficiency, and was treated with argatroban. Lower extremity non-invasive studies revealed a R posterior tibial DVT, and he was discharged on Fopndaparinux. A follow up echocardiogram revealed an ejection fraction of 31% with apical akinesis, with only mild mitral regurgitation. He was discharged to rehab on post operative day 20. 

He was discharged from rehab on June 5th. On June 7th he was lightheaded and found to be hypotensive by the VNA. His systolic pressures were 78 to 90 mmHg, and his lisinopril was decreased and his Lasix dose was cut in half. He denies any chest discomfort, throat or arm discomfort or palpitations. He denies any PND, but has been sleeping in a hospital bed with the head elevated 45 degrees. The family updated the office earlier this morning - 2 pound weight gain and shortness of breath. His Lasix was increased to 40 mg bid. However, when seen by VNA, his room air saturation was 76%. 911 was called and he was brought to WGCC ED for evaluation. 



	Past medical history:
   CM/CAD as described, Hypertension, Type II DM x 15 yrs- with nephropathy, neuropathy and retinopathy, Mild renal insufficiency, PVD, Carotid disease, Factor VII Deficiency, BPH, Hearing loss, Vitamin B12 deficiency. 

PSH: CABG 5/01/97, Cataract OD.

	

	Changes to Allergies
	
NKA: No Known Allergies - reaction: [reviewed]


	Medications (Confirmed):

	
aspirin  81mg po daily - took 4 this AM
atenolol  25mg po bid
fondaparinux  5mg sc daily
glyburide  5mg po daily
Lasix  40mg po bid
magnesium oxide  800 mg po tid
multivitamins  1 tab po daily
omeprazole  20mg po daily
Plavix  75mg po daily
potassium chloride  10mEq po daily
regular insulin  sliding scale sc tid
simvastatin  80mg po qpm
trazodone  50mg x 1/2 tab po at bedtime
vitamin b12  1000 mcg po daily


	Family history:
   F deceased with cardiomyopathy at 64; M deceased with CA at 54; 1 B at 85 with CVA; 1 S at 87 with CHF.


	Social history:
   Married, 6 adult children, retired Geochemist. 
Tobacco: Quit 2062; ETOH: None; Caffeine: 1-2 cups/day; Exercise: Very limited since discharge.


	Review of systems:
   Negative for: Frequent headaches, recent visual changes, TIA, CVA, syncope, asthma, Liver disease, anemia. 

Positive for: as stated, Laser treatment OU April 97, Hx of asbestosis, Remote PUD, Clotting disorder, PVD - with bilateral claudication at 1 block.

Physical examination:
	
-Pulse: 78  
-resp. rate: 20  100% on 2L
-General:   A&amp;O, well developed, fatigued appearing elderly male in NAD.
-Skin:   Pale, warm and dry.
-HEENT:   NC/AT.  WNL.
-Chest:   Lung sounds diminished in bases bilaterally with fine crackles 1/4 up.  No wheeze.  Mid sternal incision well approximated, without drainage.  Steri strips intact.
-Cardiac:   Normal S1 and S2, with a 1/6 systolic murmur at LSB without S3, or S4. No rub.
-Abdomen:   Soft, non-tender with active BS.  No masses or bruits appreciated.
-Extremities:   Femorals 1+ bilaterally without bruits.  Distal pulses non-palpable.  2+ edema.  No palpable cords.
-Neuro:   A&amp;O, grossly non-focal.
-BP: 134/88  


	EKG:
   Normal sinus rhythm at 86 bpm with NSSTTWA V2-V5, I and aVL.

Selected recent labs:

	 Metabolic
Date     NA       K        BUN      CRE      
06/10/97 126      5.0      23       1.22     

Cardiac enzymes
Date     CK-MB    TROP-I   NT-BNP   
06/10/97 NEGATIVE NEGATIVE 12848    

Liver and Pancreatic Enzymes
Date     LIPS     
06/10/97 50       

Hematology
Date     HCT      WBC      PLT      
06/10/97 33.5     7.1      154      

Coagulation
Date     PT       PT-INR   PTT      
06/10/97 13.8     1.2      32.2     


	


	Assessment and plan:
   CM/CAD - with recent CABG and coronary stenting, now admitted via the EW with dyspnea and hypoxia. Initial cardiac enzyme screen is negative, but BNP markedly elevated. Based on exam, suspect a combination of CHF and pleural effusions (diuretic medication was not being taken at prescribed dose accidentally). Will admit for diuresis, if significant effusion not improving with diuretics, may need thoracentesis. If BP allows, will resume low dose ACEI tomorrow. Check echocardiogram to assess EF and pericardial effusion. continue aspirin and Plavix. 

Recent DVT - on Fondaparinux - please continue and ask Dr. Hardin to see while in-patient (known to him). 

DM - continue current regimen, follow and cover as needed.

	
Helen T. Hattie Simms, NP

	
Signed electronically by  Helen T. Hattie Simms, NP

	
Addendum: 6/10/2097
Patient seen and examined.  Case d/w Hattie, NP.  Agree with assessment and plan.

In brief, 81 M with recent CABG admitted for increasing SOB with PND and orthopnea, probably 2/2 pleural effusion.  On P/E on clinical signs of left heart failure.

Plan: CXR, diuresis, +/- pleural tap.

	
Ora-Jordan Yelton, MD pager #33436

	
Signed electronically by Ora-Jordan Yelton, MD

			Document Status: Final with Addendum
		



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>