<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2155-05-17









17 May 2155





Brandon Ponce, MD

974 Parkhurst Drive

Peculiar, NE 54583



Re:	Jarome DEJESUS

	ECI 280-44-07-1



Dear Dr. Ponce:



I had the pleasure of caring for Mr. Dejesus during his ECI admission 05/16-07/14.  He is a 72-year-old man with CAD S/P diagnostic cath one week ago at SCMHC, found to have a moderately tight lesion in the LAD without significant disease in the left circumflex or RCA.  Because of the recent onset of angina and a stress test showing anterior ischemia, he was brought to ECI, where Dr. Yoseph Flint stented the LAD lesion with a 3.5mm by 32mm Taxus drug-eluting stent, with zero percent residual.  The right femoral arteriotomy was closed with an Angioseal, and there were no complications.  



He spent an uneventful evening without complaints, ambulating without difficulty.  His left groin was soft without hematoma or bruit, and extremities were warm and well perfused.  Morning labs included a BUN of 17, creatinine 0.9, hematocrit 37, platelets 236,000, and flat cardiac enzymes.  He was discharged home on Plavix, 75mg po qd for a minimum of six months; enteric-coated aspirin, 325mg po qd; digoxin, 0.25mg po qd; glyburide, 5mg po bid; metoprolol, 50mg po bid; Lipitor, 20mg po qd; Tikosyn, 500mcg po bid; Glucophage, to be resumed at 500mg po bid in two days; and Coumadin, to be resumed tonight.  He has PT/INR check arranged in several days.  He will follow up with you in the next two weeks, and will see his PMD, Dr. Paige, in the near future.  Thank you for allowing us to participate in his care.  Please call if you have questions.



Sincerely,







Barbara A. Rhoades, MD



BAR/pham

cc:	Robert-Joseph Paige, MD, 558 Paxton Terrace, Peculiar, NE 54583





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2157-07-17




DEJESUS, JAROME
28044071
07/17/2157


Yoseph Berg, M.D.
Broome Developmental Center
84 Parkhurst Drive
Peculiar, NE  54583

Dear Dr. Berg:

We had the pleasure of caring for your patient, Jarome Dejesus, during his admission to the Erie County Infirmary from 07/16/2157 to 07/17/2157 for evaluation and treatment of his anginal symptoms.  As you know, Mr. Dejesus is a very pleasant 74-year-old gentleman with paroxysmal atrial fibrillation who is on Coumadin.  He has a history of insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, hypertension and dyslipidemia.  He has known coronary artery disease and underwent stenting of his left anterior descending artery in 05/2155, at which time he had a Taxus drug-eluting stent placed.  He returns now with increasing dyspnea on exertion and had an elective cardiac catheterization performed at the Southwest Colorado Medical on 07/13/2157 that showed focal 90% instent restenosis in the left anterior descending artery with no other focally occlusive disease.  He was transferred to the Erie County Infirmary and on the afternoon of 07/16/2157, Dr. Yoseph Flint was able to dilate and stent the lesion in the left anterior descending artery with placement of a 3.5 x 28 mm Cypher drug-eluting stent.  The procedure was complicated by brief transient no re-flow that resolved immediately to intracoronary nitroglycerin.  The left femoral arteriotomy was closed using an Angio-Seal device.  Mr. Dejesus has spent an uneventful evening on our Cardiovascular Service.  He has had no complaints of chest pain or shortness of breath.  He is ambulating, eating, and voiding without difficulty.

His heart rate has been in the 70s, blood pressure in the 110s/60.  He is in atrial fibrillation.  His cardiac exam was irregular with no appreciable murmur.  His lungs were clear to auscultation bilaterally.  His left groin is moderately ecchymotic but soft.  There is no hematoma or bruit.  Extremities are warm and well perfused.

His morning labs revealed a sodium of 138, potassium of 4.9, BUN of 21, creatinine of 1.2.  His total CK is 58 with a CK-MB of 0.4.  His hematocrit is stable at 38, white count of 9, platelets of 300,000.  His fasting lipid panel showed a total cholesterol 123 with an HDL of 25, LDL of 49, and triglycerides of 244.

We are discharging him home on the following medications:  Plavix 75 mg p.o. daily, which must be continued for a minimum of the next three months, aspirin 325 mg p.o. daily is to be backed off to 81 mg after a few months.  He will resume his Coumadin at 5 mg daily, and have this checked with his primary care physician, Dr. Paige.  He will be on Lipitor 20 mg p.o. daily, digoxin 0.25 mg p.o. daily, Tikosyn 500 mcg p.o. b.i.d., glyburide 5 mg p.o. daily, Avandia 4 mg p.o. daily, Diovan 80 mg p.o. daily, NPH insulin 16 units each evening and sublingual nitroglycerin to be used as needed for chest pain.  We have asked him to arrange a followup appointment with you within the next couple of weeks and to see Robert-Joseph Paige in the near future also.  Thank you very much for allowing us to participate in the care of this pleasant gentleman, and please do not hesitate to contact us with any issues regarding his ongoing management.

With warmest regards.

Sincerely,


______________________________
Irving R. Ramirez, M.D.
ATTENDING


______________________________
Dictated by: Henry Phelps, PA



eScription document:8-0687422 DFFocus

CC: Robert-Joseph Paige M.D.
Koenen Collins County Clinic
886 Paxton Terrace
Peculiar, NE 19649


DD: 07/17/57
DT: 07/17/57
DV: 07/17/57




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2161-06-03








DEJESUS, JAROME

28044071

06/03/2161





Isaiah Y. Dill, M.D.

Southwest Colorado Medical Health Center

607 Batchelder Street

Suite 975

Robstown, NE  29768





Dear Dr. Dill:



DOB:  10/11/2082



Thank you for referring Mr. Dejesus to the Erie County Arrhythmia Service for consideration of catheter ablation of atrial fibrillation.



As you know him well, I will summarize his history briefly for our records.  Mr. Dejesus is a 78-year-old gentleman with an extensive cardiac history that includes coronary artery disease status post multiple percutaneous coronary interventions and stents to the LAD as well as RCA territories, a cardiomyopathy with an ejection fraction of approximately 35-40%, and atrial fibrillation.  In addition, he has multiple cardiac risk factors including diabetes, hypertension, dyslipidemia, and obstructive sleep apnea.  In addition to disease in his coronary vascular bed, he has a history of carotid disease status post left CEA.



He came to your attention early this year with symptoms of exertional dyspnea.  On further questioning, he reports feeling quite symptomatic when ambulating relatively short distances around his home or up and down the driveway.  He can walk no further than approximately 50-100 feet before developing significant shortness of breath and fatigue.  He was recently diagnosed as having paroxysmal atrial fibrillation that has transitioned to persistent.  He has undergone multiple cardioversions most recently in 03/19/2161, but was unsuccessful.  Prior to that, cardioversion in February resulted in a brief period of restoration of sinus rhythm during which time he felt symptomatically improved.  He also describes occasional fleeting episodes of sharp left-sided chest discomfort.  Cardiac catheterization on 01/18/2161 revealed a 30% LAD in-stent restenosis, 90% septal lesion, and 65% -70% PDA lesion that was stented.  A Ventriculogram at that time revealed an EF of 35-40%.



Other than significant exertional shortness of breath, he feels relatively well.  He has occasional symptoms of orthostatic lightheadedness but no history of syncope.  He denies any PND, orthopnea, or lower extremity swelling.  He has no history of heart failure hospitalizations.  His weight has been stable.



On review of systems, he denies any fevers, chills, or night sweats.  His weight has remained stable.  He denies any new onset cough, wheezing, or hemoptysis.



Past Medical History:

1.  CAD status post LAD PCI/stenting in 2155.  He developed in-stent restenosis in 07/2157, during which time he received a second drug-eluting stent to the LAD lesion.  He developed recurrent chest discomfort in 12/2159, and he underwent cardiac catheterization during which time he was found to have an 80% mid LAD lesion distal to his prior stents as well as a 30% proximal RCA mid PDA stenosis.  He underwent a drug-eluting stent to the mid LAD lesion.  A followup catheterization in 01/2161 revealed a 30% LAD stenosis, 90% large septal branch lesion, and a 65-70% proximal PDA stenosis.  Ventriculogram revealed an EF of 35-40%.  He underwent stenting to the PDA lesion on 03/06/2161.  An exercise Myoview performed in 01/2160 revealed no evidence of inducible ischemia.

2.  Hypertension.

3.  Dyslipidemia.

4.  Diabetes.

5.  Obstructive sleep apnea.

6.  COPD, prescribed home oxygen, though he is not taking this.

7.  Carotid disease, status post left CEA after presenting with an ipsilateral episode of amaurosis fugax.

8.? History of BLANK AAA by ultrasound in 07/2159.

9.  Atrial fibrillation.

10.  Obesity.



He has no known drug allergies.



His current medications include amiodarone 200 mg BLANK, but this has been discontinued since April, metoprolol 50 mg b.i.d., digoxin 0.25 mg daily, Zocor 20 mg daily, Plavix 75 mg daily, TriCor 145 mg daily, Lasix 20 mg daily, BLANK 5 mg nightly, aspirin 325 mg daily, Lantus insulin 62 units daily, Humalog insulin, and Protonix 40 mg daily.



His social history is notable for remote history of tobacco dependence.  He was formally employed in buidling construction.  He has multiple environmental exposures including insulation as well as spray paint and without respiratory protection.  He does not currently smoke or drink alcohol.



His family history is negative for early onset CAD, sudden cardiac death, or cardiomyopathy.  His father lived until the age of 88.  His mother died of a stroke at the age of 80.  He has a single sister who is 86 years of age and has no history of heart troubles.



Physical Examination:  His blood pressure is 115/60 BLANK of 66 beats per minute.  In general, he is overweight elderly man in no distress.  Sitting upright his jugular venous pressure is below the clavicles.  Carotid upstrokes are brisk bilaterally.  Lungs are notable for a few crackles at the bases, but otherwise clear.  There is no wheezing.  Cardiac exam reveals an irregular rate with a variable S1 and S2.  There is no audible murmur, rub or gallop.  Abdomen is obese, soft, and nontender.  Lower extremities are warm and well perfused.  There is trace pitting edema at the ankles.



Recent blood work reveals an INR of 2.2 on 05/28/2161.



EKG today reveals atrial fibrillation at a rate of approximately 66 beats per minute.  There are some nonspecific T-wave abnormalities, but otherwise no evidence of prior infarct or ST changes.  There is some low voltage in the limb leads, though I suspect this is related to his habitus.



Overall, Mr. Dejesus is a pleasant 78-year-old man with a complex prior medical history who appears to have persistent atrial fibrillation with a principal functional limitation of exertional shortness of breath.  He appears to be functional class III.  He does not have any frank evidence of volume overload on exam today, though his ventricular function and is not entirely normal.  Moreover, he has multiple comorbidities which may exacerbate his exertional dyspnea including COPD and coronary artery disease.



We discussed atrial fibrillation with Mr. Dejesus and his family today.  We explained that the brief period of normal sinus rhythm associated with symptomatic improvement may be a reason to proceed with catheter ablation.  However, given his comorbidities and the presence of persistent arrhythmia we warned that a single catheter ablation procedure may not be entirely successful and that waiting period of approximately 3-4 month post-ablation may be required to adjudicate success.  Given the length of the procedure as well as his comorbidities, we feel reasonable to consult with our anesthesia colleagues for possible consideration of performing the procedure under general anesthesia versus with MAC and had procedural sedation.  We will leave this decision to them.  Moreover, prior to the ablation, we will request a transesophageal echocardiogram to rule out left atrial clot prior to ablation.



Thank you very much for referring Mr. Dejesus to our care.  We will be in touch following the procedure.  As always, feel free to call with any questions.



Sincerely,





______________________________

Oscar U Rice, M.D.











eScription document:0-16320445 HFFocus



CC: Robert-Joseph Paige M.D.

Koenen Collins County Clinic

266 Paxton Terrace

Peculiar, NE, 54583

Fax: 

Email: 







DD: 06/03/61

DT: 06/04/61

DV: 06/03/61



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>