<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2088-06-28

Reason for Visit	

Comprehensive physical exam and ongoing management of multiple medical problems.



Problems	  

Congestive heart failure	      

He had admission to MCH 9/87 with CHF.  He was started on Carvedilol and Spironolactone during that visit.  He was aggressively diuresed with marked improvement in his symptoms.  Beta blocker was reduced during that admission as well.  Most recent echo from 5/02/88 showed severely depressed LV systolic function, EF 30%, global hypokinesis with antero-apical akinesis.  Moderate LV margin.  Mild concentric LVH and mild L atrial enlargement (41 mm.).  Dilated aortic loop.  Normal RV size and function.  Mild aortic insufficiency and trace MR.



He is now doing exceedingly well on his current regimen and denies any symptoms of SOB, orthopnea or pedal edema.  He continues to be followed regularly by regularly by Dr. Cook for his ischemic cardiomyopathy/CHF.

coronary artery disease	      

After his admission for CHF, he underwent dolbutamine stress test on 9/30/87, which revealed a small area of ischemia in mid-anterior and a moderate to large-sized area of ischemia inferiorly and there was moderate LV dilatation following stress.  Based on this, he was admitted to MCH and underwent cardiac catheterization.  10/87 he underwent stenting X4 of L circumflex coronary artery and third obtuse marginal branch.  Notably, his cath also revealed a dominant RCA which was occluded proximately and was collateralized from the LAD, which was supplied by the L internal mammary artery.  The L main had no significant lesions.  The LAD had a 50% lesion just before the first diagonal and the mid-LAD was occluded.



He had successful stenting with very good angiographic results and he received adjuvant intravenous [        ] therapy.  He was discharged the following day without complications.  Although his current activity level is somewhat limited by his DJD (see below), he is exercising regularly in the pool and he currently denies any symptoms of angina.

pacemaker	      

S/P DDD pacemaker for sick sinus syndrome 7/83 and doing well.  Continues follow-up with Dr. Whitlock/Cook.

S/P CARDIAC ARREST	      

12/76.  10/76 DEVELOPED EXERTIONAL ANGINA, POSITIVE ETT. CATH AT NEDH REVEALED THREE-VESSEL CAD. AWAITING CABG WHEN 12/76 SUFFERED CARDIAC ARREST. FOUND TO BE IN VT, HAD RECURRENT VT. TRANSFERRED TO MCH AND UNDERWENT CABG AND AICD 2/77.  [04-Nov-2078]



He is doing well S/P ICD implantation in 2/77 with revisions in 7/80 and in 2084.  

hypertension	      

BP is slightly high today, but we will recheck at next visit.  If it remains elevated, would consider increasing Carvedilol

diabetes mellitus	      

He continues on Glyburide and although he checks fasting sugars infrequently, they are typically in the 120's and he denies any symptoms of hypoglycemia.  He has not seen a podiatrist regularly and I have encouraged him to begin this process.  Will check FBS, HBA1C and urine for microalbumin today.

hypercholesterolemia	      

He has had virtual normalization of his lipid profile with Lipitor.  We will check fasting lipids and LFT's today.

nephropathy	      

S/P renal biopsy 10/79 for severe proteinuria which was consistent with diabetic nephropathy. As noted above, a 24-hour urine recently revealed 6gm of protein.  He is on new maximal doses of ACEI's.  [02-Jun-2087]



Recheck BUN and creatinine today.

peripheral vascular disease	      

He has bilateral femoral bruits and diminished peripheral pulses, but because of his limited walking ability, currently has no symptoms of claudication.

RECTAL FISTULA	      

SINCE LAST VISIT HE WAS SEEN BY DR. JENSON AND UNDERWENT A FLEXIBLE. SIG. HE HAD A SINUS OPENING IN THE LEFT POSTERIOR PERIANAL AREA. HE FELT THAT TO FULLY EVALUATE THIS TO SEE WHETHER IT WAS AN ANAL FISTULA OR A PILONIDAL CYST THAT EXAM UNDER ANESTHESIA WITH UNROOFING OF THE LESION WAS INDICATED.  PT SO FAR HAS DECLINED THIS, BUT WILL LET DR. JENSON KNOW IF HE RECONSIDERS.  CURRENTLY HE IS WILLING TO LIVE WITH HIS SYMPTOMS.

OSTEOARTHRITIS	      

He has had recent significant worsening in his L knee pain.  It has now gotten to the point where it limits his ability to walk, so that he can only "limp less than a block" and has difficulty with stairs.  Given that he has done well from a cardiac standpoint since his admissions in the spring, he is interested in pursuing a L TKR replacement if Cardiology feels it would be feasible.  Will refer him to Dr. Robles for initial evaluation.

Carotid stenosis	      

According to Dr. Cook's records, a carotid artery duplex scan from 5/06 showed 60 to 80% stenosis of the RICA, but I do not find those records of PCIS.  Apparently he is scheduled for a repeat study before he follows up with Dr. Cook.  He is S/P R cerebellar CVA back in '80 and has had stable minor neurologic deficits since that time and currently denies any new neurologic symptoms.



Review of Systems	

Small lesion on his R ear.  Recent R groin infection which required treatment with antiobiotics by Dr. Valentine in 5/06.  Nocturia X1.  Denies symptoms of hypoglycemia.  No neurologic symptoms.  Denies palpitations, SOB, chest pain, lightheadedness or syncope.  Denies peripheral edema.  No abdominal pain or change in his bowels.  He does have chronic rectal fistula and continues to have intermittent hematochezia and discharge, but he is able to self-treat this and declines surgery.  No melena.



Vital Signs	  

Weight:	 188   Pounds

Blood Pressure:	 140/60   

Pulse:	 64   Regular



Physical Exam	  

 

General Appearance	

Well appearing.

Skin	

Extensive sun damage, with several actinic-appearing lesions over scalp, forehead and pinna.  There is also one small pustule on his R pinna.  

HEENT	

Oropharynx edentulous.  No lesions.

Neck	

Neck is supple, without thyromegaly.

Chest	

Lungs are clear to A&P.

Cor	

RRR.  Normal S1/S2.  No JVD.  Carotids 2+ bilaterally, with very soft bruits.  I/VI HSM at the apex, without change.  No S3 appreciated.

Abdomen	

ICD in place.  No abdominal masses.  Nontender.  No bruits.

Rectal Exam	

Fistula present, without evidence of erythema or drainage.  No rectal masses.  Prostate diffusely enlarged, without discrete nodules.  Stool is brown, but trace guaiac-positive.

Genito-Urinary	

Testes without masses.  No inguinal hernias.  No evidence of recent R groin infection.

Extremity	

No C/C/E.  Diminished peripheral pulses.



Disposition and Plans	

(1)  Follow up in spring of '88, recheck BP.  ? increase Carvedilol.

(2)  Guaiac-positive stool.  Recent negative sig.  Will obtain barium enema.

(3)  Warm compresses and Bacitracin to pustule on R ear.  If worsening, pt. to call.  Referral to Dr. Thomas/Dermatology for a full skin evaluation.

(4)  Referral to Dr. Robles for ? left TKR.

(5)  Referral to Podiatry.

(6)  Ongoing follow-up with Cardiology.

(7)  Needs pneumovax and flu vaccine in the winter.



cc:  Keith Cook, M.D./Cardiology, EUD1

       K. Alex Whitlock, M.D./Cardiology, NOU042

       Vincent Thomas, M.D./Dermatology, AUX745

       Owen Robles, M.D./Orthopedics, KMZ928





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-06-27



                          OFFICE NOTE
                                
George, Rickey
MR #113-14-14
06/27/2089

COMPREHENSIVE EXAM. 

PERSONAL DATA AND OVERALL HEALTH:  Now 63, despite his multiple
medical problems, he continues to spend spring in West Virginia and remain
reasonably active.  Wife very helpful in cooking appropriate
meals and helping with day to day issues.  

ONGOING MANAGEMENT/MULTIPLE MEDICAL PROBLEMS:
    1.    Health maintenance.  Eye exam. Continue to recommend annual
    exams with Dr. Ortiz.  Influenza vaccine advised, Winter 89.
    PSA sent.  
    2.    Preventative counseling.  Continues to swim in a pool, no
    alcohol, no cigarettes.  Advised regular skin checks.
    Avoidance of sun.  Rectal exam neg.  Smoking status: none
    smoker.  Stool guaiac test: home with stool guaiac cards.  

PROBLEMS:
    1.    CAD.  He continues to do quite well with no evidence of
    current symptoms of angina.  He is s/p CABG and most
    recently s/p stent distal LCX 10/87.  
    2.    CHF.  He has severe ischemic cardiomyopathy with chronic
    CHF.  His most recent echocardiogram 4/88, showed a severe
    depressed LV systolic function with estimated EF of 30% with
    global hypokinesis and antero-apical akinesis with moderate
    LV enlargement and mild concentric LVH with left atrial
    enlargement, dilated aortic root, mild AI and trace MR. 
    despite this, since getting on a stable dose of Lasix and
    Carvedilol, which was added during his hospitalization for
    CHF in 10/87, he has done well and currently denies symptoms
    of orthopnea, PND or edema.  
    3.    S/P AICD.  He is s/p recent admission to MCH, 6/17 through
    6/19/89 for replacement of his cardiac defibrillator.  He
    did well without complication and he continues to follow up
    Dr. Cook on a regular basis.  He has had no VT, VF, which
    has been symptomatic or which has caused triggering of his
    AICD.  
    4.    S/P DDD pacemaker for sick sinus syndrome, 7/83.  Continues
    to do well, again, with close monitoring by Dr. Cook. 
    5.    Hypertension.  Blood pressure is excellent on current
    regimen and will continue same.  

George, Rickey
MR #113-14-14                 -2-            June 27, 2089

    6.    Diabetes mellitus.  He continues on oral agents, watching
    his diet and exercising as much as he is able.  He does not
    monitor sugars often but he reports when he does have them
    done, sugars are typically fasting 100-150 and no symptoms
    of hypoglycemia.  Will check HBA1C and urine for micro
    albumin today.  
    7.    Cerebral vascular disease.  He is s/p cerebellar CVA, 7/80
    with mild residual dysarthria and right sided weakness but
    has had no new neurologic events. His most recent carotid
    artery duplex study was from 5/88, showed a 60-80% stenosis
    of the RICA but I don't actually hear a bruit on his exam
    today.  He continues on Coumadin anticoagulation.  
    8.    Hypercholesterolemia.  His most recent lipid profile is
    quite improved with Lipitor with a total cholesterol down to
    136, triglycerides 313, HDL 25, LDL 48 on 6/11/89.
    Unfortunately, since his HDL remains low, which is
    suboptimal, but he has not tolerated Niacin in the past. 
    9.    Peripheral vascular disease. He continues to have bilateral
    femoral bruits and diminished peripheral pulses but because
    of his limited walking ability, he currently has no symptoms
    of claudication. 
    10.   Osteoarthritis. He is s/p left TKR by Dr. Robles last year
    and is now doing quite well.  Notably, he would require
    antibiotic prophylaxis for procedures.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  He denies chest pain, shortness of breath,
abdominal pain. He continues to have a rectal fistula.  Last
year, had a negative Barium enema study and several years ago a
sigmoidoscopy because of guaiac positive stool but this is
presumably secondary to the rectal fistula, which intermittently
bleeds.  He has had no recent edema in his legs. His left knee is
doing quite well and he is working to strengthen the thigh
muscles. He has nocturia one time per night. He has stable
impotence, some decreased interest as well as some decreased
ability to have erections, though he can still have a partial
erection. Generalized decreased energy level.  

PHYSICAL EXAM:  Blood pressure:  136/60, pulse: 60 and regular. 
Weight: 181. General: amazingly well appearing.  Skin: no
suspicious lesions.  HEENT: oropharynx edentulous, no lesions. 
Lungs: clear to A&P.  COR:  carotids 2+, no bruits appreciated by
my exam.  JVP flat. Thyroid: no thyromegaly. Nodes: no
adenopathy.  COR:  s/p median sternotomy scar.  Pacer left upper
chest wall. AICD with fresh Steri strips in place. No evidence 
George, Rickey 
MR #113-14-14                 -3-            June 27, 2089

of erythema.  Left upper abdomen.  S1, S2, 2/6, HSM,  apex no S3,
or diastolic murmur appreciated.  Abdomen: positive bowel sounds,
soft non tender, no HSM or masses.  Rectal: mildly diffusely
enlarged prostate without nodules, no rectal masses. Stool brown,
guaiac negative.  Extremities:  scar over the left knee, no
peripheral edema.  

DISPOSITION:  Follow up with Opal Fierro.  Flu shot in the
winter, sooner PRN. 




Opal Fierro, M.D. 
Dictated/Not Read

OF/valle


 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-07-07



 
                           OFFICE NOTE

George, Rickey
MR#: 1131414
July 7, 2090 

Reason for visit: Comprehensive annual exam/ongoing management of
multiple chronic medical problems.

Health maintenance. Complete physical examination 7/7/90.  Eye
exam: continues to follow up annually with Dr. Ortiz. 
Influenza vaccine scheduled winter 90.  PSA deferred given age,
cardiac issues.  Podiatry exam: routine.  Rectal: neg. 
Sigmoidoscopy 10/87, divertic's, Dr. Ramsey.  Smoking status: 90
pack/year, approximately 100 pack/year smoking history.  Quit. 
Stool guaiac: home with stool guaiac cards. 

Other problems: 

1.   CAD.  Status post CABG 1/77.  PTCA stent distal LCX 10/87. 
No recent symptoms of angina though he apparently was started on
Imdur during a hospitalization in West Virginia this spring.  

2.   Status post VF arrest.  Status post AICD.  Continues to
follow up with Dr. Cook on a regular basis.  AICD has not
triggered.  

3.   Status post DDD pacer for sic sinus syndrome.  He has
frequent ectopics versus ? AF by exam today.  Will check EKG and
rhythm strip. 

4.   CHF/CMCAD.  He had an episode of shortness of breath leading
to hospitalization this spring down in West Virginia.  Unfortunately, I
do not have records but there was some question of whether this
was related to asthma, allergies or CHF.  He has had two pillow
orthopnea and worsening edema than in the past.  He has also
noted some more exertional dyspnea.  He denies cough, wheeze,
hemoptysis.  ? PND. 

     Most recent echo 4/88, severely depressed LV with EF about
30%.  Mild concentric LVH.  Dilated aortic route.  Mild AI. 
Trace MR.  He is currently on a regimen of Imdur, Lasix,
Carvedilol, Zestril and Digoxin.

     Will plan increase Lasix to 80 q.d. Check chest x-ray, PFTs
and reassess.  
George, Rickey
MR#: 1131414
July 7, 2090 
Page 2

5.   Diabetes mellitus.  Continues on oral agents and has been
quite good with his diet.  Weight is actually down 10 pounds
which he attributes to excellent attention to diet.  Will recheck
FBS, HB A1c today.  He continues to receive routine dental and
podiatry care.  

6.   Status post cerebellar CVA.  Mild residual dysarthria and
right sided weakness.  No new neurologic events.  Most recent
carotid study 5/88, 60-80% stenosis right internal carotid.  He
continues on Coumadin.

7.   Hyperlipidemia.  Continues on Lipitor with improved lipid
profile though HDL remains low.  He has not tolerated Niacin in
the past.  Will recheck fasting lipids today.

8.   Peripheral vascular disease.  Continues to have bilateral
femoral bruits but no complaints of claudication.  

9.   Osteoarthritis/left knee pain.  He is status post left TKR
by Dr. Robles last year.  Unfortunately had a knee injury down in
West Virginia this spring and has quite a bit of problem with swelling
and pain.  He was seen by Dr. Robles who treated him briefly with
Vioxx but this caused significant worsening lower extremity edema
and decreased urine output requiring its discontinuation.  He is
now carefully using ibuprofen and has follow up scheduled with
Dr. Robles.

10.  Nephropathy.  Status post renal biopsy 10/79 for severe
proteinuria.  Biopsy consistent with diabetic nephropathy. 
Continues on ACE inhibitor.  Will recheck BUN, creatinine today.

Review of systems: As per HPI, no abdominal pain, nausea,
vomiting, melena, hematochezia, hematuria.  Otherwise as noted
above.

Physical examination: Weight 175 (down from 181 6/89).  Pulse 64,
? frequent ectopic beats versus irregularly irregular rhythm. 
Blood pressure 130/70.  General: thin, but well appearing.  Skin:
no suspicious lesions.  HEENT: oropharynx edentulous, no lesions.
Lungs: clear to A&P.  Cor.: Carotids 2+, no bruits appreciated on
my exam. No thyromegaly.  Nodes: no adenopathy. Cor.: status post
median sternotomy.  Pacer left 
George, Rickey
MR#: 1131414
July 7, 2090 
Page 3

upper chest wall, AICD left upper abdomen.  Distant heart sounds,
S1, S2, II/VI HSM apex, no S3 or diastolic murmur appreciated.
Femoral pulses 2+ with soft bruits bilaterally.  Distal pulses
not palpable.  Abdomen: positive bowel sounds, soft, nontender,
no HSM or mass.  Rectal: mildly diffuse prostate without nodules,
no rectal masses.  Stool brown guaiac negative.  Extremities:
knee brace, left knee.  1+ edema bilaterally.  

Disposition: Follow up with Opal Fierro after PFTs.  



Opal Fierro, M.D.
Dictated/Not Read 
/harris

cc:
Keith Cook, M.D.
Massillon Community Hospital
7 Monterey Avenue
Mexico CT 51299 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-06-10



                          OFFICE NOTE
George, Rickey
MRN: 1131414
06/10/92

REASON FOR VISIT:  Scheduled follow up of multiple medical problems.

PROBLEMS:
1.   Status post removal of infected AICD and pacer.  Admitted to Massillon Community 12/91 with infection of his AICD and permanent pacer.  He was managed by multiple
services including EP, Cardiology, and ID.  His OR cultures grew candida and he was treated
with a prolonged course of fluconazole.  Although he had runs of NSVT, he was managed
effectively with carvedilol.  Notably his digoxin was stopped because of bradycardia during the
hospitalization. He never had any sustained VT or VF.  He was subsequently discharged home
with a Life vest defibrillator.

He has done well with no recurrent evidence of infection.  He currently has no AICD or
pacemaker but saw Dr. Cook yesterday and apparently he is being evaluated for new hardware
for his arrhythmia issues.  He has a history of both VF arrest and sick sinus syndrome.  Currently
his heart rate is slightly irregular but a reasonable rate and he will continue on his current
regimen as prescribed by Dr. Cook with close follow up.  

2.   CHF.  Immediately after his discharge from CCGH after his hospitalization, he went
directly to West Virginia where his wife was able to care for him. He had one episode of CHF, which
was managed as an outpatient, and he is now on slightly doses of Lasix than previously.  At the
present time, he has no active symptoms of CHF, he continues to sleep on two large pillows at
night without symptoms of orthopnea and has minimal to no peripheral edema.  He does
continue on an ACE inhibitor and potassium along with his Lasix. 

3.   Coronary artery disease.  Despite all of his active issues, he has no current symptoms of
angina and has tolerated his multiple recent procedures well.

4.   Status post infected (staph) left knee arthroplasty.  His left TKR also required removal
due to infection and he had replacement of new hardware by Dr. Judd 10/91.  He has had no
recurrent infection, but his rehabilitation has been more limited because of his other medical
issues.  He does report that he was swimming in the pool and doing things on his own while
down in West Virginia, but we will make a formal rehab referral now that he is back in the Mexico area.

5.   Diabetes mellitus.  Throughout his numerous medical problems over the past six to
twelve months, he has had a significant weight loss and not surprisingly, his diabetes regimen
has been gradually decreased.  He is now on Glyburide 5 mg b.i.d. and he reports that his fasting
sugars which he is checking about three times a week are running quite good in the 100 to 120
range.  He has no complaints of hypoglycemia or blood sugars greater than 200.  We will check
his HbA1c today and continue his current regimen.
George, Rickey
MRN: 1131414
06/10/92
Page 2

6.   Hyperlipidemia.  He continues on Lipitor.  We'll recheck his fasting lipids, LFTs and
CPK.

7.   Diabetic nephropathy.  He remains on ACE inhibitor and will check renal function today
to re-establish baseline.

8.   Status post CVA.  Known moderate right carotid stenosis.  Minimal residual dysarthria
and right-sided weakness. Has had no recent neurologic symptoms and remains on Coumadin.

PHYSICAL EXAM:  Blood pressure by palpation 130.  Was unable to get sufficient blood
pressure by cuff.  Pulse 60, mostly irregular. General, thin, but no distress.  Lungs, clear to
auscultation and percussion.  Cor, distant heart sounds.  No S3 appreciated. Old pacer/AICD site. 
No evidence of erythema or fluctuance.  Extremities, trace edema bilaterally.

DISPOSITION:  Close ongoing follow up.

ADDENDUM:  In reviewing patient's medical records after he left today, I found mention of
both hematuria and guaiac positive stool during his recent hospitalizations.  At this time, he was
quite debilitated and I do not think it would be a good time for colonoscopy.  He did deny
abdominal symptoms as part of my review of systems today.  

At this point, my plan will be to send him some stool guaiac cards which he can do at home and
send in to me by mail.  I have also sent off a CBC today.  I will plan to repeat urinalysis at his
next visit.  If he has persistent hematuria or guaiac positive stool, then we will need to discuss
more aggressive work-up, but given his overall health condition, I do not feel the need to be
aggressive at this time and would like to see him get some strength back first. 



____________________________________
Opal C. Fierro, M.D.
Dictated/Not read
kurtz

cc:
Keith Cook, M.D.
Massillon Community Hospital
22 Monterey Avenue, Cardiology Service
Mexico, CT 33383-9795



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-10-05


  
                      OFFICE NOTE
  Rickey George
  MR#1131414
  October 05, 2092
  
  Reason for visit: scheduled follow up status post MCH hospitalization.  
  
  PROBLEMS:
  
  PVD: since last visit he was admitted to MCH with gangrene in his left second toe. 
  Admitted MCH 8/29 through 9/9/92.  Treated by Dr. Randall.  Underwent extensive
  revascularization including right common and external artery transluminal balloon
  angioplasty and stenting, bilateral common and profunda femoral artery
  endarterectomies, right and left femoral to femoral bypass graft, left femoral to above
  knee popliteal bypass graft.  With this surgery, only his left second toe remained
  gangrenous and he was able to avoid BKA.  
  
  He will likely either auto-amputate or will require amputation of his left second toe
  which remains gangrenous but he has reasonable perfusion to the remainder of his left
  foot and has follow up scheduled next week with Dr. Randall.  
  
  Renal insufficiency: during his hospitalization he bumped his creatinine quite a bit but
  this appeared to be due to acute interstitial nephritis caused by Unasyn (positive urine
  EO's), reached a high of 3.9 on 9/02 but was down to 1.4 which is baseline at the time of
  hospital discharge 9/9.  Will recheck renal function today.  
  
  Diabetes mellitus: his appetite has been poor and he had blood sugars, which were low on
  oral agents, and these have been discontinued.  His blood sugars are now in the normal
  range on no oral agents or insulin.  Will need to monitor closely through rehab.  
  
  CHF: he had been on 80 b.i.d. of Lasix prior to his hospitalization.  At the time of
  hospital discharge his dose was down to 40 b.i.d. and not surprisingly he developed quite
  a bit of recurrent peripheral edema.  He called the office and I increased his Lasix back
  up to 60 b.i.d. but he still has significant edema.  Will go back to 80 b.i.d. with close
  monitoring.  
  
  Hypertension: with diuresis and weight loss, his BP is running low.  Will hold lisinopril
  for now.  Close VNA follow up.  
  
  COPD: doing well despite recent surgery.  Continues to use Combivent inhaler p.r.n.  
  
  Anemia: Crit was in the 20's during his hospitalization in the setting of acute renal failure
  and surgery with blood loss.  His Crit at the time of discharge was approximately 28.7
  and he was being started on Epogen.  Unfortunately because of insurance issues, he has
  not actually been able to yet obtain it but the plan is for him to get 2,000 units 3 times a
  
  
  Rickey George
  MR#1131414
  October 05, 2092
  Page 2
  
  week.  For now, he is on vitamins and iron supplements as his bowels tolerate.  Given his
  history of CAD, goal is to keep his hematocrit between 30-32.  
  
  Coronary artery disease: despite his recent surgical stress and anemia, he has had no
  anginal symptoms.  
  
  Review of systems: constipation related to the iron.  Generally weak.  Home services
  now include VNA, home health aide, PTOT, walking with a walker, biggest issue is
  mostly depression in the setting of his failing health.  
  
  Social history: wife very involved with his care.  
  
  Physical exam: BP 98/60.  Pulse 64.  Lungs clear to A & P.  Cor: SEMACIAN gallop. 
  No rub.  Abdomen: mildly distended, nontender.  Multiple well healed surgical scars. 
  Extremities: incisions in the groin.  No erythema.  Right groin several cm question cystic
  structure beneath the incision.  Soft, nontender, non-erythematous.  2-3+ edema in the
  extremities bilaterally.  Dry gangrene left second toe.  
  
  Disposition: 1. Increase Lasix to 80 b.i.d. phone follow up within several days.  
  2. Temporarily hold lisinopril given low BP.  
  3. Continue Percocet for toe pain.  
  4. Follow up with Dr. Randall who needs to assess the cystic mass in his right groin.  
  5. Will continue to work with insurance to try to obtain Epogen.  In the meantime, will
  transfuse if Crit drops below 28.  
  6. Add Lexapro 10mg 1 p.o. q.d. 
  
  Addendum: long discussion with the patient and his wife (his healthcare proxy) today
  about end of life issues.  Specifically he states he would never consider any amputation
  other than his single toe at this point.  He would specifically "rather die" than undergo a
  BKA.  He also states he wishes to be DNR and would not consider intubation even under
  the circumstances of acute CHF or pneumonia.  
  
  
  Opal Fierro, M.D.
  Dictated/Not Read
  /howell
  
  
  
  Rickey George
  MR#1131414
  October 05, 2092
  Page 3
  
  cc.
  Oscar Randall, M.D.
  
  cc.  
  Keith Caldwell, M.D.
  
  
  



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>