<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2073-05-03



Reason for Visit

Issues Today:

1) CAD: Doing well, no chest pain or dyspnea with exercise, going to card rehab 2x/wk and County Sports Club other days.  To see Dr. Ishmael in 6/73.  Still on plavix. 

2) BPH: Saw Dr. Maddox w/in last 2 wks, PSA 3.2 (had been >6 in 2064). Flomax was making him sick with dry heaves when took in am, better now he's taking qhs.

3) HTN/past tobacco/elev chol: no changes in meds.



SHx: he and sisters moved from house of 31 yrs to new apartment complex in Lima with pool; likes it.



Problems



      Hyperlipidemia



      Past smoking    : 1-2 ppd x 40 yrs



      HTN



      Elevated cholesterol



      CAD    : S/P MI,PTCA/Stent RCA, LAD 50%,LCX 50%



      Elevated PSA    : (-) bx



      CVA    : (lacunar) -(L) BG 2/73



      BPH





Medications



      Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN)    10MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD



      LISINOPRIL   5MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD



      ATENOLOL   100MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD



      Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated)    325MG,     PO QD



      Flomax (TAMSULOSIN)    0.4MG,  1 Capsule(s)  PO QHS



      Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL)    75 MG PO QD





Allergies



      Penicillins    - Unknown





Review of Systems

+ occasional bruising on plavix and aspirin.

+ nocturia x1, stable.

Denies fever, chills, night sweats, or weight loss.

No nausea, vomiting, active heartburn, or dysphagia. 

No diarrhea, constipation, blood per rectum or melena.

No urinary frequency or dysuria.

No joint or muscle pains or swelling.

No visual or hearing loss.



Physical Exam

General: well appearing male, no distress.

HEENT: pupils equal, reative to light, occular movements full. oropharynx clear without erythema. no sinus tenderness. tympanic membranes obsured by cerumen, L>R. Neck: supple without lymphadenopathy or thyromegaly.  No bruits heard.  

CV: regular rate and rhythm, normal heart sounds, no murmurs or rubs heard.  jugular venous pressure normal.

Pulm: clear to auscultation posteriorly, without wheezes, ronchi, or rales.

Abd: soft and non-tender without distension or rebound. normoactive bowel sounds, no organomegaly.

Back: without spinal or costovertebral angle tenderness.

Extremities: warm and well perfused with 2/2 DP pulses. no edema. + clubbing (chronic) of fingers.

Skin: without suspicious moles. 

Prostate: deferred as done by urologist 2 wks ago.





Laboratory Data

2/15/73: chol 123, ldl 69, hdl 36, tg 89, sgot 20, ck 71

1/17/73: hgb A1c 6.80, mean glucose 141



Assessment and Plan

1. CAD: excellent control of sx on current regimen.  May be able to stop Plavix at next visit with Dr. Ishmael.

2. Chol: recheck fasting lipids in 9/73.  Cont lipitor

3. BPH: stable on flomax 0.4 qhs.

4. elevated A1c in 2/73: recheck today.

5. ceruminosis: left ear irrigated by RN.

6. f/u 9/73.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-02-06

Follow Up - post hospitalization visit



He was admitted 2/01-2/03/74 for NSTEMI.  On 1/31 he had symptoms similar to those he experienced prior to his MI in 2073: pain in back of left neck, left shoulder, and left arm.  As a result he did not exercise that day.  The symptoms improved spontaneously.  On 2/01 he did his normal exercise routine, running on the treadmill for 40 minutes; he felt fine.  Later that day, he had recurrence of the symptoms so he called Dr. Ishmael's answering service.  Dr. Patterson was covering and recommended he go to ED.  He is very impressed that Dr. Patterson saw him that evening in the ED.  There EKG showed no changes but troponin-I and CK screen were positive.  He was admitted to cardiology service and managed with integrullin and heparin.  When second set of enzymes was positive on 2/02 he went to cath lab, where old RCA stent was "pristine," LAD showed stable 50% lesion, but distal LCx showed 90% lesion.  He had PTCA and stenting with medicated stent, producing excellent result.  He was discharged on 2/03 on plavix.



Today, he says he has had no recurrence of symptoms.  He is feeling great.  He is concerned that he had the MI despite taking all his medications as prescribed and feeling so well with exercise.  He wonders whether he needs to re-start cardiac rehab.  He is avoiding exercise until he sees Dr. Ishmael next week.  He has had no groin hematoma or other complications.



Problems

Hyperlipidemia 

Past smoking : 1-2 ppd x 40 yrs

HTN 

Elevated cholesterol 

CAD : S/P MI,PTCA/Stent RCA, LAD 50%,LCX 50%

Elevated PSA : (-) bx

CVA : (lacunar) -(L) BG 2/73

BPH 



Allergies

Penicillins - Unknown

Ativan (LORAZEPAM) - Mental Status Change : agitation 



Medications

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

LISINOPRIL 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ATENOLOL 100MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 325MG, PO QD

Ntg 1/150 (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 Mg)) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN chest pain : use one tablet every 5 minutes upto 3x; if pain continues, call doctor. 

Plavix 75 mg qd



ROS

BPH stable, off flomax x 1 year.  Nocturia 1-2x/nt.

Denies fever, chills, night sweats, or weight loss.

No exertional chest pain or dyspnea.

No nausea, vomiting, active heartburn, or dysphagia. 

No diarrhea, constipation, blood per rectum or melena.

No joint or muscle pains or swelling.



Physical Exam

bp 130/76, p 60, wt 142 lbs

General: well appearing, no distress

Neck: supple, no LAD, no thyromegaly

CV: rrr, no m/r/g, jvp normal

Pulm: cta/p, no w/r/r

Abd: soft, nt/nd, +bs, no hsm

Back: no cvat, no spinal tenderness

Exts: no edema, warm, PT/DPs 2/2 bilaterally

Skin: no rash or suspicious moles

G/U: R groin without hematoma or bruit; mild ecchymosis infero-lateral R hip.



Data

2/01: CK 299 -> 398 -> 167; CPK Index 20.6 -> 31.8 -> 6.3; Trop-T 0.76 -> 0.85.

2/02: A1c 6.50.

2/02: chol 140, LDL 84, HDL 38, TG 88



A/P

1.  CAD: s/p NSTEMI 2/01: no symptoms currently s/p stent LCx.  May need increase in atenolol to bid to avoid plaque rupture in future; now on plavix (gave him some samples b/c of cost), will continue x 6 months; he will avoid exercising for now and discuss cardiac rehab with Dr. Ishmael.

2.  Lipids: good control on lipitor 10 mg qd.

3.  HTN: good control on lisinopril 5 mg qd, atenolol 100 mg qd.

4.  BPH: stable symptoms off flomax.

F/u 3 months.





_____________________________________________

Peter H Uddin, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-12-25

Episodic Visit



He has had a cold for 5 days and wanted to get checked.  He says it started Saturday with a tickle in his throat; he went to the race track on Sunday and felt the same; on Tuesday he had dry cough, occasionally bringing up clear sputum.  He had no fevers but perhaps some mild sweats.  He notes mild sinus congestion and post-nasal drip.  No known sick contacts.  He got a flu shot at the TFMC in 11/74 and pneumovax at last appt in 11/74.  He is feeling mostly better, and was able to work out on the treadmill for 1.5 miles without difficulty.  He has had no chest pain or dyspnea.  He is using Robitussin DM, but askes if there is anything better for him to use.


Problems

Hyperlipidemia 

Past smoking : 1-2 ppd x 40 yrs

HTN 

Elevated cholesterol 

CAD : S/P MI,PTCA/Stent RCA, LAD 50%,LCX 50%

Elevated PSA : (-) bx

CVA : (lacunar) -(L) BG 2/73

BPH 



Allergies

Penicillins - Unknown

LORAZEPAM - Mental Status Change 



Medications

Lisinopril 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Atenolol 100MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Ecasa (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED) 325MG TABLET EC PO QD 

Ntg 1/150 (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 MG)) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN chest pain 

Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD 

Folate (FOLIC ACID) 1MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Spectazole (ECONAZOLE NITRATE 1%) APPLY CREAM TOP QD PRN fungal rash 

Zocor (SIMVASTATIN) 40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS 



Physical Exam

bp 120/76, p 72, temp 97.5, wt 145 lbs

General: well appearing, in no distress

HEENT: PERRL, EOMI, no scleral icterus; 

OP-clear, with no exudate; TMs wnl; no sinus tenderness.

Neck: supple, no LAD, no thyromegaly

CV: RRR, no m/r/g, JVP normal

Pulm: CTA/p, no w/r/r

Abd: soft, NT/ND, +bs, no HSM

Exts: no edema, warm, PT/DP pulses 2+/2+ bilaterally



A/P

1.  URI: likely viral, already improving.  I have told him not to use sudafed containing products because of his cad and htn; he will try nasonex NAS to clear his sinuses; robitussin AC given for prn qhs use.

2.  cad: stable.  he reports his cardiologist plans to stop plavix after one year course.





_____________________________________________

Peter H Uddin, M.D.









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-02-09

 
BRENNAN CONVALESCENT HOME

Reason For Visit
Cough.

History Of Present Illness
68 year-old male presents with complaint of cough productive of white-to-clear sputum for two days.  He feels minimal chest tightness, with no shortness of breath.  No dyspnea on exertion or PND.  He denies wheeze.  He is able to tolerate exercise on treadmill without chest pain.  He denies fever or chills.  Presently, self-treating with Robitussin DM and Halls cough drops.  Has clear rhinorrhea.  No ear pain, no throat pain.  No sinus pain or pressure.

Past Medical History
CAD, status post stent x2.  
MI.  
Hypertension.  
Hyperlipidemia.  
CVA.  
BPH.  
Elevated PSA.  
Tobacco use in the past.

Physical Exam
Temperature: 97.9 degrees
Pulse: 64
Blood Pressure: 140/70
General: Well-developed white male in no acute distress
HEENT: TMs and oropharynx unremarkable.  Oropharynx is clear without exudate or tonsillar hypertrophy.  No posterior pharynx exudate.  Sinuses are nontender
Chest: Lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally
Cardiac: Regular rate and rhythm.  No murmur, rub, or gallop
Extremities: No peripheral edema

Assessment And Plan
1.  Cough, likely viral.  Robitussin DM as directed for daytime use, may use Robitussin A-C at HS PRN,(patient has own).  Reassurance re:  findings on exam.  
2.  Hypertension.  Blood pressure again today 140/70.  Continue to monitor for indication of increase in Lisinopril per Dr.  Uddin.  The patient has followup with Cardiology on 02/17/2077.
____________________________________
Yazmin Doss, NP






****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>