<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2093-07-13

CCU JAR Admission Note



Name: Urban, Russell

MRN:  4722064

Date of Admission:  7/09/93

PCP:   Georgia

Cards: ward



ID:  50 y/o man transferred to CCU for wide complex tachyarrhythmia 



HPI:  50 y/o man with no PMH and cardiac risk factors of smoking and family history (father died of MI at age 41) who presented to the ED with chest pain. He had an ETT per patient report in Georgia which was neg for ischemia 4 years ago.  He claims excellent exercise tolerance can run at least 3 miles without SOB or CP but does not exercise regularly.   At concert on day of admission, he was sitting at rest when he had sudden onset of crushing sub-sternal chest pain, 8/10, no radiation, associated with mild SOB and marked diaphoresis.  Pt reported some associated back pain with onset, like "I was being crushed like a sandwich."  Was not eating at time, not like heartburn, no fevers, chills, cough, or chest trauma.  EMT was called-2 SL ntg relieved pain, was given ASA. 



On arrival to the ED, he was chest pain free.  His HR was 52-60 in normal sinus rhythm.  On hindsight, EKG showed sinus bradycardia with 1mm STE in III,    mm aVF, 1mm STD in I, ? aVL with biphasic T in I, TWI in aVL.  He received ASA and SLTNG

Cardiac RF include tobacco (1/2 ppd x 30 yrs) and early family hx (Dad died of MI, first MI at 41).  No known HTN, DM, or hyperlipidemia.  



Course on floor:



Seen for initial H&P when patient came to CCU5.  During exam, patient became acutely diaphoretic, appeared uncomfortable, still complaining of CP with some mild back pain.  

BP:  L arm 105/66, R arm 90/63. (2 rpt BPs were equal on both arms within 5 mm Hg) HR bradycardia in high 40s, sat 98% 2L.  Tele demonstrated sinus brady, then several runs of 40-50bt wide QRS tachyarrythmia which spontaneously resolved back to sinus bradycardia. Pt was symptomatic during these episodes and appeared acutely SOB, diaphoretic.  Nursing supervisor and medical senior stat paged, 12 ld EKG repeated, pt was given 2 mg IV magnesium and 100mg of lidocaine, started on nonbreather. Heparin was ordered and pt was transferred to the CCU.  



On arrival to CCU, pt was lethargic and diaphoretic.  He denied chest pain, shortness of breath, nausea.



SDU Course:

For ventricular ectopy (likely AIVR in setting of ischemia), pt was transitioned to Amiodarone.  This was tapered off and he had no further ectopy.

 

Echo was performed 7/10:

                                  (normal)     (completed only if abn.)

MITRAL VALVE      NORM                           SEGMENT   BASE  MID  APEX

LEFT ATRIUM       NORM   LA    37

AV. A0. LVOT      NORM   AO    29                anterior

LEFT VENT.        ABN    LVIDd 50                ant.sep.

TV. RA. VC.       NORM   LVIDs 44                mid.sep.

PV. INF. PA.      NORM   PWT   10                inf.sep.

RIGHT VENT.       ABN    IVS   11                inferior

IAS. IVS.         NORM                           inf.pos.

COMPLEX CHD              EF    28 % ( >50 %)     pos.lat.

CORONARIES                                       lateral

PERICARDIUM       NORM



MITRAL VALVE

There is no evidence of mitral valve prolapse.  There is trace mitral

regurgitation by color and spectral Doppler.



LEFT ATRIUM

There is no evidence of left atrial dilatation.



AORTIC VALVE, AORTA, LVOT

There is no evidence of valvular aortic stenosis.  The aortic valve is

tricuspid.  There is no evidence of aortic insufficiency by color or spectral

Doppler.



LEFT VENTRICLE

The left ventricular cavity size is normal.  The left ventricular systolic

function is impaired.  The left ventricle is diffusely hypokinetic with

regional variation. The Inferior wall is akinetic.  The estimated ejection

fraction is 28 %.



TRICUSPID VALVE - IVC, SVC

There is color and spectral Doppler evidence of trace tricuspid insufficiency.



RIGHT VENTRICLE

The right ventricle is not dilated.  The right ventricle is diffusely

hypokinetic.



PERICARDIAL DISEASE AND EXTRACARDIAC MASSES

There is no evidence of pericardial effusion.



Pt was taken to the cath lab 7/11 where his RHC showed RA 9, PA 25/15/20, PCWP 13, CO 6.4.  Mild LAD disease, 30% circumflex stenosis, RCA 100% occlusion, stented x3 with dissection of RCA during procedure.  He also had transient reocclusion during procedure.  TIMI II flow after IC adenosine.  IABP and temp wire (for profound bradycardia) were placed during procedure.  V-gram showed basal inferior AK and anterolateral HK, EF approximately 40%.  His peak CK were 1491.

Because his initial echo showed low EF out of proportion to his ischemic event, other causes of low EF were investigated.  His serum Fe was slightly low, TSH was normal, SPEP had several low Igs but no evidence of myeloma.   Lipid profile showed Cholesterol 210, Trig 59, HDL 45, LDL 153.  HgbA1c was 6.3.  Because of reocclusion during cath, hypercoag workup was sent and was negative (including lupus anticoagulant, hypercoag panel, HIT).

He continued to have some chest pain post-cath with mild increase of CK likely d/t distal embolization.  He has now been persistently pain-free.  His IABP was d/ced 7/12.  He was continued on ASA, Plavix, Lipitor and Bblocker, Captopril were added and can be titrated up.  



PMH:

None per patient. 



FamHx:  



Father as above.  Mother no signific hx.   



SocHx:  Married, originally from Nicaragua, lives in Citrus Ridge now. Works as professional. 



HRB:

Tob:    ppd x 30 yrs.  

EtOH: Scarce. 

Drugs:  None



Medications/Doses:

 None



Medications at Transfer:

Lipitor 20 mg po qd

ASA 325 mg po qd

Plavix 75 mg po qd

Fragmin 5000 U sc qd

Captopril 25 mg po TID

Lopressor 75 mg po TID

Nicotine patch 14 mcg/d q 24 hrs



Allergies:  NKDA



Review of Systems (negative unless checked):

General:  Fatigue(  ), fevers  ( ), appetite  ( ), weight loss/gain ( ), heat/cold intolerance ( ), diaphoresis ( ), chills ( ), sweats ( ), travel ( ), sick contacts ( )

HEENT:  acute visual changes ( ), acute hearing changes ( ), dizziness ( ),  HA ( ), trauma ( ), sore throat ( ) rhinorrhea ( ), facial pain ( ) 

Respiratory:  SOB(   ), cough ( ), hemoptysis ( ), wheezing ( ), sputum ( ) 

CV:  CP x  ), vomiting (  ), pain (  ), diarrhea ( ), constipation (  ), melena/BRBPR ( ), hematemesis ( ), diff swallow ( )

GU:  dysuria ( ), urgency ( ), frequency (  ), hematuria ( ), discharge ( ) , STD ( ), burning ( ), discharge ( ) 

Musculoskeltal/neuro:  weakness ( ), pain ( ), tremor ( ), sensation ( ), skin rashes ( )



Please see today's note for exam and data. 



Imp:  50 y/o man with CRFs smoking and family history s/p RCA stent x3, s/p IABP now titrating up meds.



Plan

1.	Ischemia - 

  	ASA, Plavix, B-Blocker, Captopril, titrate up as tolerated.



2.	Pump - EF improved on LV gram at cath.  Diurese prn, plan echo in 2-3 months to assess recovery.  If persistent low EF, may need further w/u for additional causes of cardiomyopathy.



3.	Rhythm -  no ectopy, now off Amiodarone.  Replete K, Mg.



4.  Prophylaxis: Fragmin, Nexium







Louise Eisenberg, MD pgr 76699





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-08-19

August 19, 2093




John Ussery, M.D.

Worthington - Internal Medicine

80 Shattuck Street, IM 270

Citrus Ridge, MT  43782





Re:	Russell Urban	

WRH#	4722064	





Dear Dr. Ussery:



I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Russell Urban in Cardiology Clinic today.  As you know, Mr. Urban is a very pleasant 50-year-old gentleman who on July 09, 2093, while sitting at a concert in Central Park had the sudden onset of feeling    unwell   , epigastric discomfort, and profound diaphoresis.  He came to the Worthington Regional Hospital Emergency Room at that time.  By the time he arrived, his symptoms had abated.  He had an unremarkable electrocardiogram initially and negative cardiac markers, and was admitted to the medicine service to rule-out a myocardial infarction.  That evening, he had recurrent symptoms and was noted to have sustained wide complex tachycardia, which appears to be ventricular tachycardia.  He was transferred to the Cardiac Care Unit for further management.  The next morning, he underwent cardiac ultrasound, which revealed an ejection fraction of 28% and a diffusely hypokinetic left ventricle with an akinetic inferior wall.  Additionally his next set of cardiac markers returned positive.  He therefore went cardiac catheterization revealing a total occlusion of his right coronary artery and minimal non-obstructive disease of the left system.  This artery was stented with total of three stents (two Express stents 2.5 x 24 mm and one Pixel stent 2.5 x 28 mm), encompassing the entire length of the right coronary artery.  A left ventriculogram was performed and demonstrated an ejection fraction of 30% with a diffusely hypokinetic ventricle and and akinetic inferior wall.  He ruled in for myocardial infarction with a peak CK of 1490 and a peak troponin of 2.0.  A follow-up echocardiogram was performed on July 15, 2093. This study showed his ejection fraction had improved to 36%; the left ventricle was diffusely hypokinetic and the inferior wall appeared severely hypokinetic.  His reduced ejection fraction was out of proportion to his degree of coronary disease.  Because of this, a series of laboratory tests were performed which revealed normal iron studies, normal thyroid function, and a normal serum protein electrophoresis pattern. He was discharged in stable condition to follow up with me as an outpatient.



Since his myocardial infarction, Mr. Urban has been feeling quite well.  He has returned to work in the factory where his employed as a manufacturing manager.  He has had no symptoms of angina, dyspnea, nausea, or diaphoresis.  He has felt very well.  He continues to take his medications without difficulty, and denies any symptomatology whatsoever.



His past medical history prior to this hospitalization is largely unremarkable because he had not sought medical care.  Of note, he reports to me that about 8 or 9 years ago while living in Georgia, he presented to an emergency room with some chest discomfort.  He was evaluated and released.  He never had any further testing.  He did not have a stress test, cardiac ultrasound or catheterization.  Prior to his admission, he did not have any known hypertension or hyperlipidemia, but has been diagnosed with these conditions while in the hospital.



His medications include aspirin 325 mg daily, Plavix 75 mg daily, Lipitor 20 mg daily, lisinopril 10 mg daily, and carvedilol 6.25 mg twice each day.  He has no known drug allergies.



Ms. Urban is originally from Nicaragua but after working for Imports, Inc, he moved to Georgia where he lived for 24 years working as a Registered Nurse and in various other positions.  He immigrated to America about a year or so ago.  He has been working in Borders.  He currently lives in Toledo, Montana, with his wife.  He has no children.  He smoked 1 to 1-1/2 packs per day for about 30 years, but has not smoked since his hospitalization.  He drinks only socially and denies illicit drug use.



He has a family history of coronary artery disease in that his father had 3 myocardial infarctions and died at a young age of heart disease.



On physical exam, his blood pressure was 130/82 mmHg in his right arm and 126/80 mmHg in his left arm.  His heart rate is 60 and regular.  In general, he is in no apparent distress.  His jugular venous pressure is 6 cm of water.  His chest is clear to auscultation without rales, wheezes, or rhonchi.  His heart is regular in rhythm and rate with a normal S1 and S2.  He has no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  His abdomen is benign.  His extremities are warm and well perfused and without clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  On vascular exam his carotid pulses are 2+, brisk and without bruits.  His femoral pulses are 2+, brisk and without bruits.  His right femoral artery was entered for cardiac catheterization.  The site looks clean and intact with no hematoma and no bruit and a strong pulse.  His distal pulses are 2+ and symmetric throughout.



His lipid panel from his hospitalization reveals total cholesterol of 210 mg/dl, LDL of 153 mg/dl, and HDL of 45mg/dl.



His electrocardiogram revealed normal sinus rhythm.  He has T wave inversions in III and aVF, and he has a greater than 15 degree disparity between his R and T wave axis.



Mr. Urban underwent a exercise treadmill test with sestamibi imaging yesterday.  He exercised for 10 minutes 43 seconds achieving a maximum workload of 12 METS, and a peak double product of 21,600.  His electrocardiogram was negative for ischemia.  His nuclear images revealed a mild reduction in tracer activity in the inferior wall which persisted after reinjection consistent with his inferior myocardial infarction. There was no evidence of ischemia elsewhere.  His left ventricular ejection fraction was measured at 51%.



In short, Mr. Urban is a 51-year-old who had an inferior myocardial infarction, but interestingly during his hospitalization had systolic dysfunction well out of proportion to his coronary disease.  Also, his systolic function has improved over time.  I think there are two processes going on.  One is coronary artery disease.  Clearly this has manifested itself as an inferior myocardial infarction due to an occluded right coronary artery, which was treated during his hospitalization with stenting.  The other issue is his transient systolic dysfunction that is out of proportion to his coronary artery disease.  Given the rapid improvement in his ejection fraction, I can only speculate as to the etiology of this.  He does not appear to have a persistent cardiomyopathy, but a transient one.  I suspect that this is myocarditis.  Unfortunatley, I have no way of proving this for certain but clinically it seems to fit.  It is possible that whatever led to his myocarditis also triggered his acute coronary syndrome.  



From the aspect of his coronary artery disease, he will continue on aspirin for life.  He received quite a substantial amount of stenting to his right coronary artery, and I would opt to continue his Plavix for at least 12 months.  For his hyperlipidemia, I agree with Lipitor, and we will recheck his lipid profile to see if the dose of Lipitor is adequate.  His LDL goal will be less than 100.  He is well beta-blocked on his carvedilol, and we will continue with the current dose of 6.25 mg twice daily.  His blood pressure allows us to increase his lisinopril from 10 to 15 mg daily.  I will see Mr. Urban again in three months for followup.  I will repeat his echocardiogram in six months' time to see where his ejection fraction has settled out.



Thank you for allowing me to participate in the care of this very interesting and pleasant gentleman.  The patient was seen and examined, and the case was discussed with Dr. Orville Ness.



Sincerely,









Jimmy Orozco, M.D.



JO/0564

FI:  400908

DD:  08/19/93

DT:  08/20/93





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-05-11

Patient Name:  Urban, Russell

Patient ID:  472-20-64

Provider Name:  Orozco, Jimmy

Date of Visit:  05/11/2094

Visit Type:  Return Visit





John Ussery, M.D.

Worthington Internal Medicine

28 Shattuck Street, IM 270

Citrus Ridge, MT 43782



Dear Dr. Ussery:



I saw Mr. Urban in follow-up in the office today.  Since his last visit in November, he has been feeling well.  He has had no angina, no exertional dyspnea, no shortness of breath, no orthopnea, no paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea, no palpitations, and no other symptoms of note.  Since his last visit with me, he has participated in and completed outpatient cardiac rehabilitation.  He found this program to be very helpful; he sis very well with the program.  He is currently exercising on a regular basis and has no chest discomfort of dyspnea with exercise.  He has stopped smoking.  There have been no difficulties with his medications.  



On 03/16/2094, he had a follow-up echocardiogram done; this study shows an LV ejection fraction of 37% with septal hypokinesis and inferoposterior akinesis; there is trace mitral regurgitation; and aortic sclerosis, but no stenosis.  Notably, he has a right ventricular systolic pressure estimated to be 46 mmHg with a right ventricle that is mildly dilated and mildly-to-moderately hypokinetic.  He has been feeling quite well and has no other symptoms.



His review of systems is as above and is otherwise negative in detail.



Medications:

Aspirin 325 mg daily

Plavix 75 mg daily 

Lipitor 40 mg daily

lisinopril 10 mg daily

Coreg 6.25 mg daily.





Physical examination:

He appears quite well and is in no apparent distress.  His blood pressure is 112/60 mmHg and his pulse rate is 50 beats per minutes and regular.  His JVP is 7 cm of water with no Kussmaul's sign.  His chest is clear to auscultation bilaterally.  His heart is regular in rhythm and rate with a normal S1 and S2.  He has no S3 or S4 gallop and no audible murmurs.  His abdomen is soft.  It is neither tender nor distended.  He has normal bowel sounds.  His extremities are warm and well perfused.  He has no edema.



Impression:  This is a 50 year-old man with coronary disease who suffered an inferoposterior myocardial infarction in July 2093.  Additionally, he was also found to have cardiomyopathy with an LV ejection fraction of 37 percent.  He is currently asymptomatic from his coronary disease and his LV dysfunction.  Notably, his last echocardiogram shows that he has increased RV systolic pressure and some early right ventricular dysfunction.  The etiology of this right ventricular dysfunction is not clear.  There is likely a component of left heart failure.  In addition, he may have right heart failure out-of-proportion to left heart failure: he has a longstanding smoking history and may have a degree of COPD and, lastly, he may have obstructive sleep apnea.  He reports to me that he does snore at night, and his first wife in Georgia had told him for many years that during the night he had periods were he would stop breathing.  This raises obstructive sleep apnea as a consideration.  



Recommendations: Initially, I am going to start him on Lasix 20 mg daily to lower his preload to help with any component of LV failure that is leading to this.  The rest of his regimen is quite good, and I intend to continue them.  To help to see if there is any component of cor pulmonale that may be contributing to this, I am going to obtain first a chest x-ray, secondly a pulmonary function testing, and lastly a sleep study.  If indeed we find components of obstructive lung disease or obstructive sleep apnea, we will have him see a pulmonologist and treat these accordingly.  I will see him again in six months' time.



Thank you for allowing me to participate in the care of this pleasant gentleman.



Regards,









__________________________

Jimmy J. Orozco M.D.

Internal Medicine

Worthington Regional Hospital





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-09-19

Chief Complaint	

Cardiac Access Admission Note

Russell P Urban

# 472 20 64



9/19/95



Mr Urban is admitted s/p PTCA/stent x 2 (Cyphers) to his LCX today



History of Present Illness	

     This 52 yo gentleman has known CAD dating back to an MI in 7/93. He underwent RCA stenting at that time, jailing the RV marginal with sluggish flow afterward. Post MI ECHO showed EF of 36% w/diffuse HK.

     He underwent f/u ETT w/imaging in 8/93 which showed a small fixed inferior defect with considerable residual viable myocardium and no evidence of ischemia. EF at that time was 51%. He has done reasonably well since then.

    In late spring, Mr Urban noted some chest tightness and SOB similar in quality to his prior angina, but markedly less severe, which occurred with exertion. He had a repeat ETT 7/31/95. EKG was positive for ischemia. Imaging showed a defect that was c/w ischemia. His meds were adjsuted, but his symptoms have persisted.

    Today he presented for elective cath +/- via SDA. Cath showed his RCA to be totally occluded, with 2 LCX lesions. His LCX was stented with 2 cyphers (3.5 x13 and 3 x 23) with good results. He was put on reopro and transferred to Cardiology where he arrived pain free and in no distress. 



Past Medical History	

CAD

s/p IMI, RCA stent x 2 2093

Cardiomyopathy

CHF

Hyperlipidemia

Hypertension

OSA



Allergies	

NKDA



Social History	

Married, lives with wife

Works in Borders



Habits	

ETOH: occasional social

Smoking: 45 pkyr hx, none for 2 yrs

Caffeine: 2-3 cups in am daily

Diet: low fat, low chol, NAS

Exercise: was walking regularly until symptoms recurred



Family History	

Father with MI x3 at early age



Medications	

At Home:



ASA 81 mg QD

Lisinopril 10 mg QD

Coreg 6.25 mg BID

Lasix 20 mg QD

Lipitor 80 mg qPM

Klonipin 1 mg qPM





Physical Exam	

Height: 73

Weight: 182



VS: 90-110/60's, 50-60

Monitor: SR



Gen: well appearing caucasian male in NAD



Neuro: alert, oriented x 3, speech clear and articulate. CN II-XII intact. Strength 5/5 BUE- lower extremities not tested d/t activity limitations 



Neck: supple, thyroid midline without nodularity. JVP flat, no HJR. Carotid pulses 2+, no bruits. No appreciable adenopathy



Cardiac: regular S1, S2, no S3/S4, no m/r/g. PMI not displaced



Resp: clear anteriorly



Abd: soft, non-tender/non-distended. No HSM/masses/bruits. Bowel sounds in all quads



Ext: right femoral sheath in place. No hematoma/ooze/bruit. Pulses 2+ DP/PT, no c/c/e. 





Review of Systems	

Negative in detail except as noted above



Lab Test	

Labs:

















EKG:



















Disposition and Plans	

Impression: 52 yo w/+ FH, prior MI, s/p RCA stents, now w/recurrent angina and + ETT



Plan:



1. Cardiac: HR, BP well controlled. Lipids were somewhat elevated in recent past- lipitor inc to 80 mg QD- will repeat in am with LFT's and add zetia tonite for better risk modification. Increase ASA to 325 mg QD and add plavix 75 mg QD indefinitely. He is at high risk of progressive disease given his early RCA ISR. Continue reopro as ordered. Remove sheaths once PTT normalizes. Ambulate once activity restrictions lifted.

     Continue heart healthy diet, exercise, meds as ordered. Weigh daily, strict I&O given hx CHF after his MI. LP(a) was 24 last draw- Dr Orozco will consider adding niaspan after evaluating effect of zetia/lipitor in clinic. 



Further plans per Dr Ness/Dr Orozco







Rose Kang, MS, NP-C

b 28961





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-05-09



			CARDIOLOGY

			

			WORTHINGTON REGIONAL HOSPITAL

			



			Reason for visit:

   Follow-up



			Interval History:

   Mr. Urban is doing well today.  Since his last visit with me he continues to feel well without chest pain, shortness of breath or other symptoms.  He remains very physically active and has no symptoms with sctivity.



			Medications (Confirmed):

			

aspirin 325 mg po qd

atorvastatin 80 mg po qd

Coreg 6.25mg PO BID

CPAP

Klonopin 1.0mg po QPM

Lasix 20 mg po qd

lisinopril 10 mg po qd

Zetia 10mg po qd



Allergies:

			

No known drug allergy   



Physical examination:

			

-Pulse: 58  beats per minute and regular

-General:   He is well appearing and in no apparent distress.

-Neck:   His JVP is 4 cm. No carotid bruits

-Chest:   Clear to auscultation bilaterally.

-Cardiac:   Regular in rhythm, but bradycardic. Normal S1 and S2. He has no S3 or S4. He has no audible murmurs.

-Abdomen:   Soft. It is neither tender nor distended.

-Extremities:   Warm and well perfused. No edema.

-BP: 120/72  mmHg. 



			EKG:

   Sinus bradycardia. Otherwise normal



			Assessment and plan:

   Overall, Mr. Urban is doing very well. He continues to be very active with no symptoms of angina or congestive heart failure. Currently, his lipids are under excellent control as is his blood pressure. Ongoing secondary prevention and risk factor modification will continue to be paramount in Mr. Urban's care. I have discussed these issues with him in detail. 



I would like to obtain another echocardiogram to re-assess his ejection fraction which has been low in the past.  Also, I would like to see if he has had further development of pulmonary hypertension.  He will continue his current medications and return to see me in six months' time or sooner if need be.



Changes to Medications this visit

			

lisinopril 10 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 08/24/2093

Coreg 6.25mg  PO BID QTY:180 Refills:2 Start: 08/24/2093

atorvastatin 80 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 08/24/2093

Zetia 10mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3

Lasix 20 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 06/06/2094

aspirin 325 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 08/24/2093

Klonopin 1.0mg  po QPM QTY:30 Refills:3 Start: 05/01/2095

CPAP     Nocturnal.



			Signed electronically by   Jimmy  Orozco MD  on  May 09, 2096     

		



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>