<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2125-07-24

Routine F/U





================ Vital signs ================

Blood Pressure:   130/80   [Left Arm, Sitting]
Weight:   216   [Pounds]





================ Medications ================

GLUCOPHAGE (METFORMIN)  Variable PO 

ZESTRIL (LISINOPRIL) 10MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

NPH HUMULIN INSULIN (INSULIN NPH HUMAN)  Variable SC 

TOPROL XL (METOPROLOL (SUST. REL.)) 200MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ISOSORBIDE MONONIT.(SR) 30MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ASA (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS



Issues:



CAD...Now s/p CABG.  Sx preop were DOE, now no longer dyspnic even going up 2 flight stairs.  doing cardiac rehab. tolerating well, early in course, doing almost 2miles/45 min already.  Tachcardia on ToprolXL, still 80-90 at rest, 105 with exertion by design.  Advised that pulse may fall as conditioning improves.



Wt decreased 6# since last visit.



DM  Notes BGs 180 post rehab at 11am, 160s at HS, FBG~~120 or less.  On metformin 500/500/1000, NPH 30q11am/28qHS.  Discussed rational and controll.  A1C 8.1, above 7.0 goal.  Recc checking bg at 4pm as well, change am NPH to 7-8 am to cover lunch and dinner, and would increase 2U q 1-2days, watching tid-qid BGs and adjusting HS dose downward if FBGs <100.  Goal is no BGs <80, most <140.  Reduce frequ of increases as levels approach goals.



Lipids well controlled ldl=97



Claudication seems to be improving with exercise training.  Advised to continue.  Consideration for bypass only if limiting long-term progress.



HTN well controlled.



15 of 25 minute visit counseling.



RTC 3 Months, call if ? concerning DM control.

Note printed for pt.

______________________________                              



Fontenot, Leon, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2126-01-04

This is an urgent care visit for Mr. Valdivia.he is c/o URI like sx with nasal congestion, non productive couch and sore throat for several days. he is also c/o pressure in his sinuses and congestion in his eyes with excessive tearing. He has also been c/o progreesive SOB, he is diabetic with CAD s/p CABG and states that after his cardiac rehab finished about two months ago he sarted c/o progressively worsening SOB and he is now back to the level he was at before his surgery with SOB developing after walking for 50 yards. he has been compliant with his medications and contacted his cardiologist regarding these sx and was told he should be seen today by the cardiologist covering for his regular cardiologist who is away, but he refused and opted to wait till his cardiologist comes back next week. he denies any chest pain, but admits to bipedal swelling frequently. 

ROS: negative in detail except as above.

PROBLEMS

Retinopathy  s/p treatment, Dr. Lau, HWS

Hypertension  

Obesity  

Hyperlipidemia  

Peripheral vascular disease  claudication

Insomnia  since service.  NTI helped a little in past, not after a while.

Impotence  w/u neg 5/23-treated with viagra with good result

H/O Low back pain  treated with PT in the past; c/o 10/24-treated with nortryptiline

PTSD  

Glaucoma  Dr. Massey, HWS

Tachycardia  (sinus)

Coronary artery disease  s/p CABG 5/25

PAST Medical History  Tinea corporis resolved 18Axillary intertrigo 4/19h/o Substance abuse, distantR leg Fx x2Pneumonia in serviceEtOH sober 2114greater then 

Social history  Lives alone, seperated from wife 19, still work together at CNET (manager), along with son.  24 Working less.  Dating monogamously Laura 23greater then .  No pets. Grew up Brownstown, BS math Brown U., near MA math.  Served in Air Force in Canada, pilot.  

Family history  (+)(-)prostate/colonCa/CADPGP d 80s ?cause, MGF d90 age, MGM d73 CVAM d 73 stomach Ca, OA, obeseF d 84 multi-infarct dementiaS b66 DMS b74 DMSon b93D b94 GC due22D Fran b03 Abn pap24 Nephropathy  3/25 UTPro/Cre 2340/2.3 Diabetes mellitus  Type 2

MEDICATIONS

GLUCOPHAGE (METFORMIN) Variable      PO  

ZESTRIL (LISINOPRIL)   10MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  

ASA (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)   325MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN)   20MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QHS 

TOPROL XL (METOPROLOL (SUST. REL.))   200MG  1.5 Tablet(s) PO QD 

FUROSEMIDE   20MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

NPH HUMULIN INSULIN (INSULIN NPH HUMAN) Variable      SC   

insulin syringes USE AS        disp #100 order number 38/48

ALLERGY

NKDA    

PE: in no acute distress.

VITAL SIGNS

BLOOD PRESSURE  150/90 repeat BP 150/90

TEMPERATURE  97.8

Perrla eomi, throat: erythematous with lots of secretions but no pus or whitish lesions. sig nasal congestion moderate sinus pressure on percussion no pain. lungs: minimal bibasilar crackles. CVS: s1s2 rrr. abdomen: obese soft NT good BS. ext: minimal pitting edema.  neuro: non focal

A/P:

1) URI like sx with pharyngitis and some sinus pressure. will get throat cx to r/o strep throat. will also give a course of zithromax 500 x1 then 250 qd for 4 days. pt to call in AM to get results of throat cx. will give cepacol OTC for sore throat relief and afrin spray for nasal congetsion.

2) SOB/CVS symptoms I advised the patient that he needs to go to the EW now to be evaluated for his cardiac symptoms and explained to him that his diabetes, his Hx of CAD/CABG and the recurrence of his sx  puts him at a significant high risk . I offered to send him by ambulance from here, he did not want to go to EW, did not want an ECG stating that he will see his cardiologist next week. he clearly understands the risks and benefits including the risk of death if he does not go to EW today.

3) increased BP, he said he is compliant with his meds,he agreed to come back in Am for recheck.













****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2129-01-09

Team 2 Intern Admit Note



Patient: Valdivia, Elijah

EVC Unit Number: 845 52 82

Date of Admission:  9 January 2129

Attending Physician: Quentin Lemus, MD

Room: Internal Medicine 1718

Code Status: Full

PCP: Leon Fontenot, MD of Elkhorn Valley



Source: Patient



Chief Complaint: Weakness, Weight Loss



History of The Present Illness: 58 year-old man with a history of CAD s/p CABG, CHF, DM, HL, HTN, and OSA who presents with a complaint of weakness and weight loss in the setting of increased diuretic use.   

Patient has a history dietary indiscretion and difficult to control volume overload.  He called into his cardiologist's office Queenie Yeargan on 01/03/29, who was being covered by Dr. Haynes to report increasing lower extremity edema and worsening shortness of breath.  He was prescribed 5 mg of Zaroxolyn daily and had a 14 lb weight loss over the next three days.  The patient developed weakness and continued to feel weak and lose weight despite discontinuing Zaroxolyn on 01/05/29 under the advise of Dr. Haynes.  The patient did continue to take the rest of his medications. He reported to the ED for lab draw after reporting his symptoms to Dr. Quentin Lemus.  

In the ED the patient had vitals of 98.5  80  107/62  18 97% on RA.  The patient was given 1L of NS, 500 mg levofloxacin, 30 U of NPH/10 U of Regular, 100 mg of Lipitor, and 200 mg of Zoloft.

The patient noted a decreased amount of concentrated foul smelling urine, worsening SOB, and dry cough.  The pt denied lightheadedness, syncope, chest pain, F/C, N/V, abdominal pain, diarrhea.   



Past Medical/Surgical History: 

CAD s/p MI & CABG (5/25: LIMA to LAD, SVG to PDA, Radial Artery to OM1); last catheterization 1/2126  patent grafts, last stress 12/2127   adenosine MIBI, equivocal inferolateral ischemia and small posterobasal scar, last ECHO 2/2128  Mild MR, LA dilatation, EF 62 %, trace TR, RVSP 25 mmHg

CHF(diastolic dysfunction)

DM II -complicated by retinopathy s/p laser treatment, nephropathy

OSA -on BiPAP(15/10 cm)

HTN

Obesity-BMI 39 being evaluated by the weight center for possible gastric banding

HL

PVD

PSTD-Pilot (Air Force 2090-2092)

Plantar Fasciitis



Allergies: Lisinopril  cough



Medications: 

Metformin 1000 mg BID

Cartia XT 240 mg QD

Lipitor 100 mg QD

Lasix 80 mg BID

Toprol XL 100 QD

Humulin NPH 60 mg BID

ASA 325 mg QD

Zoloft 100 mg QD

Altace 10 mg QD



Social History:

Occupation - Retired communications manager

Tobacco - 30 pack-year history, quit 18 years ago

Alcohol/Illicit/IV Drugs - History of cocaine and EtOH abuse clean x 14 yrs

Lives at home with son



Family History: Non-Contributory



Review of Systems:

As per HPI, otherwise negative in detail.



Physical Examination:

T 96.7 HR 91 BP 148/77 RR 22 SaO2 97% on RA  

General - well appearing, well nourished patient in NAD, appropriate

HEENT - normocephalic, atraumatic, PERRLA, anicteric, dry mucous membranes, no JVP~10 cm H2O

Pulmonary - CTAB, good air movement bilaterally, no crackles

Cardiac - distant, regular rate and rhythm, S1 and S2 normal, no murmurs

Abdomen - obese, non-tender, mildly distended, active bowel sounds

Extremity - no cyanosis, clubbing, 2+ edema, 2+ and equal distal pulses

Neurology - AAOx3

Skin - no worrisome rashes or lesions



Data: 

   Chemistries:

 Na 133 K 3.8 Cl 104 HCO3 24 BUN 87 Cr 2.1  2.4  2.2 (baseline~1.4), Glucose 310

Ca 8.8 Phos 4.7 Mg 1.7

ALT 16AST 19AlkP 86 Tbili 0.4 Dbili 0.1

Albumin 3.3

CK         	165	186

CK-MB	--	4.5

RI		--	--

Trop T	0.02	<0.01

   Blood Counts:

     WBC 8.7  HCT 38.8 Plts 179       MCV 79, RDW 14.8

      12.9/--/23.3

   Microbiology:

U/A: 2+ Glucose, (-) Ketones. 2+ albumin, 1+ blood, nitrite (-), 1+ WBC, 0-2 casts, moderate bacteria, moderate squamous cells, 5-10 WBCs, 20-50 WBCs

   Radiology:

CXR: s/p CABG, low lung volumes, no pulmonary edema

   Cardiogram:

NSR @ 85 BPM, primary AV delay (PR interval 260 ms), LAD, RBBB, TWI in leads V1-V2



Assessment: 58 year-old man with a history of CAD CHF, and OSA who presents with weakness, weight loss, SOB, and ARF in the setting of increased diuretic use.   



Plan:

1.	ARF: 

-responding to slow hydration, will aim for euvolemia and hold diuresis and ACE-I. Gentle IVF at this time given tenuous balance between being dry and volume overloaded, will reassess volume status in the AM along with AM lytes

-hold lasix, ACE-I

-Urine lytes obtained in the ED difficult to interpret in the setting of diuretic use

-check Urine Eos (per attg)

-Renal U/S (per attg)

-treat UTI (levoflox x 10 D), f/u UCx

2.	HTN

-continue lopressor, hold Cartia XT and Altace

3.	SOB: Expected improvement in symptoms with diuresis but patient actually reports worsening of SOB.  Last ECHO demonstrated normal RSVP but concern now for progressive primary pulmonary process contributing to R heart failure not L sided dysfunction.

-repeat ECHO in the AM 

4.	DM

-holding metformin in the setting of ARF

-half home NPH dose with SSI

5.	CAD

-hold lipitor given renal failure,

-continue ASA, toprol, 

6.	Dispo

-Return to home 



                                                							___________________________

Quincey Harmon, MD

Intern in Internal Medicine

Pager # 32591



      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2129-05-10

Booked for CPE, but current symptoms took precedence.  



Pt presents very discouraged over escalating Lasix doses and persistant problems with reccurent edema and cough, each time relieved by increasing diuretics, so ACEI cough seems unlikely.  Avoiding all salt in diet with good compliance.  Did see sleep lab tech, tried new settings and mask on new machine, but still tolerates poorly.  When discussed in some detail, notes feelings of suffocation with wearing mask for any period of time.  Also notes sense of being tied down frrom mask very difficult to tolerate.  Without exploring details greatly, we discussed potential role of PTSD in precipitating symptoms related to mask use, and potentially  the effect of nocturnal hypoxia and RV strain on accumulation of fluid.  Improving tolerance of CPAP seems very key.  Pt has started atkins dt with good success (6# in first week), and improving BGs are requiring reduction in insulin, which is great.  so it seems that addressing OSA is the key to improving overall status now.  We discussed some options...Including potential for tracheostomy to fix this without having to address mask, but agreed to try to initiate trial of CBT to see if we can improve mask talerance with symptom reduction.  He remains quite clear that he has no interest in furhter "exploring" the PTSD history, and I reassured him that CBT does not require doing this.  



OSA:  Likely has near optimal mask set up now...We'll explore potential for CBT with sleep center or perhaps cardiac rehab source.  Hopefully this would address fluid imbalance to a greater extent as well.  



DM:  improving with wt loss and diet.  Agree with insulin taper as sugars drop.  UAMLB high but < 1 year ago, recheck in future.  Creatinine stable 2 months ago, recheck renal panel with labs.  Optho and podiatry current.  



Lipids: last LDL was an outlier..Has slip fro repeat FLP.  



Coronary artery disease : s/p CABG 5/25, satable on ASA/Statin/ACEI/BB



Hypertension 

Vital Signs

BP 118/70, Wt 235 lb

well controlled.  



Peripheral vascular disease : claudication limited Sx with limited exercise tolerance.  



Obesity :  adtkins dt as above.  



Glaucoma : Dr. Russo, HWS, gets regular f/u.  



Insomnia : since service. NTI helped a little in past, not after a while. CBT might help if successful.  



Reviewed HM, mostly up to date, should get Td update at some point or if wound, counseled.  



Most of 40 minute visit counseling on CBT, PTSD, sleep apnea, and concern about failing regimen.  

Emailed Barbara Fierro, Sleep center, Dr. Yeargin, and Dr. Ingham of Rehab to help identify best CBT practitioner for this.  

_____________________________________________

Leon Virgil Fontenot, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2130-08-09



			CARDIOLOGY

			

			ELKHORN VALLEY CLINIC

			



			Reason for visit:

   A 59 yr old IDDM man  s/p CABG in 25 with IDDM and CHF admitted after elective cardiac cath which revealed new RCA occlusion for post hydration/Mucomyst/bicarb.



			Interval History:

   Cardiac history began in 2125 with inappropriate sinus tachycardia. A cardiac echo revealed EF of 64% with no valvular disease and normal wall motion. An Aden MIBI 4/25 revealed inferior and PL ischemia and he was taken to the cath lab. The cath revealed mild pulmonary hypertension, PCW of 14, co-dominance with 65% PDA, moderate LCX disease and severe proximal LAD lesion. HE subsequently underwent CABG with LIMA to LAD, radial artery to LCX and VG to PDA. 1/26 he noted progressive DOE with upper chest discomfort and was brought to the cath lab. His PA pressure was 45/20 with a PCW of 20, all grafts were open and his BB and lasix were increased.

An Aden MIBI 12/27 showed an EF of 60% w small PB scar & inferior-lateral ischemia. Echo 2/28 revealed new LA enlargement with EF of 62%. He was admitted 1/29 with HF exacerbation/acute renal failure in the setting of rapid out-patient diureses with zaroxolyn.  (BUN 74, creat 2.2) Diuretics as well as Glucophage and ACE I were held and he was discharged with a creat of 1.2. An echo revealed new mild MR and RF of 59%. 

Over the last few months he has noted episodes of sudden lightheadedness/dizziness, floaters. He would take his BP with a home machine and it could be as low as 77/47. In addition, he has noted progressive DOE as well an now rest angina that is requiring a SL TNG for relief. He has 3 flights of stairs to climb to his apartment and uses 1 SL TNG prophylactically.  

An exercise adenosine MIBI was done 6/14 which revealed an EF of 75% with mild anterior  and IPL ischemia. He was admitted for a cardiac cath 6/20, however due to a creatinine of 2.4 only a right heart cath was done. It revealed  RAP of 7, RVP of 36/17, PAP of 35/17, PCW of 17 and CO 5.9.

Given his episodes of sudden hypotension as well as increasing creatinine, Diltiazem as well as Ramipril and Aldactone have been held. He reports no further episodes of hypotension since stopping these meds.

He is being followed by Dr You in renal service.

Of note, he continues to use the oxygen at night.(2 liters NP)



Cardiac cath today revealed normal LM, TO mid LAD with LIMA to LAD filling distal LAD, mild LCX disease, RCA is totally occluded with distal vessel filling via VG to RPDA, VG to RCA small vessel but patent, LIMA to LAD patent. Althought the RA graft to the PDA and VG to LCX are patent - they are small and atretic.



			Past medical history:

   CAD

IDDM x 10 yrs

retinopathy s/p laser 

HTN

CRI

OSA - can't tolerate CPAP

LBP

bilateral claudication if he walks fast

reactive airway disease

PTSD

Recovering alcoholic - sober x 16 years

remote ulcer - in his 20's

CHF - dry wt 215



PSHx:

CABG 25 with LIMA to LAD, radial artery to RPDA, VG to LCX



			Medications (Confirmed):

			

aspirin 325 mg QD

Atrovent 18 mcg/spray inh tid

Flonase 1 spray BID

furosemide 80 mg qam

isosorbide mononitrate 30 mg qd

Lipitor 80 mg QHS

Nephrocaps 1 tab qd

Toprol XL 100 mg qd

u100 NPH insulin

Zetia 10 mg qd



Allergies:

			

Drug reaction   lisinopril causes cough



			Family history:

   father mild MI age 59



			Social history:

   divorced, quit smoking in 08, sober x 10 yrs, retired communications manager



			Review of systems:

   denies ortho/PND/thyroid disease/melena/recent ulcer



Physical examination:

			

-BMI:   

-Pulse: 85  

-resp. rate: 16  

-height: 67  in.

-weight: 220  

-General:   No acute distress.

-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.

-Heent:   Unremarkable

-Neck:   JVP flat but difficult to see. - carotids 2+, bilateral bruits R>L

-Chest:   Lungs clear anteriorly

-Cardiac:   He has a normal S1 and S2, and a soft systolic ejection murmur at the left lower sternal border and apex

-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.

-Extremities:   right groin D&I, no hematoma or bruit DP/PT 1+/1+, left groin 2+, no bruit DP/PT 1+/1+

-Neuro:   A&O x3, CN 2-12 grossly intact. 

-BP: 139/85   



			EKG:

   75 RBBB -  first degree AVB w PR .22



Selected recent labs:

			 Metabolic

Date     K        CL       CO2      BUN      CRE      GLU      CA       

08/09/30 4.8                        46       1.6                        

08/08/30          100      30.9                       263      9.2      



Liver and Pancreatic Enzymes

Date     ALB      TP       ALKP     TBILI    ALT/SGPT AST/SGOT 

07/05/30 4.1                                                   

05/30/30          7.4      93       0.4      22       26       



Hematology

Date     HCT      RBC      WBC      PLT      

08/01/30 33.1     4.14     11.0     221      



Coagulation

Date     PT       PT-INR   PTT      HCYS/PBH 

08/01/30 12.0     1.0                        

01/09/29                   23.3              

07/31/27                            10.9     



Immunology

Date     HGBA1C   

04/11/30 11.40    



other

Date     CORT     RENIN    

07/25/30 37.0     8.9      





			



			Other Data:

   PFT's 7/26 VC 66%, FEV1/VC 109%



			Assessment and plan:

   77 yo diabetic male admitted after cardiac catheterization for post hydration



Plan:

Admit to Internal Medicine

Bedrest for 6 hours

Resume Lasix tonight - patient has not voided all day, just completing Bicarb drip

Fasting lipids, Lipo a, BNP in AM

Continue to hold Ramipril, Aldactone and Diltiazem

Complete Bicarb drip and total of 4 doses of Mucomyst

Follow Renal function

CNIS to evaluate carotid bruits

Continue NPH BID - s/s regular insulin as needed - especially given bicarb qtt in D5W

Nutrition consult for HBA1c 11.4, obesity

Per Attending - medical management for now - RCA lesion is long, would be challenging and require significant dye - will increase Imdur to 60 qd

Will need ABX prophylaxis for MR at discharge



Andreea Marquez RN, MN # 1-3051



Changes to Medications this visit

			

Nephrocaps  1 tab  qd

u100 NPH insulin     Start: 08/09/2130

Flonase  1 spray  BID nasally

Atrovent 18 mcg/spray  inh tid Start: 08/09/2130

isosorbide mononitrate 30 mg   qd

Toprol XL 100 mg   qd

Lipitor 80 mg   QHS

Zetia 10 mg   qd

furosemide 80 mg   qam in the and 80 mg in the qpm Start: 07/13/2130

aspirin 325 mg   QD



			Signed electronically by   Andreea  Marquez RN, NP  on  Aug 10, 2130     

		



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>