<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2070-01-05

 
 
 
 
 
January 5, 2070
 
 
Matthew Wyatt, M.D. 
Notre Dame Nursing Home 
4379 New Street 
Hyannis, NV 21113
 
Re:  William Potts
     MR#  109-16-75-8
 
Dear Matt:
 
I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Potts in follow up today.  As you
know, he recently had a complicated hospital course.  He underwent
cardiac catheterization, which revealed serial stenoses of the LAD
including 70% and 90% stenoses.  The first marginal branch had a
60% ostial stenosis.  The right coronary artery had 60 and 80%
stenoses, respectively.  The PDA had a 70% narrowing.  Given his
very significant wish not to have bypass surgery, it was decided to
proceed with angioplasty of the right coronary artery as well as
the obtuse marginal.  It was felt that the LAD was a small vessel,
and not worth going after at this time.  The RCA was successfully
stented, but was complicated by occlusion of the posterior left
ventricular branch.  By the end of the procedure, flow had been
restored to some degree to the posterior left ventricular branch,
but Mr. Potts rule in for a small subendocardial myocardial
infarction.  Due to the closure of the left posterior ventricular
branch, the obtuse marginal branch was not dilated.  
 
Mr. Potts underwent two exercise tests post procedure. The second
exercise test was performed with MIBI imaging.  He exercised for
nine minutes on a submaximal Bruce protocol, and experienced chest
pain.  He had a maximal blood pressure of 148/72 and a heart rate
of 121.  MIBI images revealed a small nontransmural myocardial
infarction of the basal 1/3 of the inferior wall.  There was
moderate to severe ischemia of the inferolateral territory in the
territory of the RCA.
 
Given these findings, it was highly recommended that Mr. Potts
undergo bypass surgery.  
 
Mr. Potts was discharged on aspirin, Ticlid 250 mg b.i.d.,
Atorvastatin 20 mg q.h.s., Atenolol 50 mg b.i.d., Imdur 60 mg q.d. 
He also takes vitamin E and a multivitamin.
 
Of note is that Mr. Potts has been under quite a bit of stress
recently.  His 89-year-old mother has been at Whitehead recovering
William Potts
MR#  109-16-75-8              -2-       January 5, 2070
 
from a hip fracture.  He is having difficulty arranging the
appropriate insurance to cover her medications. 
 
Mr. Potts has been experiencing chest pain since discharge.  This
occurs with increased activity, and is relief with either rest
and/or 1 nitroglycerin.  He has decreased his work level
considerably, and is relatively sedentary.
 
On physical exam, he was well appearing and in no distress.  He had
a blood pressure of 112/70, with a heart rate of 60.  His weight
was 203 pounds.  Chest was clear to auscultation and percussion. 
Cardiac exam revealed a flat JVP of 30 degrees, a nondisplaced PMI
with a normal S1 and S2, without murmurs, rubs, or gallops. 
Carotids are 2+ bilaterally without bruits.   His abdomen is soft,
nontender.  There is no organomegaly, and no hepatojugular reflux. 
Extremities are without edema.
 
Electrocardiogram reveals a normal sinus rhythm with a rate of 61. 
Intervals are .16/.08/.42, with an axis of -10 degrees. There are
flipped T-waves in III and AVF.   I did not have an old
electrocardiogram here for comparison.
 
Therefore, Mr. Potts returns today still experiencing angina with
mild exertion.  He has agreed to undergo coronary artery bypass
surgery.  He has found out that if he is cleared to go back to work
by his physicians, that the Screen Actor's Guild will make a good case for this. 
There has been precedent for those who have had bypass surgery to
return to work as an actor.   Given Mr. Potts's current
feeling, I will make an appointment with Dr. Earl Jacob as soon
as possible for him to be seen prior to scheduling bypass surgery.
 
It is somewhat worrisome that Mr. Potts will be caring for his 89-
year-old mother at home, along with his wife.  His mother currently
uses a walker, and I have warned Mr. Potts that he really cannot
exert himself to any great degree in terms of helping his mother in
the house.  He understands this, and if his chest pain should
become more frequent, intense, or prolonged, he will immediately
call me.  
 
If Mr. Potts is not scheduled for surgery, I will see him in two
weeks at NDNH.  
 
With best regards.
 
Sincerely, 
 
 
Olivia Xing, M.D.
Monmouth Medical Center
81 Clergy Street
Casper, NV 33182William Potts
MR#  109-16-75-8              -3-       January 5, 2070
 
 
DD: 01/05/70
DT: 01/06/70
DV: 01/05/70
 
cc:
Earl Jacob, M.D.
Cardiac Surgery
Laurel Regional Hospital
96 Clergy Street
Casper, NV 33182 
 
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-09-28

59 y/o male for f/u:

   1) BP - No CP, SOB, pedal edema

   2) low HDL - walking daily

   3) ED - Viagra working well at 50 mg 

   4) hi LDL - continues Lipitor w/o muscle pain



O/E Looks well. BLOOD PRESSURE   120/70  wt 218 HR 68 reg

  chest - CTA

  ext - no edema



A/P 1) BP - good control

    2) low HDL - much time spent discussing lifestyle treatment. Has increased exercise to walking but wght unchanged > will increase exercise

    3) ED - no change

    4) hi LDL - good control. No change













****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-08-02


Notre Dame Nursing Home
1992 Madera Circle                                      Potts, William
Hyannis, NV 21113                                      10916758
(391) 643-6925                                           08/02/74


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Potts is a 60 year old
male who comes for follow up of hypertension, hyperlipidemia
and other medical problems.
1.  Hypertension.  Continues on medications without chest
pain, shortness of breath, or pedal edema.
2.  Hyperlipidemia. Continues on medication. No myalgias..
3.  Erectile disorder.  He has run out of Viagra, which
continues to work well at 50 mg dose.  Would like more.
4.  Low HDL.  He has not been taking Lopid for the past 2
months because his prescription ran out and has had
difficulty getting in here to have it renewed.
5.  Anxiety.  He has not had any further unpredictable
attacks of anxiety.  He did recently use some lorazepam when
he had to fly, but not at any other times.

6.  Seasonal allergies. Episodic rhinitis and pruritus. Needs more Claritan
MEDICATIONS:  Viagra, lorazepam 0.5 mg t.i.d. p.r.n.,
atenolol 50 mg q.d., Lipitor 20 mg q.d., aspirin q.d.,
diltiazem extended release 180 mg q.d., and Claritin-D
24-Hour 1 p.o. q.d. p.r.n.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As above and no nausea, vomiting,
dysuria, or leg pain.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient appears well.  Blood
pressure 126/76, weight 224 pounds, heart rate 72 and
regular.  Chest:  Clear to percussion and auscultation. 
Cardiovascular exam:  Notable for 1/6 holosystolic murmur at
the lower left sternal border to the apex.  Abdominal exam:
No masses, tenderness, or organomegaly.  Extremities:  No
edema.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:
1.  Hypertension.  Good control, no change in therapy.
2.  Hyperlipidemia.  He did not return for fasting lipid
analysis.  Will continue medication at present level and
again ask him to return for fasting exam.
3.  Erectile disorder.  Viagra refilled.
4.  Low HDL.  I will try Niaspan sustained release 1500 mg
p.o. q.d.  I discussed flushing sensation.  I asked him to
take it at bedtime.  If the flushing sensation gets to be a
problem, I encouraged him to take it in the morning about
half an hour after he takes his aspirin.
5.  Anxiety.  Improved.
6.  Seasonal allergies.  Renewed Claritin prescription.

In addition to above prescriptions, renewed all other
chronic prescriptions as well.


______________________________
Matthew H. Wyatt, M.D.


eScription document:8-959314 AFFocus

DD: 08/02/74
DT: 08/03/74
DV: 08/02/74



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-03-31







Notre Dame Nursing Home

1410 Madera Circle              POTTS, WILLIAM

Hyannis, NV  21113                    10916758

(391) 643-6925                     03/31/2077





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Potts is a 60-year-old male who comes for annual review and follow up of medical problems.

1.  Hypertension.  No chest pain, shortness of breath, or pedal edema.

2.  Hypercholesterolemia.  Recent fasting lipid analysis shows total cholesterol of 118, triglycerides of 121, LDL 61, HDL 33.

3.  Coronary artery disease status post CABG 2070.  He has a stable pattern of dyspnea with exercise.  No significant chest pain.

4.  Prostate CA.  He has begun prostatic brachytherapy four months ago.

5.  Depression.  He needs to arrange follow up with our counseling department.

6.  Benign prostatic hypertrophy and bladdre outlet obstruction.  He is going to undergo further evaluation.  He has responded well to medical therapy.

MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin 81 mg daily, atenolol 50 mg daily, diltiazem 180 mg daily, fluoxetine 20 mg daily, folic acid 1 mg daily, Lipitor 20 mg daily, Naprosyn 500 mg b.i.d. p.r.n., terazosin 5 mg b.i.d., nitroglycerin p.r.n.

ALLERGIES:  Sulfa medications.

HABITS:  He denies tobacco or drug use and drinks rarely.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Unchanged.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Unchanged.

REVIEW OF SYMPTOMS:  Notable for slightly worsening back pain, which he has had for all his life since trauma as a youth.  The pain is most noticeable after standing for a long period of time.  No nocturnal back pain. No significant weight change, febrile signs or symptoms, headache, blurred vision, tinnitus, chest pain, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, abdominal pain, nightsweats, diarrhea, dysuria, skin rash, bruising, joint pain, or focal weakness.  



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Blood pressure 108/60, weight 224 pounds, height 69 inches.  BMI 33.1.  Skin exam:  No rash.  Head and neck normal.  Chest:  Clear to percussion and auscultation.

Cardiovascular exam:  S4.  No extra sounds or murmurs.  Pedal pulses 1+ bilaterally.

Abdominal exam:  No masses, tenderness, or organomegaly.  Stool guaiac negative.

GU exam:  Both testes are without masses or tenderness.  Prostate not significantly palpable.  Lymph exam: No axillary or cervical lymphadenopathy.  Musculoskeletal exam grossly intact.  Bilateral pes planus.  Neuro exam grossly intact.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:

1.  Hypertension.  Stable.

2.  Hypercholesterolemia.  Adequate LDL treatment.

3.  Coronary artery disease.  Symptomatically stable though I wish he had better exercise tolerance.  Will follow.

4.  Prostate CA.  Under treatment.

5.  Depression.  I encouraged him to follow up with our counseling department.

6.  Prostatic hypertrophy and outlet obstruction.  He has follow up arranged with Dr. Uren.

7.  Low HDL.  I will initiate treatment with Tricor.  Previous trials with niacin failed.

8.  Pes planus.  Not symptomatically a problem.

9.  Low back pain.  The pattern has been stable.  Will not further intervene.

10.  Obesity.  I discussed with him the need to reduce weight but it has been stable for some time.

11.  Adult health maintenance.  Tetanus up-to-date.  He has had endoscopy.  Guaiac cards given.  Screening blood work up-to-date.





______________________________

Matthew H Wyatt, M.D.











eScription document:2-4489673 EMS







DD: 03/31/77

DT: 03/31/77

DV: 03/31/77



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-03-09






Notre Dame Nursing Home
6250 Madera Circle              POTTS, WILLIAM
Hyannis, NV  21113                    10916758
(391) 643-6925                     03/09/2080




HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Potts is a 65-year-old male who comes in for followup of chronic kidney disease and other medical problems.
1.  Chronic kidney disease.  Creatinine stable at 1.42.  He is on no ACE inhibitor.
2.  Borderline diabetes mellitus.  He is not currently treated.  However, A1c recently 6.6.
3.  Low HDL.  Recent fasting lipid analysis showed total cholesterol 121, triglycerides 74, LDL 85, and HDL 21.
4.  History of prostate cancer.  PSA less than assay.


MEDICATIONS:  Albuterol q.i.d. p.r.n., atenolol 50 mg p.o. daily, diltiazem 180 mg p.o. daily, Flomax 0.8 mg daily, Flonase 2 sprays b.i.d., folic acid 2 mg b.i.d., Lipitor 40 mg p.o. daily, Plavix 75 mg p.o. daily, and TriCor 200 mg p.o. daily.

REVIEW OF SYMPTOMS:  No significant weight change, febrile signs or symptoms, headache, blurred vision, tinnitus, chest pain, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, abdominal pain, nightsweats, diarrhea, dysuria, polyuria, skin rash, bruising, joint pain, or focal weakness.  


PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Blood pressure 100/60, weight 226 pounds, heart rate 68 and regular.  Chest:  Clear to percussion and auscultation.  Extremities:  No edema.


ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:
1.  Chronic kidney disease.  This remains stable.  However, he should be on an ACE inhibitor.  I will initiate lisinopril 10 mg p.o. daily, substituted for diltiazem.
2.  Borderline glucose tolerance.  The patient will return for 2 hour glucose tolerance test.
3.  Low HDL.  Remains quite low in the setting of coronary artery disease despite treatment.  We will continue TriCor.
4.  History of prostate cancer.  No evidence of recurrence.
5.  Hypertension.  Good control.  Substitute lisinopril for diltiazem as noted above.




______________________________
Matthew H Wyatt, M.D., M.Sc.










eScription document:6-0114243 CSSten Tel






DD: 03/09/80
DT: 03/09/80
DV: 03/09/80



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>