<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2067-05-03

Narrative History

   55 yo woman who presents for f/u 

   

   Seen in Cardiac rehab locally last week and BP 170/80.  They called us and we increased her HCTZ to 25 mg from 12.5 mg.  States her BP's were fine there since - 130-140/70-80.

   

   

   Saw Dr Oakley 4/5/67 - she was happy with results of ETT at Clarkfield.  To f/u 7/67.  No CP's since last admit.

   

   Back to work and starting to walk.  No wt loss and discouraged by this, but just starting to exercise.

   

   No smoking for 3 months now!

   

   Still with hotflashes, wakes her up at night.

Problems

      FH breast cancer   37 yo s 



      FH myocardial infarction   mother died 66 yo 



      Hypertension



      Uterine fibroids   u/s 2062 



      Smoking



      hyperlipidemia   CRF mild chol, cigs, HTN, Fhx and known hx CAD in pt. 



      borderline diabetes mellitus   4/63 125 , follow hgbaic 



      VPB   2065 - ETT showed freq PVC 



      coronary artery disease   s/p ant SEMI + stent LAD 2/67, Dr Oakley 



      thyroid nodule   2065, hot, follow TSH. 

Medications

      NORVASC (AMLODIPINE)     5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      PLAVIX (CLOPIDOGREL)   75 MG     PO QD  



      ATENOLOL     50MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      ASA (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)     325MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      ZESTRIL (LISINOPRIL)     40MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD   



      LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN)     10MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      HCTZ (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)     25MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD   



      NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 MG)   1 TAB     SL x1  PRN prn CP 

Allergies

      CECLOR (CEFACLOR)   Rash   

Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE-SITTING   150/70 

         repeat 145/80   HR 60 reg  WT  202 lbs

Physical Exam

   Looks well.  Lungs clear,  CVS  RRRs1s2, Ext - no edema	

Assessment and Plan

   1. H/M - Pe next appt in few months.  Overdue for mammo - will need to stress this.

   2.  CAD - cont with cardiac rehab, exercise, Dr Oakley, but doing well.

   3.  BP - better on increased HCTZ.  Check labs next visit, good K recently and on ACEI.

   4.  Cigs - great!

   5. Hot flashes - doesn't want to try any other meds - will try to put up with it.

   6. Hot thyroid nodule - recheck TSH next visit.

   7. Borderline glc - ok hgba1c 3/67.

   8.  Chol - ok, fasting on next visit.

   

   





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2068-12-05

Narrative History	

 Patient presents for uri.  Walks -in .  Overdue for follow-up by 3 months.



Started last week.   Sinus pressure, post nasal drip , headache , ears blocked.  

No fevers.

Slight white nasal cdischarge.



Taking advil sinus only helps transiently.

Not getting better or worse.

No chest symptoms - coughing etc..



Got flu shot already.





Problems

FH breast cancer : 37 yo s

FH myocardial infarction : mother died 66 yo

Hypertension 

Uterine fibroids : u/s 2062

Smoking : quit 2/67 s/p MI

Hyperlipidemia : CRF mild chol, cigs, HTN, Fhx and known hx CAD in pt.

borderline diabetes mellitus : 4/63 125 , follow hgbaic

VPB : 2065 - ETT showed freq PVC's, bigeminy and couplets, nondx for ischemia

Coronary artery disease : s/p ant SEMI + stent LAD 2/67, Dr Oakley, ETT Clarkfield 3/67 - neg scan for ischemia.

Thyroid nodule : 2065, thyroid scan 2066 consistent with hot nodule and toxic multinodular goiter, saw Dr Dolan, follow TSH. 





Medications

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Nitroglycerin 1/150 (0.4 Mg) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN prn CP

Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD

ATENOLOL 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 





Allergies

Ceclor (CEFACLOR) - Rash 





Physical Exam	 

	

Vital signs  140/82  98.2

Looks well,  nontoxic

Sinuses - nontender

TM's clear

OP - negative without exudates

neck- supple without increased nodes

lungs - clear without wheezing on forced exp 

CVS - rrrs2s2

 





Assessment and Plan	

1. URI - no evidence of bact sinus infection.  Needs decongestion but would like to avoid decong systemically given history CAD and ectopy in past. Will use steam, humidity, nasal decong spray for 3 days.  Call if fevers, worsens or persists.

2. Hot thyroid nodule - was slightly higher last visit - will refer to Dr Dolan for discussion re treating this now especially given her history of cardiac ds in the last couple of years.

3. blood pressure - slightly elevated above what would want it. Will recheck on follow-up which will be soon

4. Chol- will check fastings next visit. Lfts okay in June



Due for annual - will schedule next avail.



Beverly Thiel MD



****************************************************************************************************
Record Date: 2070-12-01

Narrative History	

 Patient  presents for an annual exam.  



Seen few weeks ago for hair breaking.



GYN - thinks about 2 years since last period. Having some tolerable hot flashes.  Last saw Dr Foust of gyn in 4/66, Pap smear done then. Diff exam secondary to way uterus tipped.



Exercise - Started walking at work again daily 1 mile. also watching diet now.



Problems

FH breast cancer : 37 yo s -died 41

FH myocardial infarction : mother died 66 yo



Hypertension -excellent today - check chem 7, meds renewed



Uterine fibroids : u/s 2062 - to follow-up with gyn. Still seem unchanged



Smoking : quit 2/67 s/p MI - still not smoking! 



borderline diabetes mellitus : 4/63 125 , follow hgbaic - was 5.7 in 3/67, recheck glc and a1c today



VPB : 2065 - ETT showed freq PVC's, bigeminy and couplets, nondx for ischemia - denies palp or dizziness



Coronary artery disease : s/p ant SEMI + stent LAD 2/67, Dr Oakley, ETT Clarkfield 3/67 - neg scan for ischemia. No CP's, palp.  Saw Dr Oakley today.  Off plavix for the last several months which was what Dr Oakley intended.  She was "pleased" with everything.



thyroid nodule : 2065, hot, follow TSH. Will recheck today.  Has appt with Dr Dolan in April to discuss treatment of the subclinical hyperthyroidism - I would favor this given history of CAD, mild VEA in past.



Hyperlipidemia : CRF mild chol, cigs, HTN, Fhx and known hx CAD in pt. Check lfts and cholesterol today. Went back on lipitor for the last 3 weeks.  Does note a bit of achiness in legs, not sure if related to it or not - will let us know if so.



Medications



Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Nitroglycerin 1/150 (0.4 Mg) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN prn CP

Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ATENOLOL 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 



Allergies

Ceclor (CEFACLOR) - Rash 



Family History	

father -HTN, 78 now

mother-HTN, MI at 58 and 62 - died then

siblings-sister finally died from breast CA after 4 year battle, dx age 37.     7 sisters - one with DM,and 2 brothers - ok

No change since previous annual.



Social History	working for Convergys as Sculptor, married, one son - 26 yo who lives with them.



Review of Systems	

The following systems were reviewed today and were negative unless indicated otherwise in the history noted above: Constitutional, HEENT, Breast,CVS, GI, GYN, Skin, Musculoskeletal, Neuro, Psych, Respiratory, and Allergic



Physical Exam	

	

Vital signs

134/86      65 inches    weight -210 down 2 lbs since last year.

General:  appears well      

HEENT:  EOMI, PERRL, OP normal  

Skin: no suspicious lesions 

Neck:  no thyromegaly, no bruits

Nodes: no cervical, axillary, or supraclavicular lymphadenopathy

Breast - no nipple discharge or retraction, no dominant masses

Chest:  clear to auscultation, no rhonchi or wheeze

COR:  regular S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs or gallops   

Abd:  soft, NT, no HSM or masses

Musculoskeletal:  no erythema, swelling, or tenderness

Ext:  no CCE    , 

Neuro:  grossly non-focal





Health maintenance

Influenza Vaccine 11/29/2067 

Cholesterol 11/29/2067 182 

Mammogram 03/01/64 BilScrMammo(MC) 

Pap Smear 03/12/2066 See report in Results 

UA-Protein 03/12/2066 NEGATIVE 

HBA1C 06/15/2068 5.80 

TD Booster 12/28/59 

Triglycerides 11/29/2067 61 

Cholesterol-LDL 11/29/2067 119 

Hct (Hematocrit) 03/16/2067 40.0 

Cholesterol-HDL 11/29/2067 51 

Hgb (Hemoglobin) 03/16/2067 13.3 







Assessment and Plan	

1.  Health Maintenance - Pap smear with gyn soon, mammo - very overdue - stressed needs to do this again and promises, Stool cards. Declined sig for now but promises to think about it.

2. Menopause - calcium, consider BD when not overwhelmed with everything else - much prefer she concentrate on the appts, Pap smear and mammo.

  

Rest of issues - see above.



follow-up 6 months



Beverly Thiel 







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-07-27

 Narrative History	
 Patient  presents for an annual exam.  
Not seen for almost 2 years.

State she's had a very difficult time with her husband's death 2070.  Angry and sad and guilty feelings.  Had been staying at home a lot, missing a fair amount of work.  Did have a lot of support from her neighbors and coworkers.  Also does live with her son.  Just seems to be coming out of it now.

GYN -  no vaginal bleeding, not sexually active.

Exercise - none,

Problems
FH breast cancer : 37 yo s -died 41
FH myocardial infarction : mother died 66 yo

Hypertension -borderline today - check chem 7, refilled all her medications.  Will start doing some exercise and trying to lose weight.

Uterine fibroids : u/s 2062 -not seen Dr Foust since 2066 when difficult to obtain her Pap smear .

Smoking : quit 2/67 s/p MI - still not smoking! 

borderline diabetes mellitus : 4/63 125 , follow hgbaic - was 6.5/131 in 12/70, gradually rising, recheck glc and a1c today

VPB : 2065 - ETT showed freq PVC's, bigeminy and couplets, nondx for ischemia - denies palp or dizziness.  Does occasionally feel a split second palpitation.  Takes a deep breath and it goes away.  No associated symptoms.  Perhaps feels it twice a month.  Will check electrolytes and TSH.

Coronary artery disease : s/p ant SEMI + stent LAD 2/67, Dr Oakley, ETT Clarkfield 3/67 - neg scan for ischemia. No CP's, palp. Not seen cardiology for two to 3 years. Will make follow-up with cardiology now that Dr Oakley gone

thyroid nodule : 2065, hot, follow TSH. TReated with RAI February 2071.  Last TSH checked 12/71 and was in the normal range.  To see Dr. Dolan q. year.

Hyperlipidemia : CRF mild chol, cigs, HTN, Fhx and known hx CAD in pt. in January 2071 she was written to increase her Lipitor to 40 mg and then to follow-up in March.  She never did increase the dose at that time. Check lfts and cholesterol fasting next week, and then can decide if we need to increase the Lipitor.  Will aim for LDL less than 100


Medications
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Nitroglycerin 1/150 (0.4 MG) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN prn CP 
Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Triamcinolone CREAM 0.5% (TRIAMCINOLONE ACETONIDE 0.5%) TOP BID PRN 
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20MG TABLET PO QD 
Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Atenolol 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Ativan (LORAZEPAM) 1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1) PO qhs PRN , dea#pf 0760305 


Allergies
CEFACLOR - Rash, 


Family History	
father -HTN, 85 now
mother-HTN, MI at 58 and 62 - died then
siblings-sister finally died from breast CA after 4 year battle, dx age 37.     7 sisters - one with DM,and 2 brothers - ok
No change since previous annual.

Social History	working for Convergys as Sculptor, widowed 2070, one son - 29 yo who lives with her - Specialized Livestock Worker

Review of Systems	
The following systems were reviewed today and were negative unless indicated otherwise in the history noted above: Constitutional, HEENT, Breast,CVS, GI, GYN, Skin, Musculoskeletal, Neuro, Psych, Respiratory, and Allergic

Physical Exam 

Vital Signs
BLOOD PRESSURE 148/76 
PULSE 60 
HEIGHT 65 in
WEIGHT 217.5 lb BMI 36.3 

up 3 lbs
General:  appears well      
HEENT:  EOMI, PERRL, OP normal  
Skin: no suspicious lesions 
Neck:  no thyromegaly, no bruits
Nodes: no cervical, axillary, or supraclavicular lymphadenopathy
Breasts - no nipple discharge or retraction, no dominant masses
Chest:  clear to auscultation, no rhonchi or wheeze
COR:  regular S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs or gallops   
Abd:  soft, NT, no HSM or masses
Musculoskeletal:  no erythema, swelling, or tenderness
Ext:  no CCE    , 
Neuro:  grossly non-focal


Health Maintenance
Influenza Vaccine 11/29/2067 
Cholesterol 12/16/2070 172 
Mammogram 03/01/64 see report in Results 
Pap Smear 12/16/2070 see report in Results 
UA-Protein 03/12/2066 NEGATIVE 
Colonoscopy 06/04/2071 see report in Results 
Urine Culture 03/12/2066 see report in Results 
Td Booster 12/16/2070 
Triglycerides 12/16/2070 83 
Cholesterol-LDL 12/16/2070 108 
Hct (Hematocrit) 04/27/2072 40.7 
Cholesterol-HDL 12/16/2070 47 
Hgb (Hemoglobin) 04/27/2072 13.1 
HbA1c 12/16/2070 6.50 
Chlamydia 03/09/62 NEGATIVE. 

Assessment and Plan	
1.  Health Maintenance - Pap smear  -will do every two to 3 years. mammo -still very overdue - stressed needs to do this again and promises,  colonoscopy fine  2071. To increase exercise.
2. Menopause - calcium, consider BD when not overwhelmed with everything else
3. Sleep, stress - seems to be doing generally better now.  Discussed this for most of her 45 minute appointment.  Starting to get out now and socialize.  To work quite regularly now.  Not interested in further counseling or medications.
4. sinus congestion states she wakes up and feels her sinuses are clogged her eyes are puffy and sneezing.  No help with Claritin.  Will try Flonase for two to 3 weeks to see if it helps.
  
Rest of issues - see above.

follow-up 3 months

Beverly Thiel 





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-01-31


Narrative History      

  Patient  presents for an annual exam.  


Has been doing generally well, a bit stressed as another sister dx with breast CA last year.




GYN -  no vaginal bleeding, not sexually active.


Exercise - none,


Problems
FH breast cancer : 37 yo s -died 41, second sister dx age 51
FH myocardial infarction : mother died 66 yo


Hypertension -high today - taking all her meds. Will start doing some exercise and trying to lose weight. Gets it checked at work and 120-130/70 all the time by the nurse there. Was 138/74 recently with  Dr Koch's who found that acceptable.  Will check and chart it and if &gt; 140 to rtc sooner


Uterine fibroids : u/s 2062 -not seen Dr Foust since 2066 when difficult to obtain her Pap smear . We were able to get it with difficulty in 2070


Smoking : quit 2/67 s/p MI - still not smoking! 


borderline diabetes mellitus : 4/63 125 , follow hgbaic - was 6.5/131 in 12/70, gradually rising, recheck glc and a1c today


VPB : 2065 - ETT showed freq PVC's, bigeminy and couplets, nondx for ischemia - denies palp or dizziness.  Does occasionally feel a split second palpitation.  Takes a deep breath and it goes away.  No associated symptoms. Feels it rarely


Coronary artery disease : s/p ant SEMI + stent LAD 2/67, Dr Oakley, ETT Clarkfield 3/67 - neg scan for ischemia. No CP's, palp. Saw Dr Koch 1/75 who rec more aggressive cholesterol mgmt to LDL &lt; 70. Increased her lipitor to 80 mg although she hasn't done this yet. 


thyroid nodule : 2065, hot, follow TSH. TReated with RAI February 2071.  Last TSH checked 12/71 and was in the normal range.  To see Dr. Dolan q. year, although very overdue - still hasn't gone. Will make an appt. Check TSH. 


Hyperlipidemia : CRF mild chol, cigs, HTN, Fhx and known hx CAD in pt. Will increase to 80 mg of lipitor and then in 1 month check lfts and cholesterol fasting at Moton Hospital.  Will aim for LDL less than 70


Medications
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Nitroglycerin 1/150 (0.4 MG) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN prn CP 
Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Triamcinolone CREAM 0.5% (TRIAMCINOLONE ACETONIDE 0.5%) TOP BID PRN 
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 40MG TABLET PO QD 
Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Atenolol 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 


Allergies
CEFACLOR - Rash, 


Family History      

father -HTN, died 86 of gastric ca
mother-HTN, MI at 58 and 62 - died then
siblings-sister finally died from breast CA after 4 year battle, dx age 37.   2nd sister dx breast CA age 51 - "aggressive - XRT and chemo.   7 sisters - one with DM,and 2 brothers - ok
No change since previous annual.


Social History       working for Convergys as Sculptor, widowed 2070, one son - 30 yo Insurance Agent


Review of Systems      

The following systems were reviewed today and were negative unless indicated otherwise in the history noted above: Constitutional, HEENT, Breast,CVS, GI, GYN, Skin, Musculoskeletal, Neuro, Psych, Respiratory, and Allergic


Physical Exam  



Vital Signs
BP 148/66, P 68, Ht 64 in, Wt 233 lb - up 9 lbs
O2 SAT 97 
BMI 40.1 



General:  appears well      

HEENT:  EOMI, PERRL, OP normal  
Skin: no suspicious lesions 
Neck:  no thyromegaly, no bruits
Nodes: no cervical, axillary, or supraclavicular lymphadenopathy
Breasts - no nipple discharge or retraction, no dominant masses
Chest:  clear to auscultation, no rhonchi or wheeze
COR:  regular S1, S2, no murmurs, rubs or gallops   
Abd:  soft, NT, no HSM or masses
Pelvic - spent 10 min attempting to do Pap smear - cervix is located very high and ant, can't get speculum in place to get it  tried multiple different speculums. Otherwise, no tenderness palpated, normal vulva and vagina.
Musculoskeletal:  no erythema, swelling, or tenderness
No back tend to palp, from, from of the left hip joint
Ext:  no CCE    , 
Neuro:  grossly non-focal




Health Maintenance
Chlamydia 03/09/62 NEGATIVE. 
Cholesterol-HDL 03/05/2074 52 
Cholesterol-LDL 03/05/2074 93 ATP III Classification of LDL Cholesterol (mg/dl): &lt; 100 Optimal 100-129 Near Optimal/Above Optimal 130-159 Borderline High 160-189 High = or &gt; 190 Very High 
Cholesterol 03/05/2074 155 
Colonoscopy 06/04/2071 see report in Results 
GFR (estimated) 03/05/2074 77.2 Units: ml/min/1.73msq 
HbA1c 03/05/2074 6.6 
Hct (Hematocrit) 04/27/2072 40.7 
Hgb (Hemoglobin) 04/27/2072 13.1 
Influenza Vaccine 11/29/2067 
Mammogram 02/10/2074 see report in Results 
Pap Smear 12/16/2070 see report in Results 
Td Booster 12/16/2070 
Triglycerides 03/05/2074 51 Normal: &lt; 150 mg/dl Borderline High: 150-199 mg/dl High: 200-499 mg/dl Very high: &gt; or = 500 mg/dl 
TSH 03/05/2074 2.297 
UA-Protein 03/12/2066 NEGATIVE 
Urine Culture 03/12/2066 see report in Results 








Assessment and Plan      
1.  Health Maintenance -  Pap smear  -- unable to get this time again, was able to do it 2070, will send back to gyn. mammo -to sched,  colonoscopy fine  2071 - repeat 2081. To increase exercise. 
2. Menopause - calcium, vitamin d discussed - was 11 2074 when not taking any supplements, repleted, then maintenance recommended ,  did take it for awhile then stopped months ago, will restart and will check level in a month.Consider BD when not overwhelmed with everything else
3. Sleep, stress - seems to be doing generally better now. 
4 sugar -mildly elevated , recheck A1c
5 Lower lumbar pain- indicates discomfort in left lower lumbar area when getting out of a chair only for the last week. Seems consistent with a muscular strain, hip seems ok.  RTC if symptoms worsen,change or persist for further evaluation. 

   
Rest of issues - see above.
Meds refilled. 


Will have fasting labs at Moton Hospital in 1 month, sched appt with Dr Dolan and gyn.



follow-up 6 months


Beverly Thiel 





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>