<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2094-12-09

                     RAH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
DUVALL,BRADY C   425-03-15-1                 VISIT DATE: 12/09/94
PRESENTING COMPLAINT and HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The 
patient is a 72-year-old gentleman who presents to the Emergency 
Department.  He reports nightly fevers.  He is two week status post 
AICD replacement.  He feels this is a malaria exacerbation.  The 
patient had malaria in Cambodia, and reports he did not have 
treatment.  His past medical history is also positive for 
non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, aortic valve replacement 
with a porcine valve, and ventricular fibrillation.  He is on 
Glucophage and aspirin.  He has no known drug allergies.  The 
patient feels well.  He says that each night he gets fever up to 
101 degrees F., although it is not that high each night.  The 
patient's past medical history is also significant for CAD, with an 
MI in 2092 and ventricular tachycardia in 2086.  His AICD was 
re-done two weeks ago.  He had a triple-A repair in 2089.  He has a 
history of gout. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is well-appearing now, with a 
temperature of 97 degrees F., a pulse of 58, a respiratory rate of 
18 and unlabored, a blood pressure of 110/80, and a room air 
saturation of 96%.  The HEENT examination is negative.  The lungs 
are clear.  The heart has a regular rhythm.  The abdomen is soft 
and non-tender.  The patient appears quite well. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Blood cultures are done. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient's primary care 
physician is contacted and will follow up with the patient.  the 
patient's white blood cell count is 6.  His hematocrit is 40.  His 
potassium is 4.9, his BUN 19, and his creatinine 0.9.  The 
urinalysis is negative for infection.  He has no pulmonary 
infection evident.  There are no ischemic changes on his EKG.  The 
patient appears to be doing well after the AICD replacement.  The 
AICD has not had to fire. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Nightly fevers, etiology uncertain. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 
discharged in good condition to careful outpatient followup. 
___________________________________                    IL050/525 
IKECHUKWU SPEARS, M.D.  IS25                                D:12/09/94 
                                                       T:12/09/94 
Dictated by:  IKECHUKWU SPEARS, M.D.  IS25 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-03-27

Wt 198  146/84
72 yo male with few months of cardiac problems, including need for ablation of
arrhythmia focus, done 1/95.   Has hx CAD with MI 2062 and 2086, with echo 1/95
showing 40-45% EF with posterior and apical hypokinesis.   No CHF sx, tho has
moderate fluid retention at times.  Takes lasix 40mg PRN (about 1-2 times per
wk, when edematous, tho even with periph edema, no signif SOB/CHF sx.).
     
For past 6 wks has been on atenolol 25 qd (has not been able to tolerate
amiodarone, lisinopril in past), but has felt very malaised, weak, lacking in
energy, "weak" in the legs.  Feels his appetite was also affected and he lost 8
pounds.  He got fed up and 2 days ago on his own, he stopped the atenolol and
since then has felt nearly back to usual self.  HE says that he will not go
back on atenolol.   At last visit, was encouraged by Dr Corona to try to
continue with atenolol.
     
DM on glucophage 1500mg qd (500 AM, 1000PM), without signif poly sx, with
recent fingerstick of 180 in AM and 220 in PM.
     
EXAM:   Lungs are clear.  Extrem 3+ edema.
 
IMP:    Side effects from atenolol.
        AICD/ventricular arrhythmia, controlled recently.
        Fluid retention.  PRN lasix not ideal.
        DM not as well controlled as desirable.
        LDL 138, should be lower, tho he is so intolerant of meds.
 
PLAN:   Will discuss with Dr Corona about unwillingness to take beta blocker
          and if any other agent indicated.  BP not ideally controlled.
        Encouraged regular lasix use of 20mg twice per wk, salt restriction
        Consider lipitor for LDL 138, but next visit.
        Increase metformin to 1000 BID.
        Pneumovax today.
Patricia Islam MD




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-10-23

                     RAH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
DUVALL,BRADY C   425-03-15-1                 VISIT DATE: 10/23/95
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is an unfortunate 73 
year old man who has had two myocardial infarctions in the past, 
including an IMI, and ventricular tachycardia and ventricular 
fibrillation who has an AICD in who presents today with his AICD 
firing multiple times.  The patient's AICD actually fired multiple 
times while he was in the Emergency Department. 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  The patient has no chest pain, syncope, or 
shortness of breath.  He presents in ventricular tachycardia with 
his AICD firing. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  The patient has a significant coronary 
artery disease history and recently had his pacer placed, 
approximately a month ago.  He has had two myocardial infarctions. 
He has diabetes. 
MEDICATIONS:  Glyburide and metformin. 
ALLERGIES:  Atenolol. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Vital signs remained stable, 
including blood pressure.  HEENT:  Normal.  LUNGS:  Clear. 
CARDIOVASCULAR:  Tachycardic with a paced rhythm.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, 
non-tender.  LUNGS:  Clear bilaterally. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The patient's EKG shows ventricular 
tachycardia and some ST elevations in the inferior leads.  Chest 
x-ray was clear.  Electrolytes were sent to check his potassium. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was loaded on lidocaine 
and paced on a lidocaine drip.  He also received Lasix and 
metoprolol.  He also received 2 mg of Ativan for sedation.  He had 
no chest pain while he was in the Emergency Department;  his only 
pain was from the pacer firing. 
CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  The patient was seen by Internal Medicine and also by the Internal Medicine fellow. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  History of coronary artery disease, now with 
ventricular tachycardia and ST elevations on EKG with pacer firing. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 
urgently rushed to the Cath Lab.  He is currently in stable 
condition. 
___________________________________                    OT109/6637 
FRANK EMMONS, M.D.       FE01                           D:10/23/95 
                                                       T:10/23/95 
Dictated by:  FRANK EMMONS, M.D.       FE01 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-06-13

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

June 13, 2097

 

 

 

Dennis Cannon, M.D.

Cardiovascular Division

Redwood Area Hospital

28 Tamworth Place

Cass City MS  25448

 

RE:BRADY DUVALL

RAH#425 03 15 1

 

Dear Denny:

 

Just a note to tell you that I saw Brady Duvall again today for his 

congestive heart failure.  His clinical course is well known to you.  

He has had a slight increase in peripheral edema.  This has occurred 

despite a medical regimen that includes Lasix 40 mg daily, aldactone 25 

mg daily, Coumadin, atenolol 25 mg daily, amiodarone 200 mg daily, 

insulin, vancomycin that was recently discontinued, Zocor 80 mg daily, 

clonopin, Plavix, and glucophage.  He is also on captopril 6.25 mg po 

t.i.d.

 

From a functional point of view, he seems to be stable although, as 

noted, he has had a slight increase in peripheral edema.  His past 

clinical course is well known to you.  As you know, he had an 

epicardial abscess from electrode placement.  

 

From a clinical point of view, he is otherwise stable.

 

Physical examination today is of note for a weight of 193 pounds, blood 

pressure 120/60, with a resting pulse of 76.  Neck veins are distended, 

with positive hepatojugular reflux.  His carotid volume is diminished.  

His lungs are 

 

Page Two

RE:BRADY DUVALL

RAH#425 03 15 1

June 13, 2097

 

 

 

generally clear, without rales or rhonchi.  Examination of the heart 

reveals a quiet precordium.  There is a soft S3 gallop, no murmur of 

mitral regurgitation, and no obvious murmur of tricuspid regurgitation.  

Abdomen is of note for a liver at the right costal margin.  There is +2 

peripheral edema.

 

The resting electrocardiogram shows paced rhythm.

 

We will be increasing his Lasix to 80 mg daily and following him 

closely by telephone over the next several days.  I have made no other 

changes in his current medical regimen.

 

Many thanks for letting us participate in his care.

 

With best regards.

 

Sincerely yours,

 

 

 

U. L. Dana, Jr., M.D.

 

DD: 06/13/97

DT: 06/18/97

DV: 06/13/97

 

/elizondo

 

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-07-20

 

 

July 20, 2098

 

 

 

Patricia Islam, M.D.

Redwood Area Hospital

34 Tamworth Place/Internal Medicine

Cass City, MS  25448

 

Re:  Brady Duvall

     MR #425-03-15-1

 

Dear Patricia:

 

I saw Brady Duvall again today.  He has been very stable

clinically over these past six months.  I believe this represents

a composite of the following three major changes in his medical

regimen.  As you know, we have discontinued all beta blockers,

and this has been associated with a symptomatic stability.  He

had biventricular pacing box placed, certainly contributing to

his overall improved status and he is now taking a regular dose

of Lasix.  He is on 80 mg alternating with 40 mg per day.  He

does have symptoms of fatigue, but his overall volume status is

quite reasonable.  He is currently on Aldactone 25 mg daily and

Lasix 80 mg per day alternating with 40 mg per day, Captopril

6.25 mg p.o. t.i.d., Zocor, insulin, Glucophage, aspirin, and

mexiletine.  His amiodarone has been discontinued.  He does have

asymptomatic ventricular tachycardia, often paced out of this,

but I am reluctant to recommend ablation therapy for him at the

present time.  He has not been shocked by his ICD.

 

Functionally he seems quite stable.  He does have mild fatigue,

but is otherwise reasonably active.  He will hopefully be

traveling to Miami this spring.

 

Physical examination today is of note for a weight of 184 lbs. 

His blood pressure is 118/70, his resting pulse 69.  His neck

veins are in fact, quite unimpressive.  There is minimal jugular

distention, perhaps 6-7 cm.  There is no hepatojugular reflux.  

 

 

Re:  Brady Duvall

     MR #425-03-15-1                 -2-                07/18/98

 

Lungs were clear.  Examination of his heart reveals a quiet

precordium.  S1 and S2 seem normal.  No S3, no gallop and no

murmur or mitral regurgitation.  Abdomen is benign without

palpable liver or spleen and there was no peripheral edema. 

There are bilateral varicosities.

 

His electrocardiogram shows pace rhythm.

 

Mr. Brady Duvall is currently stable on this regimen. 

Accordingly, I have made no changes.  I have checked appropriate

electrolytes.

 

Many thanks for letting us participate in his care.

 

With best regards.

 

Sincerely,

 

 

 

U. L. Dana, M.D.

 

/paris

 

 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>