<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2079-03-23

 

  

  March 23, 2079

  

  

  

  

  Gage Yingling, M.D. 

  Protestant Home Hospital 

  57 Chinook Drive

  Whiteville, AL 73844

  

  

  RE:  Adler, Imogene

  MRN: 618-13-82-6

  

  

  Dear Dr. Yingling:

  

  Thank you for referring your patient, Imogene Adler,

  for her problem of coronary ischemia.  As you know, Ms.

  Adler is a 49 year old woman with four years of

  essential hypertension and mild dyslipidemia who is

  postmenopausal and has noticed increasing symptoms of chest

  tightness associated with exertion.  A stress MIBI SPECT

  study ordered by you demonstrated inferolateral mid and

  basal inferior ischemia consistent with a left circumflex

  distribution.  The details of the study include an exercise

  protocol for which the patient exercised for 7 minutes and

  15 seconds for 8.9 mets, with an increase in heart rate from

  74 to 159 (which is 94% of predicted peak heart rate), and

  increase in blood pressure from 134/80 to 210/80 (with a

  rate pressure product of 33,390).  The test was stopped due

  to fatigue and moderately severe chest pain.  EKG

  demonstrated 1.5mm of upsloping depression in II, III, F and

  V4-V5, and there were no noted arrhythmias.  

  

  Her past medical history is otherwise unremarkable and her

  current medications include estrogen, Premarin, Provera, and

  verapamil 240mg q.d.  A recent lipid panel demonstrated a

  total cholesterol of 203, LDL of 142, and an HDL of 39.

  

  On physical examination, she is comfortable, well appearing

  woman with a weight of 186 pounds, pulse 68 beats per minute

  and regular, blood pressure 140/82 in the left arm.  Jugular

  venous pressure was approximately 6-8cm of water.  Carotids

  demonstrates normal upstroke with no bruits.  Chest

  examination was clear to auscultation.  Heart examination

  demonstrated a normal S1, positive S4, physiologically split

  S2, no murmurs or rubs.  Abdominal examination was 

  

  

  RE:  Adler, Imogene

  MRN: 618-13-82-6

  Page 2

  March 23, 2079

  

  

  

  unremarkable.  Peripheral examination demonstrated no

  peripheral examination and 2+ bilateral peripheral pulses.  

  

  EKG demonstrated normal sinus rhythm and otherwise normal

  EKG.  

  

  I reviewed the findings suggestive of an obstructive

  coronary lesion in the left circumflex distribution and the

  probability of her having single vessel coronary artery

  disease as the culprit for her chest pain.  We reviewed the

  options which include medical therapy and/or coronary

  angiography and possible angioplasty.  I made no solid

  recommendations for her, but suggested that the angioplasty

  approach was a relatively low risk approach which may lead

  to curing the obstructive lesion as opposed to medical

  therapy, which would also be a well supported decision, and

  I reviewed the evidence to suggest medical treatment of

  single vessel disease does not shorten one's life span and

  only affects the quality of life depending on the symptom

  tolerance.  She and her husband are going to reflect on

  these recommendations and get back to me by the end of the

  week.  If she does decide to undergo coronary angiography

  and possible angioplasty, we will schedule her immediately

  in Cardiology.

  

  I have scheduled follow-up in one month regardless to see

  her in the office.  Please do not hesitate to contact me if

  I can be of any further assistance.

  

  With warm regards,

  

  

  

  William Gomes, M.D. 

  

  WG/anderson

  

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-09-13


Internal Medicine


Reason for visit
Hyperlipidemia
Weight management
Hematuria


History of present illness  
The patient is here for follow up on multiple issues. She is still experiencing episodic chest discomfort. Her blood pressure has been at target 110-115/70 daily. She feels very well but tired at times. She has lost weight on Metformin.


Medical history  
Glucose intolerance with post prandial hyperglycemia
Hyperlipidemia
Hypertension
CAD
Postmenopausal
Cervical osteoarthritis DDD
Microscopic hematuria with negative work up
Obesity


Current meds

Amlodipine 5 mg
Metoprolol XL 50 mg 
Valsartan HCTZ 160/25 mg
Atorvastatin 20 mg
Clopidogrel 75 mg qd
Metformin 500 mg bid


Review of systems
Denies nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, chest pain


Family and social history
Place of birth        Gambia 
Home residence        Jaffrey
Marital status        Married
Household members     Husband
Occupation            Carpentry Supervisor


Labs and images
Reviewed


Exam
Vitals 128/70  64  12  
HEENT eomi, conjunctiva pink, ears clear, nasal mucosa pink, no mucus, no sinus tenderness, no post nasal drip.
Neck is supple, no JVD, no thyroid imprint, no submandibular nodes.
Thorax expands symmetrically, clear to auscultation bilaterally.
Cardiovascular S1 and S2 with regular rhythm and rate. No murmurs.
Abdomen is soft, non tender, no palpable masses or organomegaly.
Extremities are symmetrical with no edema.
Neurological exam is grossly non focal.


Assessment and plan



CAD. The patient will follow up with cardiology for further assessment. She continues taking clopidogrel and would like to know if she can switch to aspirin. I mentioned to the patient that I will defer this decision to the cardiology team.
Glucose intolerance with post prandial hyperglycemia. On metformin, well tolerated, HbA1c requested. 
Weight management. The patient has lost 15-20 Lbs. She is very enthused. I have advised to continue metformin and will start exercising daily.
Hyperlipidemia. On atorvastatin. Target LDL &lt;70, new values requested.
Hypertension. Values at target, continue current medications. 
Microscopic hematuria with negative work up. Surveillance UA requested.
Follow up in 4-6 months.




                                   
David Delgado, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2086-03-02

Internal Medicine



Reason for visitDyspnea on exertion
Chest discomfort of exertion
Sore throat
Cough



History of present problemThe patient is here indicating that she has joined a gym. She has been experiencing chest discomfort and heavyness with dyspnea on exertion. The symptoms appears when she is on the treadmill and last several minutes after she stops. She is worried about it. She also complains of sore throat and cough.


Medical historyCoronary vasospastic events

Glucose intolerance with post prandial hyperglycemia
Hyperlipidemia
Hypertension
Postmenopausal
Cervical osteoarthritis DDD
Microscopic hematuria with negative work up
Obesity

 

Medications

Amlodipine 5 mg qd
Metoprolol XL 50 mg qd
Valsartan HCTZ 160/25 mg
Atorvastatin 20 mg
Aspirin 81 mg qd
Metformin 500 mg bid

 
Health maintenance overview
Last Pap smear       2085 normal
Last mammogram       2086
Last densitometry    2084
Last colonoscopy     2084 normal
Last tonometry       2083
Last audiogram       unknown
Last skin exam       unknown
Last CXR             2085
Last ECG             2085
Last ETT             2085


 
Immunization
Up to date 


AllergiesNone


Social historyPlace of birth        GambiaHome residence        Jaffrey, ALMarital status        MarriedHousehold members     FamilyOccupation            Carpentry SupervisorSupport resources     autonomous


Risk factors and habitsTobacco smoking       none
Alcohol intake        social, &lt;3 drinks per week
Xantines caffeine     moderate
Radiation exposure    noneFumes toxins exposure none
Hospitalizations      none in last yearBlood transfusions    none
 
Sun exposure          moderateSunscreen use         yes
Seat belt use         yes
Smoke detector        yesExercise              moderate
Recreational drugs    none
Injury risk           low to moderateSTD risk              lowViolence and abuse    not a current issue


Family historyMother       A       dementia 
Father       A       diabetes
Brothers     0 
Sisters      1 
Spouse       A 
Children     2 


Cancer       0 
Diabetes     +       F 
             +       M
CV Disease   0   
Stroke       0   


Review of systemsHand dexterity rightDenies fever, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, chest pain, dyspnea, coughWeight changes over last year minimalSleep consolidatedSnoring noneDiet omnivorous
Denies other significant problems with following organs or systems: skin, head, eyes, nose, throat, neck, endocrine, breasts, heart, lungs, gastrointestinal, kidney, urinary, genital, musculoskeletal, neurologic, blood, lymphatic. Denies psychological or psychiatric problems.


 
Physical Exam

56 yo WDWN person in NAD.


Habitus      meso-endomorphic
Weight       80 kgHeight       170 cmBMI          27


Vital signs:
TF  97.8BP  123/74HR  66RR  12


Mental statusAlert, oriented x 3.Cognition adequate.SkinWarm, moist, no cyanosis. Nails neat, hard, smooth, no clubbing.LymphaticBilateral submandibular lymphadenopathy.No peripheral edema.HeadEyes - Conjunctiva pink, no exudates, cornea clear, irides equal ERL, no nystagmus.Ears - Tympanic membranes visible, intact, light reflection adequate.Nose - Nasal mucosa red, no edema, secretions.Thro - Posterior pharyngeal wall red, post nasal drip.Neck - Thyroid impression not visible, trachea midline and mobile, no JVD.Chest Symmetrical expansion.Clear to auscultation bilaterally.
BreastsDeferred.
HeartRate and rhythm regular.Auscultation of five points S1 and S2, no murmurs, no clicks/snaps.Vascular Peripheral pulses symmetrical. No aortic, carotid or renal bruits.AbdomenSymmetric, no protrusions.Palpation soft, non tender, no rebound tenderness. No hepatosplenomegaly, no masses. Percussion of costovertebral angles is non tender. No arterial pulses transmitted through abdominal wall.
Genitalia female
Deferred.

Anus and rectum 
Deferred.
MusculoskeletalSpine straight when erect, no rib hump on forward flexion. Shoulders at even levels. Iliac crests at even levels. Extremities symmetrical in appearance. Muscles strength symmetrical, conserved bilaterally. Joints non tender, no locking, no clicking, no limitations, range of motion conserved. Neurologic Cranial nerves II-XII grossly intact. Gait coordinated and even. Romberg test negative. Rapid alternating movements coordinated. Finger-nose adequate, no dysmetria, no ataxia. Epicritic and protopathic sensations intact. Deep tendon reflexes symmetrical 2+ in all extremities. Babinski sign absent bilaterally. Ankle clonus absent.




Assessment and Plan



Chest pressure and dyspnea. The patient has known coronary vasospastic events for which she has consulted with cardiology. The symptoms that she describes suggest possible symptomatic cardiac ischemia. She had a baseline ECG today in my office that was normal. I have instructed the patient to follow up with cardiology for further assessment and an ETT. I will communicate with Dr. Wright. The description of symptoms do not suggest unstable angina. 
Glucose intolerance with post prandial hyperglycemia. Continue metformin, well tolerated, HbA1c requested. 
Hyperlipidemia. On atorvastatin. Target LDL &lt;70, new values requested. 
Hypertension. Stable, continue current medications. 
Microscopic hematuria with negative work up. Surveillance UA and cytology requested. 
Rhinopharyngitis. Amoxicillin and fluticasone initiated. 
Gynecology contact information provided. 
Ophthalmology contact information provided. 
Bone densitometry requested. 
Labs requested. 
Follow up after tests or in 3-6 months.




_____________________________David Delgado, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-03-22


Internal Medicine


Reason for visit
Diarrhea
Fever
Chest pain
Fatigue


History of present illness  
The patient is here complaining of several days history of diarrhea with mild nausea, mild fever and retrosternal chest discomfort. That is intermittent mild and 
insiduous. The pain is not triggered by exercise or physical activity or position. She has been feeling weak.


Medical history  
Coronary vasospastic events 

Glucose intolerance + postprandial hyperglycemia
Hyperlipidemia
Hypertension
Postmenopausal
Cervical osteoarthritis DDD
Microscopic hematuria with negative work up
Hypovitaminosis D
Obesity - now loosing weight


Current meds


Amlodipine                 5 mg qd 
Metoprolol XL             50 mg qd
Valsartan                160 mg qd       -combined
Hydrochlorothiazide       25 mg qd       -combined
Atorvastatin              20 mg qd
Aspirin                   81 mg qd
Metformin                500 mg bid


Review of systems
Denies abdominal pain, vomiting, dyspnea


Family and social history
Place of birth        GambiaHome residence        JaffreyMarital status        MarriedHousehold members     HusbandOccupation            Composer



Mother       A       dementia 
Father       A       diabetes
Brothers     0 
Sisters      1 
Spouse       A 
Children     2 


Cancer       0 
Diabetes     +       F 
             +       M
CV Disease   0   
Stroke       0   


Labs and images
Reviewed


Exam
Vitals 110/72  96  16  98.0
HEENT eomi, conjunctiva pink, ears clear, nasal mucosa pink, no mucus, no sinus tenderness, no post nasal drip.
Neck is supple, no JVD, no thyroid imprint, no submandibular nodes.
Thorax expands symmetrically, clear to auscultation bilaterally. Pain reproduced on chest palpation.
Cardiovascular S1 and S2 with regular rhythm and rate. No murmurs.
Abdomen is soft, non tender, no palpable masses or organomegaly. Increased bowel sounds.
Extremities are symmetrical with no edema.
Neurological exam is grossly non focal.


Assessment and plan




Chest discomfort. The patient's history and exam do not suggest cardiovascular origin but pain originated in the chest wall, musculoskeletal in origin. She had an ECG in my office that was unchanged from previous ones, there were no ST-TW abnormalities, no extrasystoles or any other abnormality. She was reassured. For musculoskeletal pain I have recommended stretching exercises, and low dose diazepam for muscle contracture. She will avoid NSAID due to GI symptoms.

Abdominal discomfort with diarrhea. The patient will follow a CHO diet and will avoid dairy products and other substances with low-absorption high-residue. In addition, in context of weakness I have recommended her to have a chemistry analysis for investigating electrolytes. Should symptoms persist then I will recommend the patient to initiate Ciprofloxacin and Metronidazole.

Dehydration. The patient will initiate a strict fluid replenishment plan for rehydration.




                                   
David Delgado, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>