<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2136-12-05

HIGHLAND HOSITAL VISIT
PT: Ellen Law
date of visit: 12/05/36


CC: fu cards, htn, hyperlipidemia, DM


HPI: Since our last visit, saw Cardiology re her neck and jaw pain w exertion, Dr. Uphoff who feels that she has stable angina. he recommended that she optimize her medical management by increasing her BB and CCB. At this point, she has increased her BB to 2 pills 2x per day.  she feels ok on this.  no lightheadedness or dizziness.  She is also going to start nitrates as soon as they arrive--imdur 30mg qd.  still having intermittenly jaw discomfort walking up stairs.  no chest pressure or jaw discomfort at rest. 
she has not gained any wt.  however, has not been able to increase her lantus bc she was not sent the correct amount and would run out if she increaesd to previously recommended dose. 
also started pravastain since our last visit.  has not noticed any muscle aches or generalized weakness. has only been on this for 2 weeks though. 
no hypoglycemia; good energy; feeling well overall. 
describes feeling pressure, fullness in left ear; slight decrease in hearing. 




Problems
Diabetes mellitus 
Malignant tumor of urinary bladder : stage 1, now s/p bcg treatment, followed by urology
Hypertensive disorder 
Obesity 
Retinal detachment : s/p repair Dr. Cleveland


Medications
Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 50 MG (50MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID , Member ID # 55080437876 #180 Tablet(s)
Hydrochlorothiazide 25 MG (25MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD , Member ID # 033388269 #90 Tablet(s)
Imdur ER (ISOSORBIDE MONONITRATE (SR)) 30 MG (30 MG TAB.SR 24H Take 1) PO QD #90 TAB.SR
Lantus (INSULIN GLARGINE) 100 U/ML VIAL ML SC AS DIRECTED , 65U before breakfast and 10 units at night Member ID # 033388269 #3 Month(s) Supply
Metformin 1000 MG (1000MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #180 Tablet(s)
Metoprolol TARTRATE 50 MG (50MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD AS DIRECTED , 2 PO QAM AND 1 PO QPM #180 Tablet(s)
Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 5 MG (5 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD x 90 days #90 Tablet(s)
Novolog flexpens SC AC AS DIRECTED , 10U before breakfast, 10U before lunch, 20U before dinner #15 prefilled pens
One touch ultra test strips 1 SC BID #3 Month(s) Supply
Pravastatin 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS #90 Tablet(s)
Solostar prefilled disposable lantus insulin pen 65 UNITS SC qd , Member ID# 033388269 #3 Month(s) Supply
Zostavax (ZOSTER VACCINE LIVE (PF)) 1 VIAL SC X1 x 365 days, 1. Reconstitute and inject 1 vial. Sub-cutaneous upper arm. 2. Please document vaccine administration in the LMR immunization module (or notify the practice in writing if no LMR access). #1 vial


Allergies
AZITHROMYCIN - Unknown
Ace Inhibitor - cough, 


TOB: quit 2120; smoked 2ppd x 15 yrs 
ETOH: none
IVDU/illict drugs: none 


SH: originally from Mt. Married for 39 years to Friedman, describes marriage as
good, safe. Has 2 children and 8 grandchildren. Has 2 daugthers, 1 lives in
hartsville and 1 in nuku'alofa. no pets. fulltime author. husband has h/p
prostate CA. 


FH:
(no known )h/o sudden death, hyperlipidemia
+ Dm in father (dxd in his 60-70)
+ mgm w stroke (
+CHF in ther mother
+mUncles x 2 with MIs (~ 60's_
(no known) h/o endometrial, ovarian, thyroid, melanoma, breast, prostate 
+ colon cancer in her mother, dx'd 55-60yo
(no known )h/o osteoporosis/premature bone loss
(no known )h/o colon polyp, dysplasic nevi
(no known )h/o pe, DVT, miscarriages, bleeding disorders 
(+)h/o glaucoma in mUncle
(no known ) h/o depression, suicide, schizophrenia 
+ dementia in her mother
+alcoholis in 2 muncles
+ bipolar do in grandson




VS: 130/66  76  97.1  98%RA  250 lbs  57.25
general: well- appearing F in NAD
HEENT: anicteric, PERRL, EOMI, mmm; difficult to assess JVP, L TM w nearly obstructing cerumen; R w nl TM and light reflex. 
PULM: CTAB w good air movement. no wheezes, rhonchi, or crackles
COR: rrr, nls1s1, no m/r/g
EXT: wwp, no edema
 
A/P: 61 yo F with PMH of HTN, hyperlipidemia, DM, obesity, bladder cancer presenting for fu of multiple medical issues.
1) DM: Dx'd ~ 2129, c/b diabetic retinopathy s/p laser tx and likely neuropathy. Most recent 10/36 HgbA1c: 7.0%, very near goal of &lt;7.0% and improving compared to 7.8 % since increase in lantus dose. Did not bring FS log today but continues to report that her fasting glucose in AM still often above goal and that her largest meal and need for novolg is at dinner. 
Previously recommended starting BID dosing of lantus and adding 10 units in PM, but not able to obtain yet from pfizer; discussed that for some individuals it dose not last for 24 hours adn that they get better glucose control w BID dosing. Discussed that she will likely need to decrease her PM dose of novolog
----recheck hgba1c ~ 1/2137
----continue metformin 1000mg BID, lantus 65units qam and novolog 70/30 but also adding 10 units of lantus in PM
----continue glucose monitoring for likely need for further adjustments to regimen
----7/36 urine microalbumin/crt: 35.9 above goal of &lt;30; have made changes to BP regimen and BP now within goal; will recheck u microalb/crt in 1/2137 
----OPTHO: followd by dr arias; reports uptodate
----PODIOTRY: pt w likely diabetic neuropathy and e/o oncychomycosis; referrred to podiotry for further care and monitoring at previous visit
----BP: within goal on HCTZ, Cozzar, metoprolol and norvasc
----2136 LDL: 114 above goal of &lt;100, not on statin; started simvastatin which was dc'd 2/2 myalgias and generalized weakness (nl LFTS and CK); pt has started pravastain and appears to be doing well on this
----9/36 Gabriella Yockey
----discussed nutrition referral; pt declined but plans on joining south beach diet
----discussed importance of wt loss; pt to try south beach diet; 
----PNEUMOVAX: 2136
----Flu shot/H1N1:  flu shot uptodate; receiving h1n1 today
2) HTN: Dx'd in ~ 2129. BP very near  goal today on current regimen of HCTZ 25mg qd, cozaar 50mg BId, metoprolol 100mg BID and norvasc 5 mg qd which appears to be well-tolerated.  Will not make any additional changes since pt is planning on adding imdur 30mg as soon as she received it from Pfizer. 10/2136 chem 7, renal fxn, ca wnl. 
-----encouraged low na diet, wt loss
----continue HCTZ 25mg qd, cozaar 50mg BId, and metoprolol 100mg BID, and norvasc 5 mg qd
----reviewed si/sxs for which she should seek immediate medical attention
3) dyslipidemia: 7/36 LDL 114 above goal of &lt;100 given DM  and likely CAD. Pt w brief 2 week trial of simvastatin self-dc'd 2/2 myalgias and generalized weakness but nl LFTS/CK/GFR. Pt now on pravastatin x 2 weeks and appears to be well-tolerated thus far.  Again reviewed possible side effects and she knows to call w any concerns or questions
----continue pravastatin 20mg qhs; reivwed possible side effects and instructed to call w concerns
----pt instructed that she will need repeat lipids and LFTS in ~ 6-8 weeks after starting pravasatin; will check at next visit
----recommended low cholesterol diet
4) Likely stable angina/CAD; now s/p Cardiology, consult w Dr. Uphoff who feels that clinical presentation c/w stable angina/CAD and has recommended trial of optimizing medical management w nitrates and BB/CCB for now.  Reviewed consult recs with patient.  however, if this does not work, will consider possible cath/stress test. pt appears to be tolerating increase in BB and has not yet started imdur.  recent LDL above goal but just restarted statin so will need fu measurement in ~ 4 weeks.  
----continue asa 81 mg qd; increased metoprolol 100mg BID, ARB, and pravastatin 20mg qhs
----fu appt w dr uphoff in ~ 1 week
----pt to add imdur 30mg as soon as arrives from pharmacy

5) Left ear impaction: Left TM w nearly completely obstructing cerumen. Irrigated ear w full removal and visualizatino of nl TM post irrigation. Pt confirms complete resolution of sxs w return of nl hearing.  pt felt well post irrigation w no dizziness. disucsed possible dizziness and she will sit in waiting room for a while and make sure that she does not experience. 
6) HCM:
----recevied flu shot
----will give h1n1 today 
---will give tdap today


To DO;
----fu on mammogram
---continue to discuss colonscopy




Pt to RTc in ~ 1 mos or sooner if needed. 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2137-03-20

HIGHLAND HOSITAL VISIT
PT: Ellen Law
date of visit: 3/20/2137


CC: fu DM, CAD


HPI: Since our last visit, pt has undergone cath (full report) below which demonstrated 3v CAD for which CABG was recommended.  she has now seen Dr. Urie who has recommended that she undergo a CABG which is scheduled for may.  pt expected her cath findings and recommendation. she is ok w undergoing surgery --both her parents underwent--but has fears re the post-op pain control which was very difficult for both her parents. she did not discuss when she last saw dr urie.  


she reports that she continues to have episodic SOB, primarily w exertion, rarely at rest.  sometimes the sob is not assoc'd w other sxs; other times can be assoced w a chest pressure (this is almost always exertional) but no n/v, diaphoresis, arm/neck/jaw pain.  the sob and chest pressure always resolve within a few minutes; she has never had a prolonged episode.  she has been taking meds as recommended by her cardiologist, in particular the increased dose of BB, which has been well-tolerated and reports that overall she feels better on this higher dose of BB.  denies pnd, orthopnea, LE edema, incrase in abd girth, anorexia, increased fatigue. she has been very careful now not to push herself physically and to avoid very strenuous activiies w her grandchildren 


Reports that she feels her DM is under better control now on higher dose of lantus at night. now taking 30 u in the AM and 35 units in the PM. her largest meal continues to be in the evening.  prior to increasing dose in pm, FG 120-199; now 68-172, although 172 = outlier, mostly in the 70-130.  had one episode of feling like sugar low but did not take her FS.  denies polyuria, polydipsia, polyphagia,  
has been trying to watch her portions carefully and decreasing intake to help w wt loss. 253lbs --&gt;247.5lbs.  
continues to take statin; no problems w muscle aches or cramps; darkening of urine; weakness. feels fine w med.  
last 1/2137 hgba1c 7.3%.   


Problems
Diabetes mellitus 
Malignant tumor of urinary bladder : stage 1, now s/p bcg treatment, followed by urology
Hypertensive disorder 
Obesity 
Retinal detachment : s/p repair Dr. Cleveland


Medications
Acetylcysteine 20%(200 MG/ML) 600 MG (200 MG/ML VIAL Take 3 ML) PO as directed #2 Bottle(s)
Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 50 MG (50MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID , Member ID # 55080437876 #180 Tablet(s)
Hydrochlorothiazide 25 MG (25MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD , Member ID # 033388269 #90 Tablet(s)
Lantus (INSULIN GLARGINE) 100 U/ML VIAL ML SC AS DIRECTED , 65U before breakfast and 10 units at night Member ID # 033388269 #3 Month(s) Supply
Lantus SOLOSTAR PEN (INSULIN GLARGINE SOLOSTAR PEN) 75 UNITS (300/3ML INSULN PEN ML) SC as directed , take 65 units in the AM and 10 units in the PM #3 Month(s) Supply
Metformin 1000 MG (1000MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #180 Tablet(s)
Metoprolol TARTRATE 100 MG PO BID , 2 PO QAM AND 1 PO QPM #180 Tablet(s)
Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 10 MG (10 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD x 90 days #90 Tablet(s)
Novolog flexpens SC AC AS DIRECTED , 10U before breakfast, 10U before lunch, 20U before dinner #15 prefilled pens
One touch ultra test strips 1 SC BID #3 Month(s) Supply
Pravastatin 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS #90 Tablet(s)
Solostar prefilled disposable lantus insulin pen 65 UNITS SC qd , Member ID# 033388269 #3 Month(s) Supply
Zostavax (ZOSTER VACCINE LIVE (PF)) 1 VIAL SC X1 x 365 days, 1. Reconstitute and inject 1 vial. Sub-cutaneous upper arm. 2. Please document vaccine administration in the LMR immunization module (or notify the practice in writing if no LMR access). #1 vial




Allergies
AZITHROMYCIN - Unknown
Ace Inhibitor - cough, 


TOB: quit 2120; smoked 2ppd x 15 yrs ETOH: noneIVDU/illict drugs: none SH: originally from Mt. Married for 39 years to Friedman, describes marriage asgood, safe. Has 2 children and 8 grandchildren. Has 2 daugthers, 1 lives inhartsville and 1 in nuku'alofa. no pets. fulltime Author. husband has h/pprostate CA. FH:(no known )h/o sudden death, hyperlipidemia+ Dm in father (dxd in his 60-70)+ mgm w stroke (+CHF in ther mother+mUncles x 2 with MIs (~ 60's_(no known) h/o endometrial, ovarian, thyroid, melanoma, breast, prostate + colon cancer in her mother, dx'd 55-60yo(no known )h/o osteoporosis/premature bone loss(no known )h/o colon polyp, dysplasic nevi(no known )h/o pe, DVT, miscarriages, bleeding disorders (+)h/o glaucoma in mUncle(no known ) h/o depression, suicide, schizophrenia + dementia in her mother+alcoholis in 2 muncles+ bipolar do in grandson


Vital Signs
BP 130/76, P 62, Temp 97.5 F, Wt 247.5 lb
general: well-appearing F in NAD
HEENt: anicteric, PERRL, EOMI, no clear JVD but diffuclt to  assess
NECK: supple, fROM
PULM: CTAB w good air movement. no wheezes, rhonchi, or crackles
COR: rrr, nls1s2, no m/r/g
EXT: wwp, trace, bl, symmetric edema, no clubbing or cyanosis


DATa: 


Law,Ellen 
Report Number:  EO25834097                             Report Status:  FinalType:  CATHwDate:  02/27/2137FINAL Report for CATHw Accession # EO25834097    02/27/2137                                                              Marianjoy Rehabilitation Hospital            Cardiovascular Center                                      Diagnostic Cardiac Catheterization Report____________________________________________________________________________
Patient:                LAW, ELLENMRN:                   26659527Date of Birth:      2/11/2075Procedure Date: 2/27/2137
Attending Physician:     USSERY, VINCENT Q. M.D.Assisting Physician(s): ULLOA, MISTY  PA-CReferring Physician:     UPHOFF, ANTHONY  M.D.
Philips Case Number:   HW988____________________________________________________________________________
Presentation:This is a 62 year old FEMALE who presents for a electivecatheterization with the primary diagnosis of: angina: stable
The patient's presenting cardiac condition includes:Stable AnginaAnginal Class w/in 2 weeks: CCS I: new medications w/in past 2 weeksno
Treated with:aspirin,beta blocker,statins,


The patient was admitted to the cardiac catheterization lab as a(n)outpatient .
Medical History:The patient's additional coronary risk factors include:DiabetesHypertensionDyslipidemia
The patient's past cardiac history includes:
Additional pertinent medical history includes:
Procedures Performed:Left Heart Cath: Percutaneous Retrograde (91118)Coronary Angiography (24047)PA/AO/Cor/SVG/arterial conduit S&amp;I (39865)Groin Closure (G8652)IV Push or Infusion &lt;16 min (18709)
ICD-9 Coding:Primary Dx: 605.12  CAD of native vessel
Radiation and Contrast Exposure:Total Fluoroscopy duration: 3.0 minsTotal Radiation dose: 973 mGyTotal Contrast used: 55 ccContrast Type:Radiation doses in excess of 5000 mGy or 720 Gycm2 may be associatedwith radiation skin injury. For such exposures, clinical followup toassess for radiation induced skin injury is recommended.
Procedural Complications:No acute in-laboratory complications observed.
Coronary Findings:Dominance and General AppearanceRight dominant with Three Vessel CADLeft Main Coronary ArteryNo significant Left Main lesions were identifiedLeft Anterior Descending ArteryDiscrete discrete 98% proximal lesion in LADLeft Circumflex ArteryDiscrete discrete 32% mid lesion in CIRCDiscrete discrete 57% mid lesion in CIRCRight Coronary ArteryDiscrete discrete 77% distal lesion in RCADiscrete discrete 58% ostial lesion in PLV
Comments:Dr Guerrero and husband informed
Conclusion:Diagnostic Results:Left Heart catheterization revealed:3 vessel CADin a diabetic with stable angina. CABG is the first choice.Three Vessel CADElevated Left Heart Filling Pressures Other LVEDP 27
Vascular Access Management:Pulled, Angioseal 6F device deployed to the right femoral arteryCLOSURE DEVICE:  Angioseal 6F successful
Plan:Surgical Consultation
Disposition:Discharge to Home after Recovery
As the attending physician, I was present throughout the entireprocedure and performed ordirectly supervised all manipulations during the procedure.
Signed By: USSERY, VINCENT Q. M.D. On 2/27/2137 09:47:23Attending Physician
Hemodynamics:BSA: 2   Hgb: 12   Hgb (g/l): 120   Estimated O2 Consumption: 266
Date/Time
AIR RESTECG      2137-02-27  09:10:29AO  132/65  (92)  SA    2137-02-27  09:23:20LV  121/12,  27      2137-02-27  09:27:08LVp  119/11,  0      2137-02-27  09:27:12AOp  125/62  (88)      2137-02-27  09:27:20




AIR REST
Procedure Summary-Vascular Access:
PREPPED &amp; DRAPED IN NORMAL STERILE FASHIONAttending Physician arrives to labCardiology PA arrives to labARTERIAL ACCESS 2% Lidocaine to the right groinARTERIAL ACCESS Site- 6F sheath inserted in the right femoral artery-------Post Procedure Vascular Access-------Right Iliac angiography performed RAOTOTAL CONTRAST: 55 ccSheath Management- Pulled, Angioseal 6F device deployed to the rightfemoral artery{Closure Device} St. Jude 6F Angioseal VIP Plus - Qty: 1  Each Part#: 193062CLOSURE DEVICE: {1} Angioseal 6F successfulClosure Device REF # , 358892 LOT# 8068103Total flouro time: 3.0 minsTotal radiation dose: 973 mGyPROCEDURE COMPLETEContrast Used: : 55Total Contrast Used: 55
Procedure Summary - Diagnostic:
{DW St Jude} St. Jude .035 x 180cm Fixed Core 3mm J wire - Qty: 1Each Part #: 17722GNP angiography performed in RAO CaudalLCA angiography performed in RAO CranialLCA angiography performed in LAO CranialLCA angiography performed in LAO CaudalLCA angiography performed in AP Caudal{Catheters} {6F JL} Boston Scientific 6F JL 4.0 - Qty: 1  Each Part#: 30058{Catheters} {6F JR} Boston Scientific 6F JR 4.0 - Qty: 1  Each Part#: 56520YOG angiography performed in LAO CranialRCA angiography performed in RAOPatient tolerated procedure well






Procedure Summary - Nursing Log:
Change in emotional status: Anxiety about procedure: MedicationgivenSedation Scale: 0 Alert, calmChange in emotional status: Anxiety about procedure: Emotionalsupport givenChange in emotional status: Anxiety about procedure: Preop teachingreinforcedSedation Scale: 0 Alert, calmPatient comfortable, tolerating procedure wellSedation Scale: 0 Alert, calmPatient comfortable, tolerating procedure wellChange in emotional status: Anxiety about procedure: MedicationgivenChange in emotional status: Anxiety about procedure: Emotionalsupport givenChange in emotional status: Anxiety about procedure: M.D. notified,no further ordersSedation Scale: 0 Alert, calmPatient comfortable, tolerating procedure wellSedation Scale: 0 Alert, calmPatient comfortable, tolerating procedure well
Procedure Medications:
Fentanyl IV 25 mcgVersed IV 1 mgVersed IV 0.5 mgCefazolin 1 Gram IV Bolus



A/P; 62 yo F with type II DM, HTN, hyperlipidemia, former 30 py smoker, and new do 3v CAD; a/p below.
1) DM: Dx'd ~ 2129, c/b diabetic retinopathy s/p laser tx and likely neuropathy. Most recent 1/2137  HgbA1c: 7.3%, very near goal of &lt;7.0% andimproving compared to 7.8 % since increase in lantus dose.  FS log reviewed today and demonstrated most FG near goal.  Ptnow on BID lantus dosing and FS appear to have improved significantly since she increased her PM dose.  med regimen appears well-tolerated and w very good adherence. 
----plan to recheck hgba1c at next visit----continue metformin 1000mg BID, lantus 30units qam and 35 units q pm----continue glucose monitoring for likely need for further adjustments to regimen----1/2137 urine microalbumin/crt: 22.7 (improved compared to prior 35.9); now within goal of &lt;30
----OPTHO: followd by dr arias; reports uptodate----PODIOTRY: pt w likely diabetic neuropathy and e/o oncychomycosis; referrredto podiotry for further care and monitoring at previous visit----BP: very near goal on HCTZ, Cozzar, metoprolol and norvasc----2137 LDL: 59 on pravastatin; LFTS wnl; 
----9/36 Gabriella Yockey----discussed nutrition referral; pt declined but plans on joining south beach diet----discussed importance of wt loss; pt to try south beach diet; ----PNEUMOVAX: 2136----Flu shot/H1N1: flu shot and h1n1n uptodate;2) HTN: Dx'd in ~ 2129. BP now very near goal today on current regimen of HCTZ 25mg qd, cozaar 50mg BId, metoprolol 200mg in AM and 100mg qpm and norvasc 10 mg qd which appears to be well-tolerated.  chem 7, renal fxn, ca wnl. -----encouraged low na diet, wt loss
----rechecking chem7---- continue 25mg qd, cozaar 50mg BId, metoprolol 200mg in AM and 100mg qpmand norvasc 10 mg qd----reviewed si/sxs for which she should seek immediate medical attention3) dyslipidemia: 1/2137 LDL 59 within goal of &lt;100 given DM and  CAD on pravastatin which appears well-tolerated. Past trial of simvastatin; self-dc'd 2/2 myalgias and generalized weakness but nl LFTS/CK/GFR.  Again reviewed possible side effects and she knows to call w any concerns or questions----continue pravastatin 20mg qhs; reivwed possible side effects and instructed to call w concerns----recommended low cholesterol diet4) new do 3 v CAD: reviewed recent cath results demonstrating 3 v CAD w patient and recommendations to undergo CABG. Pt is ready to undergo as recommended; has concerns re post-op pain control and recommended that she discuss at pre-op visit.  appears to have stable angina tat this time but reviewed w her si/sxs at lenght for which she should seek immediate medical attention by calling 911. continue regimen of ASA, statin (LDL&lt;70) ,BB, and ARB.  not able to tolerate nitrates in past. recommended that pt discuss physical activity limitations w cards at her upcoming appt but until then feel that not overly exerting herself and not increasing physical activity level safest. 
---rechecking chem7 post cath
---continue to follow closely




Pt to RTC in ~ 1 mos or sooner if needed. 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2137-06-01








LAW, ELLEN

26659527

06/01/2137





Margaret Alvarez, M.D.

Marianjoy Rehabilitation Hospital, Internal Medicine

96 Burton Drive, Suite 659

Kings Mountain, MT  11361



Dear Margaret,



I had the pleasure of seeing this patient in the Cardiology Clinic at the Marianjoy Rehabilitation Hospital.  Since I last saw Ms. Law, she underwent a 3-vessel coronary artery bypass surgery, internal mammary to the left anterior descending artery, free right radial graft to the obtuse marginal branch of the left circumflex, and reverse saphenous vein graft to the posterior descending branch of the right coronary artery.  She tolerated the surgery quite well and had a short rehab stay.  Currently, she is doing some walking, but is still feeling quite tired and a bit deconditioned.  However, her breathing does feel better than prior to the surgery.  She has some residual sternal wound pain, but it has improved since her discharge.



Current Medications:

1.  Aspirin 325 mg daily.

2.  DuoNeb.

3.  Diltiazem 300 mg p.o. t.i.d.

4.  Furosemide 40 mg p.o. daily.

5.  K-Dur 20 mEq p.o. daily.

6.  Metolazone 2.5 mg daily.

7.  Toprol 100 mg p.o. b.i.d.

8.  Pravastatin 20 mg p.o. daily.

9.  Furosemide 40 mg p.o. daily.

10.  Colace, ferrous sulfate, ibuprofen, senna.



Adverse Medication Reactions:

1.  Azithromycin.

2.  ACE inhibitor, cough.

3.  Latex, angioedema.



On physical examination, heart rate 81, blood pressure 106/75, and weight of 246.  In general, she is well appearing, in no apparent distress.  Jugular venous pressure is 6 cm of water.  Carotids are 2+, no bruits.  The chest is clear to auscultation and percussion, a well-healed median sternotomy, regular rate and rhythm.  No significant murmurs, gallops, or rubs.  Abdomen:  Soft, nontender, nondistended, no masses, bruits, organomegaly.  Extremities:  1-2+ edema.



Review of labs dated 05/28/2134, potassium 4.3, creatinine 0.9, ALT 16, AST 16, total cholesterol 125, triglycerides 106, HDL 36, and LDL 68.



In summary, the patient is a 62-year-old woman status post CABG, doing well.  She does appear to be mildly volume overloaded today, therefore I will make the following medication adjustments.  As far as her cardiac meds, they will change to aspirin 81 mg daily, potassium 20 mEq daily, Lasix 40 mg p.o. b.i.d., metoprolol succinate 100 mg p.o. daily, and pravastatin 20 mg p.o. daily.



I will titrate her Lasix on an outpatient basis to have her lose 5-7 pounds to improve her shortness of breath as well as her edema.  We will ask VNA to draw labs as well.



I will see her again in 2 weeks' time.  Please feel free to contact me with any questions.



Warmest regards,





______________________________

Anthony Uphoff, M.D.











eScription document:8-77995324 IFFocus











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2137-12-17

HIGHLAND HOSITAL VISIT
PT: Ellen Law
date of visit: 12/17/2137


cc: fu DM, HTN, CAD, and pre-op evaluation



HPI: Ellen is scheduled to have R cataract surgery on 1/16/2138.  Dr. Margaret Aria has requested that she be evaluated prior to surgery. Today, reports that she is doing well. She graduated from cardiac rehab and is now going to enroll in a supervisored exercise program. today, she denies any chest pain or pressure, sob at rest; mild, stable R ankle swelling.  denies DOE but describes improvement in her exercise capacity. does have to stop sometimes bc she is having the very beginnings of her prior jaw pain. however, this is much less than it was prior to her CABG and is also improving. she is really "so much better" post CABG.  reports improving energy; she is very busy, going from morning until night w no sign't limitations. no PND, sleeps on 1 pillow. no pain in her legs when she walks. 


reports that she is really working on her FS; her FS in the AM ~ 90-180 but now on the lower side.
she is taking lantus 42 units in the AM and 48 in the PM. 
no trouble w hypoglycemia.
her postprandial FS ~ 120s (~ 3 hours)
reports that she is very stressed today;  her grandson is in hte hosp (has bipolar do and struggling); feeling like it is re to stress
denies polyuria, polydipsia, polyphagia


had flu shot last visit






Problems
Diabetes mellitus 
Malignant tumor of urinary bladder : stage 1, now s/p bcg treatment, followed by urology
Hypertensive disorder 
Obesity 
Retinal detachment : s/p repair Dr. Cleveland
Coronary arteriosclerosis 


Medications
Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Kcl Slow Release Tab 20 MEQ (20 MEQ TAB PRT SR Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Lantus Solostar Pen (INSULIN Glargine Solostar Pen) 62 UNITS (100/ML (3) INSULN PEN ML) SC as directed, take32 units in the AM and 30 units in the PM #3 Month(s) Supply
Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 40 MG (40 MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #180 Tablet(s)
Metoprolol Succinate Extended Release 100 MG (100 MG TAB.SR 24H Take 1) PO QD #90 TAB.SR
Nifedipine Extended Release 30 MG (30 MG TAB ER 24 Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Pravastatin 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS #90 Tablet(s)
Solostar Prefilled Disposable Lantus Insulin Pen 65 UNITS SC qd, Member ID# 033388269 #3 Month(s) Supply
Vitamin D2 (ERGOCALCIFEROL) 50000 UNITS (50000 UNIT CAPSULE Take 1) PO #Capsule(s)


Allergies
AZITHROMYCIN - Unknown
ACE Inhibitor - cough
Latex, Natural Rubber - TONGUE SWELLING


TOB: quit 2120; smoked 2ppd x 15 yrs ETOH: noneIVDU/illict drugs: none 
SH: originally from Mt. Married for 39 years to Friedman, describes marriage asgood, safe. Has 2 children and 8 grandchildren. Has 2 daugthers, 1 lives inhartsville and 1 in nuku'alofa. no pets. fulltime Author. husband has h/pprostate CA. 
FH:(no known )h/o sudden death, hyperlipidemia+ Dm in father (dxd in his 60-70)+ mgm w stroke (+CHF in ther mother+mUncles x 2 with MIs (~ 60's_(no known) h/o endometrial, ovarian, thyroid, melanoma, breast, prostate + colon cancer in her mother, dx'd 55-60yo(no known )h/o osteoporosis/premature bone loss(no known )h/o colon polyp, dysplasic nevi(no known )h/o pe, DVT, miscarriages, bleeding disorders (+)h/o glaucoma in mUncle(no known ) h/o depression, suicide, schizophrenia + dementia in her mother+alcoholis in 2 muncles+ bipolar do in grandson


Vital Signs
BP 144/70, P 68, Temp 97.2 F
general: well-appearing F in NAd
HEENt: anicteric, PERRL, EOMI, mmm, no jvd, no carotid bruits appreciated bl, 2 + carotid upstrokes
NECK: supple, FROM
PULM: CTAB w good air movement. no wheezes, rhonchi, or crackles
COR: rrr, nl S1S1, no M/R/G
ABD: soft, ntnd, +Bs
EXT: wwp, no trace bl edema, no calf tenderness 
NEURO: appropriate, ox 3, speech fluent.  CN II-XII intact. Motor strength 5/5 in all ext. Reflex 1+ symmetric throughout. Light touch and temp sens intact




EKG (prelim): sinus at 63 bpm; nl intervals, LAD (unchanged); c/w past inferior IMI,  anteroseptal
V3 different compared to 10/2137; previusly w downward deflection; ? re to lead placement
otherwise appears unchanged compred to 10/26/2137





A/P: 62 yo F presenting re multiple medical issues. 
1) CAD s/p recent CABG: doing well.  followed closely by Cardiology dr Uphoff. now  finished w cardiac rehab and appears to be doing  very well. mild jaw discomfort (posible anginal equivalent) improving w improved conditioning. Dr. Uphoff aware and has recomemnded ongoing conditioning and close monitring. no further palpitations; she knows to c all if recurrent. recent LDL within goal.  pt confirms 100% adherence to meds. BP elevated today but reoprtedly within goal at PT/rehab and at other doctors appts
---continue asa 81 mg, metoprolol, nifedipine, and prn lasix per Cardiology
---cardiac rehab
---encouraged ongoing healthy eating, wt loss, and exercise (W cardiac rehab
2) DM: most recent 11/06/2137 hgba1c 7.6 % (from 7.8%), nearing goal. Pt w improved FS today esp w increases to lantus ~ 42-48units BID. no episodes of hypoglycemia now that she has stopped the novolog.  will rechecking hgba1c at next visit. recent LDL within goal. 1/2137 urine microalbum to creat within goal.  optho uptodate she will call w any problems, concerns, persistently elevated FS, sxs.  continue to follow closely. applauded and encouraged ongoing wt loss.  2136 pneumovax; 2137 flu shot uptodate
3) urology: h/o bladder CA: 9/2137 cystoscopy wnl; recommended fu in 1 year
4) HTN: BP typically well-controlled on current regimen; pt feels re to feeling very stressted today. She will return to see me in ~ 2 weeks and recheck then. will also have her cousin check it at home severe times to add a few more date points
5) Pre-op risk assessment prior to upcoming cataract surgery: According to AHA/ACC guidelines, pt has intermediate/mod risk for a low risk surgery and undewent successful CABG/revascularization &gt;6 months ago (5/14/2137) and has no clear significant symptoms related to this. She does not need further invasive testing at this time for low risk surgery.  I will, however, confirm this w her cardiologist to make sure he does have any issues as well with her surgery and add that as an addendum to this note. Pt's BP is mildly elevated today but typically within goal on her current regimen. I will see her back in ~ 2 weeks time, prior to surgery and make sure her BP is well controlled. Pt has no hx to suggest bleeding diathesis but will checking her pt/ptt and cbc today.  Pt will discuss with Dr. Arias regarding when she needs to stop her ASA. she is on this for her CAD so important to resume as soon as possible; I will also confirm w Dr. Uphoff re his opinions re the asa. Diabetes control improving (see above). A copy of this letter along w labs and EKG will be sent to Dr. Arias. 
6) HCM:
----reviewed mammogram: pt wishes to defer for now; understands risks/benefits; she will redisucss at fu visit
----colo: brought upt again today need for screening but pt did not wish to discuss and still &lt;1 year post CABG


Pt to RTC in 2 weeks or sooner. 


&gt;50% of 35 minute visit spent counsleing patient re above issues. 






____________________________________
Margaret Erik Alvarez, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2138-04-08



Reason for Visit
 
 






BP Follow-up







History of Present Illness




63 yo female pt of Dr. Alvarez presents to the office for f/u bp.
 
- She was restarted taking cozaar 25 ng in addition to her metoprolol 100 mg, nifedipine 30 mg. She states that she is tolerating cozaar.
- She reports some worsening  sob with exertion and experiencing jaw pain with walking x 2-3 weeks.
- She has been going for cardiac PT twice a week and has her bp taking during the therapy. Her bp is running around 122/60's.Her BP once went up to 130/70's right after she exerted herself  at the therapy.
- She denies any chest pain
- She notes that she  gained 10 lb recently

- She is on  second round of 8 weeks  in her cardiac PT
- No F/C/N/V





Problems
Diabetes mellitus 
Malignant tumor of urinary bladder : stage 1, now s/p bcg treatment, followed by urology
Hypertensive disorder 
Obesity 
Retinal detachment : s/p repair Dr. Cleveland
Coronary arteriosclerosis 
Coronary artery bypass graft : 2137
Hyperlipidemia 


Medications
Alphagan P (BRIMONIDINE Tartrate ) 1 DROP (0.1% DROPS ) OD BID #1 Month(s) Supply
Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 25 MG (25 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD, Member ID # 55080437876 #180 Tablet(s)
Lantus Solostar Pen (INSULIN Glargine Solostar Pen) 62 UNITS (100/ML (3) INSULN PEN ML) SC as directed, take 44 units in the AM and 55 units in the PM #3 Month(s) Supply
Metoprolol Succinate Extended Release 100 MG (100 MG TAB.SR 24H Take 1) PO QD #90 TAB.SR
Nevanac (NEPAFENAC Ophthalmic) 0.1% DROPS SUSP Take 1 OD QID, Start 3 days before surgery. #5 ML(s)
Nevanac (NEPAFENAC Ophthalmic) 0.1% DROPS SUSP Take 1 OS QID, Start 3 days before surgery. #5 ML(s)
Nifedipine Extended Release 30 MG (30 MG TAB ER 24 Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Pravastatin 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QHS #90 Tablet(s)
Prednisolone 1% Acetate Ophthalmic Suspension 1 % DROPS SUSP Take 1 OD QID, DO NOT START UNTIL AFTER SURGERY AS DIRECTED. #10 ML(s)
Prednisolone 1% Acetate Ophthalmic Suspension 1 % DROPS SUSP Take 1 OS QID, DO NOT START UNTIL AFTER SURGERY AS DIRECTED. #10 ML(s)
Solostar Prefilled Disposable Lantus Insulin Pen 65 UNITS SC qd, Member ID# 033388269 #3 Month(s) Supply
Vigamox (MOXIFLOXACIN Ophthalmic) 0.5 % DROPS Take 1 OD QID, Start 3 days before surgery. #5 ML(s)
Vigamox (MOXIFLOXACIN Ophthalmic) 0.5 % DROPS Take 1 OS QID, Start 3 days before surgery. #5 ML(s)
Vitamin D2 (ERGOCALCIFEROL) 50000 UNITS (50000 UNIT CAPSULE Take 1) PO #Capsule(s)


Allergies
AZITHROMYCIN - Unknown
ACE Inhibitor - cough
Latex, Natural Rubber - TONGUE SWELLING
SIMVASTATIN - Myalgia






Physical Exam
ination

Vital Signs
BP 110/70 L Arm, P 69, Temp 96.6 F



Repeat BP:       right arm: 135/60     left arm 136/65 mmHg




General: oriented X3, in no apparent distress.  


Skin: skin is warm and dry



Head: atraumatic,normocephalic

Eyes: PERRL, conjunctiva normal, no discharge.  


Neck :supple,no LAN


Pulmonary: CTA b/l


Cardio: good distal pulses bilaterally, RRR without murmurs, gallops or rubs, no LE edema



MS: Full ROM

Neuro: 5/5 strength,sensory and motor intact


 
EKG interpreted by me and by Dr. Alvarez: NSR, possible left atrial enlargement, abnormal ECG
compared with previos EKG and noticed some V3 V4 changes (?lead misplacement)










Assessment/ Plan


 
63 yo female pt of Dr. Alvarez with hx of above  presents to the office for f/u bp.




#     Hypertension 
, controlled
continue cozaar, metoprolol, and nifedipine
 
BMP 
 
# Dyspnea on exertion, and jaw pain
f/u with Dr. Uphoff (cardiology)
       Dr. Uphoff was contacted via e-mail regarding pt new symptoms
                                                



Discussed with pt potential risks, benefits and side effects of the medication that is increased in frequency.

Discussed with pt signs and symptoms that would require prompt medical reevaluation.  RTC if current symptoms fail to improve or worsen, or if new symptoms appear. The patient indicates understanding of these issues and agrees with the plan.



I personally interviewed and examined the patient.  My note incorporates my findings, plan and assessment.









****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>