<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2082-06-29

Narrative History

   The patient is here today for the following issues:

   1.  Patient is scheduled for gastric bypass surgery July 22nd.  She is leaving for vacation.  She wants to make sure she is cleared for her surgery

   2.  Patient completed Vit. D supplementation and her new VIT D level is 49 (up from 9).

   3.  Patient complaining of persistent chest pain - she saw Dr. Uzzell who feels she is cleared for surgery from a cardiac perspective.

   4.  Patient has persistednt recurrent LE edema.

   5.  She complaining of occasional shortness of breath and has a pulmonary appointment in July prior to her surgery.

   6.  Patient saw Dr. Newkirk who is still awaiting some bloodwork but feels she is cleared for surgery.  Her hct most recently was 35.6

   7. OSA - feels she does awake in the middle of the night with sob.

   8.  Patient gets an occasional leg cramp on the right - question related to LBP.  K+ normal on June 23rd.  Will follow up after surgery.  No weakness or numbness.

Problems

      Diabetes mellitus



      S/P Abortion   SPONTANEOUS 4/80 



      Chlamydia   CERVICITIS-TREATED 



      H/O Abnormal pap test



      Positive PPD   NEG CXR 



      PARONYCHIAL INFECTION    LEFT HAND 78 



      Ectopic pregnancy   74 



      Coronary artery disease



      Anemia



      Shortness of breath



      Hypertension



      Gastroesophageal reflux disease



      Elevated cholesterol



      Hyperthyroidism



      Obesity

Review of Systems

   Unless mentioned in the history above the following ROS were asked and are negative:  Constitutional,Respiratory, Cardiac, GI (above), Heme (above), Endocrine, GYN, Musculoskeletal, Psych, and Neuro.  

Medications

      ATENOLOL     100MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD   



      ASA (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)     325MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN)     20MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      INSULIN 70/30 (HUMAN)   SEE BELOW     SC 5ID   



      IMDUR (ISOSORBIDE MONONIT.(SR))     30MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      NEXIUM (ESOMEPRAZOLE)     40MG  1 Capsule(s) PO BID  



      KLONOPIN (CLONAZEPAM)     0.5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO TID   



      ZESTRIL (LISINOPRIL)     5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD   



      ZANTAC (RANITIDINE HCL)     300MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  



      VITAMIN D (ERGOCALCIFEROL)   50000 U     IM q72 HOURS  36 day(s) 



      MECLIZINE HCL     25MG  1 Tablet(s) PO TID  7 day(s) 

Allergies

      NKDA      

Physical Exam

   120/80

   GENERAL: 	obese female

   EXT:		No edema

   

   

   LABS reviewed.

Assessment and Plan

   1.  Gastric Bypass - Will proceed to preop evaluation and hopeful surgery on July 22nd.  Dr. Rivers will be consulted to assist with sugar management. 

   2.  Vit D deficiency - Corrected with Vit D supplementation.  

   3. LE edema will likely improve with weight loss.  Follow up after surgery.

   4. CAD - followed by Dr. Uzzell

   5. shortness of breath - Likely mostly secondary to deconditioning and weight but will be evaluated by pulmonary.

   6. OSA - sees pulmonary in July.

    appointment time 35 minutes - Discussed with patient at lenght surgery and what to expect after.  She seems motivated to lose weight.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-03-08

Narrative History	

The patient is here today for the following issues:

1. Patient's father recently died - massive MI.  Klonipin has been helping patient at night.  She tried it during the day but too sleepy.

2.  She has had persistent chest pain and sob since Father's dealth.  She tried SLNTG without improvement.  HAs have also returned.  

        Pain not worse with exertion.  

        3.  Patient asking about IUD removal.

        4.  Patient has lost 90 pounds so far.  Appetite is down and smaller portions.  

        5. Diabetes - Dr. Rivers started glucophage 825 BID but she doesn't take it all the time.

       6.  She admits to not taking her lipitor - worrries it had some effect on her vision.



Problems

Diabetes mellitus 

S/P Abortion : SPONTANEOUS 4/80

Chlamydia : CERVICITIS-TREATED

H/O Abnormal pap test : '76 S/P COLPOSCOPY IN PAST; RECENT PAP NORMAL

Positive PPD : NEG CXR

PARONYCHIAL INFECTION : LEFT HAND 78

Ectopic pregnancy : 74

Coronary artery disease 

Anemia 

Shortness of breath 

Hypertension 

Gastroesophageal reflux disease 

Elevated cholesterol 

Hyperthyroidism 

Obesity 





Medications

ATENOLOL 100MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Klonopin (CLONAZEPAM) 0.5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO TID

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Imdur (ISOSORBIDE MONONIT.(SR)) 30MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 40MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD 





Allergies

NKDA 





Review of Systems	

Unless mentioned in the history above the following ROS were asked and are negative:  Constitutional, Respiratory, Cardiac, GI, Endocrine, GYN, Musculoskeletal, Psych - no SI.  

Vital signs

BP 120/75, Wt 228 lb 







Physical Exam	

108/70

GENERAL: 	Healthy appearing overweight female

NECK:	            No thyromegaly, no nodes

CHEST	            Clear lungs, NL frame

COR:		RRR, NL S1S2, no murmur, rubs, or gallops.

                        BIMAN c no adnexal masses, no CMT

EXT:		No edema

NEURO:           NL MS, NL gait



Labs reviewed

EKG done and unchanged from 8/82

Assessment and Plan	

1.  Chest pain, Headaches and shortness of breath - No evidence of USA.  All likely secondary to anxiety and grief over father's death.  Patient reassured.  Will continue cardiac medications.  Return to cardiac rehab on Thursday.  Will add .5mg klonipin during the day as needed.  Continue 1mg klonipin at night.  Patient declines psychotherapy.   Also, will restart nexium as some of chest pain may be recurrence of reflux.

2.   DM - Encouraged patient to take glucophage as prescribed.  She is worried she will always have DM.  Discussed with patient importance of controlling BSs now and losing remaining weight.  She will continue to monitor home FSBS.

3.  Obesity - Impressive 90 pound weight loss.  Patient very encourage.  Continue with smaller meals.

         4.  Hyperlipidemia - Patient will restart lipitor.  Follow up fasting cholesterol and SGOT.

        5. CAD - Continue Imdur, aspirin and lipitor.  Cardiac rehab.  Follow up if new chest pain.

        6. IUD - Discussed briefly.  Stressed importance of no pregnancies with CAD.  She wants to rediscuss at end of year.

        7.  History of hyperthyroidism - Recheck. 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-10-30



Narrative History

The patient is here today for the following issues:

1. Patient is pregnant.  No bleeding or cramping.  Followed by Dr. Kilgore.  She did not intend to get pregnant again but would like to keep this pregnancy.  2.  Labs in past indicated hyperthyroidism. This is being followed by endocrine. No palpitations. 

3.  DM - Has not been taking insulin since birth of son.  HgA1C >10.  She will be seen by Endocrine today.

4.  Followed by Dr. Uzzell for CAD.  No chest pain.   On atenolol, aspirin and imdur.



Problems

      Diabetes mellitus

      S/P Abortion    : SPONTANEOUS 4/80

      Chlamydia    : CERVICITIS-TREATED

      H/O Abnormal pap test    : '76 S/P COLPOSCOPY IN PAST; RECENT PAP NORMAL

      Positive PPD    : NEG CXR

      PARONYCHIAL INFECTION     : LEFT HAND 78

      Ectopic pregnancy    : 74

      Coronary artery disease

      Anemia

      Shortness of breath

      Hypertension

      Gastroesophageal reflux disease

      Elevated cholesterol

      Hyperthyroidism

      Obesity



Review of Systems

Unless mentioned in the history above the following ROS were asked and are negative:  Constitutional, Respiratory, Cardiac, GI, Endocrine,  Musculoskeletal.  



Medications

      Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)    325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

      Natalcare Plus    1TAB   PO qd 

      ATENOLOL   100MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

      Imdur (ISOSORBIDE MONONIT.(SR))    30MG TABLET CR 24HR take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 



Allergies

      NKA



Social History

NP in Laplace - waiting for researcher job.

Son born in 2085 name Uri, older child



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   122/70 

      WEIGHT   220 lb

      AGE   32y5.7m 



Physical Exam

GENERAL: 	Healthy appearing

Labs reviewed.



Assessment and Plan

1.  Pregnancy - Counseled patient- especially on need to control sugars.  Limited weight gain.  She will discuss with ob and cardiology when to stop aspirin.  She will likely be induced early.

2.  Hyperthyroidism - Denies symptoms- repeat today  Follow up with Dr. Kirkpatrick.

3.  DM - Followed by diabetes clinic.  HgA1C> 10 .  Will need to restart insulin - counseled. 

4. CAD - On atenolol, asa, imdur. Followed by Dr. Uzzell.

25 minutes spent with the patient - the majority counseling on above.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-09-15



	CARDIOLOGY

	

	SAINT VINCENT HOSPITAL

	



	Interval History:

   Since last seen, Ursula notes that her weight continues to rise, and with this, her angina is clearly worse.  She has stable symptoms, nothing to suggest an ACS, but she's dyspneic with exertion and takes nitro occasionally.



Medications:  Atenolol 100 mg qd, Aspirin 81 mg. qd, Imdur 30 mg., Lipitor 20 mg qd, glucophage



Physical examination:  Reveals her to be obese weighing 231 lbs.  Her BP is 120/ palp in her left arm and her heart rate is 80. Her lungs are clear throughout.  Her apical impulse is non-displaced with a regular rate and rhythm, a normal S1 and S2, but no S3 or S4.  There is a grade 1 MR murmur noted.  There is no jugular venous distention and carotid pulses are 2+ bilaterally with soft bilateral bruits.  Her abdomen is morbidly obese.  Her extremities are notable for trace lower extremity edema.



EKG:  NSR with an old IPMI.  She also has non specific STT wave abnormalities.  When compared to a previous tracing there is no change. 



Impression:



1.CAD, s/p cath and stenting:  her angina is clearly related to her weight going up again; I worry about this, and wonder if she should have another weight loss surgery.  For the meantime, I will increase Imdur to 60 mg qd, and consider an increase in atenolol.

	

Umberto M. Uzzell, MD pager #12472

	

Signed electronically by  Umberto M. Uzzell, MD

Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-04-05


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	SAINT VINCENT HOSPITAL
	


	Interval History:
   Ursula is seen in the Cardiology office for a followup visit.  Since last seen, she notes a number of somewhat concerning symptoms.  First of all, she is noting some mid sternal chest discomfort with exertion.  She associates this with back pain related to a remote back injury, but nonetheless with exertions she develops some degree of mid sternal chest discomfort, non radiating, associated may be with some shortness of breath.  She has not used any nitroglycerin for it.  It gets better when she rests.  She denies palpitations, PND, or orthopnea.  Her sugars are out of control.  Her weight is down, nonetheless.

Physical examination:
	
-Pulse:   80
-BP: 130/85  
-weight:   206 lbs.
-General:   Overweight.  Well appearing.
-Skin:   No rashes.  Anicteric.
-Heent:   Unremarkable.
-Neck:   JVP less than 5, possible venous hums bilaterally.  Carotids without bruits.
-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.
-Cardiac:   Apical impulse nondisplaced and discrete.  Regular rate and rhythm.  Normal S1 and split S2.  Soft S4 gallop.
-Abdomen:   Obese, soft, nontender, and nondistended without hepatosplenomegaly, bruits, dilated aorta.
-Extremities:   No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.

Procedures:
	
Electrocardiogram  normal sinus rhythm IVCD, old IMI.  In addition, she has nonspecific ST and T-wave changes.  Compared there is no important change.


	Impression:
   1.  Coronary artery disease status post multiple PCIs.  Ursula has the return of chest symptoms which are suggestive for angina.  I will refer her for an exercise tolerance test to better evaluate this.  I will continue on the current medication program.
2.  Hypertension.  Her blood pressure is a bit elevated.  Given her diabetes, I think it is prudent to add an ACE inhibitor.  Accordingly, lisinopril 2.5 mg QD was added to her program.
3.  Lipids will be checked.  I strongly suspect that her LDL is not well suppressed.  Our goal LDL in this case is less than 70 mg/dL.

	
Umberto Uzzell, MD

	
Signed electronically by  Umberto Uzzell, MD
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>