<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2078-08-20

New office visit







Referring Physician:

Dr. Ebert

BMC





PCP:

Dr.Bryan Edmondson

BMC



CHIEF PAIN COMPLAINT:  "I have pain in the back radiating down my legs." 

 

PAIN HISTORY:  The patient's pain started spontaneously about two years ago.  It is located in the lower back, radiating to the back of the legs, to the level of the knees.  The pain is brought on by walking and made better by stopping or sitting down.  Bending over forward also helps the pain.  There is no numbness or weakness associated with the pain.  The pain is better at night than during the day.  The patient has separate pain complaint, which is burning pain in her feet, is worse at night than during the day.  Patient denies bowel or bladder changes. The patient has tried Celebrex, Vioxx and Motrin but has not found any relief for her pain.  She currently does not take any pain medications.  She denies a history of heartburn, gastric or duodenal ulcers or GI bleeds.  She has trouble falling asleep and staying asleep because of the burning pain in her feet. She is being referred to us by Dr. Ebert from Neurosurgery after an MRI scan showed spinal stenosis at L5-S1 and at L4-5 as well as spondylolithiasis between L4 and L5.  She had been reluctant to undergo surgery and was therefore referred to see if epidural steroid injections could help.  

 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes, hypertension, coronary artery disease with myocardial infarction four years ago.   

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Coronary stent placement times two in December 2074.  

 

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Metformin 500 mg q. day, Monopril 40 mg q.  day, baby aspirin 81 mg q. day,  HCTZ 12.5 mg q. day, Norvasc 5 mg q. day and Pravachol 20 mg q. day.   



Social History:  She does not smoke, does smoke, does not drink and does not use drugs.  She came from Bermuda four years ago.  She is married and retired.  

 

Allergies: NKDA



Review of systems:

Constitutional:  	Denies fever, recent weight change, fatigue, or anxiety.



Neurological:	   	Denies confusion, double vision, light-headedness.



HEENT:	   	No symptoms.  



Respiratory:	  	 Non-smoker.  No dyspnea, bronchospasm, cough, COPD.  



Cardiac:	 	 No, palpitations, syncope.



Gastrointestinal:	Denies N & V, heartburn, constipation, diarrhea, bleeding.



Renal:			No history of renal problems.   No dysuria, urgency or frequency. 



Skin:			No recent changes.



Musculoskeletal: 	Denies muscle pain, positive for leg cramps cramps, arthritis. 



Hematologic:              Pt denies spontaneous nose bleeds or easy bruising.                                                                                    













Physical examination:





Vital signs

BP 145/60 ,P 56 ,VAS SCORE 8/10 





HEENT: 	Normal.  

Lungs: 	CTA (B)

Heart: 	RRR, S1, S2, no murmurs

Abdomen: 	Soft, non-tender, bowel sounds present

Extremities: 	No cyanosis, clubbing or edema.



 

Targeted examination showed an age appropriate woman in no apparent distress.  Mental Status:  She was fully awake and alert.  Her mood was appropriate.  There was mild sensory loss in a stocking distribution over the lets as well as in a glove distribution over the hands.  There was no frank allodynia of the feet.  Patellar and ankle reflexes were retained.  Toe response was flexor.  The patient could walk, including heel and toe walk.  There was no pain on straight leg raising.  There was no local tenderness over the back, however, a moderate degree of muscle spasm over the lower back.  

 

IMPRESSION:  

 

1.  Spinal stenosis.  

2.  Diabetic neuropathy.  

 

PLAN:  

 

1.  Start Neurontin with a target dose of 300 mg t.i.d. for now.  If tolerated, we will increase to 600 mg t.i.d.  

 

2.  One week after Neurontin, start Zanaflex 2 mg p.o. q.h.s. to be titrate up to 4 mg after one week.  

 

3.  Lumbar epidural steroid injection at L4-5 or L5-S1.  If treatment with injections is unsuccessful, we will ask the patient to be reevaluate by Neurosurgery.  

 

 

Ila Easter, M.D.  





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-04-22




INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

BROADLAWNS MEDICAL CENTER



Reason for visit   elevated B/P



History of present illness   Seen in ER for HTN.yesterday  224/105

Per dau TX w/ IV lopressor x 4 doses, betalol & NTG

Today B/P 210/90 this AM

Meds not changed.

No ha, no chest pain, no SOB, no blurred vision.



Change in therapies and Renewals

Norvasc 5mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:3 Start: 3/12/2075



Assessment and plan   HTN 

Discussed w/ Dr Edmondson by phone.

Will add Norvasc 5 mg qd

Advised family.

Called to  pharm



Disposition

Appt w/ Dr Edmondson 4/28/79



Addendum

			

I was present during key portions of the evaluation of the patient and agree with Noreen Dotson's findings and plan as written.

Bryan Edmondson



Signed electronically by Noreen O Dotson RN on Apr 22, 2079     Bryan  Edmondson MD on Aug 20, 2079     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-01-26





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

BROADLAWNS MEDICAL CENTER



History of present illness   This is an 81-year-old black female with hypertension, type 2 diabetes mellitus, coronary artery disease, and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation who is here for followup.  The patient feels generally well.  Her only complaint is difficulty sleeping.  She wakes up at night.  She does not sleep soundly.  She denies any orthopnea or PND.  No chest pain.  No back pain.  She had a history of low back pain secondary to spinal stenosis; however, her pain has not been a problem lately.  She denies any palpitations, lightheadedness, or shortness of breath.



Change in therapies and Renewals

Norvasc 5 mg 1 tab   qd

aspirin 325 mg 1 tab   qd

Glucophage 500 mg   bid

hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg   QD

ibuprofen 800 mg   tid

Isordil 40 mg   tid

fosinopril 40 mg   QD

metoprolol 50 mg   BID

Pravachol 20 mg   QD



Physical examination

Blood pressure 170/80  

Weight   179 pounds

General appearance   Overweight in no acute distress

Skin   Clear

Heent   Eyes, nonicteric

Nodes   Normal

Chest   Lungs are clear

Cor   Regular rhythm.  S1 and S2 are normal.  No murmur, S3, or S4

Abdomen   Soft and nontender.  No masses

Extrem   No edema



Assessment and plan   Coronary artery disease.  Stable.  Continue present medications.

Hypertension.  Systolic a little high today.  We will not change her medicine right now.  Her blood pressure has been satisfactory in the past.

Degenerative arthritis with low back pain.  Stable and asymptomatic.  Continue ibuprofen PRN.

Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation.  Asymptomatic.  Pulse is regular today.  No change in treatment.

Diabetes.  Continue Glucophage.  Check hemoglobin A1c.

Insomnia.  Trial of trazodone 50 mg QHS PRN.



Disposition

Return in three months.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Edmondson, Bryan on Feb 2, 2080     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-06-23






      CARDIOLOGY
      


      BROADLAWNS MEDICAL CENTER
      




      Reason for visit:
    Mrs Vanmeter presents for routine follow up of her CAD, HTN and hyperlipidemia




      Interval History:
    She presents stating that she is getting along reasonably well. Her main problem is burning in her legs and feet, also present in her hands. She also reports an increased frequency of her chest tightness, occuring mainly at night, sometimes before going to sleep, sometimes durign the night. This is responsive to 1 SL TNG typically, although sometimes is goes away without intervention. She denies SOB, PND, orthopnea, presycope or syncope. She has intermittant mild LE edema. She occasionally has palpitations, lasting ~ 5 minutes, resolving spontaneously. She cannot relate them to any time of day or activity, and they are not associated w/ lightheadedness or CP.


Recently she called me w/ complaints of increased LE edema. This is minor on exam. Her echo showed preserved LV function and no significnat valvular disease.








      Past medical history:
    CAD s/p IMI in 2074, s/p stent placement x2 in 2074.
HTN
PAF
Type 2 DM
Sciatica
Hyperlipidemia
GERD
Glaucoma
Multinodular goiter




      Medications (Confirmed):


      
acetaminophen and codeine (tylenol with codeine #3) tablets 
Alphagan P  0.15% x 1 drop ou bid
aspirin  81 mg QD
fosinopril 
Glucophage  500 mg bid
Isordil  40 mg tid
Removed - lisinopril  40 mg qd
Lopressor  25 mg 1/2 bid
nitroglycerin 
Norvasc  5 mg 1/2 qd
Pravachol  20 mg qd
Trusopt  1 drop od daily
Tylenol  325mg x 2 tabs po q4-6h PRN pain


Allergies:
      
No known drug allergy   




      Family history:
    Mother died in her early 60s of "heart problems", not otherwise specified.  Father in mid 50s with "kidney problems".




      Social history:
    She is married, retired, comes originally from Bermuda. Has several children/grandchildren who help with her medical issues. She does not smoke or drink alcohol.






      Review of systems:
    Otherwise negative in detail.


Physical examination:
      
-BMI: 32.6  Obese, high risk
-Pulse: 57  
-resp. rate: 18  
-height: 61  in.
-weight: 172  lbs.
-General appearance:   No acute distress.
-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.
-HEENT:   Unremarkable
-Neck:   Carotids 2+ without bruits. JVP no jugular venous distention
-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.
-Cardiac:   Left ventricular impulse discrete and nondisplaced. Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2, with no S3 or S4. There were no murmurs, clicks or rubs.
-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.
-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema.  2+ pedal pulses. Mild fullness over the dorsum of the left foot. LLE varicosities.
-BP: 130/65  




      EKG:
    SB. 52. Old Inf apical MI. No change from the prior.


Selected recent labs:


        Metabolic
Date     NA       K        CL       CO2      BUN      CRE      GLU      CA       PHOS     MG       
05/18/82 142      4.1      105      26.1     27       1.3      107      9.4                        
11/14/79                                                                         3.4               
04/21/79                                                                                  1.7      


Date     URIC     
05/18/82 6.8      
11/14/79          
04/21/79          


Lipid/Thyroid
Date     CHOL     TRIG     HDL      LDL      TSH      T3       T4       
10/08/81 133      66       53       67                                  
01/14/81                                     0.54                       
05/23/78                                              109      10.1     


Hematology
Date     HCT      WBC      PLT      
12/22/80 32.9     6.4      323      


Immunology
Date     HGBA1C   
05/18/82 6.70     




      




      Assessment and plan:
    Mrs. Vanmeter presents today stating that she continues to have some mild nighttime chest discomfort, responsive to SL TNG. Her last stress test was in January 2082 and was without ischemia with a posterobasal scar (Adeno MIBI). A recent echo in June 2081 done to evaluate increased LE edema was normal.


Problems:
      


Coronary artery disease  -  She reports an increased frequency of her nighttime CP and takes SL TNG when with good relief. Takes it about once/month. These episodes only occur at night when she is in bed.  Her echo showed preserved LV function and no significnat valvular disease.  A repeat adenosine MIBI was negative for recurrent ischemia with an inferobasal scar and LVEF 54%. I advised her to take an H2 blocker before bedtime and if symptoms don't improve, seek a workup with her PCP.


      


Hyperlipidemia  -  Her last lipid profile showed that her LDL was in range at 67, and her TG were normal! I advised her about the metabolic syndrome and the importance of careful diabetic control as well as regular exercise.  Continue her present dose of statin.


      


HTN  -  Her BP is well-controlled today. Continue her current regimen.


      


Changes to Medications this visit
      
Glucophage 500 mg   bid half a tab
lisinopril 40 mg   qd End: 6/23/2082 - Inactivated
fosinopril 40 mg   QD QTY:90 Refills:1 year Start: 11/21/2072
Norvasc 5 mg 1/2  qd half a tab
nitroglycerin 0.4 mg  sl PRN QTY:100 Refills:3 Start: 08/20/2078
Isordil 40 mg   tid
Lopressor 25 mg 1/2  bid half a tab
aspirin 81 mg   QD
acetaminophen and codeine (tylenol with codeine #3) tablets 1-2 tabs  po q 4-6 hours PRN pain QTY:100 Refills:1 Start: 04/14/2081
Pravachol 20 mg   qd
Trusopt 1 drop  od daily
Alphagan P 0.15% x 1 drop  ou bid
Tylenol 325mg x 2 tabs  po q4-6h PRN pain


Disposition:
6 months with me


      
Barbara T. Sandoval, MD pager #19360


      
cc: Dr. Bryan Edmondson
Document Status: Preliminary





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>