<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-07-05

 
 
 
 
 
 
July 05, 2074
 
 
Paul Arteaga, M.D.
Loma Linda Community Hospital
89 Caldwell Road
Shady Cove,  NY  63363
 
RE:  Christine Olivier
     MR #652-33-21-5
 
Dear Dr. Arteaga:
 
Mrs. Olivier presented to the office today for a second opinion
regarding her current cardiac condition.  As her history is well
known to you, I will repeat it briefly for our records.  Mrs.
Olivier is a 62-year-old woman with a longstanding history of
coronary artery disease.  After several catheterizations in the
2060's which failed to document significant coronary artery disease
(done for evaluation of chest pain), angiogram in July of 2071
showed moderate circumflex coronary artery disease for which she
was managed medically.  However, she suffered a non-Q wave
myocardial infarction on February of 2072 at which time she
underwent cardiac catheterization now showing progressive coronary
artery disease and therefore underwent a multi-vessel coronary
bypass graft operation including a left internal mammary artery to
her LAD and reverse saphenous vein grafts to her PDA, D1 and obtuse
marginal branch.  She underwent repeat catheterization in February
of 2073 at the Comfrey Clinic which showed diffuse native disease
but apparently no significant bypass graft pathology.  She
underwent repeat cardiac catheterization in May of 2074 because of
a current angina and at this time she had evidence for a 60%
proximal LAD stenosis, a proximal severe circumflex artery stenosis
with no occlusion at the origin at a first obtuse marginal branch
and a 70% stenosis in the mid right coronary artery.  The saphenous
vein graft to the diagonal branch was patent with a significant
stenosis at its distal and astigmatic site, a saphenous vein graft
to the second obtuse marginal branch was patent as was the
saphenous vein graft to the posterolateral branch.  The left
intramammary artery to the LAD was a small vessel without discrete
stenoses.  Left ventriculogram demonstrated a moderate area of
posterior basal akinesis with a global ejection fraction of 60%. 
She therefore was transferred to the Midwest Eire Center
in early June where she underwent successful PTCA of her vein graft
to her diagonal artery.  She tolerated this uneventfully and was 
 
 
Olivier, Christine
MR #652-33-21-5                    -2-            July 05, 2074
 
discharged and since then has not had significant exertional chest
discomfort.  Her primary complaint is one of fatigue and mild
exertional dyspnea.  She has undergone extensive pulmonary
evaluation in the past including pulmonary function tests which
have revealed an FEV1 of 1.3 which is 59% predicted, and an FVC of
1.5 which is also 55% predicted giving her a pattern consistent
with restrictive rather than obstructive pulmonary disease.  In
addition, she has a history of a seizure disorder, diabetes,
hypertension and a nonspecific peripheral neuropathy.  
 
Medications at present:  NPH insulin 60 units sub q qAM, CZI
insulin 30 units sub q qAM, NPH insulin 60 units sub q qPM, enteric
coated aspirin one tab po q.d., atenolol 50 mg po b.i.d., Captopril
25 mg po t.i.d., amlodipine 5 mg po q.d., simvastatin 10 mg po
q.d., nitroglycerin prn, Nitropatch .2 mg for twelve hours of a
twenty-four hour period, Neurontin 300 mg one tab po t.i.d.,
Trusopt one drop ou q.d., Alantin one drop ou q.h.s. and albuterol
inhalers two puffs q.i.d. prn.
 
Cigarettes - none at present.  
 
Physical exam reveals a well-nourished mildly overweight woman in
no acute distress.  Blood pressure right arm sitting 140/70, heart
rate 75 and regular, respirations 12 and unlabored, weight 172
pounds.  The neck is supple.  JVP flat.  Carotids are 2+ without
significant bruits.  Chest is clear with a trace right basilar
rhonchi.  Cardiac exam shows a normal S1, physiologically split S2
and a I-II/VI systolic ejection murmur radiating from the apex to
the base, no significant diastolic murmur or rub.  The abdomen is
benign with bowel sounds well heard.  Extremities without
appreciable edema.  Peripheral pulses are intact.  There is 1+
bipedal edema. 
 
Electrocardiogram shows sinus rhythm at a rate of 75.  PR interval
of .14, QRS .08, QT .34, axis -20 degrees.  There is evidence of a
left atrial abnormality and poor R wave progression in leads V1
through V3.  
 
Impression:  Mrs. Olivier is a 62-year-old woman with significant 
atherosclerosis, diabetes and now a chief complaint of modest
exertional dyspnea and fatigue.  She denies any active chest
discomfort and apparently her recent angioplasty was successful at
alleviating the chest pain syndrome.  The records available to me
indicate that there is no continued efforts to diminish her beta
blocker therapy however in the past this had lead to an
exacerbation of her angina.  However, now that she is status post
her PTCA it is possible she now again will tolerate beta blocker
reduction and therefore, I suggested she decrease her atenolol to
50 mg po q.d.  She will have her blood pressure checked within the
next several days and assuming she remains asymptomatic, I will
 
 
Olivier, Christine
MR #652-33-21-5                    -3-            July 05, 2074
 
also try diminishing her amlodipine in part because of peripheral
edema and in part because she may no longer need this.  Otherwise,
I have made no specific alterations to her medical regimen except
to encourage her to continue her aerobic activity level as best she
can and watch her saturated fat and cholesterol intake and stay in
close contact with you should her chest pain syndrome at all recur. 
I would be happy to assist in her management in any way you deem
appropriate.
 
Sincerely yours,
 
 
 
Irineo Tovar, M.D.
Vereen Memorial Hospital
25 Waverly St
Colorado City,  NY  88736
 
DD: 07/05/74
DT: 07/11/74
DV: 07/05/74
 
/outlaw
 
 
 
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-12-05

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
December 05, 2074
 
 
Paul Arteaga, M.D.
228 Caldwell Road
Colorado City,  NY  43414
 
RE:  Christine Olivier
     MR #652-33-21-5
 
Dear Dr. Arteaga:
 
Mrs. Olivier returns for routine follow-up.  Currently, she
complains of mild exertional fatigue and rare exertional chest
discomfort.  In addition, she states that she has no energy and
worries that her coronary artery pathology has returned.  She
reports occasionally taking sublingual nitroglycerin for chest
discomfort but this is on an infrequent basis.  
 
She remains on a plethora of medications including NPH insulin 64
units sub q qAM along with 34 units CZI sub q qAM and 68 units NPH
sub q qPM, enteric coated aspirin one tab po q.d., Captopril 25 mg
po t.i.d., Lasix 40 mg po b.i.d., simvastatin 10 mg po q.d.,
amlodipine 5 mg po q.d., Neurontin 900 mg po t.i.d., atenolol 50 mg
po q.d., estrogen 0.05 topically q three days and a nitropatch .2
mg per twenty-four hours which she wears for twelve over 
twenty-four hour period.
 
Physical exam reveals a well-nourished woman in no acute distress. 
Blood pressure right arm sitting 140/80, heart rate 85 and regular,
respirations 12 and unlabored, weight 174 pounds.  The neck is
supple.  JVP flat.  Carotids are 2+ without significant bruits. 
Chest is completely clear.  Cardiac exam shows a normal S1,
physiologically split S2 and a I-II/VI systolic ejection murmur
radiating from the apex to the base, no significant diastolic
murmur or rub.  The abdomen is benign.  Extremities without
appreciable edema.  Peripheral pulses are intact.
 
Electrocardiogram shows sinus rhythm at a rate of 85.  PR interval
of .14, QRS .08, QT .32, axis -20 degrees.  There are mild diffuse
nonspecific ST-T wave changes as well as evidence for left
ventricular hypertrophy.  Compared to her last electrocardiogram,
her heart rate is slower and her ST-T wave changes are less
prominent.
 
 
Olivier, Christine
MR #652-33-21-5               -2-            December 05, 2074
 
Impression:  Mrs. Olivier has currently recovered from her 
multi-lesion PTCA and stent placement therapy.  Currently it is not
clear to me that her symptoms are secondary to recurrent ischemia,
however I will have her undergo an exercise tolerance test
(adenosine MIBI) to help to further evaluate this.  In addition, I
will obtain routine blood studies including an glycosylated
hemoglobin.  It is certainly possible that her fatigue and
generalized sense of lack of energy is from a non-cardiac cause. 
Pending review of these lab studies however, I have not altered her
present regimen.  She will contact you or myself should her chest
pain syndrome at all progress in terms of severity or duration.  
 
Thank you very much for allowing me to assist in her care.
 
Sincerely yours,
 
 
 
Irineo Tovar, M.D.
Vereen Memorial Hospital
47 Waverly St
Colorado City,  NY  88736
 
DD: 12/05/74
DT: 12/08/74
DV: 12/05/74
 
/outlaw
 
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-10-05

                     MEC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
OLIVIER,CHRISTINE   652-33-21-5                     VISIT DATE: 10/05/75
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The resident's note was reviewed, 
and the patient seen and examined on arrival.  This is a 
65-year-old female status post multiple angioplasties and stent 
placement.  She had recurrence of her typical angina at home, took 
three nitroglycerin with minimal relief, and activated the 911 
system.  Her pre-hospital electrocardiogram shows a small amount of 
ST depression, perhaps 1 mm, and flattening V3-V6.  This is 
comparable to a previous electrocardiogram in October, which may 
have been her most recent presentation with ischemia.  She was 
given aspirin and nitroglycerin, and continued to have pain in the 
Emergency Department.  The total duration of pain was approximately 
two hours. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her vital signs remained stable. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Her initial enzymes were flat. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  She is being taken to the Cardiac 
Catheterization Laboratory for an urgent study to rule out acute 
coronary syndrome. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Rule out unstable angina. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 
taken to the Cardiac Catheterization Laboratory.  The condition at 
the time of this dictation is favorable. 
___________________________________                    FK981/1979 
RONNIE PALMER, M.D.  RP400                           D:10/05/75 
                                                       T:10/05/75 
Dictated by:  RONNIE PALMER, M.D.  RP400 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-12-11

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
December 11, 2076
 
 
Paul Arteaga, M.D.
677 Mill Street
Shady Cove, NY 43414
 
Re:  Christine Olivier
     MR #652-33-21-5
 
Dear Dr. Arteaga:
 
Mrs. Olivier returns for follow-up.  Since last seen, she reports
return in a non-exertional left shoulder discomfort syndrome,
occasionally associated with mild dyspnea.  Of note, she underwent
a dobutamine MIBI stress test last June for evaluating a similar
syndrome, and at that time she developed her typical chest and left
back pain syndrome in association with no diagnostic EKG changes at
a peak heart rate of 127, peak blood pressure of 160/60.  A
simultaneously obtained SESTA MIBI scan revealed a global left
ventricular fraction of 42%, a non-Q-wave myocardial infarction
involving 2 out of 20 segments of the inferior wall and minimal
peri-infarct ischemia.  In addition, a venous duplex ultrasound
study done to evaluate her severe left greater than right
peripheral edema showed no evidence of DVT.  
 
Currently she remains on a regimen of amlodipine 5 mg poqd,
atenolol 50 mg poqd, simvastatin 10 mg poqd, lisinopril 10 mg poqd,
Nitropatch .4 mg q.12 hours, Neurontin 400 mg potid, furosemide 40
mg poqd (recently increased), Lamactil 150 mg pobid, Trusopt and
Xalantan drops, insulin 10 units of CZI with 72 units NPH qam and
74 units NPH qpm. 
 
Physical exam reveals an overweight woman in no distress.  Blood
pressure, right arm sitting - 110/70, heart rate - 70 and regular,
respirations - 12 and unlabored, weight - 174 pounds which is four
pounds below her weight of six months ago.  The neck is supple with
JVP flat.  Carotids are 2+ without significant bruits.  Chest is
clear.  Cardiac exam shows normal S1, physiologically split S2, and
a I/VI holosystolic murmur radiating from the apex to the axilla. 
No significant diastolic murmur or rub.  The abdomen is benign. 
Extremities reveal marked left greater than right pedal edema. 
Peripheral pulses are diminished.  
 
Electrocardiogram shows sinus rhythm at a rate of 70, PR interval
of .12, QRS of .06, QT of .36, axis of -25.  There is borderline
Paul Arteaga, M.D.
December 11, 2076
Page Two
 
Re:  Christine Olivier
     MR #652-33-21-5
 
 
evidence for left ventricular hypertrophy with secondary ST and T-
wave changes.  Compared with the last electrocardiogram, there has
been no significant change. 
 
Presently, Mrs. Olivier has evidence of continuing chest and left
shoulder discomfort which she believes is similar to her pre-bypass
surgery angina.  In this setting, a dobutamine stress test
performed last June showed no evidence of provokable ischemia.  I
have spent some time discussing with Ms. Olivier our various
therapeutic and diagnostic options.  She made it quite clear that
she would not consider repeat cardiac catheterization at this time,
and furthermore, was very disinterested in pursuing the possibility
(should she require it) of either mechanical or surgical re-
vascularization.  It is not entirely clear to me that her left
shoulder syndrome is in fact ischemic in origin, and she certainly
understands it may be secondary to musculoskeletal abnormalities. 
I have suggested that she discuss that further with you.  In the
meantime, I have asked her (as her back and chest discomfort
syndrome appears to occur mostly at night prior to lying down for
bed) to apply her Nitropatch in the evening and take it off in the
morning.  She will call me within the next several days to report
how this helps her discomfort syndrome.  I do not believe that she
is having GERD to explain her symptoms.  In light of her reluctance
to undergo any further diagnostic cardiac studies, I will try to
tailor her anti-ischemic medications to minimize her chest
discomfort syndrome.  I, of course, will keep you fully informed as
to her progress, and I thank you for allowing me to assist in her
care. 
 
Sincerely yours,
 
 
Irineo Tovar, M.D.
/vuong
 
DD: 12/11/76
DT: 01/14/77
DV: 12/11/76
 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>