<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2076-08-10





BARROW MEDICAL CENTER

Johnsonville Family Clinic

4897 Governors Lane

Oroville, AL  89389



Osborne, Mattison
48423663

08/10/76



This patient is seen here in follow-up of the following medical 

problems:



PROBLEMS:  

1.	Coronary artery disease status post coronary artery bypass 

(saphenous vein) in 2072.

2.	Pulmonary embolus 2074.

3.	Idiopathic hypertension.



SUBJECTIVE:  He is entirely asymptomatic.  He has no complaint.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative.  There is no chest pain, shortness 

of breath, cough, peripheral edema, orthopnea or PND.  All the 

other review of systems is negative as well.



MEDICATIONS:  He continues on lisinopril 10 mg q.d., 

hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg q.d., atenolol 50 mg q.d., and Plavix 

75 mg q.d.



OBJECTIVE:  On examination today, the patient appears well.  He 

is cheerful and feisty.  Blood pressure 138/80 in the left arm, 

sitting.  Weight 175 pounds.  Apical pulse rate 80.  Cardiac 

rhythm is regular without murmur, gallop, rub or click.  Breath 

sounds are clear to percussion and auscultation.  No jugular 

venous distension.  No peripheral edema.



ASSESSMENT:  

1.	New York Heart Association functional class-I ISHD, status 

post CABG.

2.	Well-controlled hypertension.



PLAN:

1.	Current regimen.

2.	Please note that Lipitor was added to his regimen at his last 

visit for hypercholesterolemia.  Repeat cholesterol (which had 

been 263) is now 103.  He will continue the Lipitor as well.

3.	He is to return prior to his planned winter sojourn in the United Kingdom in December.





Oscar Nall, M.D.

ON:fairchild;11-56649670.doc;DD:08/10/76;DT:08/11/76;DV:08/10/76







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-05-10



Vital signs

BP 140/88, P 68, Wt 172 lb 

69 year old male returns with daughter and grandson for follow-up of diabetes and hypertension. he was seen here several weeks ago after a 4 month absence when he was in the UK. hgba1c and creatinine were checked at the time, and bp was to be rechecked as it was not optimally controlled. the patient returns feeling well, denies chest pain, shortness of breath, PND, orthopnea, change in exercise tolerance. he is taking medications as directed. daughter states that he saw an eye doctor in Anchorage Northeast in 11/77, had his pupils dilated, was checked for DM, was told everything was fine and he should return in 1 year

VS as noted

chest clear to ausc. RR 12

cardiac normal s1/s2 no m/s3/s4 HR 58 reg

no peripheral edema

hgba1c 6.5 (decreased from 8.9 in 11/77) creatinine stable at 1.4

Assessment - improved diabetic control. renal function stable. suboptimal bp control for diabetic with history of CAD; already bradycardic on atenolol 50 mg qd

Plan - continue current regimen with the exception of lisinopril - will increase to 20mg qd. pt has PE scheduled 5/31/78. bp recheck at that time

no ophthalmology referral was made as he appears to be up to date with eye care

N. levine, MD





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-06-14







Johnsonville Family Clinic

5388 Main Street              OSBORNE, MATTISON

Oroville, AL  89389                    48423663

(468) 429-7459                     06/14/2080





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 71-year-old male who returns to the clinic for a followup visit.  The patient has a history of diabetes mellitus and hypertension.  He also had an episode of bronchitis about 2 months ago, which was treated with antibiotics.  The patient feels improved today



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  An elderly male in no acute distress.  Blood pressure is 142/90 and pulse is 64.  Chest is clear bilaterally.  Heart:  Regular rate and rhythm.  Positive S1 and S2.  Negative S3 and S4.  No murmur.  Abdomen is soft, nontender, positive bowel sounds.  Lower extremities, no edema, nontender.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:

1.  Diabetes mellitus.  The patient reports blood sugars which have ranged from 106-158 and reports overall good control of his diabetes mellitus.  We will continue current treatment, especially in view of the fact that his most recent hemoglobin A1c in February was 6.1 and repeat hemoglobin A1c when he returns for his next visit.

2.  Hypertension.  The patient's atenolol was recently decreased from 50 mg to 25 mg because of bradycardia and lisinopril was increased to 60 mg because of microalbuminuria.  The patient's heart rate is appropriate at 64 even though his blood pressure remains borderline elevated.  We will check a microalbumin today.

4.  Recent TSH was mildly suppressed and we will repeat this today.

5.  Regular healthcare maintenance.  A CT of the patient's chest will be repeated when he returns for his next visit as recommended by radiology.





______________________________

Willie Knapp, MD











eScription document:9-3577639 HFFocus transcriptionists







DD: 06/17/80

DT: 06/17/80

DV: 06/14/80



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-08-01







OSBORNE, MATTISON

48423663

08/01/2082





Willie Knapp, M.D.

Johnson Family Vision Care

0529 Governors Lane

Oroville, AL  89389



Dear Dr. Knapp:



It was our pleasure to care for Mr. Osborne to help with his decompensated heart failure.  He was admitted on 07/23/2082, one month after previous admission for abdominal pain.  In retrospect, that admission may have been related in part to GI symptoms of heart failure.  He came in complaining of continued GI discomfort, orthopnea, lower extremity edema, and 9 pounds of weight gain with increasing abdominal girth.  His medications at the time of admission included beta-blockers and ACE inhibitors for hypertension, with no diuretics.



During his hospitalization, he underwent 7.5 kilograms of diuresis with resolution of his jugular venous pressure from approximately 25 cm to 8 cm.  His echocardiogram showed an ejection fraction of approximately 20% with LV dimension of 5.1, enlarged right ventricle with mild decrease in RV function, but severe RV pressure overload with estimated PA pressure 80 plus the right atrial pressure.  After he had his diuresis, he underwent right heart catheterization, which revealed a right atrial pressure of 8, pulmonary capillary wedge pressure of 18, PA pressure of 65/35.  He underwent a trial with IV nitroglycerin, then with sildenafil.  The IV nitroglycerin decreased his BLANK pressures only by approximately 8-10 mm but he noted a further improvement in his dyspnea.  There was no clear improvement with the sildenafil in either his symptoms or hemodynamics.  His cardiac output varied between 3.1 and 4.5 on all the medications.  The decision was just to put him on oral nitroglycerin in addition to the other standard heart failure medications.  He also underwent a MIBI looking for any evidence of active ischemia, which there was none.



At the time of discharge, he is walking easily without postural change or symptoms.  His medications are Isordil 10 t.i.d., Lasix 40 mg p.o. b.i.d.  He is on Toprol-XL 12.5 daily.  His lisinopril was decreased from 40 mg to 20 mg, but should he have any problems with hypotension, this could certainly be decreased further to 10 or even 5 mg if necessary to allow him comfortable ambulation.  He is on Plavix 75 mg daily as well and simvastatin 40.  His discharge blood pressure is 102/60, jugular venous pressure is 8-9 cm.  His creatinine is 1.3 with a BUN of 44, hematocrit 40, white blood count 5000, potassium 3.9, sodium 139.



It has been my great pleasure to participate in his care.  He is trying very hard to learn how to manage his disease at home, with the help of his family.  We have emphasized not only the salt restriction but also a fluid restriction to 2 liters a day, which includes all fluids,   We would encourage him to resume his daily exercise such as walking.  He has an appointment to see Dr. Anderson on 08/20/2081, and is looking forward to returning to your care. 



 I would be happy to answer any further questions about it.



Sincerely,





______________________________

Ursula Michael Troyer, MD











eScription document:3-8959007 IFFocus



CC: Forrest T. Anderson M.D.

23 Azalea Lane

Cardiovascular Division

Scottsville, AL 99112





DD: 08/01/82

DT: 08/01/82

DV: 08/01/82



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>