<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2071-11-20

Patient Name: LILLY, LARRY;  MRN: 2155941
Dictated on: 11/20/2071 by ANDRE-ISRAEL SANTIAGO, M.D. 

 
DIAGNOSIS:  Bilateral, right greater than left, carpal tunnel syndrome.  
 
HISTORY:  This is a first office visit for this 77-year-old, right-hand-dominant, founder of Bed Bath and Beyond, who comes for evaluation of right greater than left hand and wrist pain.  The patient reports having a longstanding history of greater than four months of worsening pain, paresthesias, and "numbness" on the right worse than left hand.  This is worse at night and does occasionally wake him up from sleep.  Also bothers him during prolonged activity.  He also reports recently over the past few months noting difficulty with the key pinch, grasp, and fine motor function.  Previous evaluation consisted of cervical spine MRI as well as EMG nerve conduction studies demonstrating findings significant for severe compression neuropathy of the median nerve at the level of wrist.  He now comes for evaluation for potential carpal tunnel surgery release.   
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Glucose intolerance, history of previous CVA, status post CABG, hypertension, GER.   
MEDICATIONS:  Lopressor, Zocor, Ecotrin, Effexor, and Nexium.  
 
ALLERGIES:  None.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On examination today, he is very pleasant, well appearing in no apparent distress.  
Examination of the right hand demonstrates marked thenar atrophy.  There is no active abductor pollicis brevis and 
very weak opponens.  He has a positive Tinel's, positive Phalen's, and positive median nerve compression test at the wrist.  His interossei and extensors are full.  Sensation is intact throughout.  
 
EMG studies from 11/09/2071, performed here at Folsom Convalescent Hospital, significant for right worse than left median nerve compression neuropathy at the wrists.   
IMPRESSION:  The patient is seen and examined with Dr. Santiago.  At this time, we feel that Larry has indeed a significant, right worse than left, bilateral carpal tunnel syndrome.  Given the amount of weakness and thenar wasting, he has difficulty with abductor pollicis, we have recommended proceeding with both carpal tunnel release as well as 
possible FTS of ring finger to thumb tendon transfer.  We discussed with Larry the risks and benefits of this procedure and he is in agreement of the plan.  We will try to schedule him to proceed with surgery at some point in the near future.  We filled out both history and physical, as well as a surgical consent form today in the office.   
__________________________ 
Andre-Israel Santiago, M.D.  
 
CC:  
Stephen Mccullough, M.D.  
Folsom Convalescent 
Dictated by: _____ 
 
DD:11/20/2071 
DT:11/22/2071 
CH:18306     :0077 
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-04-02





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

FOLSOM CONVALESCENT HOSPITAL



Reason for visit   Annual examination.



History of present illness   The patient has done very well over the last year.  He has maintained his weight, which has been quite difficult given the social commitments that he has.  He is requiring to eat out quite a bit.  He has also done a large amount of traveling over the last three to four months.  This caused him to be more exhausted than usual.  His incarcerated hernia repair has stood up.  He has some discomfort occasionally in that area, but for the most part feels that this is back to normal.  He is careful with his diet as much as he can be.  He had a cold over the last month or so.  It slowly resolved.  He is asymptomatic presently.



Major Problems

Hypertension



Hyperlipidemia



Glucose intolerance





Change in therapies and Renewals

Nexium 20 mg PO QD Refills:2 total of 90

Toprol XL 50 mg PO QD Refills:2 total of 90

Effexor 75 mg PO QD Refills:2 total of 90

Ecotrin 325 mg PO QD Refills:3

Zocor 10 mg PO QD Refills:3 90

vitamin e   

vitamin c   

calcium supplement   

flaxseed oil   

metformin hydrochloride 500 mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 4/2/2073 take with meals



Procedures

Coronary artery bypass  STATUS POST.

Hernia repair  Incarcerated Hernia repair.. STATUS POST.



Social history   Still active in business.  He is Treasurer for the Masons.  Does not smoke.  Drinks a few glasses of wine or Martini at night.  He has 10 grandchildren.



Review of systems   Recent night sweats, chronic tinnitus, leg cramps on walking, no GI or urinary problems, and notes some easy bruising.



Physical examination

Pulse   72 and regular

Blood pressure 120/70  

General appearance   Well appearing

Heent   Oropharynx clear

Neck   Carotids, no bruits.  Thyroid, nonpalpable

Chest   Clear

Cor   RRR

Abdomen   Benign

Rectal exam   Guaiac negative.  Prostate, slightly enlarged

Genitalia   Genitalia, within normal

Extrem   Within normal limits.  Pulses intact.  He has fungal infections of his nails on his 

feet

Musc skel   There is some bruising of his left deltoid



Assessment and plan   The patient is generally doing well.  His cardiac risk management is doing fine.  His blood pressure is in good control.  His recent cholesterol profile is excellent.  He has slightly elevated fasting blood sugars.  We discussed options including diet and exercise which I think he has been very good on.  Discussed starting metformin based on recent data that this may help prevent his development of diabetes.  We will begin metformin 500 mg PO QD.  We will check his renal and liver function in one week and his bruising is likely due to his aspirin.  We need to follow up on a renal ultrasound for cysts that were discovered during his hernia operation, and I will make these arrangements.  The patient is to return to clinic in three months     Coronary artery diseas



Selected recent labs   We reviewed his laboratories.  These were done earlier in the week.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by   Stephen  Mccullough   on  Apr 09, 2073     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-07-07





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

FOLSOM CONVALESCENT HOSPITAL



Reason for visit

			

  Annual Examination



History of present illness

			

  Feeling great. Weight gain. Spinal stenosis still aggravating and limiting. Groin rash.  Recenrt examination by Dr. Delarosa (all well).



Problem List (reviewed)



Hyperlipidemia MAJOR 

Anemia MAJOR 

Coronary artery disease MAJOR 

Stroke MAJOR 

Dizziness MAJOR 

Hypertension MAJOR 

Impotence MAJOR 

Benign prostatic hypertrophy MAJOR 

Glucose intolerance MAJOR 

Radiculopathy MAJOR 

Hematuria MAJOR 

Spinal stenosis MAJOR 

Squamous cell carcinoma of skin 

Overweight 

Diabetes mellitus (adult onset) 

Tinea cruris 



Major Problems





Hyperlipidemia

LDL still > 70 may need more statin 10/1/73



Anemia

Dr. Vitale colonoscopy at Parker Hospital 1/2069 results?



Coronary artery disease

s/p bypass 5 vessel 6/16/2069

Dr. Delarosa and Dr. Land



Stroke





Dizziness

resolved off Altace



Hypertension





Impotence

No erections for two years. Thinking about Viagra. Asked Dr. Delarosa in June 2070 who advised against use.



Benign prostatic hypertrophy

s/p TURP X 2 ( In PH)



Glucose intolerance





Radiculopathy

New symptom. Decreased sensation at finger tips - 2nd,3rd, and 4th digits. Also notes suble weakness with change in handwriting. 8/29/71 Carpal tunnel per EMG/NCS 1/3/72



Hematuria

Negative work up by Dr. Villalobos (cystoscopy , CT) 2073



Spinal stenosis

Feels legs are heavy. No pain. Upright position.



Other Problems





Squamous cell carcinoma of skin





Overweight





Diabetes mellitus (adult onset)





Tinea cruris





Active Medications



calcium supplement 

Ecotrin 325 mg PO QD

Effexor 75 mg PO QD total of 90

erythromycin (ilotycin) ointment 2 tubes apply bid

flaxseed oil 

folic acid 

metformin hydrochloride 850 mg po bid take with meals

Nexium 20 mg PO QD total of 90

Toprol xl 50 mg PO QD total of 90

vitamin c 

vitamin e 

Zocor 40mg po qpm



Family history

			

			



Social history

			

  Still active in business.  He is Treasurer for the Masons.  Does not smoke. Drinks a few glasses of wine or Martini at night.  He has 10 grandchildren.



Habits/Risk Screening

Smoking status: never smoked  

Alcohol use status: moderate  

Activity level: moderate  



Review of systems

			

  Leg cramps. Early fatigue.  No chest pain, SOB, GI or GU issues



Physical examination

Blood pressure 140/80  

Pulse   72 and regular

Respiratory rate 16  

Weight 185  

General appearance   Well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.

Skin   groin rash

Heent   NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, O/P clear without erythema or exudates.

Neck   Carotids, no bruits.  Thyroid, nonpalpable

Nodes   No cervical, axillary or groin adenopathy appreciated.

Chest   Clear to auscultation bilaterally. scar

Cor   PMI at 5th ICS, MCL. RRR nl s1, s2 without m/r/g.

Abdomen   NT/ND, no HSM. Normal active bowel sounds.

Rectal exam   Guaiac negative.  Prostate, slightly enlarged

Genitalia   Genitalia, within normal

Extrem   Within normal limits.  Pulses intact.  He has fungal infections of his nails on his  feet

Musc skel   Stands, walks , squats w/o difficulty. pulses intact strength intact. DTRs intact



Assessment and plan

			

  Severe spinal stenosis. CAD/CABG stable. Lipid, BS, BP managed. Tinea start ketoconazole. BPH. Weight issues.  H/o SCC.



Disposition

rtc 3 months 



Signed electronically by Mccullough, Stephen N on Jul 07, 2075     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-12-14



	CARDIOLOGY

	

	FOLSOM CONVALESCENT HOSPITAL

	



	Interval History:

   Mr.  Lilly is now 81 years old and it has been six and half years since his coronary bypass procedure.  Since I saw him last six months ago, he has generally done well.  He has not had any angina.  No dyspnea, orthopnea, lightheadedness, dizziness, palpitations, or syncope.  He has reduced his exercise to three days a week-he exercises vigorously when he does exercise, but this seems to give him a little bit more in the way of stamina.



	Past medical history:

   Noncontributory.



Current Medications:

  Nexium 40 mg BID

 Ecotrin 325 mg qd

 Toprol XL 50 mg qd

 Effexor 75 mg qam; Dir: and 37.5 mg qpm

 metformin hydrochloride 850 mg BID

 Zocor 40 mg; Dir: 4 days a week and 80 mg 3 days a week

 ranitidine HCl 300 mg qhs

 flaxseed oil; Dir: Gel

 vitamin b12 1 mg qd

 vitamin c

 Omega 1 tab tid; Dir: 3 fatty acids



	Family history:

   Noncontributory.



	Social history:

   He has four children and 10 grandchildren.  He just returned to Tunisia to visit family.  He does not smoke.  Minimal alcohol.  His wife recently had quite a bad fall.



	Review of systems:

   Weight is stable.  No GI problems.  Otherwise negative.



Physical examination:

	

-Pulse:   60

-BP: 145/70    140-145/70

-resp. rate:   16

-General:   He looks great

-Neck:   The jugular venous pressure was less than 5.  No carotid bruits.  No palpable lymph nodes

-Chest:   The lungs were clear to percussion and auscultation

-Cardiac:   Showed an S4.  Normal S1.  No murmurs

-Abdomen:   Liver and spleen are not enlarged

-Extremities:   Good femoral, popliteal, and pedal pulses



	EKG:

    shows first-degree AV bock and minor ST and T changes.  No change from July 2075.



	Assessment and plan:

   Mr.  Lilly is generally doing well.  His blood pressure is a little higher than it usually is in the office today, and we probably should have him on ACE inhibitor with his mild diabetes.  On the other hand, he is a little worked up over his wife's injury, and we will monitor his pressure.  For now, we will sit tight.  He will have a full battery of chemistries tomorrow-he sees Dr.  Mccullough, so far so good with respect to his cardiac sinus.  



Plan: Monitor blood pressure.  Low threshold for starting an ACE inhibitor.  Chemistries tomorrow.  See again in six months.



Changes to Medications this visit

	

Nexium 40 mg   BID

Ecotrin 325 mg   qd

Toprol XL 50 mg   qd

Effexor 75 mg   qam and 37.5 mg qpm

metformin hydrochloride 850 mg   BID

Zocor 40 mg    4 days a week and 80 mg 3 days a week

ranitidine HCl 300 mg   qhs

flaxseed oil     Gel

vitamin b12 1 mg   qd

vitamin c    

Omega  1 tab  tid 3 fatty acidsCC:

	Stephen N Mccullough M.D.

	



	Signed electronically by   Michael  Delarosa MD  on  Dec 15, 2075     





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>