<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2069-09-17


  
                        OFFICE NOTE
  
  Andrew Conner
  MRN: 9911852
  September 17, 2069 
  
  
  Problems:
  1.  Diabetes mellitus.  He continues on Glucotrol and
  Glucophage.  Blood sugars appear to be in pretty good range. 
  Last A1C was respectable.  To be repeated today.
  2.  Hyperlipidemia.  Lipids are pending.
  3.  Angina.  Previous stress test showed positive EKG
  changes, equivocal scan.  Mild angina.  Started on trans-
  derm nitro.  Totally must quit all cigars.  Lipids to be
  repeated.
  4.  Hypertension.  On captopril, atenolol and trans-derm
  nitro.  Blood pressure _____/70, pulse 60 and regular, COR
  normal.  
  Impression:  Good control.
  5.  Weight.  His weight is 192, should be 175.  Discussed. 
  Overall, he has got things he can do to improve, and these
  were all discussed in detail with the patient and his wife.
  
  
  
  Brandon Walls, M.D.
  
  Dictated/Not read
  
  BW/yamamoto
  
  



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2071-05-18



                        OFFICE NOTE

Conner, Andrew
MR #9911852
May 18, 2071

Andy comes in for followup of hospitalization on May 6, for coronary artery disease and he had
increasing angina pectoris leading to catheterization.  He underwent angioplasty of the
circumflex vessels and then angioplasty and stenting of the first diagonal branch to the LAD. 
The latter one was done in the second setting and part of the study where the ____ the stent
versus a plain stent.  This was done by Dr. Winn, and Dr. Cook.  Since then he has been
tired, otherwise felt well.  He had reasonable lipids but low HDL syndrome.  His blood sugars
have been controlled recently with A1C's in the 6 range.  He is overweight and does not do any
regular exercise program.  He is on        for arthritis.  

His current medications consist of aspirin 325 mg per day, Plavix 75 mg per day, Glucatrol 10
mg twice daily and Glucophage 500 mg twice daily, Atenolol 25 mg daily, Nexium 20 mg per
day, Flomax .4 and Zestril. He feels well.  He is a little fatigued.  No obvious angina.  His blood
pressure is running 110/70, his pulse is running 60 and regular.  JVP is normal. Carotids are
normal.  The lungs are clear.  Coronary:  S3.

IMPRESSION:  Doing well.  I think he should probably be on Lipitor even though he is on low
lipids and I also think that he would benefit from cardiac rehabilitation. He will also pay close
attention to diabetes and he is prepared to move on with insulin.



Brandon Walls, M.D.

Dictated/Not Read

BW/yen


    



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-12-14

CARDIOLOGY

COLLINGSWORTH GENERAL HOSPITAL



Current Medications:



			



Changes to Medications this visit

Ecotrin 325 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073

Plavix 75mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073

Glucotrol tablets 20 mg   BID QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073

Glucophage 1000 mg  po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073 take with meals

Actos 15mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073

atenolol 50mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073

Protonix 40 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073 do not cut/crush/chew

lisinopril 20 mg  po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073

lorazepam 0.5mg  po  QHS QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/14/2073



Signed electronically by   Xavier V Cook MD  on  Dec 20, 2073     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-10-08



	CARDIOLOGY

	

	COLLINGSWORTH GENERAL HOSPITAL

	



	Reason for visit:

   Pt is seen @ r/o Dr Quintana in ER obs unit - in o/n with chest pain



	Interval History:

   He has had angioplasty of the circumflex vessel and angioplasty and stenting of a diagonal branch of his LAD, both in May 2071. A relook in February 2072 revealed that the stent was patent.



His sx with original stenting were chest presure and burning



He has now come to ER with brief unprovoked stabs of L high lateral point pain w no associated sx occurring repeatedly over several hours w NO other relevant hx. The pain seemed to improve with local massage







	Family history:

   He has one sister living in St. John's who has diabetes. Both his parents had diabetes as well. They are both deceased



	Social history:

   He is now fully retired from quarrying. He is married and lives with his wife.  



Physical examination:

	

-resp. rate: 16  

-General:   No acute distress.

-Skin:   No rashes, anicteric.

-Heent:   Unremarkable

-Neck:   Carotids 2+ without bruits. JVP no jugular venous distention.

-Chest:   Clear to auscultation and percussion.

-Cardiac:   Left ventricular impulse discrete and nondisplaced. Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2, with no S3 or S4. There was a 2/6 systolic murmur of MR

-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.

-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. 2+ femoral pulses without bruits. 2+ pedal pulses.

-BP: 130/75  



	EKG:

   NSR and WNL



Selected recent labs:

	 Cardiac enzymes

Date     CK       CK-MB    CKMBRI   TROP-I   TROP-T   

10/08/74 63       2.3                        <0.01    

10/07/74                            NEGATIVE          





	



	Assessment and plan:

   He has presented with very atypical chest pain with negative markers and unchanged ECG. Thjis is chest wall pain - not cardiac. It is clearly - in pt's view and mine - different from the pain of his CAD. He is OK to go home with dx of chest wall pain. OK to use Ibuprofen prn - should be ok in low dose on full stomach despite his h/o dyspepsia. F/u w Dr Cook.



	Signed electronically by   Bob D Kirkpatrick MD  on  Oct 8, 2074     





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>