<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2079-07-28

                     MIDLAND EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

NOONAN,FRANKIE   516-39-35-7                    VISIT DATE: 07/28/79

The patient was interviewed and examined by myself along with the 

resident, Dr. Welsh.  Please see his note for full details. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  In brief, a 60 year-old male 

complaining of shortness of breath.  Ran out of his Lasix about 5-6 

days ago and now is with increasing lower extremity edema, 

orthopnea, PND.  Denies fever, chills, nausea or vomiting.  Sent 

here for evaluation by his PCP today. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  No palpitations, no diaphoresis. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus, 

hypertension, coronary artery disease, and atrial fibrillation. 

MEDICATIONS:  Insulin, Glucophage, Verapamil, Lasix, Relafen, and 

Coumadin. 

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Does not drink, does not smoke. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Blood pressure 136/88, O2 

saturation 95 percent, heart rate 54, temperature 97.8.  GENERAL: 

Well-developed, well-nourished male in no apparent distress, 

denying chest pain at this time.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, 

atraumatic.  Pupils were equal, round and reactive to light. 

Extraocular muscles full.  NECK:  No evidence of jugular venous 

distension.  Supple.  LUNGS:  Clear to auscultation.  HEART: 

Regular rate and rhythm.  Normal S1 and S2.  No murmurs, rubs or 

gallops.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, non-tender and non-distended.  Active 

bowel sounds.  EXTREMITIES:  3+ pedal edema.  NEUROLOGIC:  Cranial 

nerves II-XII grossly intact.  Alert and oriented times three. 

Motor 5/5.  Sensation intact to light touch throughout. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Basic labs included a white count of 6.9, 

hematocrit 39, BUN and creatinine of 10 and 1.0, with a potassium 

of 5.7.  CK was 186, troponin 0.04.  Amylase was 61.  Blood sugar 

was 253.  Chest x-ray showed cardiomegaly.  EKG showed atrial 

fibrillation at about 50.  Nonspecific ST-T wave changes. 

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Differential of his shortness of 

breath includes congestive heart failure, ischemia.  He was 

admitted to the hospital for training of his congestive heart 

failure regimen.  His primary M.D. was notified. 

FINAL DIAGNOSIS: 

1.  Shortness of breath. 

2.  Congestive heart failure. 

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  He was admitted 

in stable condition. 

___________________________________                    CQ102/93848

ROSE R. WALSH, M.D.     RW88                      D:09/04/79 

                                                       T:09/05/79 

Dictated by:  ROSE R. WALSH, M.D.     RW88 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-10-02


Spanish
69 Sheffield Road                                        NOONAN, FRANCE
Burkburnett, NE 97618                                      51639357
(842) 544-2703                                           10/02/81


CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Mr. Noonan is a 69-year-old man who has type
II insulin-requiring diabetes, obesity, hypertension,
dyslipidemia, chronic atrial fibrillation, degenerative
osteoarthritis and diabetic neuropathy.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  He comes today complaining of one
week with mild chest pain not irradiated to the head, to jaw or
the arm, but with very mild shortness of breath.  He denies
nausea, vomiting or sweatiness.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Protonix 40 mg p.o. b.i.d., verapamil SR
190 mg q.d., Lasix 20 mg p.o. q.d., Neurontin 900 mg in the
morning 900 mg at noon and 300 mg at night, Lipitor 10 mg q.d.,
Zestril 10 mg q.d., Glucophage 1000 mg twice a day, and 75/25
insulin 40 units in the morning and 40 in the evening, Tylenol
with Codeine p.r.n. for severe pain and Coumadin 3 mg alternating
with 4.5 mg.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The blood pressure today is 120/88 and his
weight is 256 pounds.  The examination of the neck with no lymph
nodes.  He is oriented and in no acute distress.  The cardiac
examination with arrhythmia consistent with atrial fibrillation. 
The lungs with hypoventilation in both bases and no evidence of
acute congestive heart failure.  He has edema that has been
chronic in both extremities.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  Review of an EKG obtained in August of this
year showed atrial fibrillation with premature ventricular or
apparently conducted complexes, nonspecific T-wave abnormality
probably digitalis effect, abnormal EKG that when compared to the
one in June showed nonspecific T-wave abnormalities that were not
evident at that time and now present in anterior leads.

I have talked to people in the emergency department and he is
being sent right now for an evaluation of possible angina.


______________________________
DANNY WOODY, M.D.

eScription document:0-567955
DD: 10/02/81
DT: 10/03/81
DV: 10/02/81



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-10-01

EDVISIT^51639357^Noonan, France^10/01/82^ELROD, RYLEY

This patient was seen on 10/01/2082 with the resident, Dr.

Jacob.  Please see her note for details.  The resident's

history and physical examination were reviewed and confirmed. 

Please see her note for details.  The plan of care and

disposition of the patient were discussed with the resident.

IMPRESSION:  This is a 70-year-old male who presents with two

weeks of back pain radiating from the mid back to the chest.  He

also has pain in his left leg up to his flank.  He also has some

scrotal swelling and lower abdominal pain.  The pain has been

intermittent and the patient has been taking Vicodin for the past

two days.  The pain that he has been having is actually chronic,

except for the left-sided flank pain and the chest pain.  He was

found on the ground by his daughter, and it was unclear to the

patient how he ended up in that position.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for myocardial infarction,

atrial fibrillation, diabetes, cerebrovascular accident, low back

pain, sciatica, Bell palsy, reflux, osteochondritis, peripheral

vascular disease, and diabetic neuropathy.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is afebrile, heart rate 80,

respirations 16, blood pressure 126/82, and oxygen saturation is

100%.  He is in severe distress.  His lung exam is normal.  His

cardiac examination shows no abnormality.  His abdomen is

distended, and there is tenderness to palpation in the left lower

quadrant, and there is CVA tenderness in the left flank.  There

is also significant pain on movement of his left leg either

passively or actively.  It is not possible for us to evaluate the

strength in his left hip or knee because of pain.  He is alert

and oriented to person, place, time, and event.  His cranial

nerves are intact.  Rectal examination shows mildly decreased

sphincter tone, but no evidence of saddle anesthesia.

LABORATORY STUDIES:  Show a CK of 128 with MB fraction of 3.8,

and troponin I is less than assay.  INR is 2.8.  UA shows 0 to 1

white blood cells and 1 to 2 red blood cells.  Electrocardiogram

shows atrial fibrillation with bradycardic rate of 47.  His head

CT shows no abnormality.  There is stranding around his left

kidney.  The aorta appears normal.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient was given an aspirin

325 mg p.o. and morphine 4 mg IV for pain.  His pain improved

significantly.  However, he had another recurrence of the pain

and with rising discomfort.  It was decided to admit the patient

to the hospital for management of his pain and further workup to

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

markedly bradycardic.

______________________________

ELROD, RYLEY M.D.

D: 10/23/82

T: 10/23/82

Dictated By: ELROD, RYLEY

eScription document:8-9823511 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-07-25

EDVISIT^51639357^NOONAN, FRANCE^07/25/85^ELROD, RYLEY

This patient was seen with Dr. Ussery.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 73-year-old male with a

history of cough and pleuritic type chest pain.  The patient

denies any nausea or vomiting.  He does have history of MI as

well as multiple risk factors for coronary artery disease.  He

also reports lower extremities swelling worse than usual, and has

left greater than right edema at baseline due to a reconstructive

surgery following motor vehicle collision.  Of note, the

patient's medications include Coumadin, which he is on for atrial

fibrillation.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is awake, alert, and in no

distress.  His vital signs show heart rate of 70, respiratory

rate of 24, blood pressure 112/72, and oxygen saturation 96% on

room air and 98% on 2 liters.  His lungs are clear and heart is

irregularly irregular.  This is somewhat limited due to body

habitus.  The abdomen is soft and there is a chronic left upper

quadrant tenderness.  The back shows left CVA tenderness.

LABORATORY DATA:  The laboratory analysis shows a hematocrit of

42.1 and a white blood cell count of 7.6.  Cardiac biomarkers are

negative, and the troponin is less than 0.1.  A d-dimer is less

than 200.  The INR is 1.7.  UA is pending.  ECG shows an atrial

fibrillation with some nonspecific T-wave changes in leads V3

through V6.

IMAGING STUDIES:  A chest radiograph was a markedly limited due

to patient's habitus.

DECISION MAKING AND EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  There was no

clear etiology to the patient's shortness of breath.  Given his

anticoagulation and a negative d-dimer, we feel that this is

unlikely to be PE.  It is clearly possible to be cardiac, given

the history of coronary artery disease and a slightly abnormal

electrocardiogram.  This may be pneumonia, and the chest x-ray is

not terribly helpful.  We are obtaining a CT scan of the chest

without IV contrast to better delineate the pulmonary

architecture, and are admitting the patient to the Medicine

Service for monitoring and cycling of enzymes and ECGs.

DIAGNOSES:

1.  Shortness of breath.

2.  T-wave inversions on electrocardiogram.

______________________________

ELROD, RYLEY M.D.

D: 07/25/85

T: 07/25/85

Dictated By: ELROD, RYLEY

eScription document:5-9812947 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-11-29

LCFMC D Housestaff Admission Note
Intern: Woods
Att:Ball




CC: 

Dyspnea/Chest pain


HPI: 76 year old Spanish speaking male with numerous medical problems (IDDM, Afib, HTN, PVD, Cr baseline 1.7, no prior HF,, normal echo 2085, normal MIBI 2085) who was just dishcharged 28 days ago for LE edema admission, who complains of 3 weeks of sore throat. He states that because of this he has suffered from a gradual dyspnea, complicated by orthopnea and PND for two days.  He states he has left sided pleuritic chest pain worse with inspiration.  He states he also has noticed increased baseline LE edema for 2 weeks, but denies and increase in abdominal girth.  He states he decided to seek medical treatment for his gradual onset shortness of breath.


The patient states he has been taking all of his medications and has not increased the sodium in his diet recently.  He denies fever, chills, dysuria, asymettric leg swelling, or any palpable blood vessels in his legs.


Of note the patient is on 80 mg BID of lasix for his LE edema though his most recent echo, 2085, shows a normal EF and the patient has no history of CHF.


Ed Course: Routine labs and blood cultures were drawn.


ROS:  As above


PMH:

chronic LE ulcers AF on Coumadingout - currently no symptomsDMHTN OSAPVD CRI, bl cr=1.8Hypercholesterolemia


MEDS: patient doesnt know, from last DC summary

1. WARFARIN SODIUM   4 MG PO  QPM  2.  ACETAMINOPHEN   650 MG PO  Q4H     PRN Pain3.  ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID   325 MG PO  DAILY  4.  DOCUSATE SODIUM   100 MG PO  BID  5.  FLUTICASONE PROP/SALMETEROL 250/50   1 INHALATION INH  BID  6.  FUROSEMIDE   80 MG PO  BID  7.  GABAPENTIN   300 MG PO  TID  8.  INSULIN ASPART   Sliding Scale (subcutaneously) SC  AC+HS  9.  INSULIN NPH HUMAN   50 UNITS SC  BID  10. IPRATROPIUM AND ALBUTEROL SULFATE   2 PUFF INH  QID  11. LORATADINE   10 MG PO  DAILY  12. METOPROLOL TARTRATE   25 MG PO  BID  13. MUPIROCIN   TOPICAL TP  BID  14. NORTRIPTYLINE HCL   25 MG PO  BEDTIME  15. PROTONIX  (PANTOPRAZOLE)   40 MG PO  BID  16. POLYETHYLENE GLYCOL    17 GM PO  DAILY  17. SENNOSIDES   8.6 MG PO  BID  18. SIMVASTATIN   20 MG PO  BEDTIME  19. SPIRONOLACTONE   25 MG PO  BID  20. ALISKIREN   150 MG PO  DAILY  
ALL: NKDA


SH:Born in Paraguay. Wife died of colon cancer. Used to work in publishing, now retired. No smoking, rarely drinks EtOH. Occasionally smokes marijuana for pain relief.  Now lives w son. 



FH:Mother and brother with DM. Brother with MI 



PE: VS: T^ 96.4 P 69, P 114/62 RR 18 90% RA
General: well appearing, NAD
HEENT: Eyes: PERRLA, EOMI
Neck: very obese neck with no visible JVD
Lungs: CTA b/l, no rales/rhonchi/wheezes
Heart: RRR, 2/6 SM at LUSB
Abdomen: obese, soft, ND/NT, +BS, no hepatosplenomegaly
Extremities: 2+ radial/DP pulses, his lower extremities are wrapped in ace bandages and when unwrapped show signs of chronic venous stasis with no sign of active infection


LABS:
Results11/29/2088 NA 133 (*),  K 4.5,  CL 94 (*),  CO2 29,  BUN 72 (*#),  CRE 2.75 baseline 1.7 (*#),  EGFR 23 [1],  GLU 194 (*#)[1] RESULT COMMENT: (Abnormal if &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2If patient is black, multiply by 1.21)11/29/2088 ANION 1011/25/2088 GLU-POC 340 (*)11/29/2088 CA 9.6,  PHOS 3.8,  MG 2.6,  TBILI 0.4,  TP 8.3,  ALB 3.8,  GLOB 4.5 (*)11/29/2088 ALT/SGPT 15,  AST/SGOT 17,  ALKP 103,  TBILI 0.411/29/2088 CK 165,  CK-MB 5.0,  TROP-T 0.03 (*), Troponin I always less than assay in past11/29/2088 WBC 8.68,  RBC 4.86,  HGB 15.2 (#),  HCT 45.1,  MCV 92.8,  MCH 31.3,  MCHC 33.8 (#),  PLT 18911/29/2088 RDW 14.311/29/2088 %POLY-A 62.4,  %LYMPH-A 31.1,  %MONO-A 5.2,  %EOS-A 0.9,  %BASO-A 0.411/29/2088 ANEUT-A 5.42,  ALYMP-A 2.69,  AMONO-A 0.45,  AEOS-A 0.08,  ABASO-A 0.0311/29/2088 PT 18.7 (*),  PT-INR 1.5 (*),  PTT 35.711/25/2088 PT 20.5 (*#) [1],  PT-INR 1.7 (*),  PTT 36.2 (#)[1] RESULT COMMENT: VERIFIED11/29/2088 proBNP 210


STUDIES:
11/29 EKG: Afib, rate 66, no ST changes


11/29 CXR:  IMPRESSIONS: Lingula opacity may represent pneumonia and/or     effusion. No effusion on Lateral view.     



9/13/85 Echo: Left Ventricle: Overall left ventricular function is normal. The estimatedejection fraction is 60%. There are no regional wall motion abnormalities.

2085 Cardiac MIBI: In summary, the test results were:     1.  Clinical Response:  Non-ischemic.     2.  ECG Response:  No ECG changes during infusion.     3.  Myocardial Perfusion:  Normal.     4.  Global LV Function:  Normal.



A/P: 76 yo male with PVD, COPD, LE edema, DM, comes in pan-pos ROS and chest pain/dyspnea x2-3d. Doing well until 3wks ago and then got sore throat. Chest pain/SOB started 2d ago. 
#) Chest Pain: nl echo in 2085; nl MIBI '06; symptoms w/inspiration not exertion; troponin up, MB flat, EKG w/out change; ? PE; ?Bornholm; pleuritis more likely-trend cardiac markers-Echo in AM*#) Acute/Chronic Renal Failure: ? from aggressive diuresis; spironolactone; s. poor forawrd flow-hold spriro/lasix/aliskiren-Echo in AM as above-renally dose all meds-gentle IVF over night*#) SOB: ?pnd; ?orthopnea: BNP nl, does not appear in any resp discomfort; cxr w/?pna but no other clincal sx-start levo 750mg q48hr-f/u echo
- will obtain non-con chest CT for better visualization*#) DM, type II: poorly controlled at home-NPH 50unit BID + SSI-diabetic diet*#) LE edema/Ulcers: looks good- cont wraps; wound care*#) HTN: on aliskiren/aldactone/metop- holding aliskiren/aldactone*#) FEN/PPx-heparin SC q8hr; renal diet; dM diet; coumadin;


Code: Full Code
HCP:NOONAN, WENDY
, child, 424-995-4624 





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="not met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>