<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2063-11-28

HPI

51 yo F with MMP comes to establish primary care as she is unhappy with the cre she is geting at CityMemorial. She was 40 mislate to her appt and time was limited. She has multiple medical problems for which she is on a variety of medications, none o which she has taken x1 month as she ran out of refills.



1. CVA-She reports 3-4 mos ago she had a stroke (she was told there was a clot in her brain) which left the L side of her face paralyzed and some residual weakness in her LUE. She also notes her handwriting has completely changed since. Since the stroke she has had multiple episodes during which her tongue becomes very heavy and she has difficulty speaking (distinctly different from her now mildly imapired baseline) At these times she feel somewhat confused and her L vison seems blurry. This has happened 4-5 times and lasts all day. er family has encouraged her to seek medical care but she has refused bc she did not think they would do antyhing for her. Of note, pt has not been on ASA as it was d/cd when she changed to celebrex. Pt also c/o memory loss that started even before the CVA.



2. CAD-She reports a h/o multiple MIs, incl cardiac cath x2, unknown if she had intevention, she thinks the last was about 1 yr ago. She has stable 3 pillow orthopnea. She becomes SOB when she climbs 5 steps and gets SOB sometimes when she walks, which resolves ith rest, but she is able to walk a fair amt still (cannot pin down how much).  She denies CP with exertion, did have CP with her MIs. She says smx she has lower and upper extremity edema. She has not had a recent ETT.



3. DM-Pt has been on glucophage and Humulin 70/30 100U in am and 60 in pm, but has not been monitoring her BS or taking insulin for the past month. She has all the necessary equipment. She says she tries o monior her carb intake. She has been gaining weight, bout 5 lbs in the past 2 mos, and notes polydypsia and polyuria fo the past 2 weeks.



4. HTN-has not been taking Zestoretic or Atenolol x1 mo



5. Depression-Pt has h/o depression for which she has been medicated in the past. She currently feels she has very depressed mood, apathy, trouble sleeping and with memory tasks. She denies SI/HI/AH.



6. In terms of health maintenance, her last PAP was 2 yrs ago as was her last Mammo. Her last HgA1C is fr 199 as are her lipids.



PMH

HTN 

IRDM 

CAD 

HX OF GASTRITIS BY UGIS H PYLORI + 

S/P TAH 2/2 FIBROIDS 

Depression

CVA



MEDS

ATENOLOL 50 MG PO QD x 30 day(s)

Azmacort Inh 5 PUFF AER BID x 30 day(s)

Insulin 70/30 (HUMAN) 50 U SC QAM x 30 day(s)

GLUCOPHAGE 500 MG PO BID x 30 day(s)

Claritin D 10 MG PO QD x 30 day(s)

LIPITOR 40 MG PO QD x 30 day(s)

CELEBREX 100 MG PO QD x 30 day(s)

Humulin 70/30 30 UNITS qpm x 30 day(s)

Zestoretic (LISINOPRIL/HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 20-12.5, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 30 day(s)

Ranitidine Hcl 150MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID x 30 day(s)

Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 30 day



ALLERGIES   NKDA 



FAMILY HISTORY 

Defered



SOCIAL HISTORY

Currrently unemployed

Sexual History: defered

ETOH/Drugs/Tab:denies. Quit tab 20 yrs ago

Nutrition: tries to eat low carb diet

Exercise: walking



PHYSICAL EXAM

VS: BP 172/100  HR 84  Wt 166 lbs  FS 347

General: Pleasant in NAD, facial asymmetry

HEENT: PERRL. EOMI. Oropharynx clear. TMs intact. Fundi could not be visualized.

Neck: No JVD. No thyromegaly. No LAD. No carotid bruits.

Cor: RRR, nl S1S2, 2/6 sys M at LUSB

Lungs: CTA b/l, no rales, rhonchi or wheezes

Abd: Soft, NTND. Normal active bowel sounds. No hepatosplenomegaly.

Breast/GYN: defered.

Ext: No clubbing, cyanosis or edema. Distal pulses present and symmetric.

Neuro: A + O x3. Cranial nerve exam sig for L sided facial hemiparesis, unable to smile or raise eyebrow. o/w cn II, III, IV, VI intact, VII/VIII intact, IX, X,XI intact. Tongue deviates to R. Strength 5/5 throughout except LUE extensors 4/5. Sensation: intact to light touch and temp throughout. DTR's 1+ throughout, Babinski difficult to interpret 2/2 very strong withdrawal response (ticklish).  No nystagmus. Normal gait.



A/P 51 yo F with MMP incl recent CVA, CAD, HTN, DM, Depression p/t transfer her primary care.

1. Neuro-h/o recent CVA per pt report with residual L facial hemiparesis and LUE weakness, no records available. Concern that she continues to have TIAs, is high risk for another CVA.

--head MRI

--ECASA 325 mg qd

--referal to Neurology

--instructed pt to present to ER if she notes neurologic sx.



2. CV-CAD:h/o MI and 2 cardiac caths per pt, stable othopnea, exertional dyspnea wich may be aginal equivalent. HTN: poorly conrolled but has not been taking meds.

--Will try to obtain records fr OSH of caths

--check EKG

--check lipid profile and LFTs

--Add ECASA, cont Lipitor, Atenolol, Lisinopril/HCTZ

--Monitor BP closely

--Will need ETT in the future



3. Endocrine--DM, FS today 347, very lrge insulin requirement but pt has been extremely noncompliant with insulin regimen.  

--Cont glucophage

--Humulin 70/30 cut in half to 50 in am and 30 in pm for now. 

--Instructed pt to take her fasting BS in am and before dinner and keep a careful record. She will increase her Humulin if her BS remains very high. Reinforced importance of tight glucose control and low carb diet.

--nutrition referal for diabetic teaching

--referal to Bridget Jamieson NP for diabetic teaching and close follow up of BS

--will check HgA1C, microalbuminuria, chem 7

--pt will need optho and podiatry referal at next visit



4. Depression--Pt has sx and history of depression. Will start Celexa 20 mg qd and follow closely



5. Health maint--will refer for mammo at next visit. Will perform PAP and full breast exam at next visit as wel as obtain close sexual history. Will check lipids as above. 



6. F/u in 1 mo





_____________________________________________

Ione Kerr, M.D.







========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================





I saw and evaluated the patient and agree with Dr Kerr's findings and plan as documented in her note.



______________________________                              



Ursula Olivia Oconnell, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2065-06-27

HPI: 51 yo F with HTN, DM, CAD, gastritis, depression, s/p CVA returns for f/u. 

Very noncompliant with meds and appts

Today c/o significant fatigue. Also occ has left sided chest pressure and DOE. In the past she c/o orthopnea and this is unchanged. CP comes unrelated to exertion. No n/v or radiation/diaphoresis.

In terms of s/o TIA, she denies dizziness, falls, visual changes, ataxia, no syncope or presyncope, no other focal neurologic sx, she does get frquent headaches.



Problems

HTN 

DM 

CAD:

-EKG with LVH and repol abnlity. 

-Stress echo () Limited, only able to walk 0'47".  MHR 122 (72%predicted), BP 230/100. Stopped 2/2 dizziness, SOB and SSCP. EKG shwed 1 mm ST depressions in II, III, F, V5-6. Read as c/w but not diagnostic of ischemia.  Echo showed baseline EF of 60% with no RWMA. After exercise there was minor nonspecific inferoposterior WMA. Read as no evidence of inducible ischenia (but low sensitivity 2/2 low MHR)

HX OF GASTRITIS BY UGIS H PYLORI + 

S/P TAH 2/2 FIBROIDS 

OA

Depression

Asthma

s/p CVA



Medications

Humulin 70/30 60 UNITS qpm x 30 days

Insulin REGULAR HUMAN 3 UNITS SC AC+HS , use per sliding scale-2U if 150-200, 4U if 200-250, 6U 250-300, 8U 300-350

Protonix (PANTOPRAZOLE) 40MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Trazodone 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO qhs PRN insomna 

Naprosyn (NAPROXEN) 500MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 

Polytrim (TRIMETHOPRIM/POLYMYXIN B SULFATE) 1 DROP OU Q4-6H x 7 days

Proventil INH 2 PUFFS INH Q 6 H PRN SOB , PRN: SOB/WHEEZING

Azmacort INH 2 PUFF AER BID 

Glucophage 500 MG PO BID 

Lipitor 40 MG PO QD 

Zestoretic (LISINOPRIL/HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 20-25 TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Ecasa (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED) 325MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Clarinex (DESLORATADINE) 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD 

Paxil (PAROXETINE) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Atenolol 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Flucoconzole 150 MG PO x1 x 1 day

Lotrimin 1% CREAM (CLOTRIMAZOLE 1% CREAM) 1 APPLICATION TOP QD , apply to vaginal area (external) qd prn itch

Insulin 70/30 (HUMAN) 30 U/30 U SC QAM/Qpm 



EXAM:

VS 138/80  HR 72   

Neck No JVD No thyromegaly  No carotid bruits

Cor RRR, S1S2, 2/6 sys M at RUSB

Lungs CTA bl, no crackles/wheezes

Abd Soft NTND +BS

Ext No c/c/e

NEURO: PERRL. Facial asymmetry, unable to smile or raise eyebrow on L, tongue deviates to R. Strength 4/5 LUE extensors, o/w 5/5 throughout. Normal gait. Unchanged fr previous



A/P:

53F with MMP incl DM, high chol, depression, s/p TIA, noncompliance, for f/u



1) Recent possible HIV exposure: Neg HIV and other STDs, need to recheck 6 mos after exposure in 12/65



2) DM:

--Now on Humulin 70/30 at 60qam and 30 qpm after off for several mos. Last A1c was 13.9.

--Cont glucophage 500 bid

--cont ASA, statin

--at next visit will schedule eye exam and recheck A1C



3)NEURO-s/p CVA, did not f/u with neurology but will resched appt today. ASA 325 qd, Plavix 75 mg PO QD.



4)CV-Recent stress echo with low sensitivity given poor exercise tolerance but nondiagnostic of ischemia. HTN poorly controlled likely bc pt not compliant with meds.

--Restart  Atenolol at 25 qd, likely need to titrate up, used to be on 100. Cont  Lisinopril 20/HCTZ 25 qd. 

--Cont Lipitor 40 mg qd, will check LFTs and lipid panel in 6-8 weeks

--Cont ASA 325 qd

--Check EKG and resched adenosine MIBI which she has missed multiple times

--check chem 7 given recent restart BP meds



5)PSYCH-Depression. Cont Celexa to 40 qd



6)PULM-Asthma. Cont albuterol and asthmacort



7)GI-GERD. Cont Protonix



8)Fatigue: check TSH and CBC



9)Health Maint:

--Overdue for PAP (last 3 yrs ago), will schedule

--Overdue for Mammo (last 3 yrs ago), will schedule

--check chol,LFTs, renal fxn, cbc



8)F/u in 1 mo 



Results

06/27/2065 NA 137,  K 3.9,  CL 97 (*),  CO2 30,  BUN 12,  CRE 0.7,  GLU 372 (*), CA 9.6, TSH 1.798,  HCT 41.2









_____________________________________________

Ione Kerr, M.D.



















========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



I have discussed this patient with Dr. Kerr and agree with above.



______________________________                              



Diane Rhonda Welsh, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2066-09-16

51 yo F with HTN, DM, CAD, gastritis, depression, s/p CVA returns for f/u. 

Pt reports that she has not been taking any medications for one month. She left for Poland for two months and ran out of medications. 



Pt reprots her sugars have been in the 400-500. 

Pt reports numbness of both feet, and the loss of her her toe nails. 

 

Very noncompliant with meds and appts

Also c/o thick, cottage cheesy vaginal d/c and itch.



Problems

HTN 

DM 

CAD:

-EKG with LVH and repol abnlity. 

-Stress echo () Limited, only able to walk 0'47".  MHR 122 (72%predicted), BP 230/100. Stopped 2/2 dizziness, SOB and SSCP. EKG shwed 1 mm ST depressions in II, III, F, V5-6. Read as c/w but not diagnostic of ischemia.  Echo showed baseline EF of 60% with no RWMA. After exercise there was minor nonspecific inferoposterior WMA. Read as no evidence of inducible ischenia (but low sensitivity 2/2 low MHR)

HX OF GASTRITIS BY UGIS H PYLORI + 

S/P TAH 2/2 FIBROIDS 

OA

Depression

Asthma

s/p CVA



Medications

Humulin 70/30 60 UNITS qpm x 30 days

Insulin REGULAR HUMAN 3 UNITS SC AC+HS , use per sliding scale-2U if 150-200, 4U if 200-250, 6U 250-300, 8U 300-350

Protonix (PANTOPRAZOLE) 40MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Trazodone 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO qhs PRN insomna 

Naprosyn (NAPROXEN) 500MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 

Polytrim (TRIMETHOPRIM/POLYMYXIN B SULFATE) 1 DROP OU Q4-6H x 7 days

Proventil INH 2 PUFFS INH Q 6 H PRN SOB , PRN: SOB/WHEEZING

Azmacort INH 2 PUFF AER BID 

Glucophage 500 MG PO BID 

Lipitor 40 MG PO QD 

Zestoretic (LISINOPRIL/HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 20-25 TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Ecasa (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED) 325MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Clarinex (DESLORATADINE) 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD 

Paxil (PAROXETINE) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Atenolol 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Flucoconzole 150 MG PO x1 x 1 day

Lotrimin 1% CREAM (CLOTRIMAZOLE 1% CREAM) 1 APPLICATION TOP QD , apply to vaginal area (external) qd prn itch

Insulin 70/30 (HUMAN) 30 U/30 U SC QAM/Qpm 

.. of note , pt is not taking any of her medications. 





EXAM:



Vital Signs

BP 170/86, P 86, Wt 154 lb

Neck No JVD No thyromegaly  

Cor RRR, S1S2, 2/6 sys M at RUSB

Lungs CTA bl, no crackles/wheezes

Abd Soft NTND +BS

Ext No c/c/e

NEURO: PERRL. Facial asymmetry, unable to smile or raise eyebrow on L, tongue deviates to R. Strength 4/5 LUE extensors, o/w 5/5 throughout. 

Loss of sensation

Normal gait. Unchanged fr previous





Results

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            

05/08/2066                       4.2                                          

05/06/2066        134 (*)        4.2            97 (*)         28             

05/01/2066        137            3.4 (*)        96 (*)         33 (*)         



Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            ANION          

05/08/2066                       0.9                                          

05/06/2066        13             0.7            285 (*)        9              

05/01/2066        19             0.8            187 (*)        8              



Date/Time         CA             TBILI          TP             ALB            

05/06/2066        9.6                                                         

05/01/2066        9.5            0.3            7.2            3.8            



Date/Time         GLOB           

05/01/2066        3.4            



Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          

05/01/2066        15             16             89             0.3            



Date/Time         CHOL           TRIG           HDL            LDLCAL         

05/08/2066        272 (*)        301 (*)        46             166 (*)        



Date/Time         VLDL           

05/08/2066        60             



Date/Time         MALB           MALB/CRE       

05/08/2066        9.8 (*)        59.8 (*)[1]    



Date/Time         UTIME          

05/08/2066        RANDOM         



Date/Time         UTIME          U/UCRE         

05/08/2066        RANDOM         163.9          



Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            

05/01/2066        10.40 (*)      4.29           13.3           37.6           



Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            

05/01/2066        87.6           31.1           35.5           302            



Date/Time         RDW            

05/01/2066        12.4           



Date/Time         %POLY-A        %LYMPH-A       %MONO-A        %EOS-A         

05/01/2066        65.5           29             4.2 (#)        0.9            



Date/Time         %BASO-A        

05/01/2066        0.4            



Date/Time         ANEUT-A        ALYMP-A        AMONO-A        AEOS-A         

05/01/2066        6.81           3.01           0.44           0.09           



Date/Time         ABASO-A        

05/01/2066        0.04           





[1] RESULT COMMENT:   Units = mg Alb/g Cre











A/P:

53F with MMP incl DM, high chol, depression, s/p TIA, noncompliance, for f/u



1) Recent possible HIV exposure: Neg HIV and other STDs, pt did not return for recheck 6 mos after exposure in 12/65, pt will think about re testing adn decide at next visit 



2) DM:  Humulin 70/30 at 70qam and 30 qpm after off for several mos. Last A1c was 13.9. 5/23, 

-- seeB. Jamiesonfor insulin titration.

--Cont glucophage 500 bid

--cont ASA, statin

--referred to opthamology



3)NEURO-s/p CVA, needs to f/u with neuro given this light headedness she feels, which she thinks is how she felt before the last CVA. ASA 325 qd,will refer to Neurology at next visit.



4)CV-Recent stress echo with low sensitivity given poor exercise tolerance but nondiagnostic of ischemia. HTN poorly controlled likely bc pt not compliant with meds.

.- Will schedule MIBI again.

--BP elevated: Atenolol 50 Cont Zestoretic. Will see NP in 1 wk and may need further incr in Atenolol (used to be on 100)

--Cont Lipitor 40 mg qd, Lipids continue to be elevated, will recheck in 3 months 

--Cont ASA 325 qd



5)PSYCH-Depression, doing well fr this. Cont Celexa to 40 qd



6)PULM-Asthma. Cont albuterol and asthmacort



7)GI-GERD. Cont Protonix



8)Heme: Hct 37 and MCV 



9)Vaginal candidiasis: Diflucan 150 x1

Cream 



10)Health Maint:



--Overdue for Mammo (last 3 yrs ago), scheduled

--Will schedule colonoscopy at next visit



11)F/u in 2 weeks 



referred to Social work for assistance with compliance. 

Discussed with Dr Blanchard





Hope Roberts, MD

      



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



51 yo woman with HTN, DM, CAD, gastritis, depression, s/p CVA, noncompliance for f/u.  Ran out of medications 1 month ago, sugars in 500s.  C/o dysuria/vaginal itching.  Had stress test in 2065 that was c/w but not dx ischemia, didn't f/u for MIBI.  BP 170/86.  LDL 166.  Last a1c 13.  Plan. Will restart all medications.  Had HIV exposure and one test but not a f/u test.  F/u in 2 weeks to assess medication compliance and check BP. D/w Dr. Roberts. Blanchard ,MD





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>