<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2150-02-06

 

Neurology ED Consult Note



Patient: Klein, Michelle

MRN:	2474410

Date: 	2/6/50

Time: 	10:00 p.m.

PCP:	Whitney Keller, M.D.



Reason for consult: garbled speech



HPI:   Patient is a 74 yo RH woman with history of HTN, hyperlipidemia, CAD s/p LAD stent (2144) who was in her USOH until this afternoon at 12:15 p.m. when she experienced sudden onset of garbled speech and difficulty "expressing myself" while cooking lunch for she and her husband.  This episode was accompanied shortly thereafter by a dull, L fronto-temporal headache that persisted for several hours.  She states she did not have word-finding difficulties but simply had trouble articulating herself.   The episode came on suddenly and lasted 1-2 hours before she resolved back to baseline.  In addition to headache, associated symptoms included generalized weakness, feeling cold and mildly nauseated.  She denied visual changes, chest pain, sob, palpitations, lightheadedness, vertigo, difficulty with swallowing, coordination or gait.  She describes having a glass of orange juice with the thought that her sugar might be low, without apparent effect.



She recalls one similar episode ~ 2 years ago at which time she had her husband drive her home and she went to bed.  The speech difficulty had resolved by morning, and she apparently never told her physician or had any further work-up.  She has no known history of seizures.  Migraines occur 1-2x/year, preceeded by scintillating scotoma, associated with nausea, photophobia, relieved by sleep.  No recent fevers, chills,  weight loss or weight gain, cough, abd pain, diarrhea.  Reports regular exercise including this morning (stationary bicycle).



Time of onset/Last seen normal: 12:15 pm

Witnessed onset: yes

Onset: acute

Mode of arrival:  walk-in	

Clinical Course: improving

Pre-morbid neurological status: independent

Code status: full code



PMHx:

HTN

Hyperlipidemia

CAD sp LAD stent (2144)

Migraines (as above)

Familial tremor

Nephrolithiasis

S/p appendectomy

S/p mastoid surgery as a child

"borderline dm" per patient



Meds:

Lipitor

Atenolol

ASA 325

Protonix

HCTZ

Vitamins B12/B6

MVI

Ginko



All: Sulfa  hives



SocHx:

Lives with husband in Sherman.  Mother of 4 children.  Very active at baseline, secretary of her methodist church.

Tob: active for "several years" quit ~20 years ago

ETOH: denies

Illicit:  denies



FamHx: 

Father with vascular disease, asbestosis.



VS:   97.2             71             146/68                 18          98% (RA)

PE:  Gen: 	Pleasant woman appears younger than stated age, resting comfortably NAD

HEENT: 	NC/AT, o/p clr, mmm

Neck: 	supple, no LAD, no carotid or vertebral bruits

CV: 	rr, nl s1s2, no m/r/g

Chest: 	CTA b/l, no w/r/r anteriorly

Abd: 	soft, nt/nd, +nabs

Ext:	no c/c/e, distal pulses 2+, no rash



Neurologic Exam:

MS:	A&Ox3, appropriately interactive, normal affect 

Attention: DOW, MOY backwards	 

Speech: fluent w/o paraphasic errors; repetition, naming, reading, writing intact

Memory: 1/3 at 5 minutes; 3/3 with prompting

Calculations: serial 7s 100   93   86   79   62

L/R confusion: No L/R confusion

Praxis: Able to mimic saluting the flag, brushing teeth with either hand.



CN: 	I--not tested

II,III-Pupils equal 2.5  2 b/l, VFFC, optic discs sharp

III,IV,VI-EOMI, no nystagmus, no ptosis

V--sensation intact bilaterally to LT/PP/temp/vibration, masseters strong bilaterally

VII--face symmetric without weakness

VIII--hears finger rub bilaterally

IX,X--voice normal, palate elevates symmetrically, voluntary cough

XI--SCM/trapezii 5/5

XII--tongue protrudes midline, no atrophy or fasciculation



Motor:	Normal bulk and tone; postural tremor; no rigidity, cogwheeling or bradykinesia. 

No pronator drift. 

Strength:

              


****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2150-04-20

April 20, 2150

Whitney Keller, MD
980 Penny Lane
Punta Gorda, OK  98634

Re:  KLEIN, Michelle
   MRN: 2474410
   DOB: 8/6/2075

Dear Dr. Keller,

Ms. Klein was seen in general neurology clinic today following her recent admission for complex migraine.   Dr. Remigio Allison was present for or performed all salient aspects of the history and physical exam and together we discussed with the patient the work-up and treatment plan. We spent greater than 50% of the visit in education and counseling of the patient and family.

HPI: As you know, Ms. Klein is a 74 yo RH woman with history of HTN, hyperlipidemia, CAD s/p LAD stent (2144), migraine, who was in her USOH until the afternoon of 2/6/50 when she experienced sudden onset of garbled speech and difficulty "expressing myself" while cooking lunch for she and her husband.  This episode was accompanied shortly thereafter by a dull, L fronto-temporal headache that persisted for several hours.  She states she did not have word-finding difficulties but simply had trouble articulating herself.   In particular she related several examples of semantic paraphasic errors.  The episode came on suddenly and lasted 1-2 hours before she resolved back to baseline.  In addition to headache, associated symptoms included generalized weakness, feeling cold and mildly nauseated.  She denied visual changes, chest pain, sob, palpitations, lightheadedness, vertigo, difficulty with swallowing, coordination or gait.  She describes having a glass of orange juice with the thought that her sugar might be low, without apparent effect.  She recalled one similar episode ~ 2 years ago at which time she had her husband drive her home and she went to bed.  The speech difficulty had resolved by morning, and she apparently never told her physician or had any further work-up.  She has no known history of seizures but migraines occur 1-2x/year, last 30 minutes to several hours and are typically preceeded by scintillating scotoma (   jagged horizontal lines   ), associated with nausea/photophobia, and relieved by sleep.

Given her multiple vascular risk factors, she was admitted for TIA work-up which was unremarkable with the exception of mildly elevated HbA1c (7.0) including lipids, ESR, homocysteine, lipoprotein (a), TTE and holter.  CT/CT-a and MRI did not show any evidence of acute stroke or significant cervical or intracranial arterial stenosis.  She was discharged on her home medications, which included ASA 325mg po qd, with a diagnosis of complex migraine.  Since return home, she has had additional typical episodes of migraine, (about every 2 weeks) without the aphasia which brought her into the hospital.  She has tried Excedrin migraine a few times recently, with good results.

ROS:  Sometimes    sees stars    when she stands up too quickly after bending over.  Similarly feels that her balance is transiently affected when getting out of bed in the morning (   I rock   ).  She is awaiting thyroid biopsy of the nodules incidentally discovered on CT-CT-a.  Negative in detail including change in weight, energy, appetite, CP, palpitations, SOB, DOE, N/V/D/cough, fever, chills, rash, BRBPR, melena, abdominal pain, change in bowel or bladder habits.  In addition, patient denies change in vision, hearing, tinnitus, vertigo, numbness, weakness, slurred speech, difficulty with language, swallowing, eating, or gait.

Past Medical History: 
CAD s/p LAD stent 2144
HTN
Hyperlipidemia
Migraine HA: +scintillating scotoma, +photophobia, +nauea, relieved with sleep.
Familial tremor
Nephrolithiasis
S/p appendectomy
S/p mastoid surgery as ahild
S/p borderline DM

Medications: 
ASA 325
Lipitor 10
Isordil
Verapamil 240
Atenolol 25
Protonix 40
HCTZ 12.5
MVI
B6/B12

Allergies: Sulfa drugs cause hives, laryngeal edema
     
Social History: Lives at home with husband, mother of 4 children, works as performer.
Denies tobacco, ETOH, or illicit drug use.

Family History:  Father with history of asbestosis, construction.  No known history of stroke or migraine.
Physical Examination:
	VS:  AVSS
	GEN: WDWN, NAD
	HEENT: NC/AT, o/p clear, mmm, sclera anicteric
	Neck:  supple, no LAD, no JVD, no carotid or vertebral bruits
	Lungs:  cta b/l, no w/r/r
	Cor:  rr, nl s1s2, no m/r/g
	Ext:  wwp, no c/c/e
	
Neurologic Examination: 
	MS: 	Alert & oriented x3, following all commands.  Speech fluent w/o paraphasic errors; comprehension, repetition, naming, reading, and writing intact.  Memory: 3/3 w/o prompting at 5 min. WORLD, DOW backward without errors, serial 7's intact; No L/R confusion; able to salute and brush teeth with either hand.
CN II-XII:  	Fundi normal. Visual fields full to confrontation; pupils equal and reactive 3  2; no ptosis; Extraocular movements full without nystagmus; facial sensation normal; hearing intact to finger rub bilaterally; face, tongue and palate are symmetric; SCM and traps 5/5.
Motor:  	Normal bulk and tone.  Strength 5/5 throughout including: biceps, triceps, brachioradialis, finger flexors and extensors, hip, knee and ankle flexors and extensors.  .  No pronator drift, cogwheeling or abnormal orbital movement.  No fasciculations, no myoclonus.  
	Sensation:	Intact to light touch, pin prick, temperature, vibration and proprioception.  No extinction.
	Reflexes:  	Normal and symmetric with deep tendon reflexes 2+ at biceps, triceps, brachioradialis, patella and ankles. Plantar response downgoing bilaterally.  No Hoffman.
	Cerebellar:  	Finger-nose-finger, rapid alternating movements, heel  shin normal and symmetric b/l.
Gait:	Normal gait and stance.  Posture, stride, arm-swing normal.  Able to walk on heels and toes.  Tandem gait intact.  Romberg negative.

Data: 
Chol	128
HDL	55
LDL	47
TG		131
Lp(a)	13
TSH	2.38
HbA1c	7.0
ESR	13
Hcys	8.6

TTE: No LA dilatation, no RWMA, LVEF ~ 71%
Holter: normal sinus rhythm with occasional sinus arrhythmia

CT/CT-a Head/Neck: Small L PICA infundibulum.  Multiple thyroid nodules.
MRI Brain: No evidence of acute infarct, partially empty sella, nonspecific periventricular white matter T2 hyperintensities consistent with small vessel disease.

Impression and Recommendations:  74 yo RH woman with history of HTN, hyperlipidemia, CAD s/p LAD stent (2144), migraine s/p recent episode of transient aphasia and headache thought most likely to represent complex migraine given clinical presentation and after largely unremarkable stroke/TIA work-up.  Since discharge, she has continued to have her baseline migraines at a frequency of ~ 2x/month.  At this point, we would not recommend beginning prophylactic therapy, but would consider doing so if attacks become more frequent.  Given her clinical response to Excedrin migraine, we have suggested continuing this drug for abortive therapy, but have spoken at length about the phenomenon of rebound headache and cautioned her about using it more than once every 10-14 days.  We have discussed the phenomenon of complex migraine and reinforced the inherent difficulties of distinguishing these attacks from TIA/stroke; thus we have urged to continue to take unusual non-stereotyped deficits seriously.  She will follow-up with us in 4-6 months or sooner if the need arises. 

Thank you for allowing us to participate in the care of this patient.  We look forward to seeing her in follow-up.

Sincerely,

___________________________________
Olen X. Laughlin, M.D.
Neurology Resident
Pager 63030

I have seen and examined the patient with Dr. Laughlin, resident in Neurology, and repeated or observed all the key elements of the encounter before discussing the assessment and management. I agree with the information including the history, examination and assessment/plan documented in this note. I've reviewed and edited this note and agreed with the content prior to finalizing this entry.



Remigio L. Allison, Ph.D., M.D. 
Attending Neurologist
Valley County Hospital
VBK 197
 Russell Avenue St. Augustine, OK
Tel. 110 227 3266






****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2151-08-30

 
76 year old mother of four - 1 grandchild.
Retired  performer.
Husband Nathaniel Klein


Nodular thyroid


HPI
Health generally ok.
Complex migraine.
CAD - stent  2144. T. William is cardiologist.
XRT - none.

2150			CT scan -multiple nodules in thyroid
				US - Multiple nodules. Largest is L lower 1.6 x 1.3 x 1.2 cm 					Hypoechoic. Smaller right nodules are also hypoechoic. Some
				macrocalcification in the larger nodule.

June 2150		FNA. Benign follicular cells and colloid.  L nodule

Aug 2151		US -  Right 4 x 4 x 4 mm
				Midpole right 9 x8 x8
				Midpole 7 x 4 x 9
				Lower pole 1.1 x 1 x 1.3 solid.
				Right 8 x 5 x 1
				Left thyroid 6 x 5 x 7
				Midpole L 1.5 x 1.0 x 1.5 cm. 
				Lower pole 5 x 3 x 6 mm

Interim History and ROS

Compared current and prior US. No change in size. L nodule has been FNA'd
Question is whether right will need FNA. 
Now has diabetes and is now on Metformin. Discussed stopped before contrast agents. 
She and husband have been working on estate of friend. 

ROS

Constitutional:  Weight stable. Appetite normal. Tends to be hot.  Energy down.
Head No frequent headaches. No hair loss. 
Eye : Vision down - has cataracts. 
Throat : No difficulty swallowing. Voice unchanged. No neck pressure
Cardiac:  No chest pain. No palpitations.
Respiratory : No exertional dyspnea. Increaed cough since Jan 2151. Had chest x-ray ok. Takes protonix in a.m. 
GI: Digestion fine. No difficulty with bowel movements.
GU: Urination without difficulty. Menopausal. 
NM: No pain or aches - save occ ankle aches. Strength is good. 
Psych: Difficulty sleeping - up to urinate or suddently awake or husband snoring.  Mood is fine.
 
 

Medications
Lipitor 10
Isordil
Verapamil 240
Atenolol 25
Metformin 500 x 2
ASA
Protonix 40 
HCTZ 12.5 each a.m.
Vits

Allergies
Sulfa
Vinegar

H Social History

Born Estill
Husband Nathaniel Klein - pt of mine. 

Past Medical History

Appendect
D and C
Migraine
CAD
Mastoid surgery at age 7 month.

   


Physical Examination
Increased weight. blondish hair. Glasses.
Vital Signs:  P 84     BP 140/80    Resp 12
HEENT: PRERLA Full EOM Conj clear. No proptosis. Pharynx without lesions. 2plus carotids. No post cervical supra clavicular nodes. Thyroid: Diff feeling but probable rt lower pole nodule. Left nodule 1 plus cm. 

Impression

Thyroid Nodules. Multinodular thyroid.
Compared current and prior US  - Stable but consider whether the right nodule will need an FNA.
Review with radiology and decide.

 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2152-08-26


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	VALLEY COUNTY HOSPITAL
	

Whitney V Keller M.D. 
052 Penny Lane
Punta Gorda, OK 98634

Dear Whitney:

  I was pleased to see Michelle Klein this morning for a post hospitalization followup evaluation.  You know Michelle well, she does have coronary artery disease, has had an LAD stent placed in 2148, and had a normal stress sestamibi study in November 2151.  She has moderate mitral insufficiency.  Her left atrial dimension is 52 and RV pressure 42.  She is diabetic and has hypertension.  She was hospitalized with a diarrheal bleeding issue attributed to salmonella infection attributed to tomatoes it also affecting her husband and this was accomplished at the Copley Hospital.

Her medications were modified somewhat.  She presently takes atenolol 50 mg a day, verapamil 120 mg per day, Lipitor 10 mg a day, Diovan 80 mg per day, they held her aspirin and her Imdur, she takes Prilosec 40 mg BID, and metformin 500 mg BID.  Her blood pressure remains high today at 147/70, it had been similar range when I saw her in June this year.  Pending her diarrhea at home, we may need to go back up on some of her medications, but at this point we will change.  She is symptom free vis-a-vie her heart.

Her exam shows no cyanosis, clubbing, or edema.  Normal thyroid, normal neck veins, and arteries.  Clear lungs.  Normal abdomen, nontender, and no mass felt.  Her heart palpates normally.  There were no thrills and no scars.  Her first sound is soft and second is normal.  There is a 1/6 apical mitral insufficiency murmur with positive response to isometrics.  There were no diastolic murmurs.  Blood pressure is 145/70.

The electrocardiogram was normal with trace nonspecific ST flattening.

I will plan to reassess Michelle in four months and she will have a recheck several times a month of her blood pressure at home and she will send diaries to me.  If her blood pressure is continued at home to be in her present level, we will advance her medications to accommodate this.  If there are any questions feel free to call me.

Sincerely yours,

	
Tony Wilkinson, MD

	
Signed electronically by  Tony Wilkinson, MD
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2154-07-21


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	VALLEY COUNTY HOSPITAL
	

Eva  Newby M.D. 
Valley County Hospital
____
,  

Dear Dr. Newby:

  I was happy to see Michelle Klein (2474410: DOB August 6, 2075) who comes along with her husband, Nathaniel, for follow up cardiac evaluation. Michelle has been stable from a cardiac point of view. She has coronary artery disease and underwent LAD stent placement in 2148. She had negative stress sestamibi study in November 2151. She has been free of angina or cardiac-related symptoms. She notes occasional orthostatic dizziness. Her prior stamina symptoms have improved greatly. She has well-controlled hypertension on stable medical regimen. Her recent diagnosis of myelofibrosis has been followed through closely by her hematology group here at Valley County and we have discussed this at length. Michelle feels far better than at her last several visits and I am very happy to see this.

On clinical exam, blood pressure right arm is 130/80 mmHg, pulses are equal, normal and all well felt. First heart sound is normal to soft. Second is normal. There is a 1+/6 systolic apical murmur. No diastolic murmurs are present. No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. Thyroid is postoperative and stable. Neck veins are flat. Carotid upstrokes are normal. Lungs are clear. Abdominal exam is normal. I do not feel enlargement of the abdominal aorta.

The electrocardiogram is unchanged. It continues to show minimal nonspecific ST flattening and left atrial prominence.

Medications: Michelle no longer takes the verapamil, atenolol 50 mg per day, Lipitor 10 mg per day, Diovan 40 mg daily, Protonix 40 mg b.i.d., Synthroid 1.12 mg per day, vitamin B12 500 mg, B6 100 mg, magnesium 400 mg per day, and D3 2000 IU per day.

If there are any questions at anytime, please call me. I am happy to see Michelle 's spirits are good and that she is feeling better and actually, her clinical exam seems excellent as well. She does not manifest tachycardia. I note that her hematocrit is 31%.  Visit duration 40 min.-half in discussion re he cardiac and hematologic issues.

Best regards.

Sincerely yours,

	
Tony Wilkinson, MD

	
Signed electronically by  Tony Wilkinson, MD
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>