<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2097-03-04


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	ELIZABETHTOWN STATE HOSPITAL
	

RE:  I had the pleasure of seeing Verna Cantu in consultation today for management of coronary artery disease and aortic stenosis.

Dear Dr. Levon Nichols,

  She is a very pleasant 60 year old female with cardiovascular risk factors of non-insulin dependent diabetes mellitus, hypertension, peripheral arterial disease, and prior tobacco abuse. She has no prior history of myocardial infarction, arrhythmia, or congestive heart failure. About 15 years ago she underwent an ETT for evaluation of exertional lightheadedness which by her reports was unremarkable. 
She has an extensive vascular history s/p right popliteal PTA/Stent and left common femoral endarterectomy for which she has been receiving regular care from Dr. Nichols. She has a history of mixed connective tissue disease with Raynaud's for which she has been followed by Dr. Lucille Jackson. 

She reports that for the past year she has had dyspnea on exertion which typically manifests itself when she is trying to climb the 2.5 flights of stairs that she has at home. She feels shortness of breath requiring her to stop when she gets to the top. She denies exertional chest pain or lightheadedness. She denies orthopnea, paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea, or edema. She denies lightheadedness, dizziness, palpitations, or syncope. Currently she reports no symptoms of claudication. No regular exercise. A couple of times a day. Bowls on Sunday night with no shortness of breath. She has also been noted to have a systolic murmur on previous exams. An echocardiogram in 2094 revealed aortic valve leaflet thickening but did not report significant aortic stenosis, though this was a technically difficult study by report. 

For evaluation of these symptoms she underwent an ETT-MIBI which was notable for poor exercise capacity, drop in blood pressure, exercise induced LBBB, and perfusion abnormality suggesting distal LAD territory ischemia. 



	Past medical history:
   1. Diabetes Mellitus: On oral medications for 7 years +Retinopathy both eyes ~ 7 yrs ago, no nephropathy. +neuropathy 
2. Hypertension controlled on medication ~ 5yrs, requiring frequent adjustments of meds, 140/70 
3. Peripheral arterial disease. Status post left common femoral endarterectomy by Dr. Vanover 11/26/95. 
4. Carotid artery disease. Mild bilateral internal carotid artery stenoses duplex ultrasound 6/96. 
5. Mixed connective tissue disease with Raynaud's. Followed by Dr. Lucille Jackson. In 2094 was having leg pains. 
6. Melanoma involving right thigh. s/p surgical resection 20 years ago 
7. Arthritis primarily of hands 

Prior surgeries: tonsillectomy, melanoma resection. 

Supplements: 
Calcium with Vit. D.

	

	Changes to Allergies
	
NKA: No Known Allergies - reaction: [reviewed]


	Family history:
   Mother had rheumatic heart disease, had 3 valve surgeries. Died at the age of 49 from complications of a urinary infection in the setting of stroke. 
Father had cirrhosis and died at the age of 51, alcoholic. 
Sister: alive and well. 
There is no family history of premature coronary artery disease, cardiomyopathy, or arrhythmia. 


	Social history:
   Works as Broadcast Technician NPR for 10 years. 
Tobacco: quit 20 years ago. 1 ppd for 25 years. 
EtoH: none 
Lives with husband and son. 



	Review of systems:
   No bright red blood per rectum or melena. No transient ischemic attack, or stroke. She reports some left forearm muscle tightness with usual activities. Relieved with rest for the past one year. 

Physical examination:
	
-BMI: 28.3  Overweight, moderate risk
-Pulse: 91  reg 
-resp. rate: 18  
-height: 58  in.
-weight: 135  lbs.
-General appearance:   overweight, pleasant, in no distress
-Skin:   No rashes. No jaundice. 
-HEENT:   Conjunctivae clear, oropharynx benign. Upper and lower dentures
-Neck:   Neck is supple. Bilateral carotid upstrokes are diminished in volume and delayed in timing with radiation of aortic murmur. JVP is normal and estimated at 7 cm H20 with no hepatojugular reflux. There is no cervical adenopathy or thyromegaly. 
-Chest:   Mild bibasilar rales at the bases.  No rhonchi or wheezes.
-Cardiac:   Regular, soft S1, There is a III/VI late peaking crescendo-decrescendo murmur at the base which radiates to the carotids and throughout the pre-cordium and left thorax.  P2 is preserved and heard towards the apex. No RV heave. PMI does not feel displaced. 
-Abdomen:   Soft, non-tender, non-distended with normal bowel sounds. abdominal bruit over epigastric area. No hepatosplenomegaly. 
-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. 2+ femoral pulses with a left bruit. 2+ pedal pulses.  High pitched bruits appreciated while measuring brachial blood pressure in both arms.
-Neuro:   Alert and oriented x 3. Normal gait 
-BP: 162/60  RA 144/66 LA


	EKG:
   Normal sinus rhythm at 91 bpm. Left anterior fascicular block. Compared with prior from 11/95 there has been no significant change. 

Selected recent labs:
	 Metabolic
Date     


****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-03-31


	CARDIAC SURGERY
	

	ELIZABETHTOWN STATE HOSPITAL
	
Date of Service: 03/31/2097 14:37

Demographics
Race: Caucasian
Surgeon: Gonzalez, Norma
Staff Cardiologist: Triplett, Jackson
Referring Physician: Avalos, Holly

History of Presenting Illness
Mrs. Cantu is a 60 year old female with a history of peripheral arterial disease, aortic stenosis, diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and coronary artery disease.

For the past year she has had dyspnea on exertion, especially with a flight of stairs. She must stop at the top to rest. She denies chest pain, lightheadedness, orthopnea, paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea, syncope, or lower extremity edema. A recent echocardiogram in February revealed an ejection fraction of 71%, mild mitral regurgitation, aortic stenosis with a peak gradient of 45mmHg, mean of 29mmHg, and a valve area of 0.8 sq cm. There are no wall motion abnormalities of the left ventricle. A stress test in February revealed a reduced exercise capacity with a small area of mild apical ischemia and ejection fraction of 77%. A cardiac catheterization on 3/8 revealed 50% left main stenosis, 40-50% left anterior descending, 30% circumflex and 50% right coronary artery stenosis. Aortic valve area was noted at 0.98 sq cm. Carotid non-invasive studies revealed bilateral 20-49% stenosis.

She was referred to Dr. Gonzalez for an aortic valve replacement and coronary artery bypass graft surgery. She presents today for preoperative testing and evaluation. She currently notes dyspnea on exertion with two flights of stairs. She denies chest pain, dizziness, or diaphoresis. 





Indications
Dyspnea

Pre-operative risk factors
Weight (lb): 134.9
Height (in): 59
Smoker
Diabetes type: Diabetes Mellitus Type II
Diabetes Control: Oral
Dyslipidemia
Preop Creatinine: 0.71
Hypertension
Chronic Lung Disease: No
Peripheral Arterial Disease: Claudication, Arterial vascular reconstruction

Prior CV Interventions

Other Past Medical/Surgical History
Hypertension
Carotid Disease 20-49% stenosis bilaterally in the ICA bilaterally
 no significant stenosis in the external carotid arteries. 
Coronary Artery Disease
Aortic Valve Stenosis
Diabetes Mellitus Type II
Hyperlipidemia
Peripheral Arterial Disease-extensive disease followed by Dr. Nichols
-s/p left common femoral endarterectomy with bovine patch, and profunda femoral endarterectomy with Dr. Vanover 11/95.
-s/p percutaneous angioplasty of right popliteal artery with Dr. Vanover 6/94 for gangrene, non healing ulcers
Claudication
Diabetic Retinopathy both eyes
Neuropathy
Raynaud's Syndrome mixed connective tissue disease, followed by Dr. Lucille Jackson
Melanoma right thigh, s/p surgical resection 20 years ago
Arthritis hands
Tonsillectomy

Allergies
NKA: No Known Allergies

Admission medications
Aspirin (acetylsalicylic acid) 325 mg PO DAILY; Stop: 4/8/2097
Hydrochlorothiazide 50 mg PO DAILY
Lisinopril 40 mg PO DAILY; Stop: 4/13/2097
Lopressor (metoprolol tartrate) 25 mg PO DAILY
Metformin 1000 mg PO Bid; 2 tabs AM, one noon, one tab PM
Norvasc (amlodipine) 10 mg PO DAILY
Plaquenil sulfate (hydroxychloroquine) 400 mg PO DAILY
Prilosec (omeprazole) 20 mg PO DAILY
Zocor (simvastatin) 20 mg PO DAILY

Current Medications
None

Preop Cardiac Status

Preoperative Hemodynamics and Diagnostic Testing

Echo
Elizabethtown State Hospital 2/2097
ejection fraction 71% 
see report in chart.

ECG
SR 1st AV Block
LBBB 
75bpm

Cath report
Report Number:  OW974079                              Report Status: Final
Type:  Cardiac Catheterization
Date:  03/08/2097 09:15

    CORONARY ANATOMY FINDINGS: 
     Dominance: Right
     Left Main: The left main coronary artery is of moderate length, 
     intermediate sized vessel. It  bifurcates into the LAD and LCX coronary 
     arteries.  The LMCA has a  50 % stenosis in its ostium.
     LAD: The Proximal LAD has a diffuse 40-50 % stenosis. The Mid LAD has 
     a 50 % stenosis.
     Left Circumflex: The Proximal Circumflex has a 30 % stenosis.
     RCA: The right coronary artery is a dominant vessel. The Proximal RCA 
     has a tubular 50 % stenosis.



Carotid Non-Invasive Study
Report Number:  EPW246325                              Report Status: Final
Type:  Vascular Study
Date:  06/18/2096 09:00

IMPRESSION
 1. Bilateral mild 20-49% stenosis of the internal carotid arteries.
 2. No significant stenosis in the external carotid arteries bilaterally.
 3. Antegrade flow in both vertebral arteries.

Social History
Other Notes: She lives in Mendon, ID with husband. She has three children. Works as Broadcast Technician NPR for 10 years. Quit smoking 20 years ago, 1 PPD for 20 years. No Etoh. Denies illicit drug use.

Family History
Other notes: Mother-rheumatic heart disease, had 3 valve surgeries, died at age 49 from complications of a urinary tract infection in setting of strokeFather-cirrhosis, died age 51, alcoholicSister alive and well. She has Diabetes. 

Review of Systems
HEENT: Denies headache, sore throat, rhinorrhea, difficulty swallowing. 
Cardiac: See HPI 
Resp: Denies cough, hemoptysis. 
GI: Denies nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, melena, hematochezia, heart burn. 
GU: Denies hematuria. Has dysuria, frequency, nocturia, hesitancy. 
Neuro: Denies dizziness, syncope, history of stroke or TIA, seizures. 
M/S: Denies arthritis, arthralgias, recent fracture. 
Hemat: Denies anemia, easy bruising. 


Physical Exam
BP (right arm): 153/74 BP (left arm): 141/73 Pulse: 84 Normal sinus rhythm  99% RA Temp 98.2
General: Pleasant woman wearing glasses, well developed, no acute distress 
HEENT: pupils equal round and reactive to light, extra-ocular movements intact, oropharynx benign 
Teeth: full upper and lower dentures. no bleeding noted.
Neck: supple, no jugular venous distention, no lymphadenopathy 
Cardiac: regular rate and rhythm, II/VI systolic murmur heard at RSB, rub or gallups 
Pulm: clear to auscultation No crackles or wheezes
Skin: warm, dry, no bruises or rashes  Previous scars from her melanoma on right thigh and PAD procedures.
Abdomen: soft, non-tender, + bowel sounds, normoactive bowel sounds 
Rectal:  guaiac exam deferred
Neuro: alert and oriented x3, cranial nerves II-XII intact; strength and sensation equal in upper and lower extremities bilaterally; steady gait and ambulation. Mini mental exam 30/30
Extremities: no edema 
Saphenous vein: no varicosities seen 
Pulses (bilateral) 
Carotid: 2+ Radial: 2+ brachial 2+ Ulnar 1+  popliteal 1+ post tibial 2+
Femoral: 2+ Dorsalis Pedis: 2+ 
Bruits (bilateral) 
Femoral: none appreciated Carotid: none appreciated



Chest X-ray
Elizabethtown State Hospital 3/31/2097
Stable fine reticular opacities noted peripherally in both lungs and predominately at both lung bases, consistent with underlying mild pulmonary fibrosis (UIP pattern). No evidence of pneumonia or pulmonary edema. 

Most Recent Labs (since admission)

Problems and Plans
1: Aortic Stenosis and Coronary Artery Disease Plan AVR and Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting with Dr. Gonzalez on 4/15
-ESH CATH 3/8
-CNIS and echocardiogram in chart 
2: CNIS -mild dz 
3: Dental Examination Edentulous
Full upper and lower dentures. 
4: Conduit vein mapping completed. In chart. 
5: Preop Issues -hold Lisinopril 48 hours prior to surgery. Hold ASA one week prior. continue Lopressor 
-Labs: pending
-UA: pending
-EKG: Normal sinus rhythm  with 1st AV block LBBB
-CXR: Stable fine reticular opacities noted peripherally in both lungs and predominately at both lung bases, consistent with underlying mild pulmonary fibrosis (UIP pattern). No evidence of pneumonia or pulmonary edema. Informed Dr. Gonzalez
Blood Bank: pending
VRE: pending
-Bactroban Rx given. 
6: Diabetes Mellitus Type II -hold metformin 48 hours prior to surgery 
7: Informed Consent Cardiac surgical consent obtained from Dr. Gonzalez 3/21, in chart
Anesthesia eval and consent pending 

Signed by Olympia Jett   on 03/31/2097 14:37




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-05-30

CARDIAC SURGERY
ELIZABETHTOWN STATE HOSPITAL

Narrative Note:
   May 30, 2097


Re:  Verna Cantu
ESH #:033-98-74


I had the pleasure of seeing Verna and her daughter in my office today after her aortic valve replacement with a 19 mm Magna Ease, aortic root enlargement, and two-vessel coronary bypass grafting with a LIMA to the LAD and a saphenous vein to the posterior left ventricular branch.  

As you know, she is a 60-year-old woman with a history of peripheral arterial disease, aortic stenosis, diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and coronary artery disease who has had progressive dyspnea on exertion especially with walking up into her house which is 25 stairs.  We did her surgery, and she had a very uneventful postoperative course.  

She was discharged home on postoperative day seven and has continued to make progress.  She is walking each day.  Her medications include 5 mg of Norvasc, 25 mg of Toprol-XL, 20 mg of simvastatin and an aspirin and her Plaquenil.  She has no complaints of pain.  She is eating well.  She is sleeping well.  Her incisions have healed nicely.  Her sternum is stable, and she has no murmurs.  Overall, I am extremely pleased with her progress.  I told her to suggest to you that she was interested in cardiac rehab which she should be able to start in the next week or two.

Thank you so much for the opportunity of caring for her.


Norma Gonzalez, M.D.


cc:Holly Xavia Avalos, M.D.
Jackson X. Triplett, M.D.



Transcribed by: Julie L Cobb

Signed electronically by  Norma C. Gonzalez, MD
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-01-26



Rheumatology Visit
CANTU, VERNA L                        
MRN:  0261948

Date of Visit:  01/26/2098



Background:

Ms. Cantu is a 61-year-old diabetic woman with long-standing hypertension and peripheral vascular disease. She is followed in rheumatology for mixed connective tissue disease. She was initially seen in March 2094, when she was admitted with fever, nausea and chest pain. Her chest CT showed an interstitial pattern and a patulous esophagus; the interstitial lung disease was thought to be in part due to the mixed connective tissue disease and in part due to aspiration. She was also noted at that time to have an ANA 1:2560 speckled with positive RNP, negative Scl-70. Clinically, she had Sjogren's with sclerodermatous changes to her hands and telangiectasias across her face. The Raynaud's was exacerbated by the extensive peripheral vascular disease and she had to undergo stenting of the right common femoral artery 11/2095. Slowly these lesions healed. 


Interim Issues:
The diabetes and hypertension slowly became well controlled. But on exercise tolerance test, she presented with significant coronary artery disease and was noted to have significant aortic stenosis. In April 2097 she underwent stenting and she had a prosthetic aortic valve placed. Recovering from surgery has been slow. But it has been steady and uncomplicated. She can now go up 2 flights of stairs, then rest to go the third flight to her home. She has had no recurrent chest pain. She keeps her hands and feet warm and has had no tissue damage. She feels a little tightness in the chest wall in taking a deep breath (points anteriorly), but no dyspnea per se. She healed well postoperatively. She has recently been seen by cardiology and Dr. Nichols and seems to be in good shape. Her medications were reviewed and updated in the LMR. 



In terms of the MCTD, she continues to have some Raynaud's. She tries to keep her hands warm and she has had little breakdown of the tissue but rather thickening of her hands. What troubles her most is the intermittent synovitis. She felt much better on 5 mg of prednisone daily. She remains on Plaquenil 200 mg daily. She has had no worsening swallowing.  She has had no fever, pneumonia or progressive dyspnea on exertion. She sleeps on two pillows. She denies waking up with any bitterness in her mouth. She continues on omeprazole. Complete ROS in detail is otherwise negative. 


MEDS:
Amlodipine 5 MG QD 
Aspirin  325 MG QD  
Hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 MG QD 
Lisinopril 2.5 MG QD 
Metformin 500 MG BID 
Metoprolol Succinate Extended Release 25 MG QD 
Plaquenil  200 MG  QD 
Simvastatin 20 MG  QHS



FH/SH: She comes in with her husband, who feels she is doing very well and is delighted to see her better. Ms. Cantu went back to work 3 months after surgery. 


PMH: 

DM. 

Hypertension. 

Peripheral artery disease. 

ASCVD with mild bilateral carotid stenosis (2096). 

Melanoma (surgical resection right thigh in 2077). 

T&amp;A.




ALLERGIES: NKDA. 



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: 
BP 132/71, P 86, RR 16, Temp 97.7 F, Wt 132 lb
O2 SAT 98
PAIN LEVEL (0-10) 0
She has telangiectasias over her face. She looks well to me. Her color is good and she smiles easily. She has profound dryness of her mouth, but no particular injection of her eyes. Her neck is reasonably supple, the skin tightened here. Perhaps tightened a bit over her face as well. But the chest wall itself has no scleroderma. The midline scar has healed beautifully. The respiratory excursions appear full. There is no splinting. There are some bilateral crackles. Her hands are thickened from the scleroderma aspect of her disease. There are no nail bed infarcts. There is some peripheral pitting of digits. Her feet are well healed, warm and well perfused. Her joints are benign today with no active synovitis. Heart: S1, S2 with a soft crisp, S2 noted. No insufficiency murmurs. 



IMPRESSION: 

MCTD/Raynaud's.
Sjogren's

ASCVD with aortic valve replacement 4/2097. 

PVD. 


PLAN

Education regarding the importance of protection re: trauma to finger tips and prevention of Raynaud's. 
Continue Prilosec, refill Plaquenil
Prescribe prednisone 5 mg p.r.n. arthritis. I think it would be safe for her to take every morning as long as her diabetes remains well controlled and she feels much better on it; that is, the benefits outweigh the risks. 


Her labs have been sent and a chest x-ray obtained. 


I will see her in 6 months, sooner if there are any issues in the interim. 
Interview time 45 minutes due to medical history review, questions and verification of medications with the patient. 


She and her husband agree with this plan. 













___________________________

Lucille Jackson, M.D.


Dictated Date:  01/26/2098                        Dictated by:  Lucille Jackson, M.D. 




DD: 01/26/2098 12:19:21

TD: 01/26/2098 15:22:25

TR: 8279572

BackJob ID:  0324547

VoiceJob ID:  01397820




Results01/26/2098 NA 141,  K 4.9 (H),  CL 99 (L),  CO2 28.4,  BUN 19,  CRE 0.74,  EGFR &gt;60,  GLU 124 (H)01/26/2098 ANION 1401/26/2098 CA 10.0,  PHOS 4.0,  MG 1.8,  TBILI 0.3,  TP 8.9 (H),  ALB 4.8,  GLOB 4.1,  25 OH-VITD PEND01/26/2098 ALT/SGPT 10,  AST/SGOT 20,  ALKP 82,  TBILI 0.301/26/2098 CK 5201/26/2098 FE 63,  TIBC 33801/26/2098 WBC 6.4,  RBC 4.08,  HGB 11.9 (L),  HCT 35.0 (L),  MCV 86,  MCH 29.3,  MCHC 34.1,  PLT 30601/26/2098 RDW 14.7 (H)01/26/2098 METHOD Auto,  %NEUT 74 (H),  %LYMPH 18 (L),  %MONO 6,  %EOS 2,  %BASO 001/26/2098 ANEUT 4.73,  ALYMP 1.15,  AMONS 0.40,  AEOSN 0.11,  ABASOP 0.0101/26/2098 ANISO None,  HYPO None,  MACRO None,  MICRO None01/26/2098 ESR 83 (H)01/26/2098 CRP-MG/L 3.0

CXR
ResultsRadiologyExam Number:  55708166                        Report Status:  FinalType:  Chest 2 ViewsDate/Time:  01/26/2098 12:35Exam Code:  MTNS5Ordering Provider:  Jackson, Lucille MDHISTORY:       Chest pain - RoeID04109093     REPORT     Frontal and lateral views of the chest.           COMPARISON: 12-21 -97               FINDINGS:     Sternal wire sutures and mediastinal clips indicate CABG. AVR.       Coronary stents.           Lungs:  Both lungs have minor linear opacities, likely scarring at      the bases.  There is no evidence of pneumonia or pulmonary edema.           Pleura:  There is no pleural effusion or pneumothorax.           Heart and mediastinum:  The heart and the mediastinum are stable.           Bones:  The thoracic skeleton is unremarkable.                IMPRESSION:      No pneumonia or pulmonary edema identified.                  RADIOLOGISTS:                           SIGNATURES:     Lutz, John Gregory                  Lutz, John Gregory





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>