<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2067-08-08

Urgent visit 80 yo man with CAD, anemia.



Just hospitalized while I was away on vacation with DOE and cath showed multivessel CAD. Had PTCA of his RCA and was transfused for worse anemia. Feels less dyspneic. It has been difficult to arrange a colonoscopy. Noted to have some afib but not anticoagulated secondary to anemia. Has some low back pain radiating into his thighs when he walks very far. His wife is concerned about the amount of alcohol he was drinking and Dr. Estrella at the Newton Hosp has ordered a strict limit of 1 oz.





================ Medications ================

ASPIRIN   325MG PO QD

GLUCOTROL     PO 

LISINOPRIL

LASIX

AMBIEN (ZOLPIDEM TARTRATE)  10MG PO HS PRN .

PROCARDIA XL  120MG PO QD

LIPITOR

CLOPIDOGREL



ALLERGIES:  None.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  Married.  Retired.  No cigarettes.



ROS   Back pain. Thigh aching. Fatigue. Rest of ROS is negative.



PE  Looks less fatigued.

197   144/80    60  irreg irreg

HEENT: EOMI  No scleral icterus.

Lungs: Clear

Cor: irreg irreg. No audible murmurs or gallops.

Abd: Obese. Non tender.

Ext: No edema. Trace DP pulses.





================ Problems ================

ANEMIA    We need to work this up quickly as his hematocrit dropped further. He has a chronic hx of mild anemia in the past. Our endoscopy service is overwhelmed at this point. Referred to the Fairfield.         

         

HYPERTENSION    Has had some cough. Will switch back to Cozaar.      

         

DIABETES (FOLLOWED AT CLAIBORNE)     Brings an A1C of 6.1. Continue Actos and Glucotrol.

     

PROSTATE CA        Stable.



ALCOHOL   Reiterate the importance of keeping limit on alcohol.



BACK/THIGH PAIN  Probable spinal stenosis. Would not advocate surgery.



AF  Will check EKG today. This has been sporadic in the past.



CAD  Doing well after angioplasty.



Add: 12 lead EKG in the office shows him to be in AF at 52 with PRWP and T wave abnormalities. We will need to expedite his GI w/u so we can start anticoagulation.  

   











______________________________                              



Jacobson, Isaiah Peter, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-10-03

80 yo man with CAD, anemia, and the chief complaint of buttock pain with ambulation.



He has had some pain in his buttocks when he ambulates a short distance which resolves with standing still. Hip films were unremarkable. No calf pains. He saw Dr. Jaimes for a second opinion and was advised to exercise more and cut down on alcohol. He has had some anemia and his GI w/u at Fairfield was negative. I then started him on Coumadin which he finally started taking.





================ Medications ================

COZAAR  50MG PO QD

HCTZ  25MG PO QD

AMBIEN (ZOLPIDEM TARTRATE)  10MG PO HS PRN .

PROCARDIA XL  120MG PO QD

GLUCOTROL  20MG PO BID

ACTOS (PIOGLITAZONE) 45MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ATENOLOL 50MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN) 40MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS

LASIX (FUROSEMIDE) 40MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

COUMADIN (WARFARIN SODIUM) 2.5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QPM





ALLERGIES:  None.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  Married.  Retired.  No cigarettes.



ROS   Back pain. Thigh aching. Fatigue. Rest of ROS is negative.



PE  Looks less fatigued.



================ Vital signs ================

Blood Pressure:   170/82
Weight:   198   [Pounds]
P 60 irreg irreg

HEENT: EOMI  No scleral icterus. No retinopathy.

No lymphadenopathy. No carotid bruits.

Lungs: Clear

Cor: irreg irreg. No audible murmurs or gallops.

Abd: Obese. Non tender.

Ext: No edema. Trace PT pulse on the right. Could not palpate any on the left.



================ Problems ================

BUTTOCK PAIN   With ambulation. Probably spinal stenosis but I will check some vascular studies.



ANEMIA    GI w/u at Fairfield was negative. I referred him to Dr. Emmons in Hematology today.

         

HYPERTENSION   Did not take meds today.

         

DIABETES (FOLLOWED AT CLAIBORNE)     Brings an A1C of 6.1. Continue Actos and Glucotrol.

     

PROSTATE CA        Stable.



ALCOHOL   Reiterate the importance of keeping limit on alcohol.



AF  I am relieved that he has finally agreed to start the Coumadin.



CAD  Doing well after angioplasty.



PATIENT/PHYSICIAN  He has wanted to see Dr. Jaimes in Cardiology. I explained to him that I am a cardiologist as well and that I have found in the past it does not work out well to have two cardiologists involved in his care. I think Dr. Jaimes is a superb cardiologist and I gave him the number for GCH teleservices to find himself a new internist. He clearly is somewhat conflicted about this and will think about it.











______________________________                              



Jacobson, Isaiah Peter, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2068-10-10


Sheboygan Memorial Medical Center
38 Aston Street                                        SCHWARTZ, XAVIER
Helena, MD 97756                                      49921666
(871) 720-9439                                           10/10/68


This patient of Dr. Bridges was seen because Dr. Bridges was
called away on an emergency basis.

His major concern is results of recent vascular studies.  He has
known diabetes and has a history of several years of exertional
cramping and discomfort in his legs.  This occurs only with heavy
exertion.  Dr. Bridges documented normal pedal pulses the last
visit.

His recent vascular studies showed no significant drop off and
perfusion pressures level of the ankle.

Did given his history a more inclined to suspect this might be
pseudoclaudication due to neuropathy or spinal stenosis.  He will
follow up with Dr. Bridges about next steps.

Ret he declines a flu shot today.


______________________________
FRANK J. XI, M.D.

eScription document:3-638570

DD: 10/10/68
DT: 10/11/68
DV: 10/10/68



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2069-04-15

EDVISIT^49921666^Schwartz, Xavier^04/15/69^NOLAN, N. YANCY(49863884)

TIME OF DICTATION:  10:40 p.m.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Schwartz is an 82-year-old male

who presents to Gwinnett County Hospital Department of

Emergency Medicine.  He was sent to ED by his primary care

physician because of cough, productive of whitish sputum,

wheezing, and mild shortness of breath.  He denies fever.  He

denies chills.  He denies any other acute complaints.  He admits

to the above-mentioned symptoms.  At times they last for two to

three days' duration.  He has a temperature of 95, a pulse of 80,

respiratory rate of 20, blood pressure 153/80, and O2 saturation

95% on room air.

The resident's note was reviewed.  The patient was interviewed. 

The patient was examined by me.  I concur with the workup and

evaluation of the patient in ED.  For a more detailed note on

this patient, please review the resident's note.  Please review

the resident's note for past medical history, surgical history,

review of systems, medications, allergies, family history and

social history.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils

were equal, round, reactive.  Fundi were benign.  Neck was

supple.  Chest was positive for coarse rhonchi and wheezes

bilaterally.  Heart:  Notes a normal S1, S2.  No S3, S4.  No

murmur.  Abdomen is benign, soft, nontender, no masses, guarding,

rebound, and organomegaly.  Extremities:  Grossly within normal

limits.  Neurologically, awake, alert, able to follow all

commands.  Negative Babinski.

Chest x-ray in the emergency department was negative for

infiltrates.  Also negative for interstitial edema.  The EKG

notes a paced rhythm at a rate of 91.  White count of 8,

hematocrit was 36, normal serum electrolytes.  Normal CK, normal

troponin.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

breath most likely secondary to acute bronchitis.

PLAN:  Admit to the Inpatient Service for further workup and

evaluation.

______________________________

NOLAN, N. YANCY M.D. (49863884)	D: 04/15/69

					T: 04/16/69

Dictated By: NOLAN, N. YANCY





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-01-20



Sheboygan Memorial Medical Center

69 Aston Street                                        SCHWARTZ, XAVIER

Helena, MD 97756                                      49921666

(871) 720-9439                                           01/20/70





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is an elderly patient, 82, with known diabetes and coronary artery disease, which has required placement of a pacemaker.



I last saw his blood sugar and it was 276 and his A1c in October was 7.  So, I had him back today to discuss diabetic management and also review his general health in terms of his diabetes and his other medications.



We went over his medications to start with and he is taking them exactly as it was shown in the computer.  These include atenolol 25, Glucotrol 10 twice a day, Actos 45, Lipitor 40 a day, Lasix 40 a day, and Procardia XL 60 mg q.d., and Coumadin.  He is followed by Dr. Itzel Jaimes for his cardiac problems and by a diabetologist at the Claiborne for managing his diabetes.



He had no other complaints.  His bowel movements are regular.  He still has nocturia x3 and was recently seen by a urologist who felt there was no need for any intervention.



He otherwise was in good spirits and has no immediate complaints.



His social situation, his allergies and and his family history and past medical history, are overall as previously recorded.  There are no other pertinent findings in the review of systems.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  His blood pressure was 140/60.  He looks well.  I did not measure his weight.  His heart rate was around 64-68.  His pupils are equal and reactive to light and extraocular movements were full.  Mucous membranes of the mouth and tongue were normal.  Lungs were clear to percussion and auscultation.  Cardiac exam showed regular sinus rhythm, a normal S2 and no significant murmurs.  Liver and spleen were not palpable.  He had only 1+ peripheral edema which is less than usual.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  He seems stable, I think the biggest problem is regulation of diabetes and I have asked him to get a hemoglobin A1c and to measure his blood sugar when he gets up in the morning and in the afternoon before he has supper.  He will come back to see me in about a month's time to follow up on these issues. CAD is stable with pacemaker



HGB A1c is 7.0, Hct is down to 31.6, epo 37, creatinine stable at 1.6, MCV 93.3.  Most likely anemia of chronic illness but need to check smear and stools







______________________________

Xenia Bridges, MD



Plan send stool cards, check iron if not done recently, reviedw smear. 



Dictated By: Xenia Bridges





eScription document:6-0750267 EMSSten Tel







DD: 01/20/70

DT: 01/20/70

DV: 01/20/70



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>