<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2069-03-26



Problems



      Diabetes mellitus

Taking meds below, HbA1C not incontrol at last measure.

      Hypertension

On meds below, feels tired.

      Coronary artery disease

No chest pain.  Had both exercise stress test and dobutamine echo showing borderline inferior thinning.  Seeing Dr. Ily Light.  Had episode of A flutter last month in setting of chest pain and snow shovelling.  Easily converted in hospital.  Now on Coumadin for another 2 wks.

      Atrial flutter    : Converted to NSR

See above.

      Hyperlipidemia    : Syndrome X

Low HDL, high triglycerides, abd obesity, Type 2 DM.  Now starting to exercise regularly and diet.



Medications



      ALLOPURINOL   300MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)



      Potassium Citrate    1020 MG PO TID PRN kidney stones : Takes usually for 4 days



      Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)    81MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD



      Viagra (SILDENAFIL)    100MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO x1



      Zestril (LISINOPRIL)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)



      Micronase (GLYBURIDE)    5MG,  1.5 Tablet(s)  PO BID x 30 day(s)



      Glucophage (METFORMIN)    1000MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO BID x 90 day(s)



      ATENOLOL   50MG,  1.5 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)



      Coumadin (WARFARIN Sodium)    5MG,  1.5 Tablet(s)  PO QPM x 30 day(s)



      Lopid (GEMFIBROZIL)    600MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO BID x 30 day(s)





Narrative History

Here for monitoring of above.  Got event monitor from Ilya Light for occ palps.



Past Medical History

L Bell's 2064 saw Dr. Quint, L eye still tears. Umbilical hernia. Saw Dr. Umstead, said to just watch it.  Records received from Dr. Alcala via Dr. Adams.  2064 value for HbA1C was 9.1,  BP 10/31/64 was 190/105.  EKG WNL.  Records from Dr. Quint and Dr. Faust re Bell's and stones.  On Urocit and allopurinol.



Health Maintenance



      Cholesterol   02/23/2069 182  DESIRABLE: <200



      Rectal exam   03/22/2068    Prostate normal size and consistency.  No masses or tenderness.



      M-alb/creat ratio   03/25/2068 120.5  PERFORMED AT HOLLY MANOR NURSING HOME

(NOTE)Reference Range:  <30.0 mg/g creatinine



      EKG   03/02/2069 RBBB, otherwise normal  



      UA-Protein   04/16/2066 NEGATIVE  



      Ophthal Exam   07/03/2067  Done elsewhere 



      HBA1C   03/23/2068 10.30  



      Microalbumin   03/25/2068 20.0  PERFORMED AT HOLLY MANOR NURSING HOME

(NOTE)Reference Range:

   Random urine    <2.0 mg/dL

   24 hr urine     <300 mg/24 hr





Allergies



      Penicillins    - Rash : 2061.





Social History

  Married. Lives with wife. Sexually active, usually needs Viagra. Communications senior manager, marketing, worked for Brinker International, now Facebook. Then Twitter. Now about to start job as securities investment dealer.



Review of Systems

  General - Neg Eyes - see above Ears - ext ear infs from swimming, wears wax earplugs Mouth - Neg Heart and Lungs - Had chest pain, stress test done at Delnor, 2067, neg. Occ feels skipped beat. Adm in Feb 2069 for A flutter, see above.  GI - Neg GU - impotence, needs Viagra. Musc-skel - elbows bother him at times, after lifting. Skin - legs stasis dermatitis, has cream that helps. Steroid.  Neuro - Bell's in past. Emotional - Neg Endocrine - DM Hematologic - Neg



Vital Signs



      BLOOD PRESSURE   130/70



      PULSE   80



      TEMPERATURE   97.8



      WEIGHT   263 lb





Physical Exam

Skin - stasis dermatitis changes, tr edema both lower legs.  Neck - no adenopathy, thy normal, carotids 2+ without bruit.  JVP < 5 cm.  Lungs - clear to P&A.  Heart - S1S2 normal, no murmur, rub, gallop. Abd - BS normal.  No LSKK, masses, hernias, tenderness, aneurysm.  Feet - no sores.



Assessment

DM - not well controlled in past.  CAD - stable. Atr flutter - resolved.  PVCs.  Hchol.



Counseling

On DM care, importance of controlling blood sugar, wt reduction, need for regular follow-up to work on controlling above.



Plan

Ret 1 mo.  PT/INR, lipids, AST, HbA1C.  Continue above meds.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-02-14

                                                       Patient Name: VERA,XANDER N [ 2152363(BMH) ]





Problems

      Diabetes mellitus

On meds below.  Missed earlier appointment.  Last fasting sugar was 140.

      Hypertension

On meds below, no side effects.

      Kidney stone    : Uric acid

No episodes of colic.  Has small stones on CT one year ago.

      Atrial flutter    : Converted to NSR

No symptomatic palpitations.  No chest pains.  Off Coumadin.

      Hyperlipidemia    : Syndrome X

Taking statin and fibrate, no myalgias, weakness, abdominal pain or anorexia.



Medications

      Zestril (LISINOPRIL)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)

      ALLOPURINOL   300MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)

      Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)    81MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Glucophage (METFORMIN)    1000MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO BID x 90 day(s)

      ATENOLOL   50MG,  1.5 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)

      Lopid (GEMFIBROZIL)    600MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO BID x 90 day(s)

      GLYBURIDE   5MG,  2 Tablet(s)  PO BID x 90 day(s)

      OMEPRAZOLE   20MG,  1 Capsule(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)

      Urocit-k (POTASSIUM Citrate)    10MEQ,  1 Tablet(s)  PO TID x 30 day(s) PRN kidney stone

      Pravachol (PRAVASTATIN)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QHS x 90 day(s)

      Valisone 0.1% (BETAMETHASONE Valerate 0.1%)     LOTION TOP BID x 90 day(s)

      Avandia (ROSIGLITAZONE)    4MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD x 90 day(s)

      Tng 0.4 Mg (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 Mg))    1 TAB SL x1 x 90 day(s) PRN chest pain



Narrative History

Has seen urologist for erectile dysfunction since last visit.  Is taking injections for impotence now.



Past Medical History

  L Bell's 2064 saw Dr. Quint, L eye still tears. Umbilical hernia. Saw Dr. Umstead, said to just watch it.  On Urocit K and allopurinol.  Takes former only when he is having a stone passage problem, because it upsets his stomach.  CAD found in May.  DM recently diagnosed.  Longstanding Hchol on two drugs now.  HT, good control.  GERD, controlled on omeprazole.   Stasis dermatitis, ankles.  T. pedis with nail involvement.



Health Maintenance

      EKG   03/02/2069 RBBB, otherwise normal  

      Ophthal Exam   04/16/2069 No diabetic complications Done elsewhere 

      Colonoscopy   06/20/2068 Normal  

      Cholesterol   07/17/2069 164  

      M-alb/creat ratio   03/25/2068 120.5  PERFORMED AT HOLLY MANOR NURSING HOME

(NOTE)Reference Range:  <30.0 mg/g creatinine

      UA-Protein   04/16/2066 NEGATIVE  

      HBA1C   07/18/2069 9.50  

      Triglycerides   07/17/2069 142  

      Cholesterol-LDL   07/17/2069 104  

      Microalbumin   03/25/2068 20.0  PERFORMED AT HOLLY MANOR NURSING HOME

(NOTE)Reference Range:

   Random urine    <2.0 mg/dL

   24 hr urine     <300 mg/24 hr

      Hct (Hematocrit)   02/22/2069 40.2  

      Cholesterol-HDL   07/17/2069 32  

      Hgb (Hemoglobin)   02/22/2069 13.8  

      Rectal exam   03/22/2068    Prostate normal size and consistency.  No masses or tenderness.



Review of Systems

General -obese, has not been able to lose weight.

Heart and Lungs -see above.

GI -heartburn, improved with omeprazole.

GU -erectile dysfunction, history of kidney stones, none recently.

Skin -feet much improved, seen podiatrist.  Neuro - Neg

Endocrine - AODM



Habits

Tob -     Alc -   Exercise -  



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   140/80

      TEMPERATURE   97.5 F

      PULSE   66



Physical Exam

Lungs - clear to P&A.  Heart - S1S2 normal, no murmur, rub, gallop. Abd - BS normal.  No LSKK, masses, hernias, tenderness, aneurysm.  Rectal - pros 1+, normal consistency, no masses or Feet - no edema or sores.  Position, light touch intact. 



Assessment

DM, fair control.  Hchol.  HT.  GERD.  Erectile dysfunction.  Kidney stone.  A flutter, no symptomatic recurrences since August.



Plan

Fasting lipids, CK, AST, HbA1C, chem 8, Ret 3 mos.  Continue above meds.  All meds renewed. 









______________________________

Xavier Tristan Huerta, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2071-01-30

CARDIOLOGY

BETHESDA MEMORIAL HOSPITAL



Xavier T Huerta M.D. 

BMH Health Associates

583 Appaloosa Place

CHESTERTOWN, NY 91987



Dear Dr. Huerta:



Reason for visit:

   Today, I had the pleasure of seeing Irving Vera in Cardiology clinic. He is a former patient of Dr. Ilya Light. He is a 59-year-old man with diabetes type 2, hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, and mild coronary artery disease who had a brief episode of atrial flutter in 2069. He presented in 2069 with chest pain and rapid heart rate following snow shoveling. He was found to be in atrial flutter with a rapid ventricular response. He was cardioverted two days later and has remained in sinus rhythm since then. Echocardiogram performed on 02/22/2069 showed normal ejection fraction of 72%, borderline left atrium at 43 mm, and no significant valvular abnormalities. Stress test performed on 03/16/2069 showed 5 minutes of exercise, 7 METS, and a peak double product of 22, 000. He had no EKG changes, and a small mild posterobasilar defect suggestive of a very limited area of mild ischemia. The patient has been managed medically since then. He has used an event monitor and since then has not had any subsequent episodes of atrial flutter or fibrillation.



The patient has been doing well over the past several months. Currently, he exercises once or twice a week by swimming 30 minutes in a pool. A few months ago, he was exercising almost everyday. His weight has been up and down. He does not complain of any chest pain, shortness of breath, or other symptoms. Occasionally in the morning when he takes his pulse, he notices a skipped beat. I have reassured him that this is not a cause for concern.



Past medical history:

   Diabetes, hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, atrial flutter as above, coronary artery disease as above, Bell's palsy with residual left eye tearing, kidney stones, and glaucoma.



Current Medications:

  lisinopril 20 mg QD

 Glucophage 1 g BID

 glyburide 10 mg BID

 atenolol 50 mg QAM; Dir: and 25 mg QPM

 Lopid 600 mg BID

 allopurinol 300 mg QD

 omeprazole 20 mg QD

 aspirin 81 mg QD

 Pravachol 80 mg QD

 Avandia 8 mg QD



Allergies:

Penicillin allergy   Penicillin and erythromycin, causing rash.



Family history:

   Not significant for coronary artery disease.



Social history:

   Former tobacco user, works part time in securities.



Review of systems:

   As above, otherwise negative.



Physical examination:

-Pulse:   60

-General:   Obese talkative man in no distress

-Chest:   Lungs are clear bilaterally

-Cardiac:   JVP is 7 cm with normal waveform.  PMI is discrete and nondisplaced.  Regular rate and rhythm with normal S1 and S2.  Soft 2/6 holosystolic murmur heard at the lower left sternal border

-Abdomen:   Obese and tender

-Extremities:   Have trace edema with chronic venous stasis changes



Selected recent labs:

   On 06/18/2070, total cholesterol 168, triglycerides 104, HDL 38, and LDL 109.  His Pravachol dose has been increased since this time.



Assessment and plan:

   This is a 59-year-old man with metabolic syndrome, diabetes type 2, hyperlipidemia, hypertension, obesity, and mild coronary artery disease that has been medically managed. He is doing well. He had an episode of atrial flutter for two days in 2069 but has not had any repeat episodes. He is currently not anticoagulated. Given new recommendations, his target LDL should be less than 70. He is due for a fasting lipid profile in one week. If his LDL is not below 70, then he should either be switched to Lipitor 80 mg day or Zetia should be added to his present regimen. He is slightly hypertensive today with a blood pressure of 140/75. The patient will check his blood pressure at home since he is somewhat anxious male. In the office today, if his blood pressure remains elevated, then I will increase his lisinopril to 30 mg a day. Otherwise, he is doing very well without any cardiac symptoms.



Changes to Medications this visit

lisinopril 20 mg   QD

Glucophage 1 g   BID

glyburide 10 mg   BID

atenolol 50 mg   QAM and 25 mg QPM

Lopid 600 mg   BID

allopurinol 300 mg   QD

omeprazole 20 mg   QD

aspirin 81 mg   QD

Pravachol 80 mg   QD

Avandia 8 mg   QD



Thank you for allowing me to participate in the care of this patient.  If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me.









Steven Vega MD



Signed electronically by   Steven  Vega MD  on  Feb 3, 2071     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-11-16

 

Internal Medicine JAR ADMIT NOTE


Name: Xander Vera
MR #: 2152363
Date of admission: 11/16/2072
Attending: Hodges
Cards Fellow: Steven Vega
PCP: Dr. Xavier Huerta
Code: FULL
 
CC:  SOB, LE edema

HPI:  60M with obesity, DM2, HTN, hyperlipidemia, and stress test in 2069 with mild posterobasal reversible defect managed medically sent to ED by PCP for LE edema and SOB. The patient reports several days of increasing LLE swelling and erythema. He presented to his PCP with a chief complaint of SOB, although he currently denies that. He has also apparently had intermittent left-sided chest pressure x 1 day, which he also denies. +fevers at home to 101. No cough. No nausea/vomiting/diarrhea. No abdominal pain. No urinary symptoms. 

In ED: Febrile to 103. HR in 90s. BP 91-175/46-81, R20s, 95-100% RA. EKG with baseline RBBB. Tn+ at 0.44. LENIs negative for DVT. CT PE negative for PE/DVT. Started on IV heparin. Vanco and levo. Mucomyst x1 dose. ASA 325. Lopressor 25po. NSx 1L.

PMH:   
CAD
--3/69 ETT mibi METS 7, ECG non-dx due to submax HR, small, mild posterobasal defect which improves at rest suggestive for a very limited area of mild ischemia
--2/69 TTE EF 72%, no WMA, no valvular abnormalities, RVSP 27
Diabetes mellitus type 2: 7/72 HbA1c 6.10, +microalbuminuria, mild retinopathy
Hypertension 
Hyperlipidemia: 8/72 chol 169, Tgl 67, hdl 37, ldl 119
Obesity
OSA- recently started on home CPAP at 12cmH20
H/o atrial flutter sp DCCV 2069, no anticoagulation
RBBB
Rectal bleeding: felt to be due to hemorrhoids
Anemia: colonoscopy 2068 wnl; 6/72 Fe 47, TIBC 464, 10%sat, ferritin 38, b12 nl; 7/72 bilis and SPEP normal; 8/72 epo elevated
Nephrolithiasis: uric acid
Glaucoma 
Bells palsy
Stasis dermatitis 
Tinea pedis 

Medications on admission (confirmed with patient):
Allopurinol 300MG PO QD
Asa 81MG PO QD 
Atenolol 75MG PO QD 
Avandia (ROSIGLITAZONE) 8MG TABLET PO QD 
Clobetasol PROPIONATE 0.05% 0.05% CREAM(GM) TOP BID 
Glucophage (METFORMIN) 1000MG PO BID 
Glyburide 10MG TABLET PO BID 
Lopid (GEMFIBROZIL) 600MG TABLET PO BID 
Multivitamin W/IRON 1 TAB PO QD 
Omeprazole 20MG CAPSULE CR PO QD 
Vytorin (80 simvastatin/10 zetia) PO QD
Tng 0.4 MG (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 MG)) 1 TAB SL x1 PRN chest pain 
Urocit-k (POTASSIUM CITRATE) 10MEQ TABLET CR PO TID PRN kidney stone 
Valisone 0.1% (BETAMETHASONE VALERATE 0.1%) LOTION TOP BID 
Vitamin B12 (CYANOCOBALAMIN) 1000 MCG PO QD 
Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ALL:  penicillins, erythromycins, tape   rash

SH: Married with 5 adult children. Works in communications. Denies tobacco/etoh/illicits.

FH:   Father with HTN, arrhythmia. Mother with DM, CAD. Sister and daugther w/ITP.

Physical Exam:  
V:  T 99.2, P72, R18, 112/54, 98% 4L
Gen:  lying with eyes closed
HEENT: PERRL, EOMI, OP clear, thick neck    
Neck:  Supple, no thyromegaly, no carotid bruits, JVP 8cm
Nodes: No cervical or supraclavicular LAN
Cor: RRR, nl S1, S2.  No m/r/g.  Distant heart sounds
Chest: CTAB  
Abdomen: S/NT/ND, +BS. No HSM 
Ext: marked LLE erythema with warmth, 2+ pitting edema; 2+ pedal pulses bilat; chronic venous stasis
Neuro: AAOx3, CNII-XII intact, muscle strength/sensation intact

Labs and Studies:
Na 137, K 3.7, Cl 107, CO2 23.8, BUN 27, Cr 1.5 (baseline 1.3-1.4), glu 85
WBC 15.2 w/ 96%polys, Hct 30.6 (baseline 33), MCV 82, RDW 15.8,  Plt 229

CK-MB, Tn-I POSITIVE at kiosk
#1 CK 347, CK-MB 11.5, CKMBRI 3.3, Tn-T 0.44
#2 CK 663, CK-MB 15.7, CKMBRI 2.4, Tn-T 1.07 

INR 1.4, PTT 32.9

CXR: 2 views, no pneumonia or CHF

LENIs: no DVT bilaterally
PECT: negative for PE/DVT

UA: SG >1.030, 2+blood, 3+protein, nit neg, 0-5 RBC, 3-5 WBC, few bact

Blood cultures: gram +cocci in pairs and chains 2/2 bottles

EKG: NSR at 74bpm, baseline RBBB, no ischemic changes


A/P:  60 yo man with metabolic syndrome presents with LLE edema and SOB with +troponin. Initially concerning for PE but ruled out with LENIs/CT scan. He does have a severe LLE cellulitis now with bacteremia likely due to strep.  His cardiac enzymes continue to increase suggesting ongoing myocardial damage either from silent cardiac ischemia or demand from fever/tachycardia.  Could also consider endomyocarditis secondary to bactermia.


ISCHEMIA
-cont ASA, BB, heparin, statin
-plan for cardiac cath to r/o flow-limiting CAD, although likely delayed due to bactermia
-check TTE r/o endocarditis
-cont to cycle cardiac enzymes
-follow EKGs

BACTEREMIA
-Likely seeded blood stream from cellulitis due to strep, must also consider enterococcus
-Minimal response to vanco overnight
-gentamicin x 1 dose to cover anaerobes/GN
-consider VRE, ?source
-surveillance cultures
-TTE as above

DM
-hold oral hypoglycemics for now
-RISS coverage

RENAL INSUFFICIENCY
-creatinine mildly above baseline
-high risk for contrast nephropathy given DM and underlying renal insufficiency
-continue mucomyst and bicarb, especially with upcoming cath
-follow renal function

NUTRITION
-cardiac, diabetic diet

PPX
-nexium, anticoagulation

FULL CODE




___________________________________________________________
Edan I. Frederick, MD                               
Pager 00212
PGY-2 Medicine






****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-02-07

 

Internal Medicine JAR Admit Note 

Pt: Xander Vera
MR#: 2152363
Date of Admission: 2/7/73
Attending: Alton Uher
PCP: Richard Huerta
Contact: Molly Vera (Wife) 371-514-1494 
Code: Full Code


CC/RFA:  Pt is a 61-year-old man w/ CAD, DM, HTN hypercholesterolemia and recurrent atrial flutter admitted for atrial flutter ablation. 

HPI:  Pt   s cardiac hx begins in 2069 when he presented with chest pain and palpitations while shoveling snow and was found to be in atrial flutter. Pt was subsequently cardioverted to NSR. Pt did well post cardioversion. He was suffered NSTEMI in 11/72 in the setting of bactermia and Streptococcal cellulitis. Coronary angiography showed diffuse non-critical disease; decision was made to manage CAD medically. Pt was found to be in atrial flutter on follow up visit with cardiology. He was referred to Dr. Uher in appx two weeks prior to admission, who recommended radiofrequency ablation of atrial flutter. 

Pt underwent radiofrequency ablation of atrial flutter on 2/7/73. The procedure was was successful and the patient was transferred to the floor in normal sinus rhythm. He has no complaints and specifically reports no CP/SOB/palpitations.

PMH:
Coronary artery disease
Diabetes
Hypertension
Hypercholesterolemia
Atrial flutter.
Hx Bell   s palsy: residual left eye tearing thought to be due to aberrant reinnervation
Kidney stones
Glaucoma
Mild renal failure

Cardiac Hx/Risk Factors: 
Echocardiogram (11/72): EF 71%; left ventricular function normal with symmetric hypertrophy; minimal valvular disease

Stress Test (3/69): normal exercise capacity (METS achieved =  7.); ECG response to stress was  nondiagnostic for ischemia; myocardial perfusion scan show a small, mild posterobasal defect which improves at rest suggestive for a very limited area of mild ischemia

Cardiac Catheterization (11/72): Diffuse mild to moderate CAD: LMCA - 20% plaque; LAD - diffuse plaque; LCx - Diffuse plque in a small AV groove artery; RCA - patent proximally; calcified; Occluded right after take off of PDA, distal branches fill by collats from L


Meds on Admission:  	
  1. Atenolol  PO 50 MG BID
  2. Lisinopril  PO 20 MG QD
  3. Metformin  PO 1000 MG BID
  4. Glimepiride  PO 1 MG QD
  5. Rosiglitazone (Avandia)  PO 8 MG QD
  6. Gemfibrozil (Lopid )  PO 600 MG BID
  7. Ezetimibe And Simvastatin (Vytorin)  po 10mg/80mg qhs
  8. Allopurinol   300 mg QD
  9. Furosemide  PO 20 MG QOD
 10. Omeprazole  PO 20 MG QD
 11. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)  PO 81 MG QD
 12. Cyanocobalamin (Vitamin B12 )  PO 1000 MCG QD
 13. Coumadin (Warfarin Sodium)  PO  QPM
14. Ferrous Sulfate  PO 325 MG QD

All:  	
Clindamycin     rash
Azithromycin     rash
Erythromycin     rash

SHx:	Pt lives with his wife in Guatemala City. He has five children. Former communications manager; currently works part time in securities
Tob:  minimal past use	EtOH:	1 drink/wk	Illicits:	none


FHx:  	Mother: CAD s/p CABG
	
ROS:	
Ten point review of systems negative except as noted in HPI.  

Exam:  	Pt is a well appearing middle-aged man lying comfortably in bed
	VS:  T- 97, HR- 95, BP- 141/63, RR- 18 	
HEENT: MMM, w/o exudates.
Neck:  	supple, NT, full ROM
Chest:  	CTAB; no crackles, no wheezes
CV:  	RRR; normal S1S2, no m/r/g appreciated; JVP 7cm; 2+ carotids without bruit; 2+ radial and DP pulses; R groin dressing w/ small amount of blood, pulse 2+, no obvious hematoma 
Abd:  	bruising across lower abdomen, NABS; soft, non-tender, distended; no organomegaly
Nodes: 	no cervical LAD
Extr:  	1+ bilateral lower extremity edema to knees with chronic erythematous skin changes, non tender 
Neuro: 	AOx3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact, motor and sensory nonfocal

EKG:	NSR, RBBB

________________________________________________________________________________

I/P:  61M w/ CAD, DM, HTN, hyperlipidemia and atrial flutter s/p flutter ablation

Atrial flutter: NSR s/p ablation
Groin check every four hours; monitor for signs of tamponade; anticoagulation with Heparin/Coumadin bridge
Ischemia
Continue ASA, Atenolol
HTN
Continue Lisinopril
DM
Continue Metformin, Avandia, Glimepiride
Hyperlipidemia
Continue Gemfibrozil


Nutrition: Cardiac Diet
Therapists: None
Access: Peripheral 
IV fluids: None
Telemetry: Continuous
Prophylaxis: Heparin /Coumadin, Nexium
Code status: Full Code




_______________________________
Andrew Kendrick, M.D.   (pager # 99225)




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>