<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2088-06-26

Personal Data and Overall Health	

66 year old white female scheduled for surgery on July 1st.



Chief Complaint	

The patient is scheduled for bone-muscle graft from the fibula to the right arm.



History of Present Illness	

The patient complains of a nonunion fx of the right arm in January 2087.



Past Surgical History	

Prior surgery includes:  10 procedurews on the right arm, colectomy, brain tumor.  General anesthesia for all procedures without problems.



Family History	

There in no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.



Past Medical History	

Current medical problems include:  diabetes mellitus, pituitary adenoma, CAD, meningitis, fibromyalgia, severe fatty liver; see attached problem list.



Social History	

Smoking: stopped 15 years ago.

Alcohol use: no history of excessive use

Substance abuse: none



Review of Systems	

Medications:



Prilosec

Vasotec

Serzone

Diflucan

Lipitor

Reglan

Bactrim

Synthroid

Permpro

Prednisone 2.5 mg QD

Valium

Lancet

Humulin NPH 20 units BID



Allergies:  none



Cardiovascular:  no history of hypertension, no MI; hx of well controlled angina, uses NTG rarely, very little exercise, no ankle edema, syncope.

Respiratory: no history of asthma or chronic lung disease; denies unusual shortness of breath; recent productive cough following URI, started on Levaquin.

Neurological: hx of pituitary adenoma with hypophysectomy in 2081, no stroke

Gastrointestinal: no history of PUD; denies reflux but is on Prilosec

Hepatobiliary:  history of liver disease with fatty liver, LFTs are normal at this time except for hypoalbuminemia; denies jaundice or hepatitis

Renal/Genitourinary: no history of renal failure; denies hematuria, dysuria, obstructive uropathy

Musculoskeletal: see PI

Endocrine/metabolic: history of diabetes since hypophysectomy in 2081, BS ~ 100-150; endocrinopathy with pan hypopit, T4 is low.

Heme/Onc:  no history of bleeding, blood diseases; no history of malignancy, chemotherapy, or radiation therapy

Psychiatric: no significant psychiatric problems





Exam	

Ht: 68"

Wt: 224#

BP: 106/58

P: 88

SaO2: 98%



HEEN&T:  good range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat, no bruits

Airway:  Mallampatti Class I or II

Teeth:  dentures

Lungs:  coarse rhonchi bilaterally

Heart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop

Abdomen:  not examined

Extremities:  not examined



Assessment	

ASA Physical Status:  III

Well prepared for surgery; subacute respiratory infection is being treated with Levaquin.  Consider delaying surgery if not improved by time of surgery.



Plan	

Proposed Anesthetic: general anesthesia

Monitors:  standard

Pain Management:  IVPCA

Autologous blood:  none

Premedication:  none

Usual Medications:  take on day of surgery

Medications to be held on day of surgery:  none

Diabetic medications:  10 units NPH on am of surgery

NSAIDS:  avoid for 3 days before surgery

Aspirin:  avoid for 7 days before surgery

NPO: after midnight 



Consider steroid supplement.

Consider insulin infusion.



External Labs	

She has had a stress test.  I will try to get results from PCP.



Attending Anesthesiologist Reassessment Note	

I have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with the following exceptions:











______________________________                              







Hunt, Xavier I., MD



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-10-07





 

NAME:     Olivo, Kimberly

MRN:      3299811 



INITIAL VISIT 



This is a 69-year-old white female coming for her fu visit. 



The patient has a history of type II diabetes mellitus and pituitary adenoma and

recently was hospitalized at American Legion Hospital with general malaise

syndrome and back/chest pain.  Initially the patient was seen at Neligh Clinic and cardiac ischemia was ruled out.  She was found to have a blood

pressure of 250 systolic at Neligh Clinic associated with persistent

headaches.  She was transferred to American Legion Hospital after being

found collapsed on the floor of the hospital bathroom.  She was transferred to the

Intensive Care Unit at Neligh Clinic and treated for tonic-clonic

convulsions with diazepam and lorazepam. She also suffered a urinary tract

infection in hospital, treated with Cipro.



She was transferred to the American Legion Hospital on October 02, 2089,

at which time she was awake but unable to give a history. 



On admission to American Legion Hospital she had a blood pressure of

127/70, pulse was 80, and temperature was 99.3.  She had a myxedematous face and

was obese.  She was cardiovascularly stable.  Neurologically, she was able to move

all four extremities with good strength and symmetrical reflexes.  Cranial nerves

intact.  Initially, the impression was that patient suffered seizure secondary to

elevated blood pressure.  Most likely, she suffered hypertensive encephalopathy. 

Patient underwent neurologic evaluation including MRA of the brain, lumbar

puncture, both of which were negative.  Electroencephalogram was  performed and

showed no epileptiform foci and diffuse temporal slowing bilaterally.  The patient's

alertness and responsiveness increased gradually during the hospital stay.  She had

an episode of chest pain which was associated with some ST flattening in the lateral

leads.  Acute cardiac event was ruled out.  The patient underwent a course of

physical therapy and then, finally, was transferred to a rehabilitation facility.  A

specific cause of the patient's seizure was not found although it was assumed that

this might have been provoked by the hypertensive encephalopathy associated with

use of ciprofloxacin for the treatment of the UTI which could have lowered her

threshold for seizure activity.  Upon discharge, the patient was in stable condition.



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Remarkable for seizure, type II diabetes mellitus,

panhypopituitarism secondary to pituitary surg, hypertension, right arm bone

tumor excision associated with right radial neuropathy, and hyperlipidemia.



MEDICATIONS:  See LMR.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Negative.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Denies alcohol intake, smoking.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Denies visual or hearing disturbance, headaches,

weakness, numbness, seizure activity, chest pain, palpitations, syncope, dyspnea,

wheezing, cough, coryza, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, abdominal pain. 



Positive for mild nocturia with no dysuria.  No polydipsia.  Positive mild

paresthesias right upper extremity.  Occasional mid-morning reactions.  Home

blood glucose monitoring b.i.d. with most glucose readings between 100 and 200. 

Positive mild tiredness without any hoarseness, heat or cold intolerance.  Mild

arthralgia.  No bleeding, rash, pruritus. 



Diet:  Low salt.  Mets 2-3. 



ALLERGIES:  Sulfa, codeine, morphine. 



PHYSICAL EXAM:  General appearance:  Well-developed, well-nourished.  Vital

signs:  Blood pressure 130/80, respiratory rate 18, heart rate 76, temperature

afebrile.  HEENT exam:  No exophthalmos, no lid lag, equally reactive pupils,

difficult to visualize fundi; pharynx clear; ears clear.  Neck:  No JVD, no bruits,

thyroid within normal limits.   Chest:  Clear, no rales or wheezes.  Heart sounds

normal.  No murmurs.  Abdomen:  Soft, nontender, no organomegaly.  Extremities: 

No edema.  Neuro:  Awake and alert although at times forgets details of past

history; no focal neurologic signs.  



A/P:  

1.   Type II diabetes mellitus.good control.  Plan - Continue diet. 



2.   Panhypopituitarism secondary to  pituitary surgery for pituitary adenoma. 

     Need to obtain record from surgeon for details on what type of tumor this

     was.  Patient on replacement therapy with levothyroxine and prednisone. 

     She will continue both with the understanding that should she become sick

     for whatever reason she needs to double or triple dose her prednisone and

     contact me.  She needs to wear a bracelet for this as well as for her diabetes. 

     

3.   Seizure disorder, ? etiology.  She saw the neurologist; she will need to remain on anti-seizure medications.  



4.   Hyperlipidemia:  Plan - Check fast lipid profile.  Discussed with Dr Xavier;P:: lipitor 10 mg /d.



5  Cryptogenic cirrhosis, LFT ok; discussed with Dr Xavier ; no absolute contraindication to lipitor.



6  ? CAD x family; no clear documet; P: adenosine MIBI  since pt is diabetic and unable to perform exercis eETT.



WT loss ? etiol; ct abd neg and cxr neg; P: colonoscopy.



refuses vaccines



To follow up in 2 months. 







Isaac Ng, M.D.

IN/rowe/yeater



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-12-16

Team D Intern Admission Note

Patient Name Here: Olivo, Kimberly

MR# 3299811

Location: Suite 53-02Q

Date of Admission:  December 15, 2091	

PCP:	Isaac Ng 



ID/CC:	Change in mental status



HPI:  70 y/o Female with PMHx significant for Pituitary adenoma s/p resection, cryptogenic cirrhosis, presenting with confusion for the past 3 days. Patient confused and unable to give history at time of admission. As per son and daughter, they have noticed increasing confusion and inappropriate behavior over the past 3 days. They report that she has woken up in the middle of the night c/o feeling weak and confused. The first two nights, her son treated her  initially with increasing lactulose administration when she would wake up at night (although it is unclear whether she had any increase in her stool) and he reports that she would behave better during the day. On the night prior to administration, the patient urinated in her bed at night and called her daughter on the phone in the middle of the night. She also forgot the names of her grandchildren. The son became worried about her behavior, contacted her PCP, and brought her to the ALH ED.



The family reports that she experienced similar behavior prior to grand-mal seizures that were a consequence of uncontrolled hypertension about 2 yrs ago. She also suffers from chronic UTI's and often becomes confused during times of infection.





ED Course: Vitals T 98.2, HR 64, BP 215, 115, RR 24, Sa02 100% NRB. 

Blood Pressure: Treated with labetalol 10 mg IV x 1, Hydral 10 mg IV x 1, decreased to 176/74. 

Hyponatremia: NS x 1 L





PMH:

Pituitary adenoma  2080 s/p resection, XRT

Diabetes mellitus Type II - On Humulin 15/15 

Hypertension - on Avapro, allergy to Ace-I

Angina pectoris - negative stress 



Seizure - According to discharge summaries in YPZ, patient had two episodes of general tonic-clonic seizures at OSH prior to transfer to ALH. Extensive neuro work-up at ALH including MRI/MRA, carotid non-invasives, TCVs, EEG, LP revealed no definitive etiology of seizure but thought to be likely related to her uncontrolled hypertension with systolic BP 250's, her morbid state in setting of UTI, and lower seizure threshold with ciprofloxacin.



Hyperlipidemia - was on zocor, recently switched to zetia, ?myositis

Hypothyroid - central, secondary to pituitary XRT

Arthritis   



Cryptogenic cirrhosis - HIV, HBV, HCV negative (4/90), ANA negative, Anti-mitochondrial Ab negative, no evidence of hemachromatosis, alpha-1-antitrypsin deficiency or Wilson's disease on biopsy, findings consistent with NASH. 



Medications:

Avapro 75MG 1 QD  

Cabergoline 0.25 QWEEK   

Humulin 15 bid  

Kcl slow release 20MEQ 1 QD  

Lactulose 30 TID    

Levothyroxine sodium 100MCG   

Macrodantin 100MG 1 QD    

Nortriptyline hcl 25MG 1 HS   

Prednisone 2.5 QD     

Prempro 0.625 QD     

Serax 15MG 1 QHS     

Zoloft 75MG QD 





Allergies:  	

Sulfa drugs

Codeine

Lisinopril



SH:  	Lives in Ardmore with son. Husband died 3 years ago. Three children.

	Tob:	1 ppd x many years		

	EtOH:  	Denies

	Illicits:  Denies	



Exam:  	VS:	

General:  NAD, extrapyramidal movements, responding to commands. 

HEENT: NC/AT,  Right pupil w/minimal proptosis and unreactive to light, left pupil RRLA, anicteric. EOMI.  OP w/ MMM,

Skin:	No rashes

Neck:  	Supple, full ROM, 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no thyromegaly or nodules, no nodes

Chest:  CTA b/l, coarse upper airway sounds

CVS:  	RRR nl S1 S2, no m/r/g

Abd:  	nl BS, soft, non-tender, no HSM, no fluid wave, no fluid shift

Extr:  	no c/c/e 2+ DP's bilaterally

Neuro: Oriented to person and place. Somnolent but arousable.  Able to follow simple commands. Muscle strength 5/5 except RUE where limited by prior surgery.



DATA: 

Sodium (Stat Lab)        125                L        (135-145)        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)     3.8                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)      98                 L        (100-108)        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)           25.8                        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)           7                  L        (8-25)           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)    0.6                         (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)       128                H        (70-110)         mg/dl

Calcium                  8.8                         (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus               1.9                L        (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                1.5                         (1.4-2.0)        meq/L

Total Protein            6.2                         (6.0-8.3)        g/dl

Albumin                  3.4                         (3.3-5.0)        g/dl

Globulin                 2.8                         (2.6-4.1)        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin         0.2                         (0-0.4)          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin          0.5                         (0-1.0)          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase     75                          (30-100)         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT        12                          (7-30)           U/L

Amylase                  25                          (3-100)          units/L

Lipase                   2.7                         (1.3-6.0)        U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT        18                          (9-32)           U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

Troponin-I               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)



Nortriptyline            <50                                          mcg/L

Desmethylsertraline      PRESENT                                      mcg/L

Sertraline               <50                                          mcg/L

     REF. RANGE: 40-160



WBC                      5.5                         (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                      37.0                        (36.0-46.0)      %

HGB                      13.3                        (12.0-16.0)      gm/dl

RBC                      4.21                        (4.00-5.20)      mil/cmm

PLT                      187                         (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                      88                          (80-100)         fl

MCH                      31.6                        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                     36.0                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                      12.4                        (11.5-14.5)      %

Superstat PT             12.9                        (11.1-13.1)      sec

Superstat PT-INR         1.1

Superstat APTT           30.7                        (22.1-35.1)      sec

Poly                     65                          (40-70)          %

Lymphs                   28                          (22-44)          %

Monos                    4                           (4-11)           %

EOS                      3                           (0-8)            %

Basos                    0                           (0-3)            %



UA-Specific Gravity      1.025                       (1.001-1.035)

UA-pH                    7.0                         (5.0-9.0)

UA-WBC Screen            NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Nitrite               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Albumin                                           (NEG)

     2+SAMPLE SENT TO HEME LAB FOR ADDITIONAL TESTING

UA-Glucose               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Ketones               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Occult Blood          NEGATIVE                    (NEG)



CXR: 

no acute cardiopulmonary process



HEAD CT:

	CT HEAD WITHOUT CONTRAST

	History: Mental status change. Right sided weakness. Hypertension.

	Procedure: Contiguous axial images of the head were performed from

	the skull base to the vertex without intravenous contrast. Bone

	and soft-tissue windows were reviewed.

	Comparison: MRI dated 7/16/91

	Findings:

	The cerebral parenchyma, posterior fossa, basal cisterns and

	ventricular system appear normal. There is no evidence of any mass

	or mass effect. There is no evidence of acute infarction although

	this would be better assessed by MR with diffusion. There is no

	evidence of parenchymal or extra-axial hemorrhage.

	A right frontal mucocele has enlarged since the previous exam. It

	extends into the right orbit resulting in proptosis.  There are

	bilateral lens implants.

	

IMPRESSION:

	No acute intracranial hemorrhage. Enlarging right frontal mucocele

	which causes right proptosis.



Pituitary MRI: (7/91)

	No evidence of recurrent pituitary adenoma.  Interval increase in

	the size of an expansile lesion within the right ethmoid bed, with

	increased extension into the right orbit.  The lesion contacts the

	right globe.  This lesion most likely represents a mucocele.

	

EKG:	NSR @ 73, normal axis, normal intervals, biphasic t wave v2, no sttw changes.



ALH  Cardiology        

25-Oct-2090 13:00  

      DURATION @ MAX DOSE (min:sec) 5:00

      HR (REST=>MAX)          57 => 76  (50% PREDICTED)

      BP (INITIAL=>PEAK)      146/60 => 146/60   (MINIMUM = 114/52)

      PEAK DOUBLE PRODUCT:    11096

ENDPOINT(S):

The protocol was completed. Chest pain did not occur.

The baseline cardiac rhythm was normal sinus rhythm. The rest

electrocardiogram revealed nonspecific ST segment and T-wave

abnormalities. Small inferior q's.  No ST segment changes were observed during this test.  Negative for ischemia. However, the sensitivity of Adenosine-induced ST segment changes for detecting significant CAD is limited.

SCAN RESULTS:

The left ventricle is normal in size. Regional left ventricular perfusion is normal. The left ventricular ejection fraction was 77% on the stress study. Regional wall motion was normal on the stress study.

CONCLUSIONS:

The ECG response to pharmacological stress was  negative for ischemia. The myocardial scans are within normal limits and do not demonstrate evidence of myocardial ischemia or infarction.



ALH  CARDIAC ULTRASOUND        11-May-2087        Serial#  732087     Final

                                     (normal)     (Completed only if abn.)

MITRAL VALVE       NORM  AO    29 mm.(24-39mm)    SEGMENT   BASE  MID  APEX

LEFT ATRIUM        NORM

AV. AO. LVOT       ABN   LA    38 mm.(25-38mm)    anterior

LEFT VENT.         NORM                           ant.sep.

TV. RA. VC.        NORM  LVID  44 mm.(37-53mm)    mid.sep.

PV. INF. PA.       ABN                            inf.sep.

RIGHT VENT.        NORM  PWT   11 mm.( 7-11mm)    inferior

IAS. IVS.          NORM                           inf.pos.

COMPLEX CHD        NORM  IVS   11 mm.( 7-11mm)    pos.lat.

CORONARIES         UV                             lateral

PERICARDIUM        NORM  EF    75 % ( >50 %)



MITRAL VALVE

  There is trace to  mild mitral regurgitation by color and spectral Doppler.

LEFT ATRIUM

  There is no evidence of left atrial dilatation.

AORTIC VALVE, AORTA, LVOT

  Multiple aortic leaflets are thickened but there is no stenosis. There is no

evidence of aortic insufficiency by color and spectral Doppler.

LEFT VENTRICLE

  The left ventricular size and systolic function are within normal limits.

There are no obvious segmental wall motion abnormalities. The estimated

ejection fraction is 75%.

TRICUSPID VALVE - IVC, SVC

  There is color and spectral Doppler evidence of mild tricuspid

insufficiency. There is a prominent Eustachian valve.

PULMONARY VALVE, INFUND., P.A.

  Color and spectral Doppler study c/w trace pulmonary insufficiency. The RV

systolic pressure estimated from the regurgitant tricuspid velocity is 53 mmHg

(assuming an RA pressure of 10mmHg).

RIGHT VENTRICLE

  The right ventricle is not dilated. The right ventricular systolic function

is within normal limits.

PERICARDIAL DISEASE AND EXTRACARDIAC MASSES

  Echo free space between visceral & parietal pericardium is c/w pericardial

fat.



TEST TYPE:  CAROTID ULTRASOUND 10/2089

FINDINGS

 No carotid bruits are heard.  Blood flow velocity is within normal limits in

 the common, internal, external carotid, and extracranial vertebral arteries,

 bilaterally.  Ophthalmic artery flow is normal in direction, via the

 transorbital approach, bilaterally.  Ultrasound visualization of the

 bifurcations is good.  There is dense plaque visualized in each bifurcation.

 Plaque does not alter flow in either vessel.



 IMPRESSIONS:

1.	MINIMAL DISEASE OF BOTH CAROTID ARTERY BIFURCATION.



LIVER, BIOPSY: (11/2089)

     

     NOTE:  There is established cirrhosis, confirmed on trichrome

     stain.  There is a mild to moderate mixed portal tract

     inflammatory infiltrate, composed of lymphocytes, plasma cells,

     and eosinophils.  There is no interface or lobular activity.

     There is mild macrovesicular steatosis. There are scattered

     glycogenated nuclei in periportal hepatocytes, consistent with

     diabetes and/or obesity. There is mild periportal edema and

     copper deposition, consistent with chronic cholestasis. There is

     no Mallory's hyaline.  There is no evidence of hemachromatosis,

     alpha-1-antitrypsin deficiency or Wilson's disease based on iron,

     PAS/D, and copper stains, respectively. The inflammatory

     infiltrate is not ductulocentric, and there is minimal bile duct

     damage. Immunostains for cytokeratins 7 and 19 highlight

     bile ductular reduplication, but there is no ductopenia. The

     findings of cirrhosis are not specific, but are compatible with

     end-stage non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH).

___________________________________________



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



70 y/o female with PMHx sig for pituitary adenoma s/p resection, cryptogenic cirrhosis, hypothyroidism, htn, DM, who presents with increasing confusion and depressed mental status.



1.	Change in mental status

1.	Hyponatremia - Euvolemic by exam, Serum sodium 125, Serum Osm 262, Urine sodium 126, Urine Osm 387. Consistent with SIADH (euvolemic hypotonic hyponatremia, Uosm>100, Una>20). Will place on fluid restriction, follow correction rate slowly. Past Na levels: 130 (10/91), 135 (6/91), 133 (1/91). Other etiologies: diuretics, polydipsia, adrenal insufficiency, hypoaldo, third-spacing less likely. 

2.	Hepatic encephalopathy - known cirrhosis, on home standing lactulose. By exam, no asterixis. Abdomen obese but no obvious fluid collection. Somewhat tender, no peritoneal signs. Will schedule for Abdominal U/S to r/o ascites. Low suspicion for SBP, will hold off prophylaxis antibiotics.

3.	Hypertensive encephalopthy - history of mental status changes and seizures with elevated blood pressures in the past. Extremely hypertensive upon presentation to the ED. Will continue to titrate up beta-blocker as tolerated, MAP goal reduction of 25% obtained, will continue to lower with PO agents. Consider MRI to look for PLE changes.

4.	Infection - history of chronic UTIs. U/A negative, CXR negative. Will send blood cx and urine cx to complete fever work-up. 

5.	Standard work-up - TSH, RPR, B12, Folate, cortisol



2.	Diabetes - Finger sticks with sliding scale insulin coverage QID

3.	Hypothyroidism - check TSH, T4, T3. Recent adjustment to synthroid dose. 

4.	Prolactinoma - Check prolactin level, have patient bring in home cabergoline for weekly dose.











_________________________________

Taquan Q. Cantu, MD

Pager #30547




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-06-29


AMERICAN LEGION HOSPITAL 
 
NEUROCRITICAL RESIDENT ADMIT NOTE

Name: Ollivo, Kimberly

MRN: 3299811

Date: 6/29/97

Time of Exam: 5:20 p.m.

NICU day: 1




Critically ill secondary to: 
R. BG/thalamus hemorrhage with IVH extension, with potential for fatal neurologic deterioration

Critical Care Min: 35 min




History: Ms. Olivo is a 75-year-old RHW with DM, HTN and dementia, LSW at 11:00 a.m., then found by son at 1:45 pm to be less responsive with left-sided weakness. BP was 200/96 when EMS arrived. Here her SBP was in the 220s with heart rate in the 50-60s.  Her initial exam revealed somnolence, but able to follow some very simple commands like squeezing hand, nodding head; she had right gaze deviation, left hemianopsia, left facial palsy, left arm 
and leg plegia, right arm and leg paresis, and dysarthria.  She received 10 mg of hydralazine for her SBP greater than 220.  CT revealed a right basal ganglia/thalamic hemorrhage with intraventricular extension including casting of the 4th ventricle, 7 mm mls to the left, contrast extravasation suggestive of active hemorrhage but no evidence of any vascular abnormality.  She was intubated for worsening mental status and had an a-line placed for Bp monitoring and management. 



At baseline, Ms. Olivo is wheelchair-bound, according to her daughter, due to her neuropathy.  She is dependent for all of her ADLs and has a home health aide.  



PMHx: DM, HTN, dementia, h/o sz d/o not on AED now, Pituitary adenoma, s/p hypophysectomy, hypothyroidism, COPD, dyslipidemia, obesity, fatty liver, fibromyalgia, arthritis, depression, anxiety, meningitis, Rt humerus fx/osteo/nonunion, Cirrhosis or unclear etiology with hyperammonemia, Neuropathy with paresthesias, presumably due to diabetes



Home meds: Mirtazapine 15 mg daily, Namenda 10 mg daily, Potassium supplementation 20 meq daily, Levothyroxine 100 mcg daily, Metoprolol (unclear if metoprolol succinate or tartrate) 25 mg daily, Prednisone 2.5 mg daily, MVI



All: Morphine ( Unknown ) Codeine ( Unknown ) ACE Inhibitor ( Unknown ) LISINOPRIL (cough ) CIPROFLOXACIN HCL (dec effects of sz med ) ATORVASTATIN (abnormal LFT )



SH: Lives with her son in Ardmore. Has two sons and a daughter. Daughter, Yolanda, is the HCP (817-638-1328) and primary caregiver.  She quit smoking 16 years ago.




24 hour events: admitted to NICU




Flowsheet Data:

VS: Tm  HR 
52-70 SR SBP 223/90 &#224; 148/53 MAP  RR 19 O2 sat 100 % on FiO2 1.0

CVP ICP  CPP 

ICU Titrateable Drips: propofol

Vent Settings: AC f12 PEEP 5.0 FiO2 1.0 PC 12

TBB:  since MN 

EVD output: 

Maintenance IVF: D5NS 

Nutrition:  npo

IVF: D5NS

FSBG: 




Lines: L. Rad art line



Significant Medications: propofol
, RISS, peridex, synthroid, lactulose



Significant LABS: INR  1.1 Plt 273


Physical Exam 

Cardio: S1, S2, reg

Pulm: CTAB

Abd: soft, hypoactive bowel sounds

Skin:  erthematous lesions with centers of white rash in skin folds: neck, under breasts

Ortho: R. arm fracture (old)



Neuro Exam: Off sedation &#8211; no verbal response to noxious stimuli, intermittently extensor postures; minimally reactive small pupils, midline gaze in primary position, able to x-midline, no BTT, + R. corneal brisk vs. L., grimace to nasal tickle better on the L. than on the R., R. UE slight w/d to deep noxious stim, plegic in LUE., w/d briskly in the L. LE vs. RLE, toes up b/l




Imaging/Studies/TCD: 

Head CT/A (6/29):  Prelim read shows a right basal ganglia/thalamic hemorrhage (1.87 cm x 4.5 cm in largest dimension) with intraventricular extension including casting of the 4th ventricle, and mls of 7 mm to the left.  CTA showed at least 3 spot signs indicating active hemorrhage but no evidence of any vascular abnormality.





Assessment: 
Olivo is a 75-year-old right-handed woman with diabetes mellitus, HTN and dementia, and found with a ~ 11 cc R. BG/thalamic bleed with pan-ventricular extension with casted 3rd and 4th ventricles, and mild midline shift. The etiology appears to be hypertensive in nature; CTA was negative for a vascular anomaly. A mass lesion cannot be excluded at this time however, and will need an MRI. Her prognosis is somewhat difficult to articulate at this time using the conventional FUNC  (8) and ICH (2) scores given her clinical status and medical  comorbidities. 




Plan:

Neuro: ICH with IVH, prior h/o sz d/o not AEDs now

-Serial neuro exams

-repeat I-HCT in 6 h  (at 9:45 p.m.), 24 h (6/30/97 at 3:45 p.m.), and STAT with exam change

-SBP goal &lt; 140 mm Hg

-A-line

-propofol for  BP control

-HOB &gt; 30 degrees

-no antiplatelet or anticoagulants 

-labetalol prn, nicardipine prn

-no need for AEDs unless declares self with new sz (has been stably off AEDs for prior h/o Sz d/o)

-MRI to r/o underlying mass lesion when able

-N. Surg c/s appreciated for EVD placement




Pulm: 

-intubated

-wean as tolerated

-daily CXR while intubated




CV: HTN, HL, angina

-BP control as above

-Tn x 3

-SBP goal &lt; 140 mm Hg






RENAL: 


-foley, strict I/O

-no hypotonic fluids

-D5 NS for now

-trend UOP, Cr

-renoprotection for iv contrast

-replete lytes



ID: 


-follow U/A, temp, WBC 

-nystatin for crural dermatophytosis



GI/Nutrition: Cirrhosis

-daily LFTs
, NH3
-lactulose at home dose

-npo

-IV fluids for now



Heme: 

-trend CBC

-type and hold

-no antiplatelet or anticoagulation for now




Endo: DM, hypothyroid

-synthroid 

-Fsg q6h

-RISS




Skin:

-Nystatin

-turn and position q2h




Ortho:


-Old R. arm fx per family

-baseline R. elbow XRay pending



Prophy: DVT teds &amp; boots, fragmin if repeat CT stable in 48 h Sz - 
GI PPI VAP peridex Restraints -




CODE/Dispo: FULL/ICU

-continue code status discussion with the family








_______________________________

Yuval Xaysana, M.D., Ph.D.

Neurology Resident



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>