<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2088-03-06

                     RHINELAND EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

PIERRE,EDEN   241-52-56-3                      VISIT DATE: 03/06/88

The patient was evaluated by me with a resident.  The resident's 

history was reviewed and the patient interviewed and examined.  

Briefly, history is as follows.    

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 72 year-old 

female complaining of chest tightness lasting approximately 30 

minutes after climbing stairs at home.  She reports she has been 

having increasing bouts of shortness of breath over the preceding 

week.  She denies diaphoresis, palpitations or radiations.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  There is chest pain, as noted above, and 

shortness of breath, as noted above.  All other systems are 

negative except as noted. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Previous myocardial infarction and 

hypothyroidism.

MEDICATIONS:  See nursing note.

ALLERGIES:  Morphine sulfate. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  The patient is a past smoker 

and a nondrinker who lives alone.  Family history is 

noncontributory.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Awake, alert and in no acute 

distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Stable and normal.  HEENT:  Benign.  NECK: 

Supple.  LUNGS:  Breath sounds showed left lower lobar rales and 

rhonchi.  HEART:  Regular rate and rhythm.  ABDOMEN:  Soft and 

non-tender. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Electrolytes were normal.  Cardiac enzymes 

were negative.  CBC was normal.  EKG showed sinus rhythm with 

nonspecific ST-T wave changes.  Chest x-ray showed mild 

cardiomegaly without other abnormality.  

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was treated with 

aspirin, beta blockers, and oxygen.  Ultimately she was admitted to 

the hospital for definitive evaluation and further care following 

consultation with the DHD cardiologist.  See resident's note for 

further details. 

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Admitted in 

stable condition.

___________________________________                    FT188/35814 

ORLANDO R. PIERRE, M.D.   OP63                            D:03/07/88 

                                                       T:03/07/88 

Dictated by:  ORLANDO R. PIERRE, M.D.   OP63 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-03-28

                     RHINELAND EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

PIERRE,EDEN   241-52-56-3                      VISIT DATE: 03/28/89

The patient was interviewed and examined by myself with the 

resident on 3/28/89.  Please see resident's note for full details.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a female with 

history of coronary artery disease, AICD, and cardiomyopathy who 

comes in today with chest pain, onset iffy while she is walking, 

substernal right anterior chest.  Went to sleep, had some shortness 

of breath, no diaphoresis, nausea or dizziness.  Similar to this 

pain in the past was her myocardial infarction.  She has chronic 

risk factors of hypercholesterolemia, apparent menopausal, 

echocardiogram on 9/87, 10 to 15% global hypokinesis.  

Catheterization is left main disease, 50% ostial disease.           

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As in history of present illness but no recent 

upper respiratory infection symptoms or orthopnea, or exercise 

intolerance.    

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As above.  Surgery procedure:  ASAD 

placement.   

MEDICATIONS:  See nurses notes for details. 

ALLERGIES:  See nurses notes for details. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  No tobacco or ETOH.  Lives with 

family, accompanied by a friend tonight.  Family history:  

Diabetes.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Alert and awake, pleasant female in no 

apparent distress.  Agree with resident's documentation including 

normal pulse, blood pressure 120/86, 02 sat 98%.  Clear lungs.  

Heart is regular rate and rhythm.  Abdomen is soft.  Neuro:  Alert 

and oriented x3.  No obvious cranial, or motor or sensory deficit.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Given her history of coronary artery 

disease and her symptoms an electrocardiogram was unchanged.  

Hematocrit is 37.  BUN and creatinine 19 and 1.  Liver function 

tests are within normal limits.  CK 127, troponin .01.  

Electrocardiogram, rhythm is paced, unchanged from priors.  Chest 

x-ray is mild congestive heart failure compared to prior 

examinations.    

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Aspirin was given and she is chest 

pain free currently.  Case was discussed with Guzmans Hospital 

Cardiology.  Will try for an exercise tolerance test later on in 

the afternoon.  Care was discussed with Dr. Rhodes.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain, rule out acute coronary syndrome.  

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Patient 

currently in stable condition.  

___________________________________                    ZP289/32887 

FLORENCE F. CASEY, M.D.     FC44                      D:03/28/89 

                                                       T:03/28/89 

Dictated by:  FLORENCE F. CASEY, M.D.     FC44 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-07-15

EDVISIT^24152563^Pierre, Eden^07/15/90^MCCARTY, QUINTON

Seen with Dr. Feliciano.  The past medical history, social

history, family history, review of systems, medications, and

allergies were reviewed and confirmed.  Please see resident's

note for further details.  I had interviewed and examined the

patient myself.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, this is a 75-year-old

female with a known history of CAD, status post MI, EF of 10 to

15% with an AICD placement.  Also, history of CHF and

hyperparathyroidism.  She presents with complaints of shortness

of breath for the past 3 hours with some epigastric discomfort. 

She denies fever, chills, or cough.  She has had some abdominal

and chest discomfort.  She may be from 1 year ago showing no

reversible ischemia but a previous catheterization showing no

disease.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She lives with her family.  She is a former

smoker.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative.

MEDICATIONS:  She takes albuterol, Lipitor, captopril, digoxin,

Levoxyl, Lasix, and Coumadin.

ALLERGIES:  Has allergies to morphine.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile, heart rate111, blood

pressure 105/7118, and oxygen saturation 100% on 4 liters.  She

is awake, alert, and in moderate distress.  HEENT: 

Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils:  Equal, round and reactive to

light.  Sclerae are anicteric.  Neck is supple and nontender. 

Chest is with bibasilar crackles.  Cardiovascular exam: 

Irregularly irregular with a 2/6 systolic murmur at the left

upper sternal border.  Abdomen is soft and nontender.  Skin is

warm and dry.  Extremities without clubbing, cyanosis, or edema. 

Neurological:  Alert and oriented.  Cranial nerves II through XII

are intact.  There are no motor or sensory deficits.

Initial cardiogram showing numerous PVCs with occasional negative

complex is consistent with her previous EKG with the appearance

of likely atrial fibrillation.  After some diuresis and a beta

blockade, she has slowed down to the 90s from the 130s and

appeared to have normal sinus rhythm with frequent PVCs.  Her

chest film shows some mild CHF, and she was started on heparin.

LABORATORY DATA:  Sodium 134, glucose 178.  Normal extending

chemistries.  CK of 115 with an MB of 2.  Digoxin level is 0.8. 

TSH is 8.8.  Troponin is less than assay.  White count is 7.5,

hematocrit 42, and platelets 238,000.  INR 2.1.  Heparin was not

initiated as she was already anticoagulated, but she did receive

diuresis.  She is admitted in stable condition.

CLINICAL IMPRESSION:  Unstable angina with frequent PVCs.  Her

cardiology consultation is pending at this time.

______________________________

MCCARTY, QUINTON M.D.

D: 07/16/90

T: 07/16/90

Dictated By: MCCARTY, QUINTON

eScription document:1-6926631 BFFocus

******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-10-14

EDVISIT^24152563^Pierre, Eden^10/14/91^PITTMAN, THOMAS

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Shortness of breath.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 67-year-old female

with end-stage cardiac disease with ischemic cardiomyopathy, who

I see together with the resident.  The resident's history was

reviewed.  The patient was interviewed and examined by me.  In

brief, apparently the EMS was summoned to the scene inadvertently

this morning.  She is end-stage, she is on hospice and comfort

measures only, and she apparently was quite poorly feeling this

morning and was transported.  Her son has called several times

and wants to transport her back in a discussion with her.  She is

quite weak and understands her circumstances, wishes to be

transported back as well.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY, REVIEW OF SYSTEMS, SOCIAL HISTORY,

MEDICATIONS, AND ALLERGIES:  All per the chart.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is alert.  She certainly appears

end-stage.  She has a JVP at 14-16 cm.  She has lungs with

decreased breath sounds throughout her heart.  There is a 3/6

holosystolic murmur heard very weakly.  Her abdomen is soft and

nontender without organomegaly.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  She has electrocardiogram, which is

remarkable for sinus rhythm with nonspecific intraventricular

conduction delay and ugly appearing.  Electrocardiogram is rather

wide complexed.  She has a first-degree AV block and a leftward

axis.  The case was discussed with her cardiologist, social

worker, case manager, and family and she is discharged home.

IMPRESSION:  End-stage ischemic cardiomyopathy.

DISPOSITION AND PLAN:  She is discharged home to continue with

hospice and expectant care.

______________________________

PITTMAN, THOMAS M.D.

D: 10/14/91

T: 10/14/91

Dictated By: PITTMAN, THOMAS

eScription document:1-6434630 BFFocus

******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>