<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2096-02-15

                     ST VINCENT EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
LAU,HELEN M.   544-41-32-1              VISIT DATE: 02/15/96
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Syncope.  History and Physical reviewed.
Patient examined with the Medicine Resident and medical student.
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this is a 68 year old
female with a history of coronary artery disease and syncope in the
past who presents with two syncopal episodes today while in the
Orthopedic Clinic.  The patient was in the Orthopedic Clinic having
her trigger finger evaluated and had a digital block done with
Lidocaine.  As she was walking out of the Clinic, she slumped to
the chair, hit her head on the table and was out for a few minutes.
Patient felt a pressure like sensation in the left chest with
radiation to the neck, some shortness of breath and diaphoresis
immediately preceding the event.  When patient came to was slightly
disoriented and approximately five minutes later felt the same
light headedness and again lost consciousness while sitting in the
chair.  Patient had no fever, chills or recent illness.
Past Medical History, Current Medications, Social History,
Allergies all per Resident's note.
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Per HPI, otherwise negative.
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Patient's temperature was 98.2; Pulse 62;
Blood Pressure 163/89; Respirations 20; Oxygen saturation 97%.
General: Well developed elderly female in no apparent distress
sitting on the gurney.  HEENT: Is unremarkable.  Neck: Supple.
Chest: Is clear.  Heart: Is regular rate and rhythm.  Abdomen: Is
soft, nontender.  Extremities: No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.
Neurologic exam: Patient is alert and oriented x three, cranial
nerves are intact, motor 5/5, sensation intact throughout.
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  EKG shows normal sinus rhythm with no acute
changes.  CPK was 98, troponin pending.  Other labs were
unremarkable.
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Syncopal episode with chest pressure.
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Patient will be
admitted to the Hospital for rule out MI, Short Stay Unit, for
further work up and care.
Condition on admission stable.
___________________________________                    XD305/7899
IVAN UHER, M.D.  IU67                                D:02/15/96
                                                       T:02/15/96
Dictated by:  IVAN UHER, M.D.  IU67
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-07-19

                     ST VINCENT EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
LAU,HELEN M.   544-41-32-1              VISIT DATE: 07/19/96
The patient was seen by me and Dr. Foust 07-19-96 at 8:30 a.m. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT and HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The 
patient is a 67-year-old black female complaining of substernal 
chest pain times one hour while at the Pain Clinic this a.m.  The 
complaints are presently resolved.  The patient states she was 
being seen in the Pain Clinic for back pain, and developed the 
sudden onset of substernal chest pain associated with shortness of 
breath, nausea, vomiting, and diaphoresis, as well as syncope. 
The patient states the pain was a 10/10, worse than normal angina, 
and also reports one episodes of hematemesis this a.m., with a 
small amount of red blood in the vomitus.  The patient denies 
abdominal pain, weakness, or any other complaints. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Positive for angina.  Positive 
catheterization approximately two years ago, with 30-40% lesions. 
Also, history of insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus and spinal 
stenosis. 
CARDIAC RISK FACTORS:  Hypertension, increased cholesterol, 
diabetes mellitus. 
MEDICATIONS:  Metoprolol, lovastatin, Macrodantin, Motrin, insulin 
70/30, nitroglycerin, and aspirin. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  This is a well-developed, well-nourished 
female lying on the stretcher, presently without complaints.  The 
blood pressure is 194/88, the pulse 90, the respirations 16, and 
the O2 saturation 97% on 2 liters per nasal cannula.  The HEENT 
examination reveals a normocephalic, atraumatic head.  The pupils 
are equal and reactive, and the extraocular movements are intact. 
The chest shows positive bibasilar rales and is otherwise clear. 
The abdomen is obese and soft, with positive bowel sounds.  The 
heart has a regular rate and rhythm.  The extremities are without 
cyanosis, clubbing, or edema.  The rectal examination is 
guaiac-negative.  On Neurologic Examination, the patient is alert 
and oriented times two (could not give the exact date); otherwise, 
no focality. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The EKG shows a sinus rhythm unchanged from 
previous EKGs, with a normal interpretation and no signs of acute 
ischemia. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient is admitted to the 
hospital for rule out MI.  Aspirin is given.  Further work-up as 
per the inpatient Medicine team.  The patient was admitted in 
stable condition at 11:15 a.m. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Rule out myocardial infarction (MI). 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  As above.  The 
condition on admission is stable. 
___________________________________                    OX540/6976 
MARY LUND, M.D.  ML82                               D:07/19/96 
                                                       T:07/19/96 
Dictated by:  MARY LUND, M.D.  ML82 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-10-17

                     ST VINCENT EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
LAU,HELEN M.   544-41-32-1              VISIT DATE: 10/17/96
PRESENTING COMPLAINT and HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The 
patient is a 68-year-old female status post CABG in September of 
this past year.  She comes in with an acute headache this morning, 
followed by a syncopal event, which lasted approximately five 
seconds.  Currently, she is complaining of intermittent chest pain 
and a continuing headache across her head and down to her eyes. 
PAST MEDICAL and SURGICAL HISTORY:  The past history is notable for 
her CABG, as well as for a history of temporal arteritis. 
MEDICATIONS:  She was on prednisone, which was recently stopped. 
The rest of the PAST MEDICAL HISTORY, MEDICATIONS, and ALLERGIES: 
As documented in the written chart by the resident physician, and 
as reviewed by me. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On physical examination, she is an elderly 
black female in no acute distress.  She has a temperature of 100 
degrees F., a pulse of 90, and a blood pressure of 150/70.  The O2 
saturation is 97% on room air.  The examination is notable for a 
surgically altered pupil in the right eye, which is non-reactive. 
The extraocular movements are intact.  She has no palpable temporal 
or skull tenderness.  The lungs show rhonchorous breath sounds 
throughout.  The cardiovascular examination shows a midline scar, 
with a regular rate and rhythm and no murmur.  The abdomen is soft 
and non-tender.  The extremities show 1+ pitting edema bilaterally. 
The neurologic examination is grossly intact. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  This is an elderly female status 
post recent CABG, who had a syncopal episode this morning after 
complaining of a headache.  The plan at this time is to obtain a 
head CT to rule out an intracerebral process.  She has had an EKG, 
which does show some T-wave changes, different from when she was 
here for her CABG.  She will also have cardiac enzymes sent and 
will be admitted to the hospital for further monitoring of her 
syncopal event. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  As above.  The 
patient's condition on admission is stable. 
___________________________________                    HA563/486 
FRANCES LOVELL, M.D.  FL01                           D:10/17/96 
                                                       T:10/17/96 
Dictated by:  FRANCES LOVELL, M.D.  FL01 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-01-30

                     ST VINCENT EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
LAU,HELEN M.   544-41-32-1              VISIT DATE: 01/30/97
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain and shortness of breath. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a lady who has a history 
of a coronary artery bypass graft in September of 2096, who 
presents complaining of chest pain.  The patient describes it as 
being sharp and stabbing.  It was associated with some diaphoresis. 
She states that this pain is similar to her angina, however, it is 
more frequent and persistent.  She has no fever, no chills, no 
cough, no vomiting, no diarrhea, no abdominal pain, and no urinary 
symptoms. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Past medical history is significant for 
hypertension, coronary artery disease, insulin dependent diabetes, 
chronic renal insufficiency, breast cancer, depression, mitral 
valve replacement, and hypothyroidism. 
MEDICATIONS:  Medications are multiple and are on the chart. 
ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  The patient never smoked. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient was afebrile and vital signs 
were stable.  This is a well-developed, well-nourished female who 
was alert and oriented times three.  Heent examination was 
normocephalic, atraumatic.  Neck was soft and supple with no 
jugular venous distention.  Mouth and throat normal with well 
hydrated, moist mucosa.  Conjunctiva was clear.  Sclera were 
anicteric.  Heart had a regular rate and rhythm.  Lungs were clear. 
Abdomen was non-tender and non-distended.  The patient had no 
hepatosplenomegaly.  Extremities showed no clubbing, cyanosis or 
edema.  Rectal was heme negative. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  EKG showed first degree AV block, no acute 
ischemic changes.  Chest x-ray showed mild pleural effusion.  White 
count was 9.7.  Hematocrit was 28.  CPK and troponin were negative. 
Electrolytes were normal for her.  BUN and creatinine were 32 and 
1.2. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  Nursing notes were reviewed.  The 
patient was seen with the resident physician, Dr. Nix, and I 
agree with his note.  Please see chart. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Unstable angina. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 
be admitted.  Condition at this time is satisfactory. 
___________________________________                    MG040/1987 
VIRGIL HARRELL, M.D.  VH79                                D:02/12/97 
                                                       T:02/13/97 
Dictated by:  VIRGIL HARRELL, M.D.  VH79 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>