<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2089-02-20



Vi K. Xayarath, M.D., Ph.D.

Resident, Phoenix Neurology

Neurology ED Consult





   





Date:	Thursday, February 20, 2089    21:42	

PCP:	Rhonda Riddle; (called by Valerie Xian)	

Patient:	Garrison Sexton	

HDH Record #	4210443	



	

Chief  Complaint:  "dizzy, slurred speech" 		

History of Present Illness:  65 year old RH gentleman with Hx notable for HTN and CASHD, was working on taxes and making barbecued chicken this afternoon, when at 1am he had the sudden onset of feeling "dizzy, disoriented" and having "slurred speech". He reports that he "couldn't remember what I was trying to say", and that his words both sounded "like [I] was drunk". He also stated that at times, when he would try to talk, nothing would come out. He walked downstairs, with difficulty, and his wife noticed that in the hallway he was bumping into items on (falling to) his right. Denies weakness, paresthesias, pain.  EMTs report that when asked the President's name, pt responded "Chrysler Dodge". Brought initially to OSH, symptoms mostly resolved within 20 minutes. I- CT at OSH negative. Pt transferred to HDH ED at suggestion of covering PCP.  		

Past Medical Hx:  HTN, Coronary artery disease (s/p angioplasty and atherectomy; s/p CABG x 5 in 2081), diabetes mellitus, prostate ca (s/p radical retropubic prostatectomy 4/0, negative nodes and margins), obesity. Bladder suspension.  Baseline bradycardia (40s average).  		

Allergies:   Hydrochlorothiazide, furosemide, gemfibrozil, amoxicillin, hydrocodone, oxycodone 		

Medicines: Isosorbide 20 qid Cardizem  HCM 180 qD Atenolol 25 qD ECASA 325 qD Atorvastatin 10 qD Glucophage 500 bid Avapro 150 qD Bumetanide 1 qD Claritin 1 qD 		

Family History:  Mom with stroke in her 80s 		

Social History:  Married 41 years. Pastor (still practicing). No cigarettes. EtOH < 1 glass wine/month.   		

Review of Systems:  Mild frontal HA, no tinnitus, no CP/SOB/abdom pain. + diplopia occasionally this AM (horizontal), no dysuria. 		

Examination:	 

Gen:  Pleasant 65 yo RH gentleman, NAD 148/67 P44-48  R16 RRR No carotid/occipital bruits.  

Neurologic exam 

MS: Alert, interactive, NAD. Fully oriented. Accurate describes stroke card scene.  

Speech: Articulate, appropriate. Reading and repetition intact. Naming all items on stroke card ("couch"; when asked for alternative, "chair"). Several hesitancies of speech, occasional phonemic paraphasic error (recognized).  

CN: PERRL 4  2 bilaterally, EOMI, VFFtC, facial sensation intact, eyes shut tight, smile symmetric, hearing intact, palate elevates symmetrically, shoulder shrug strong, tongue midline.  

Motor: 5/5 strength UE/LE bilaterally proximally and distally. Normal tone/bulk. No fasciculations noted. No drift. Rapid finger movements slightly slower on R (dominant side) than L.  

Sensory: Pinprick, temperature, light touch, vibration, proprioception intact.  

Reflexes: 2+ B/T bilaterally. 21+ patellar, 1+ ankle reflexes. R toe up, L toe down (could not repeat 1 hour later).   Coordination: F-N-F intact. Rapid alternating movements intact.  

Gait: Normal. Tandems well. Romberg negative.              

  CXR: pending 

CT: from OSH, mild cortical atrophy with mild hydrocephalus ex vacuo. Basilar artery is prominent, though not severely hyperdense.   	



 







Labs:  

NA        	142       	          	          	          	          

 K         	4.0       	          	          	          	         

  CL        	102       	          	          	          	           

CO2       26.2      	          	          	          	           

BUN       34   	          	          	          	           

CRE       1.6   	          	          	          	           

GLU       106    	          	          	          	         

CA        	8.7       	          	          	          	           

PHOS      3.3       	          	          	          	           

MG        1.6       	          	          	          	            

WBC       	9.4       	          	          	          	           

HCT       	37.1(L)   	          	          	          	         

  HGB       	13.3(L)   	          	          	          	          	          	          	          	          

 PLT         	152       	          	          	          	           

MCV       	80        	          	          	          	          	          	          	          

 RDW       	13.0      	          	          	          	          	          	           

%NEUT     	58        	          	          	          	           

%LYMPH    	32        	          	          	          	         

  %MONO     	6         	          	          	          	          

 %EOS      	3         	          	          	          	           

%BASO     	1         	          	          	          	           	          	          	          

 PT        	12.8      	          	          	          	         

 PTT       	25.8      	          	          

	          	          		

 Impression: 65 year old gentleman with multiple stroke risk factors, onset of dysarthria, aphasia, dizziness, ataxia at 13:00 today. Symptoms improving over first 30-60 minutes, but residual RUE drift, dysarthria, and (initally) upgoing R toe. Suspicious for L MCA cortical event. L ICA stenosis and/or embolic event +/- fetal left PCA possible concerns (?cortical vs v-b etiology of dizziness). Cannot obtain CTA secondary to elevated creatinine.  



Plan:  

1.	Admit to RDA 

2.	MRI/MRA. MR Perfusion study if L ICA stenosis or suggestion of intracranial stenosis. 

3.	As event occurred on ASA, provide heparin PTT 60-80, continue ASA at decreased dose (81 qD). Watch platelets, as pt starting with platelets =  150

4.	Hold antihypertensive, but continue isosorbide for known cardiac ischemic history. 

5.	Echo, Holter (for known bradycardia; eval for events with HR <<40. 

6.	PT/speech therapy. 

7.	Careful glycemic control (holding metformin).    		

	 	

  

Vi K. Xayarath, M.D., Ph.D. 

Resident, Phoenix Neurology	









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-03-17





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

HOLDEN DISTRICT HOSPITAL



Reason for visit   Three months of followup for multiple medical problems.



History of present illness   Since his last visit, he has started to resume exercising on his treadmill, but has not been watching his weight or diet.



Major Problems

Hyperlipidemia

His most recent labs are within reasonable range with an LDL of 76 and fasting triglycerides 263, which improved from his previous values.  He has been intolerant to Lopid which resulted in pancreatitis.  He has not lost any weight, but has begun to exercise.

Allergic rhinitis

He has chronic postnasal drip and nasal congestion for which he uses Nasonex on a regular basis with some improvement.  He has had no sinus pains, headache, or recent sinusitis.

Cerebrovascular accident

The patient has had no recent neurological symptoms or changes.  He had a mild aphasia which has totally resolved.  He has had no headaches or any focal symptoms.

Gastroesophageal reflux disease

The patient continues on his ranitidine at night with improvement in his intermittent epigastric discomfort.

Sleep apnea

The patient had a sleep study in November 2091 due to excessive fatigue and snoring.  He was noted to have sleep apnea, and CPAP was prescribed.  He has not been using the CPAP since he was recently on vacation, but he plans to start in the near future.  During his sleep study, he was not uncomfortable wearing the mask and hopefully, this will help.

Prostatic carcinoma

The patient is followed regularly by the urologist and last had a visit in January 2092 with PSA in a very good range at less than 0.2.  He has no dysuria, urgency, frequency, or significant nocturia.

Carpal tunnel syndrome

Currently, he does not complain of any pain or paresthesias in his wrists.

Coronary artery disease

The patient has had no angina since his last visit.  He exercises on a treadmill five times a week and can walk up to five miles in any given setting.  He does not have any palpitations, chest pressure, pain, or significant dyspnea on exertion.

Diabetes mellitus

The patient checks his blood sugars at home, and they have been in the 120 range, although he admits to not losing weight and on his recent trip was not exercising as regularly.  He has had no symptoms with hypoglycemia.

Hypertension

The patient monitors his blood pressure closely at home and finds it to be at around 120/70.  He has not had any headaches or any other focal symptoms.

Atrial fibrillation - Inactivated



Bronchitis - Inactivated





Allergies

Allergic drug reaction   Acf inhibitor - cough. Procardia - leg edema. Lopid - pancreatitis. Cardura - ankle swelling. Dyazide - elevated bun/creat. Exedrin - rash. Amox - vomiting. Norvasc - leg edema. HCTZ - rash per derm. Estynil - rash.

Drug allergy   ACE inhibitor-cough procardia-leg edema lopid-pancreatitis cardura-ankle swelling dyazide-elevated bun/creat edecrine-rash amox-vomiting norvasc-leg edema hctz-rash per derm catapres-rash aggrenox - pancreatitis.



Active Medications

 Lipitor 20mg po qd

 Glucophage 500 mg po BID; Dir: take 1 tab  am and 2 tabs pm

 atenolol 25mg po bid

 glyburide tablets 1.25 po qd

 Isordil 20 mg QID

 Cardizem cd 180 mg PO QD

 Bumex 1 mg 2 tabs PO QD

 Avapro 150 mg

 Nitro stat 0.3mg SL PRN; Dir: chest pain,max 3 pills & call pcp

 Coumadin 5 mg po as directed

 folic acid 1 mg PO 4 QD

 Clarinex 5mg po qd

 Zoloft 100 mg po QHS

 aspirin 81 mg

 ranitidine hcl 300mg po qhs

 Nasonex 50mcg/spray nasal qd; Dir: 2 sprays/nostril; start 2wks before expected allergy season

 free text medications lipitor 10mg po qd; Dir: as directed

 Continuous positive airway pressure

 Accucheck advantage glucose test strips



Change in therapies and Renewals

Lipitor 20mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 2/06/2087

atenolol 25mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 3/25/2087

free text medications       QTY:  Refills:  Start: 03/17/2092  CPAP as directed



Past medical history   History of coronary artery bypass surgery in August 2081.

History of carpal tunnel surgery bilaterally.

History of prostatectomy in June 2088 for prostate cancer.



Procedures

Colonoscopy  in June 2087.



Family history   Mother with hypertension.  Father with hypertension and Alzheimer's disease.  Mother with a stroke and diabetes.  Two brothers and a grandfather with colon polyps.  A grandfather with colon cancer.  A grandmother with breast cancer.  Two brothers with hyperlipidemia.  No history of prostate cancer.



Social history   The patient is a retired pastor who lives with his wife.  He is active, independent, and cares for his grandchildren on a regular basis.



Habits

Smoking status: never smoked  

Alcohol use status:  occasional.

Drug use status: none  

Activity level: active  



Review of systems   Constitutional, some mild fatigue and snoring.  A recent eye exam in January 2092 by report, no retinopathy.  Musculoskeletal, no recent joint problems or complaints.  Dermatologic, he sees the podiatrist every six weeks for foot care.  The remainder of his review of systems is negative in detail except for noted up in his problem list above.



Physical examination

Pulse   56 and regular

Blood pressure 134/70    132-134/70

Weight   186.5 pounds

Skin   No evidence of skin lesions

Heent   Full extraocular movements.  No nystagmus.  Nose, mild erythema.  No discharge.  Oropharynx, no lesions.  Dentition in good repair

Neck   Thyroid, not enlarged.  No fibroid nodules.  Carotid upstrokes brisk.  No bruits

Chest   Clear to auscultation and percussion

Cor   Normal S1 and S2.  Regular rhythm.  No murmurs, gallops, or rubs

Abdomen   Obese and nontender

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  Distal pulses, dorsalis pedis, and posterior tibial are full and symmetrical

Foot exam   No evidence of skin lesions

Neuro   Grossly nonfocal.  Speech fluent without paraphasic errors.  Memory, excellent and intact.  Gait normal



Assessment and plan   The patient's multiple issues were reviewed in detail and his medications were updated.  He remains overweight, and this was discussed with the patient in terms of portion control and continuing his vigorous exercise program.  He will try to lose weight.

Diabetes.  His last hemoglobin A1c was not in adequate control.  In the past, we have tried to increase his Glucophage.  He did not tolerate it due to severe GI upset.  If his sugars remain high, he will need his regimen adjusted.  His eye exam and throat exam are up-to-date and urine for microalbumin was negative.

Coronary artery disease.  No recent angina.  He will continue on his current regimen.

Sleep apnea.  It was highly recommended that he start his CPAP therapy for overall improvement in his health.

Hypertension.  Very well controlled, and no side effects to his current medications.  Laboratory studies were sent, and he will return for followup in three months or sooner if needed.



Addendum   Allergies were reviewed.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Riddle, Rhonda on Mar 31, 2092     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-09-18





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

HOLDEN DISTRICT HOSPITAL



Reason for visit

			

  Followup of multiple issues.



History of present illness

			

  Since his last visit, the patient has had two episodes of pressure in his chest.  This occurred approximately one week ago in the setting of walking up the stairs and carrying a heavy package.  He notes that his pulse went up to 101 and he had overall felt "tired in his chest".  He did not take any nitroglycerine, and his symptoms promptly resolved.  He has continued to notice episodes of intermittent rapid pulses with pulses up to 100.  He has had no syncope or near syncope.  Generally, he has been walking on the treadmill up to four to six miles a day several times a week.  Over the last few weeks, he has felt a little bit more fatigued and now can only walk approximately four miles.  He has not had any sustained palpitation, syncope, or near syncope, but has noted a slight decrease in his exercise tolerance.



Problem List (reviewed)



Coronary artery disease MAJOR 

Hypertension MAJOR 

Diabetes mellitus MAJOR 

Carpal tunnel syndrome MAJOR 

Allergic rhinitis MAJOR 

Angina pectoris MAJOR STATUS POST

Prostatic carcinoma MAJOR 

Cerebrovascular accident MAJOR 

Sleep apnea MAJOR 

Gastroesophageal reflux disease MAJOR 

Hyperlipidemia MAJOR 

Colonic polyp MAJOR 



Major Problems





Coronary artery disease

see HPI



Hypertension

The patient monitors his blood pressure closely at home and finds it to be at around 120/70.  He has not had any headaches or any other focal symptoms.



Diabetes mellitus

The patient checks his blood sugars at home, and they have been in the 120 range, he has been exercising more regularly.  He has had no symptoms of hypoglycemia and generally has been doing well



Carpal tunnel syndrome

Currently, he does not complain of any pain or paresthesias in his wrists.



Allergic rhinitis

He has chronic postnasal drip and nasal congestion for which he uses clarinexon a regular basis with some improvement. He has had no sinus pains, headache, or recent sinusitis.



Angina pectoris STATUS POST

Unstable angina 1/86 cath lad stenosis. ETT 1/84. ETT 3/2091 mild ant./basal ischemia



Prostatic carcinoma

The patient is followed regularly by the urologist and last had a visit in July 2092 with PSA in a very good range at less than 0.2.  He has no dysuria, urgency, frequency, or significant nocturia



Cerebrovascular accident

The patient has had no recent neurological symptoms or changes.  He had a mild aphasia which has totally resolved. He has had no headaches or any focal symptoms.



Sleep apnea

The patient had a sleep study in November 2091 due to excessive fatigue and snoring.  He was noted to have sleep apnea, and CPAP was prescribed.  He has  been using the CPAP ..



Gastroesophageal reflux disease

The patient continues on his ranitidine at night with improvement in his intermittent epigastric discomfort.No dysphagia, odynophagia



Hyperlipidemia

taking his medication, and  watching his weight



Colonic polyp

7/11/92 2 polyps excised transverse colon



Allergies

Drug allergy   ACE inhibitor-cough procardia-leg edema lopid-pancreatitis cardura-ankle swelling dyazide-elevated bun/creat edecrine-rash amox-vomiting norvasc-leg edema hctz-rash per derm catapres-rash aggrenox - pancreatitis.



Active Medications



Lipitor 10mg po 3 tabs qd dose has been  increased to 30mg 

Glucophage 500 mg po BID take 1 tab  am and 2 tabs pm

atenolol 25mg po bid

glyburide tablets 1.25 po qd

Isordil 20 mg QID

Cardizem cd 180 mg PO QD

Bumex 1 mg 2 tabs PO QD

Avapro 150 mg

Nitro stat 0.3mg SL PRN chest pain,max 3 pills & call pcp

Coumadin 5 mg po as directed

folic acid 1 mg PO 4 QD

Clarinex 5mg po qd

Zoloft 100 mg 1/2 tab po QHS

aspirin 81 mg

ranitidine hcl 300mg po qhs

Nasonex 50mcg/spray nasal qd 2 sprays/nostril

Advair 100/50mcg spray inh bid

free text medications lipitor 10mg po qd as directed

Continuous positive airway pressure use as directed

Accucheck advantage glucose test strips use as directed qty:300 rfl:3



Past medical history

			

  History of coronary artery bypass surgery in August 2081.

History of carpal tunnel surgery bilaterally.

History of prostatectomy in June 2088 for prostate cancer.



Family history

			

  Mother with hypertension.  Father with hypertension and Alzheimer's disease.  Mother with a stroke and diabetes. Two brothers and a grandfather with colon polyps.  A grandfather with colon cancer.  A grandmother with breast cancer.  Two brothers with hyperlipidemia. Brother with prostate cancer.



Social history

			

  The patient is a retired pastor who lives with his wife. He is active, independent, and cares for his grandchildren on a regular basis.



Habits

Activity level: active  treadmill 1-2 hours 4-6X per week

Smoking status: never smoked  

Alcohol use status: none/minimal  occasional.

Drug use status: none  



Procedures and Immunizations 

Influenza vaccine STATUS POST [ 9/18/2092 ] 

 Fluzone Lot #S3124HR Exp. 26 Jun 92 (l) Deltoid

Left deltoid lot # STGLX647RM



Review of systems

			

  The patient has had no fevers, chills, or night sweats.  He haschronic  bilateral nasal congestion .  He has no sputum production.  No joint symptoms, GI, GU, or neurological complaints.  No skin rashes.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 120/70  

Pulse   72, irregularly, irregular

Weight   182lbs

General appearance   Well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.

Heent   NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, O/P clear without erythema or exudates.

Neck   JVP flat; carotids brisk, 2+ bilaterally without bruits, no goiter.

Chest   Clear to auscultation bilaterally.

Cor   PMI at 5th ICS, MCL. RRR nl s1, s2 without m/r/g.

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, edema. Full pedal pulses.

Neuro   Grossly nonfocal.  Speech fluent without paraphasic errors. Memory, excellent and intact.  Gait normal

Foot exam   Negative

Preventive eye exam   5/92



Selected recent labs

			

  ECG new atrial fibrillation at rate 74. Right bundle branch block, no ischemic changes



Assessment and plan

			

  The patient's symptoms and exam as well as EKG are consistent with atrial fibrillation.  Of note, the patient had a history of paroxysmal atrial fibrillation after his CABG.  However, he has not had any significant symptoms since that time.  He remains active without any evidence of congestive heart failure on exam.  He continues to exercise on a regular basis.  Given his slightly elevated pulse rate, his atenolol will be increased to 25 mg PO BID from one per day which is what he is currently taking.  His blood pressure is under good control.  Given his recent episode of repeat stress test will be sent.  If there is any prolonged episode of pain, he will come to the emergency room immediately.  He is encouraged to use nitroglycerine sublingually if he has any evidence or any chest pressure.  For his diabetes, his labs will be sent.  He remains on Coumadin for anticoagulation, and his INR has been therapeutic.  He will follow up in three months but sooner pending the above evaluation.  If he has any increase in his symptoms, he will be admitted immediately.



Note transcribed by outside service

			

  Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Riddle, Rhonda on Sep 25, 2092     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-12-31





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

HOLDEN DISTRICT HOSPITAL



Reason for visit

			

  Followup of recent MI and multiple medical problems.



History of present illness

			

  Since the patient's last visit, he developed a maculopapular rash and his Plavix was discontinued.  Since this is the only new medication, it was presumed that Plavix was the cause of the new skin rash.  He also changed his beta blocker and started Toprol XL approximately one week ago.  At home, he states his pulse has been under better control, and now, is in the 60 range.  He denies any palpitations, PND, orthopnea, or shortness of breath.  He has had no recurrent angina and has tried this week to slowly start to walk for about 15 minutes on his treadmill at a low pace.  He has not had any angina or chest pain with this walking routine.  He also knows that his sugars at home had been very low at 55 and 56 in the evening.  He has had weight loss and slightly diminished appetite and this may account for his low blood sugars.  He is here for a followup.  Of note, his Bumex dose was decreased due to an elevated BUN and creatinine.  His weight has been stabled, and he feels better on the lower dose of diuretics without symptoms of congestive heart failure.



Major Problems





Coronary artery disease

see HPI



Atrial fibrillation

Rx with rate control, and coumadin. rate 60,s at home. No CHF, neuro Sx



Hypertension

The patient monitors his blood pressure closely at home and finds it to be at around 110/70.  He has not had any headaches or any other focal symptoms.



Diabetes mellitus

See HPI



Allergic rhinitis

He has chronic postnasal drip and nasal congestion for which he uses clarinex on a regular basis with some improvement. He has had no sinus pains, headache, or recent sinusitis.



Angina pectoris STATUS POST

Unstable angina 1/86 cath lad stenosis. ETT 1/84. ETT 3/2091 mild ant./basal ischemia. S/P MI 12/92 with cardiac cath, stent RCA.



Cerebrovascular accident

The patient has had no recent neurological symptoms or changes.  He had a mild aphasia which has totally resolved. He has had no headaches or any focal symptoms.



Sleep apnea

The patient had a sleep study in November 2091 due to excessive fatigue and snoring.  He was noted to have sleep apnea, and CPAP was prescribed.  He has  been using the CPAP ..



Gastroesophageal reflux disease

The patient continues on his ranitidine at night with improvement in his intermittent epigastric discomfort.No dysphagia, odynophagia



Hyperlipidemia

taking his medication, and  watching his weight



Allergies

Drug allergy   ACE inhibitor-cough procardia-leg edema lopid-pancreatitis cardura-ankle swelling dyazide-elevated bun/creat edecrine-rash amox-vomiting norvasc-leg edema hctz-rash per derm catapres-rash aggrenox - pancreatitis.Plavix-rash



Active Medications



Accucheck Advantage glucose test strips 

Advair 100/50mcg spray inh bid

aspirin 325 mg po qd

Avapro 150 mg

Bumex 1 mg 2 tabs PO bid

Cardizem cd 180 mg PO QD

Clarinex 10mg po qd

Continuous positive airway pressure 

Coumadin 5 mg po as directed

folic acid 1 mg PO 4 QD

free text medications toprol xl 100mg po qd

Glucophage 500 mg po BID

glyburide tablets 1.25 po qd

Isordil 20 mg QID

Lipitor 80mg po qd

Nasonex 50mcg/spray nasal qd 2 sprays/nostril

Nitro stat 0.3mg SL PRN chest pain,max 3 pills &amp; call pcp

ranitidine hcl 300mg po qhs

Toprol XL 50 mg po qd

Zoloft 100 mg 1/2 tab po QHS



Change in therapies and Renewals



Lipitor 80mg po qd Start: 2/06/2087

atenolol 25mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 3/25/2087 End: 12/31/2092 - Inactivated

Clarinex 10mg po qd Start: 1/24/2090

aspirin 325 mg po qd Start: 4/27/2090

Levaquin 250 mg po qd x10d QTY:10 Refills:0 Start: 12/11/2092 End: 12/31/2092 - Inactivated

free text medications toprol xl 100mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/31/2092

Plavix 75mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 12/15/2092 End: 12/31/2092 - Inactivated



Habits/Risk Screening

Smoking status: never smoked  

Alcohol use status: none/minimal  occasional.



Review of systems

			

  The patient has had no fevers, chills, or night sweats. No cough. He has chronic nasal congestion .  He has no sputum production.  No joint symptoms, GI, GU, or neurological complaints.  No skin rashes.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 110/60  

Pulse 94   irregularly, irregular

Weight 172lbs  

height 60in  

Office O2 saturation 99%  

General appearance   Well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.

Heent   NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, O/P clear without erythema or exudates.

Neck   JVP flat; carotids brisk, 2+ bilaterally without bruits, no goiter.

Chest   Clear to auscultation bilaterally.

Cor   PMI at 5th ICS, MCL. RRR nl s1, s2 without m/r/g.

Extrem   No clubbing, cyanosis, edema. Full pedal pulses.

Musc skel   No bony deformities.

Neuro   Grossly nonfocal.  Speech fluent without paraphasic errors. Memory, excellent and intact.  Gait normal

Preventive eye exam   5/92



Assessment and plan

			

  The patient's multiple issues were reviewed with the patient in detail.  His weight has remained fairly stable on the lower dose of diuretics, and a repeat BUN and creatinine were sent today.  He was volume depleted at his last visit.  Currently, he has no symptoms of unstable angina and no evidence of congestive heart failure on exam.  His blood sugars have been low, and therefore, he will hold his glyburide for now.  His pulse remained somewhat elevated, and he will follow up with his cardiologist relative to the need for cardioversion for an attempt to get him back into normal sinus rhythm.  His weight control has been a problem.  He will slowly increase his ambulation and will check his pulse and blood pressure at home.  He will follow up here in two months or sooner if needed.



Note transcribed by outside service

			

  Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Riddle, Rhonda on Jan 07, 2093     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>