<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2100-05-19

Date:  5/19/00, 1100 am



Medical Record Number:  9125902, Jorgenson, Andrew.



Procedure:  The patient is a 69 year old male scheduled for a right femoral BPG. Surgery is to be performed on 6/02/00, by Dr. Ximenez.



Chief Complaint & Present Illness: Patient has a history of diabetic peripheral vascular disease. He has bilateral claudication after 1 block. Claudication has been present for many years, but has become worse since summer 2099. Initally he was planning on surgery, but had MI 6/00, and underwent CABG 7/99. He developed lesions to the top of his 4th toes bilaterally 1/00. Lesions became worse and were treated with "cream" which have since improved. The lesions are healing, but toes remain painful. Claudication has not improved since CABG. 



Past Medical History: 

1. HTN

2. Non insulin dependent diabetes

3. Rheumatoid arthritis -affects shoulders, arms, hips, neck

4. CAD s/p CABG 7/99, s/p MI 7/04/99



Past Surgical History: 

1. CABG x3 7/10/99

2. Stent placement 2094

3. Esopahgeal hiatal hernia with Schotzsky ring

4. Double hernia 2089

5. Appendectomy 2060

6. Lithotripsy 1/99, 4/99 (calcific stones)

7. Cataract surgery 4/00

Denies problems with general anesthesia



Family History: There is no family history if adverse reactions to general  anesthesia.



Medications: prednisone 5 mg qam, 4 mg qpm, plaquenil 200 mg bid, folic 1 mg/qam, methotrexate q Wednesday 12.5 mg, fosamax 70 mg (Sat), metformin 5/500 mg bid, actos 45 mg qam, plavix 75 mg/d (stopped yesterday), lopressor 50 mg bid, protonix 40 mg qhs, provachol 20 mg qhs, ASA 325 mg/qam (stopped yesterday), multivitamin, colace



Allergies: glucovance - hypoglycemia/hyperglycemia



Social History:

  Smoking: quit 2091, smoked 1ppd/30 years

  Alcohol use: 3-4 beers/d until 8 years ago for 30 years

  Substance abuse: none

  Allergen Exposure: (transfusion/pregnancy): none in last 3 months.

  Exercise: cardiac rehab until 11/99, can carry 13 lb dog from basement to upper floor ( 2 flights) without SOB

  Occupation: retired

  Marital Status: married



Review of Systems:

General: Independent with ADL, well developed, well nourished. Lost 30 lb prior to CABG, has regained 15 lb 



HEENT:History of cataract surgery.  No history of head injury, glaucoma,  eye redness, eye/nose/throat pain, earaches, ear infections, nose bleeds, excessive tearing, eye/ear discharge, vision changes (including double vision, spot, specks, or flashing lights), tinnitus, vertigo, motion sickness, sinus infection, or hearing loss.



Respiratory:  Denies cough sputum, hemoptysis, wheezing, asthma, bronchitis, emphysema, pneumonia,  tuberculosis, COPD, sleep apnea, or pleurisy.



Cardiovascular: History of HTN and hypercholesterolemia. History of MI 7/04/00. States was outside painting and did not feel well. Rested on couch for 3-4 hours with chest pain which later radiated to right arm without SOB, nausea, or diaphoresis. Went for cath at Ocilla Hospital then to Marquette for surgery 7/99. Had CABG x3 with LIMA 7/10/00. Has not had any symptoms or taken NTG since surgery. Echocardiogram shows trace MR, mild dilation of aortic root, no wall motion abnormalities, LVEF 55%. Stress test after CABG 8/99, was indeterminate for ischemia due to baselkine EKG abnormality. No history of  rheumatic fever, syncope, palpitations,  edema, dyspnea, chest pain,  orthopnea, or paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.



GI: History of hiatal hernia. History of rectal bleeding pre CABG. Had HCT of 29 and went on iron after surgery. Colonoscpy and endocscopy were negative for bleeding 1/00. No history of GERD, PUD, changes in bowel habits, difficulty swallowing, appetite changes, nausea, vomiting, constipation, diarrhea, abdominal pain, food  intolerance, excessive belching or gas.



Hepatobiliary: No history of jaundice, hepatitis, or colic.



GU: History of kidney stones. No history  of CRF, hematuria, obstruction, colic, UTI, polyuria, nocturia, decreased caliber or force of urinary stream, hesitancy, incontinence, or frequency of urination.  



Musculoskeletal: History of rheumatoid arthritis diagnosed 8/98. Presently taking prednisone, plaquenil, folic acid, methotrexate, and fosamax.No history of  muscle pain, joint pain, stiffness, gout, or limitations with ROM.



Neuro:  No history of seizures, stroke,  TIAs, migraine, fainting, weakness, paralysis, numbness, tingling, tremors, or other involuntary movements.



Peripheral Vascular: History of bilateral claudication. History of ischemic ulcers to 4th toes.No history of  DVT, varicosities, cramps .



Endocrine: History of non insulin dependent diabetes diagnosed 2095. Checks BS QD or QOD.  BS usually run 130 qam. No history of thyroid problems, heat or cold intolerance, excessive sweating, excessive thirst    



Heme/Onc: History of anemia pre CABG, easy bruising.  No history of bleeding,  lymphadenopathy, chemotherapy or radiation.



Psychiatric:  No history of anxiety, panic attacks, depression, or psychosis.  



Skin:  No history of rash, abnormal pigmentation, prutitis, lumps, or sores.   



Physical Exam:



     SaO2: 98

     Resp: 16

     Temp:94.9

     Ht: 68"

     Wt: 183.4

     BP: 118/77

     AP: 65

    

     General:  Well developed, well nourished

     

     HEENT:  Normocephalic, cranium intact without depressions. no icterus, thyroid non-palpable, neck veins flat, carotids palpable without bruits, no swelling, lumps, masses, tenderness, or visible pulsations. Movement symmetrical with limited range of motion upon extension to 40 degrees. Frontal and maxillary  sinuses non-tender.



     Airway:  Mallampatti Class III, opens 3 fingerbreadths wide, can protrude jaw



     Teeth: upper plate, crown to lower left molar



     Chest:  Breath sounds  clear.  No abnormal retraction  or impairment of lower interspaces during inspiration.  Symmetrical, even respiratory movement.



     Heart: Regular rhythm, normal rate, no murmurs, rubs or gallops, S1=S2.



     Abdomen:  Soft, non-tender, with scars, no distention, normal bowel sounds, no organomegaly or palpable masses.  Contour flat, symmetrical,  without  lesions, striae, or dilated veins.  No visible peristalsis or pulsations.



     GU/Rectal:  No CVA tenderness or hernias.



     Lymphatics:  No lymphadenopathy



     Peripheral Vascular:  No edema, varicosities, or   prominent veins.

       Carotids- 2+

       Radials- 2+

       Femorals- not palpated

       Anterior tibial- 1+ to right, not palpable to left

       Dorsalis pedis- 1+ to right, not palpable to left



    Neuro:         

      CNII:  Visual Acuity:  Able to read newspaper with glasses.  Visual fields full to confrontation. Decreased periphral to vision bilaterally

      CN III, IV, and VI, : EOMs intact, parallel, no ptosis.s/p cataract surgery to right

      CN V & VII: Intact. Temporal and masseter muscle contractions equal  in symmetry and strength.  Equal sensation to sharp stimulus to forehead, cheek, and jaws.

      CNVIII: Intact. No loss of hearing to either ear via whisper test.

      CN IX, X:  Intact.  Voice without hoarseness or nasal quality.  Uvula midline.

      CN XI:  Intact. Equal strength and contraction to trapezii and sternomastoid muscle.

      CN XII:  Intact.  Tongue movement symmetrical without deviations or protrusions.  No atropy or fasciculations as tongue lies on floor of mouth.

      Mental Status:  Oriented x 3.  Appearance neat and clean.  Pt pleasant and cooperative for exam.  Able to answer questions appropriately and clearly. Able to articulate own thoughts and questions logically and coherently.

      Coordination:  Gait - steady without ataxia

      Strength and Tone: Tone and strength intact to upper and lower extremities.

      Sensory: Intact.

      Reflexes: not tested

  Extremities: No clubbing  or cyanosis.

  Musculoskeletal:  Normal range of motion.

  Skin: sores to right 4th toe, and left 4th, 3rd, and 5th. Warm and dry to touch.   Color consistent.  No rashes or edema.



Assessment:  ASA physical status: III. Pateint is a 69 year old male scheduled for a right femoral popliteal BPG. Patient has history of HTN, CAD S/P CABG X3, hypercholesterolemia, non insulin dependent diabete, hiatal hernia, and rheumatoid arthritis. He denies problems with general anesthesia. Anesthesia consent form reviewed and explained.Patient requests to sign anesthesia consent form day of surgery.



Plan:  Proposed anesthetic: epidural, possible general 

          Monitors: standard, arterial line, possible CVP, PA line

          Pain Management:  IVPCA

          Autologous Blood:  none

          Premedication: stress dose steroids

          Usual Medications: prednisone 5 mg qam, 4 mg qpm, plaquenil 200 mg bid, folic acid 1 mg/qam, methotrexate q Wednesday 12.5 mg, fosamax 70 mg (Sat), metformin 5/500 mg bid, actos 45 mg qam, plavix 75 mg/d (stopped yesterday), lopressor 50 mg bid, protonix 40 mg qhs, pravachol 20 mg qhs, ASA 325 mg/qam (stopped yesterday), multivitamin, colace

          Medications to be held on day of surgery: plaquenil to be stopped 5 days before surgery, folic acid,actos,  methotrexate, metformin (to be stopped after morning dose 6/01), pravachol to be stopped 3 days before surgery, colcace, and multivitamin to be stopped 1 week before surgery

          Diabetic Medications: actos, metformin to be held after morning dose 6/01

          NSAIDS: Avoid for three days prior to surgery

          Aspirin:  Avoid for one week prior to surgery.

          NPO: after midnight



Ancillary Studies: Bloodwork and urinalysis pending.EKG shows sinus bradycardia, T wave inversions, II, V2, V3, V4, V5, V6. Similar to previous EKG from cardiologist office. Formal reading pending.









__________________________________________________________________

Martha Tharp, MSN, RNC









___________________________________________________________________





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2104-02-15


February 15, 2104
OFFICE VISIT (CHC)
The patient is seen in followup at the Community Health.  He came back from Pennsylvania after being there about a month.  He has had an eventful past six months.  In October, he apparently had a TIA or small stroke.  He was evaluated with an MRA of his neck and was told that there was not enough blockage to warrant surgery.  His symptomatology fortunately clear.  His symptoms were related to loss of feeling in his right upper extremity.  About this time, he also developed a traumatic lesion of the left second toe.  He apparently develops some cellulitis and was treated with ampicillin.  Not long after this, he went into renal failure.  He was told that they could not tell if that was due to the antibiotics or the gadolinium.  According to the patient and his wife, his creatinine went as high as 9.  Fortunately, it is currently back down to 2.4.


His toe lesion has been very slow to improve.  He describes pain in the toe and often has to sleep in a chair with his foot dependent.  He has seen various physicians and podiatrists in Pennsylvania, without much improvement.  They finally told him, he would do well to come back here for further care and evaluation.


On examination today, I can feel femoral and popiteal pulses.  I do not feel any definite pedal pulses on either side but noninvasive study show good pulsatile flow at the calf and transmetatarsal level.  Resting ABI is good, although his diabetic calcinosis probably makes this unreliable.  He has some slight pulsatile flow at the right toe level and flat tracings at left toes.  He has 1 cm escharover the dorsum of his second toe.  There is some erythema of the toe and proximal dorsal forefoot.  This certainly has the appearance of some cellulites.  There is minimal to no swelling of the toe.


We will place him on Keflex 250 mg q.i.d. for 7 to 10 days to see if this helps with any possible associated cellulitis.  I will refer him to Dr. Caldwell for recommendations regarding wound quick care and an opinion whether or not hyperbaric oxygen therapy might be worth considering.  I do not think there is anything further we can do to improve his distal blood flow.  Further imaging will also be very difficult in view of the possible problems with gadolinium as well as his creatinine, which limit contrast administration.  His noninvasive studies suggest that his problems are all diabetic small vessel disease and it is unlikely that we could be of benefit with this.  I will await Dr. Caldwell&#8217;s opinions.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2105-08-11


















 
 



Vascular Surgery/Emergency Department Surgical Admission Note



                                                                                                             

Patient: Jorgenson, Andrew C.  

MRN: 9125902

Date: 8/11/05



CC: cool right foot and progressive claudication



HPI: The patient is a 74 yo male with a history of CAD, PVD s/p right femoral to above knee popliteal bypass with PTFE (5/00) who presents to the ED with right foot pain. 



The patient has developed progressive R calf pain over the past 2 months, which has become worse over the past 10 days. 
He is unable to walk more than a half block without cramping pain in his calf.  Because of his previous bypass surgery and current complaints, he underwent vascular studies today demonstrating critical atherosclerotic disease in the RLE, with markedly reduced flow through the R graft. 
The toe-brachial index was not able to be calculated on the R, and was 0.31 on the L.   He is currently taking ASA 325 mg po daily, but no plavix or Coumadin.  



Over the past week, the patient reports that his pain has become more severe.  He has otherwise felt well and in his normal state of health, and denies fevers/chills, chest pain, shortness of breath, and all other symptoms.   



Past Medical History:

CAD w/ EF 50%

PVD s/p bypass surgery as above

RA 

DM

HTN 

CRI 

h/o TIA (RUE weakness) 

h/o esophageal 

stricture s/p esophageal dilation 4/2104



Past Surgical History:

s/p L CEA 5/05

Angioplasty of L SFA, Pop, Tibioperoneal trunk 6/05/04

Right femoral to above knee popliteal bypass graft with 6 mm PTFE. 5/00

CABG x 3 (2099)

Esopahgeal hiatal hernia with Schotzsky ring

Bilateral hernia repair 2089

Appendectomy 2060

Lithotripsy 1/99, 4/99



Medications:

1. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)  325 MG PO QD

2. Ezetimibe 10 Mg - Simvastatin 20 Mg (Vytorin 10/27)  1 TAB PO QD

3. Folic Acid  1 MG PO

4. Hydroxychloroquine (Plaquenil Sulfate)  200 MG PO BID

5. 
Metoprolol Tartrate (Lopressor)  50 MG PO BID

6. 
Multivitamins  1 TAB PO QD

7. Prednisone  3 mg PO QD

8. Glipizide 2.5mg QD

9. Avapro 150mg QD

10. Calcitriol 0.25 mcg QD

11. Darbepoetin Alfa (Aranesp)  

12. Fish oil



Allergies: 

NKDA



Social History: 

The patient is married with adult children. He lives with his wife in SC but winters at their home in PA. He is a former smoker. He quit smoking approx 15 years ago. 30 pack year history. Denies ETOH or illicit drug use.



Family Hx:  

non-contributory



Physical Exam:


Vitals:  T: 98.9   HR: 60  BP: 163/61  
RR: 14   99% RA    

GEN:  awake, alert, non-toxic appearing

CV: regular, no murmurs/rubs/gallops

PULM:  some crackles heard on the left side, otherwise unremarkable

ABD: obese, positive bowel sounds in all 4 quadrants. Soft &amp; non-tender/non-distended, no masses or hepatosplenomegaly

EXT: 

RLE: 
warm with a slightly cool foot and diminished distal pulses with right toes erythematous and tender to palpation; no clubbing, cyanosis. No signs of loss of sensation or tingling are apparent on examination of right foot. 

LLE: warm, well perfused 



Labs:

WBC                              5.4                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              38.1             L        (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              12.6             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              3.90             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              140              L        (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              98                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              32.4                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             33.2                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              13.4                      (11.5-14.5)    %

Superstat PT                     12.9                      (10.8-13.4)    sec

Superstat PT-INR                 1.1

Diff Method                      Auto

Poly                             67                        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           24                        (22-44)        %

Monos                            7                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              2                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %

Absolute Neuts                   3.54                      (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  1.29                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   0.39                      (0.2-1.2)      th/mm3

Absolute EOS                     0.13                      (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.02                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm

Aniso                            None                      (None)

Hypo                             None                      (None)

Macrocytes                       None                      (None)

Microcytes                       None                      (None)



Plasma Sodium                    145                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.2                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  109              H        (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            24.3                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 12                        (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          8.9                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             23                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.99             H        (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             35                                       mL/min/1.73m2

Plasma Glucose                  
101                       (70-110)       mg/dl



Imaging:

Vascular studies done today, OSH: 
patent right femoral to popliteal artery bypass graft with markedly reduced flow, toe-brachial index 0.0 &#8211; confirmed with PVR in UMH ED



Assessment/Plan:
 

The patient is an 74 yo male with a history of CAD, PVD, s/p right femoral to above knee popliteal bypass graft who presents with progressive R foot claudication X 2 weeks.  His vascular studies are concerning for progressive arterial ischemia, presumably the result of graft stenosis. 



He will be admitted to the vascular surgery service, be placed on systemic heparin, and will undergo angiogram in the next 1-2 days for possible angioplasty/stent.



Plan:

-          Systemic anticoagulation w/ IV heparin, bolus 3000 units followed by drip at 1000 units/hr

-          Home meds

-          NPO past midnight

-          Mucormyst/bicarbonate for renal protection given creatinine 1.99

-          Plan for likely angiogram tomorrow, 8/12/05



This patient was discussed with Dr. Francis Pratt, Vascular Surgery Fellow. 
 
 
 


__________________________________

Kenneth Felton MSIII

UMH ED Surgery

Pager 59917



Agree with above note, changes made.









Jerry F. Addison

ED Surgery Senior Resident

Pager 79915




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2105-08-27

SICU visit (Hamilton 04239)

8/26/05 11 45 pm


74 yo male with a history of CAD, PVD s/p right femoral to above knee popliteal bypass with PTFE (5/00) and recent admission for RLE angioplasty X 22 who presents with R foot rest pain and discoloration and underwent fem pop bypass graft. The case was complicated by large blood loss anemia and hypotension.  In the PACU the patient continued to be hypotensive and have low uop. We placed a central line (starting CVP was 0) and continued resuscitation. The patient developed ST changes and also had acute on chronic renal failure (RIFLE F). WE transfused and transferred him to the ICU.  We discussed this at length with the surgical service as well as cardiology.
 
I examined the patient reviewed the chart and discussed the case. I agree with history and exam as outlined in residents note
 
Issues:
Cardiac ischemia:  Ischemia was mostly due to hypotension and low HGB as well as tachycardia .  Will give aspirin and lower HR to 70's with Beta blockers. Contue statin.  Willt ransfuse to HGB around 10 and continue to check troponins
 
Decreased myocardial function: he has low central venous saturation and increased lactate . Will give fluids and transfuse the patient.  Will get echo in am. If his central venous sat  and lactate does not signficantly improve with these measures would stay away from inotropes for now given his rate related ischemia
 
Acute blood-loss naemia: will transfuse to 
 
Metabolic acidosis: the patetin has signifcant metabolic acidosis. We will for now give volume. 
 
Acute renal failure: He has significantly decreaed uop. We are sending  urine lytes and casts. Will increase filling pressures. For now would not use furosemide given low central filling pressures.     
 
V. Hamilton 
cc 122 min       



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>