<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2093-01-13

Uriah Oliver

NYSH # 791-60-07









Medications:

Colace		100 mg bid

Relafen		500 mg qd PRN

fosinopril		40 mg qd

Glucophage	1000 mg bid

glyburide		10 mg bid

metoprolol	50 mg bid

Ecotrin		325 mg qd

hydrochlorothiazide    25 mg qd

Darvocet N. 100	

Viagra		100 mg

Coumadin		followed at ANRC



Patient is here for follow-up.



1.  Basal cell carcinoma.  Status post recent excision.



2.  CAD.  Patient hospitalized at Atlantic North Rehabilitation in mid-December after apparently experiencing some chest pain and being found to have an abnormal EKG.  He apparently had cardiac catheterization and an initial stent was placed, following this he had a stress test which showed some  continued changes and a second catheterization showed a second blocked vessel and a second stent was placed.  Medical regimen was adjusted.  I do not have any further details of this hospitalization and the above details are based on patient history.  He was started on Coumadin which she was told he would have to take for a limited period.  This is monitored from the ANRC.



3.  Diabetes.  Last HgbA1c was in October and was 7.7 which is a moderate improvement for him.  Reports compliance with his regimen.



Physical Exam



Patient is in no apparent distress.

Weight: 180 pounds

Blood Pressure: 130/68

Neck: supple without thyroidomegaly.

Lungs: Clear.

Cor. S1, S2 without gallops, rubs or murmurs.

Abdomen: non-tender,without organomegaly. 

Extremities: without edema. 



Assessment and Plan



1.  CAD.  Need more details of recent hospitalization.  Will center Atlantic North Rehabilitation Center for recent medical record.  For now he will continue on his current regimen.  He denies any recurrence of chest pain.



2.  Diabetes.  Continue current regimen.



I will see him for follow-up in two months.

      



                                                                                                Kevin Patterson, M.D.

Typed with voice recognition software; please excuse any transcription errors.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-06-30




NAME:     Oliver, Uriah 
MRN:       7916007

Primary Care Provider:  Dr. Patterson

Mr. Oliver returns for follow-up of several issues.

Weight 175.  Blood pressure 130/80. 

MEDICATIONS:   He finished Flagyl last night, and he took his last dose of levoflox
today.  Glyburide is on hold.  He is taking hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg q.d., Lovastatin
20 mg q.d., fosinopril 40 mg q.d., verapamil SR 240 mg q.d., ASA 1 q.d., metoprolol
75 mg three times a day and Glucophage 1000 mg b.i.d.  

(1)  Diverticulitis and history of colon cancer.  

     S:   His pain is gone although he continues to have a bad taste in his mouth
          since he has been on antibiotics. 

     O:   His abdomen is soft with normal bowel sounds.  There is no tenderness
          today.  

     P:   He will need colonoscopy at the Atlantic North in a month or so. 

(2)  Diarrhea.  

     S:   He has continued to have several soft, dark bowel movements a day
          while he has been taking the antibiotic.  He has not seen any bright red
          blood per rectum.  He has been using Equal and eating ice cream.  

     O:   Stool for C. diff. and stool C&S were both negative. 

     P:   I asked him to discontinue artificial sweeteners and milk products,
          except for yogurt, for 3 days.  He will call if the diarrhea persists off the
          antibiotic.  

(3)  Guaiac-positive stool on examination last week.  

     O:   His hematocrit had increased to 35.7 last week.  

     P:   Recheck CBC.  He will bring me the name of his GI physician at the
          Atlantic North so that I can communicate with him about the recent events
          and arrange for follow-up colonoscopy.  

(4)  Dizziness.  

     S:   This has resolved. 

(5)  Diabetes. 

     S:   He stopped glyburide as directed last week when his 4 p.m. blood sugar
          was 44.  His fingerstick blood sugar was 192 this morning.  He reports
          that he is eating much better.  

     P:   He will restart glyburide 5 mg q.d. when his blood sugar is greater than
          200.

(6)  Systolic murmur and right bundle branch block.

     P:   His echocardiogram has been requested but he has not yet received the
          appointment.  

(7)  Coronary artery disease.  

     S:   He has had no chest pain.  He apparently had an appointment last week
          for an exercise tolerance test at the Atlantic North but the technician was
          not there.  He has another appointment later this week with the doctor
          at the Atlantic North.

     P:   I gave him a copy of the final NYSH discharge summary from his recent
          hospitalization as well as copies of the EKGs done during the
          hospitalization and a copy of the abdominal CT report to take to his
          doctor at the Atlantic North.

(8)  Proteinuria during the hospitalization. 

     O:   His serum creatinine was 1.5 (likely elevated given his age).  Repeat
          urinalysis showed 1+ albumin with no other significant abnormalities. 

     P:   Check 24-hour urine for protein and creatinine.  Check serum protein
          electrophoresis and urine immunoelectrophoresis. 

(9)  Chronic anemia.  

     O:   He had normal iron studies, B12 and folate several months ago.  His
          hematocrit was stable as of last week.  

     P:   Check serum protein electrophoresis and urine immunoelectrophoresis.  

(10) Decreased HDL.  

     A:   We could either add niacin or change his statin from Mevacor to Lipitor
          to increase the HDL.  

     P:   I have deferred this issue to his primary care physician. 

He will return for follow-up in 2 weeks so that we can make final arrangements for
the colonoscopy and to check progress with his diabetes. 



Ciara J. Goldberg, M.D.

CG/nation/olivo 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-05-18

Uriah Oliver

NYSH # 791-60-07









Medications:

simvastatin	20 mg qd

fosinopril		40 mg bid

glyburide		10 mg bid

Glucophage	1000 mg bid

metoprolol	100 mg bid

aspirin		81 mg qd

amlodipine	7.5 mg qd

omeprazole	20 mg qd

hydrochlorothiazide	25 mg qd



Patient is here for follow-up.



1.  Diabetes.  Continues on both glyburide and Glucophage although recently has been out of glyburide and sugars have been somewhat high.



2.  Hypertension.  Medications changed by either cardiology or the ANRC and now on amlodipine 7.5 mg qd as well as fosinopril 40 mg bid, continues on hydrochlorothiazide as well.  Reports compliance with his regimen.



3.  CAD.  Switched from lovastatin to simvastatin, continues on a baby aspirin a day.  No complaints of any palpitations or chest pain or shortness of breath.



4.  GERD.  Recently started on a proton pump inhibitor for chronic symptoms of heartburn type pain.



There were some confusion regarding patients medications as he gets many of his medications from the ANRC and I had been on aware of some of the medication changes that have been made recently.  Has stated above no longer on verapamil but now on amlodipine, changed to simvastatin.  He brought in a list of all his medications and dosage adjustments were made to the LMR medication list.



Physical Exam



Patient is in no apparent distress.

Weight: 183 pounds

Blood Pressure: 148/74; 136/74

Neck: supple without thyroidomegaly.

Lungs: Clear.

Cor. S1, S2 without gallops, rubs II/VI SEM at apex radiating to axilla. 

Abdomen: non-tender, without organomegaly. 

Extremities: without edema. 



Assessment and Plan



1.  Diabetes.  Has been out of medication any is given a new prescription for his glyburide which he is now taking 10 mg bid.  Continuing on Glucophage.  Will check a fasting glucose, urine for microalbumin and HgbA1c just before his next appointment.



2.  Hypertension.  Blood pressure initially elevated today but on subsequent reading within normal limits.  Continue current regimen but will monitor.  Check BUN and creatinine and potassium with next phlebotomy.



3.  CAD.  Continue current regimen, check lipid profile just before next visit.  Also will check LFTs.



I will see him for follow-up in two months.

      



                                                                                                Kevin Patterson, M.D.

Typed with voice recognition software; please excuse any transcription errors.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-12-10

Internal Medicine Medical Student Admission Note - Willie Nix, TMSIII

Name: Oreilly, Uriah

MR# 7916007

PCP: Kevin Patterson

Date: 12/09/94

Source: Patient and Medical Notes



CC: SOB, DOE x 5 days



HPI: This is a 73yo male w/ a complicated PMH that includes HTN, DM, hyperlipidemia, CAD, and a past MI, which resulted in the placement of an AICD, who now p/w severe SOB and DOE.  Five days PTA, the Pt became SOB while walking up the stairs to his apartment on the 3rd floor.  He took a SL NG pill which he says alleviated the SOB and allowed him to continue.  Over the next few days, his SOB became progressively worse and occurred at rest.  His SOB would awaken him from his sleep, occurring 3-4x/ night.  He states that SL NG pills alleviated his PND.  The Pt sleeps on one pillow.  During the course of his worsening SOB, his exercise tolerance decreased from a baseline of walking 2.5 hours without any SOB to walking for 1.5 hours with multiple stops due to SOB.  These episodes of SOB were not associated w/ CP (pleuritic or otherwise), palpitations, F/C, N/V, diaphoresis, abdominal discomfort, or pain in his arms or jaw.  



Also during this time, the Pt noted progressive b/l swelling of his legs (from ankles to knees) and increasing abdominal girth.  He states that his legs would pit when he pressed on them.  The LE swelling were not associated w/ calf pain.  On the day before admission, however, he did develop a non-productive, dry cough.  On the DOA, his Sx had worsened to the point where he felt like he needed to be seen by a doctor.  He was subsequently driven to NYSH-East by his wife and son, where he was seen and then re-directed to NYSH.     



At NYSH-East, the Pt's vitals were: T 97.6 P 52-55 BP 167/77 O2Sat 98% Wt 188.5# w/ clothes.

The Pt received Lasix 40mg IV and O2 @ 3L/min.



At NYSH-Ed, the Pt's vitals were: P 48 BP 157/78 RR 20 O2Sat 99% on 2L

The Pt received ASA 325mg PO. 

Since receiving the Lasix, the Pt's LE edema has drastically diminished, and the Pt states that he feels a lot better.



The Pt has not experienced any recent weight loss and is on a regular diet without salt restriction (he uses salt 2-3x/wk).  He also claims that he is adherent to taking his meds.



PMHx:  

DM

HTN

hyperlipidemia

s/p MI - 6/93

AICD - 9/93 

CAD w/ LAD stent - 2092

chronic anemia - Hct w/in the 30-33 range

colon cancer resection - 2078

diverticular disease



MEDS:

Amlodipine 7.5mg QD

ASA

Fosinopril 40mg BID

HCTZ 25mg QD

Metoprolol 100mg BID

Lipitor 10mg QHS

Glucophage 1g BID

Glyburide 10mg BID

Omeprazole 20mg QD

Viagra 100mg PRN



ALLERGIES: oxycodone, plavix    rash



SOCIAL Hx: The Pt lives at home w/ his wife (49yo in good health) and son (27yo in good health).  He states that he does not drink alcohol and quit smoking 20 years ago after having smoked 2 cigars/day for 20yrs. He denies using illicit drugs.  He has 2 pitbulls at home and has no recent travels. 



FAMILY Hx: No FHx of HTN, DM, hyperlipidemia, or cancer.

       

ROS: 

Const: No lethargy, weight gain/loss, good appetite.

HEENT: No HA, vision changes, auras, or injuries.

CV/Resp: See HPI. 

GI: No diarrhea, difficulty swallowing, abdominal pain, blood.

GU: No nocturia, discharge, dysuria, or hematuria. No increased frequency. 

Musco/skel/Skin: Has arthritis. No skin changes. 

Neuro/Psych: No numbness, tingling, pain, loss of coordination or balance, weakness, or loss of memory.



PHYSICAL EXAM:

       VS:  T 98.7 P 60 BP 158/62 RR 22 O2Sat 94% on 2L

        Gen: Pt was breathing comfortably on RA. Able to get out of bed and ambulate.

        Skin:  No telangiectasias, palmar erythema, or rashes.  Acanthosis nigricans present on the back of the neck.

        HEENT: nonicteric, conjunctiva pink, EOMI.  OP clear without exudates, MMM.

        Neck:  supple, NT, no thyromegaly, no carotid bruits, no JVD, no LAD

        Lungs: CTA and percussion b/l

        Heart: RRR, nl S1 and S2, II/VI SEM at LLSB. No S3 or S4 appreciated. 

        Abd: +BS, soft, NT. Distended abdomen. Liver edge palpable 3cm from costal border.  Paradoxical rise during inspiration. No caput medusa.

        Extr: Pitting edema 6in from ankle b/l in LE. PT pulses 2+ b/l. No cyanosis.

        Neuro: AOx3, CN II-XII intact.  Motor 5/5 throughout except L arm, which was limited by pain. 

DTR's not appreciated in any of the extremities (triceps, brachioradialis, knees, and ankles).



LABS:



Test Description         Result             Flags    Ref. Range       Units



Sodium (Stat Lab)        143                         (135-145)        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)     3.9                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)      109                H        (100-108)        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)           25.8                        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)           24                          (8-25)           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)    1.4                         (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)       150                H        (70-110)         mg/dl



Calcium                  9.0                         (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Phosphorus               3.1                         (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl

Magnesium                1.4                         (1.4-2.0)        meq/L



WBC                      8.4                         (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                      33.4               L        (41.0-53.0)      %

HGB                      10.8               L        (13.5-17.5)      gm/dl

RBC                      4.14               L        (4.50-5.90)      mil/cmm

PLT                      291                         (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                      81                          (80-100)         fl

MCH                      26.1                        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                     32.4                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                      14.8               H        (11.5-14.5)      %

PT                       11.8                        (11.1-13.1)      sec

PT-INR                   0.9

     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.

APTT                     26.0                        (22.1-35.1)      sec

     Specimen not received on ICE



UA-Specific Gravity      1.015                       (1.001-1.035)

UA-pH                    5.0                         (5.0-9.0)

UA-WBC Screen            NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Nitrite               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Albumin                                           (NEG)

     3+SAMPLE SENT TO HEME LAB FOR ADDITIONAL TESTING

UA-Glucose               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Ketones               NEGATIVE                    (NEG)

UA-Occult Blood                                      (NEG)

     TRACE INTACT

UA-SED-RBC               0-2                         (0-2)            /hpf

UA-SED-WBC               0-2                         (0-2)            /hpf

UA-SED-Bacteria          NEGATIVE                    (NEG)            /hpf

Hyaline Cast             0-2                         (0-5)            /lpf

Squamous Cells           NEGATIVE                    (NEG)            /hpf

.

Creatine Kinase Isoenz   	NEGATIVE x2 

Troponin-I               	NEGATIVE x2 



EKG:   NSR, bradycardia (54bpm), LAE, TW-flattening in V5,V6. Biphasic TW in V2-V4. LVH by voltage criteria.  No difference from past EKGs.



CXR FINDINGS:

	Cardiac AICD projecting over the left hemithorax, unchanged. Lung fields are clear. 

Cardiomediastinal contours are unchanged. Right sided diaphragmatic hernia, unchanged. Bony 

thorax is unchanged.



No evidence of active cardiopulmonary disease. 



Echo (6/93):  EF 60%, symmetric LVH



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN: This is a 73yo male w/ a complicated PMH that includes HTN, DM, hyperlipidemia, CAD, and a past MI, which resulted in the placement of an AICD, who now p/w SOB.

	

PE - This is still possible given the lack of diagnostic studies to rule out.  Although, there were no 

CP or calf pain suggestive of DVTs.  Consider D-dimer to rule out recent PE.   

	Ischemia  - EKG and the negative set of cardiac enzymes x2 does not suggest this. However, Pt 

has not had any acute Sx while on the floor. 

PNA - This is less likely given the lack of fever or elevated WBC.

Tumor - This is also less likely given the lack of weight loss, the acute nature of the symptoms, 

and the lacko f lymphadenopathy.



1)	SOB - Most likely CHF>PE/DVT>ischemia>>PNA,tumor; however, he currently appears asymptomatic. PE is still possible given the lack of diagnostic studies to rule out, although there were no CP or calf pain suggestive of DVTs, and the onset was not acute.  The Pt may have had an exertional ischemia but the lack of CP and EKGs changes makes this less likely; however, the Pt has been asymptomatic on the floor and so no EKG tracings concomitant with the SOB are available to completely rule out this possibility.  PNA and tumor are less likely given the lack of fevers and chills and any hx of weight loss.  



Will start the Pt on O2 in addition to his normal medicinal regimen of diuretics, beta-blockers, and ACE-I.  Will consider the addition of spironolactone.  Order echo to determine EF and to identify structural myocardial changes if any.  Order LFT's to check for decreased perfusion to vital organs.  Monitor UOP for kidney functions.  Monitor EKG for any changes.  Will send for a D-dimer to r/o recent PE. 



2)	HTN - Poorly controlled, may be 2o to missing meds today. Will also be treated using meds for CHF.

3)	DM - Sugars elevated.  Will treat w/ his home medication of glucophage and glyburide.

4)	Hyperlipidemia - Stable. Cont home medication of Lipitor.

5)	FEN - Switch to low salt diet with no concentrated sweet.  Consider a diabetic diet as well.

6)	Dispo - Will d/c once Pt is stabilized.



Willie Nix, TMS III

Pager:  20243









12/10/94 Intern addendum:



Patient seen and examined with med student above.  Agree with overall assessment above.  Briefly:



This is a 73M with a hx of CAD s/p MI, s/p AICD, IDDM, HTN, and hyperlipidemia, who presents with DOE, PND and bilateral leg edema x4 days.  DOE is not associated with anginal symptoms including CP, nausea, vomiting, and diaphoresis, although the patient reports it is relieved by nitroglycerine.  Physical exam findings here are notable for a flat JVP, absence of crackles, 2/6 SEM at LLSB and apex, and mild, symmetric, pitting edema in bilateral lower extremities.  Per chart notes, in clinic he was noted to have bulging neck veins.  



Favor CHF >?pacer malfunction, ischemia > PE.  CHF is a somewhat confusing picture as symptoms suggest L-sided failure with pulmonary edema while there is little objective data (no crackles on exam, CXR clear) to suggest this.  Prior to our evaluation he received 40 of IV Lasix and diuresed at least one liter (with subjective improvement), which may account for this discrepancy.  



Plan is for echo to evaluate his LV function, pacer interrogation, and stress.  D-dimer should be sufficient to pursue PE as this is a low-prob possibility.









Noah Escobar, MD, PhD

Internal Medicineintern

Pager #08163





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>