<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2075-10-17

					

Novolog 3/4-5/5/6	683-51-28

Lantus 20-21 at hs	Xuan, Wendy

Neoral 100/100 mg bid 

CellCept 1000 mg bid 

Lopressor 12.5 mg bid

Lipitor 10 mg qd

Neurontin 600/600/1200 mg tid

Tums 200 mg ii bid 

Prilosec 20 mg bid

MVI i bid

ASA 325 mg qd

Quinine Sulfate 260 mg at hs

Bilberry to help with night vision - from acupuncturist

Flax Seed Oil ii qd



October 17, 2075



Interim History:	

Comes to review her medical problems.

Has been feeling well. 



Home Blood Tests:  Records downloaded from meter with little detail and somewhat scattered BS.

B 	57-448

L	71-222

S	101-254

HS	163-399

No food records. No severe hypoglycemia. Has had a couple of nocturnal reactions. There are not enough data points to determine whether the Lantus dose is appropriate.



Retinopathy:	Saw Dr. Aragon over the spring. Has had extensive laser in the past, and had some last year OS after her surgery.

Nephropathy:	Her creatinine was stable at 1.3 in July

Neuropathy:	Feet are not bothering her. Sometimes has a peculiar diffuse tingling sensation precipitated by motion. 

Cardiac:	No chest pain. No unusual dyspnea on exertion. Has been able to exercise in the gym twice a week, walking steadily at a pretty fast pace for an hour. 

Vascular:	No claudication



Past Medical History: 

Medications: no significant changes

Immunizations. Has not had flu shot yet this year. Had the second of hepatitis A series in L deltoid today.



Review of Systems: above

Breast: Saw Dr. Bruce a few weeks ago. Ultrasound showed what is being interpreted as a stable slightly enlarge intramammary lymph node. She find the lower part of the sternotomy scar to be very uncomfortable in most bras and wants to consider whether it can be improved.

Gyn: Overdue to see Yareli Kilgore; she will make the appointment.

Skin: Has noted some crusting lesions on her scalp.



Physical Exam:	

Looks well. In very good spirits. Jake is with her.

BP:   134/80		P:   72	Seated

BP:   116/76		P:   76	Standing

Wt:   168 without shoes, stable

HEENT:	Anicteric. 

Carotids:	Normal pulses, without bruits

Chest:	Clear to percussion and auscultation

	There is a small keloid at the inferior portion of the median sternotomy scar

Heart:	Normal S1; physiologic S2.  No gallops.  2/6 systolic ejection murmur

Abdomen:	No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness. No palpable AAA. 

Extremities:	No edema.        DP 1+,=.  PT 1+,=.  No open areas of feet. Has several toe deformities, dystrophic nails and probable onychomycosis.

Skin:	Crusting lesion on scalp



Impressions and Plan:	

Hard to assess control. She is reluctant to keep hand records.

Will try to add an ACE inhibitor again. Start captopril 6.25 mg bid and increase the 12.5 mg bid if tolerated. Check BP at home.

She would like to consider treatment for onychomycosis. Would suggest that Dr. Xie send a paring for fungal culture before we consider it. Also, LFTs were slightly abnormal in July and will need to be repeated. Finally, would have to check medication incompatibilities before proceeding.

Refer to Dr. xia for consideration of modification of her sternotomy scar. Warned her that he may not feel that it is a good idea either on pure surgical grounds on because of her immunosuppression, but it is worth asking his opinion.

Refer to Dr. Keeler for evaluation of scalp lesions.

Flu shot R deltoid with usual preamble. Aventis Fluzone Lot L5317YR. Exp. 7/10/76.

A1c, SGOT, SGPT, alkaline phosphatase, Bili T/D, Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine 

Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine again in 1 month if she is taking captopril at that time.



Appointments:	



cc:	Xavier Dotson, M.D.

	Yael Keeler, M.D.

	Ysidro Xia. M.D.

	Transplant Associates





			Yacob T. Kane, M.D., Ph.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-11-21

					

Novolog 3-7 tid	683-51-28

Lantus 19-20 at hs	Xuan, Wendy

Neoral 100/100 mg bid 

CellCept 1000 mg bid 

Lopressor 12.5 mg bid

Captopril 12.5 mg bid

Lipitor 10 mg qd

Neurontin 600/1200 mg bid

Tums 200 mg ii bid (often forgets)

Prilosec 20 mg bid

MVI i bid

ASA 325 mg qd

Quinine Sulfate 260 mg at hs



November 21, 2076



Interim History:	

Comes to review his medical problems.



Hip X-Rays may have shown early degenerative changes. Still has pain from them on a daily basis but it is minor. Has not tried any analgesics, even acetaminophen. 

Shoulders have bothered her for years and she has seen Dr. Baird with diagnosis of adhesive capsulitis. Hands have bothered her in the past but do not currently. 



A1c has been over 9 % and she says that control has not changed. Does not have records but says that she tests about tid.

Retinopathy:	Saw Dr. Aragon a few weeks ago. Now going only yearly. Last laser was about 2.5 years ago. Reports that vision was 20/20 in one eye and 20/25 in the other.

Nephropathy:	Cr was 1.4 in July. Says that transplant clinic wanted her to return a month after the last visit but she did not want to do so. She thinks that it was for follow-up of an elevated WBC. However, her WBC has been normal over the last several visits. 

Neuropathy:	Not consistent with taking the Neurontin, and notes it she misses it.

Cardiac:	No chest pain or unusual dyspnea on exertion. Does feel out of shape if she climbs    100 stairs   .  She is seeing Dr. Dotson in two weeks.  

Vascular:	No claudication



Past Medical History: 

Medications: no changes



Social History: 

Jack has had a UC flair and several other problems recently. Both of his parents have cancer. 

They is thinking of going on a vacation to (high altitude) in Argentina if he is well enough. 



Review of Systems: above





Physical Exam:	

Looks well.

BP:   114/82		P:   72, regular	

Wt:   163 without shoes, down 0.5

HEENT:	Anicteric. 

Carotids:	Normal pulses, without bruits

Chest:	Clear to auscultation

Heart:	Normal S1; paradoxical S2.  .  No gallops.  No murmurs

Abdomen:	No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness. No palpable AAA. 

Extremities:	No edema.        DP 1-2+,=.  PT 2+,=.  No active foot lesions.



Impressions and Plan:	

Hard to refine her diabetes control without more data.

No specific indication of recurrent problems with coronary artery disease, but she seems worried about the dyspnea on exertion which she experiences and so will try to clear the air with ETT. ETT with sestamibi.

Try to get flu shot locally.  If unsuccessful, call here every few weeks to see whether we have them. 

Mammograms

A1c, TSH, Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine



Appointments:	4 months



cc:	Xavier Dotson, M.D.

	Transplant Clinic





			Yacob T. Kane, M.D., Ph.D.

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-01-29

					

Novolog 3-7 tid	683-51-28

Lantus 19-20 at hs	Xuan, Wendy

Neoral 100/100 mg bid 

CellCept 1000 mg bid 

Lopressor 25/12.5 mg bid

Captopril 12.5 mg bid

Lipitor 10 mg qd

Neurontin 600/1200 mg bid

Tums 200 mg ii bid (often forgets)

Prilosec 20 mg bid

MVI i bid

ASA 325 mg qd

Quinine Sulfate 260 mg at hs

Senekot



January 29, 2077



Interim History:	

Comes to review her medical problems.

Her ETT showed mild distal anterior and antero-apical ischemia. The last p-CABG ETT was done in September, 2074, and did not included nuclear images. The electrocardiographic portion of both tests was considered to be uninterpretable because of inadequate elevation of the heart rate. Dr. Dotson asked her to double the atenolol dose. Since she has had low BP in the past, we increased it to only 25/12.5. BP 80/50-90/60 at home and she has not felt so well, tired. Not sure whether the dyspnea on exertion that led us to get the ETT has changed since she has not challenged it. 



Home Blood Tests:  Not very good by history. A1c over 9%. She still has trouble focusing on it. 

Retinopathy:	Visions stable.

Nephropathy:	Cr slightly up to 1.5

Cardiac:	above

Vascular:	No claudication



Past Medical History: 

Has had flu shot this year.



Review of Systems: above



Physical Exam:	

Looks well.

BP:   110/76   120/80 by me (not sure she took meds this AM)		P:   72, regular	

Wt:   167 without shoes, up 4

Neck:	No JVD

Chest:	Clear to auscultation

Heart:	Normal S1; ? physiologic S2.  No gallops.  No murmurs

Extremities:	No edema.            





Impressions and Plan:	

Reduce the captopril to 6.25 mg bid.

Report back BP; may have room to go up to 25 mg bid on the atenolol.

She does have some hypoglycemia and symptoms are sometimes subtle. Stressed the likely greater difficulty in perceiving hypoglycemia on beta blockers. 

Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine



Appointments:	As scheduled



cc:	Xavier Dotson, M.D.





			Yacob T. Kane, M.D., Ph.D.

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-06-03

					
Novolog 3-10 tid	683-51-28
Lantus 19-20 at hs	Xuan, Wendy
Neoral 100/100 mg bid 
CellCept 1000 mg bid 
Toprol XL 25 mg qd, not yet started
Lipitor 10 mg qd
Neurontin 600/1200 mg bid
Tums 200 mg ii qd (should be at least bid)
Prilosec 20 mg bid
MVI i bid
ASA 325 mg qd
Quinine Sulfate 260 mg at hs
Tylenol 1325 mg over the day for arthritis
Wellbutrin 150 mg bid
Androgel to leg qd
DHEA qd

Jun 03, 2078

Interim History:	
Comes to review her medical problems.

Has lost weight thanks to some spring viral illnesses     she is pleased about it.
Reports that her control has not been good and does not have records.
No severe hypoglycemia.
Retinopathy:	Still has not seen Dr. Aragon. No subjective change in visual acuity.
Nephropathy:	Cr 1.7 in January. Has not seen transplant MDs in a couple of years. Formerly saw Dr. Hayes. 
Neuropathy:	No foot discomfort.
Cardiac:	Has occasional high substernal chest tightness, every couple of weeks, over about 6 months, unrelated to exercise. Can last up to 15 minutes. Has not become more frequent. Sees Dr. Dotson annually. Has sensation about weekly that she cannot swallow, liquids>solids. Has had this for over a year and it has not been progressive.  
Vascular:	No claudication.

Past Medical History: 
Medications: wants to reduce costs     asks about generics for Lipitor, transplant meds. 

Family History: 
Wendee has been profiled in the media because of her work as an industrial engineer 

Social History: 
Jake is well. His parents have been ill. 

Review of Systems: above
Psych: Referred to urologist at KJH, Dr. Xayachack (? sp) because of absent libido. He made the switch from Celexa to Wellbutrin and added Androgel and DHEA. She has noted more acne or no more libido. The loss of libido precedes the Celexa and the possibility of its relationship to Neoral or CellCept has been raised. 
She sees her gynecologist regularly.

Physical Exam:	
Looks remarkably well.
BP:   160/98   170/88		P:   60, regular	
Wt:   153 without shoes, down 15
HEENT:	Anicteric. 
Fundi:	Limited views; laser scars; some ? fibrous bands OS. No active lesions seen.
Carotids:	Normal pulses, without bruits
Thyroid:	20-25 grams, firm without nodules.
Chest:	Clear to auscultation
Heart:	Normal S1; physiologic S2.  S4.  2/6 systolic ejection murmur
Abdomen:	No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness. No palpable AAA. 
Extremities:	No edema.  Pedal pulses all 1-2+ except L PT not palpable.           Small blister, resolving L 5th toe. Small crust L medial malleolus. 

Impressions and Plan:	
Hard to assess control without data. Hopefully her weight loss does not reflect terrible control.
BP much too high. Start Toprol 25 mg qd.
I have no objection to switch to simvastatin from atorvastatin for  cost reasons, but she must check with the transplant MDs re: this switch because of Neoral interaction with statins.
Her chest pain does not sound particularly cardiac but will ask Dr. Dotson whether he wants any further evaluation. 
MUST     see Dr. Aragon, see transplant MD. Make these appointments for her today.
Will get barium swallow because of her dysphagia - ? disorganized esophageal contractions; consider manometry with Dr. Quam.
A1c, Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine, Ca, P, A/G, 25-(OH) vitamin D, PTH, CBC, urinalysis. Has already taken her Neoral today.
Fasting lipids another day.
Stool guaiacs. Has not done them.

Appointments:	NP 1 week to check BP
	Me 3 months

cc:	Xavier Dotson, M.D.
	Transplant Clinic


			Yacob T. Kane, M.D., Ph.D.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-06-10

					

Novolog 3-10 tid	683-51-28

Lantus 19-20 at hs	Xuan, Wendy

CellCept 1000 mg bid 

Rapamune 2/1 mgs qod

Toprol XL 25 mg qd

Lipitor 10 mg qd

Neurontin 600/1200 mg bid

Tums 200 mg ii qd (should be at least bid)

Prilosec 20 mg bid

MVI i bid

ASA 325 mg qd

Tylenol 1325 mg over the day for arthritis

Wellbutrin 150 mg bid

Androgel to leg qd

DHEA 25 mg qd

Celexa 80 mg qAM  (Dr. Colin Keane)



Jun 10, 2079



Interim History:	

Comes to review her medical problems.

She has been well overall but has been bothered by trigger finger (R ring). She has seen Dr. Ibarra, who has suggested surgery since a steroid injection did not help.

Brings no test results. No severe hypoglycemia.

Retinopathy:	Saw Dr. Aragon yesterday. Stable. Last laser was about 5 years ago. 1 year.

Nephropathy:	Reports that she cannot do blood tests at KJH since she gets copays. Covered if done at Promptcare. She does not recall when her BUN/Cr were last checked but says that it was prior to January and that results were sent to Dr. Hayes. 

Neuropathy:	Not much troubled by neuropathy.  She still has the sensation of food or liquid getting stuck mid sternal level. BaS last year showed GERD and dysmotility. I am not sure that Reglan would help, but have reluctance to try it in any case because of her long history of depression. 

Cardiac:	She thinks that she may be having dyspnea on exertion that is easier to precipitate than it had been. She has had some sternal discomfort at rest on two occasions while sitting at rest - felt bony. She says that she has been    trying to ignore    the possible increase in dyspnea on exertion. She sees Dr. Dotson in October. 

Vascular:	No claudication



Past Medical History: 

Medications: Stopped Quinine; increased Celexa. Did not start simvastatin since did not have blood work done. 



Social History:

Ivory is well. 



Review of Systems: above

Skin: Saw colleague of Dr. Keeler yesterday. Given cream for scalp.

Gyn: Report that Yareli Kilgore will no longer see her for routine follow-up. Periods are regular. Does not use contraception. Has never been pregnant. Discussed this and she left it that she is not worried about it.



Physical Exam:	

Looks well.

BP:   120/76		P:   82, regular

Wt:   161.5 without shoes, stable

HEENT:	Anicteric. 

Carotids:	Normal pulses, without bruits

Chest:	Clear to auscultation

Breasts:	No masses; no nodes	

Nodes:	No cervical, supraclavicular, axillary

Heart:	Normal S1; physiologic S2.  S4.  2/6 systolic ejection murmur

Abdomen:	No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. No tenderness. No palpable AAA. 

Extremities:	No edema.        DP 1-2+,=.  PT absent.   L great toenail appears to be about to be lost, thickened with probable subungual hematoma.

Neurological:	AJ absent.  



Impressions and Plan:	

Will get ETT with imaging. Need approval from her insurance. Call if she has any more convincing cardiac symptoms.

She should see Yareli Holcomb, NP for Pap with history of HPV and abnormal Paps in the past. 

She should see Dr. Xie for foot care. 

Strongly suggest she get some labs in the next week or so, fasting:

A1c, lipids, Electrolytes, BUN/Creatinine, CBC, SGOT, SGPT, alkaline phosphatase, Bili T/D, urinalysis





Appointments:	Yareli Holcomb, NP as above

	Me 4 months



cc:	Xavier Dotson, M.D.

	Henry Hayes, M.D.





			Yacob T. Kane, M.D., Ph.D.





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>