<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2092-03-10

History of Present Illness	

ID: 70 yo AMI s/p LAD intervention



HPI:

11/90 episode mild CP radiating to both arms and DOE. 

ETT- 6', HR 150 (99%), -CP, +SOB, EKG normal, occ PAC, rare PVC (no imaging), SL TNG prescribed but not used



Did well, able to con't walking 1 mile or more a day and daily exercise routine of jumping rope and pushups



2 weeks ago intermittent angina (SSCP/pressure to bilat arm with dyspnea, nausea, "cold sweat" +/- dizziness) with inclines/pushing, relieved by rest, lasting up to several mins but denies nocturnal, rest or prolonged episodes; decreasing exercise tolerance



3/10 awoke 2 AM with stuttering angina, took 1 SL TNG (expired) with transient relief; 7 AM to RDC ER, 7/10 CP, EKG RB3, Q V1-3, TWI III/V1, biphasic V2-3, I/L/V4-6 0.5 mm STE (neg rt sided leads); rx SL TNG, ASA, IV Heparin, improved CP but nausea- resolved with addition of IV Lopressor, Aggrastat, Mylanta (painfree by 8:45 AM); CK 179/9/5%, Troponin T  0.124; some confusion and ?visual halluc (reported seeing red spots on daughters face and green lines on wall transiently) after Ativan 1 mg IV for anxiety at RDC and Fentanyl 50 mcg/Versed 0.5 mg at LMH: cath- right dom, distal RCA collat to dist LAD, 50% OM1 bifurcation lesion, 100% prox/severe long mid LAD- s/p PTCA/stent (4 X 15 AVE Bestent 2) proximal, PTCA mid with prolonged inflations, 25% resid, ?small dissection mid/distal; Integrelin and 375 cc dye, 3/10 CP on arrival to lab 1:30 pm, persistent 1-3/10 CP with nausea +/- dyspnea since arrival in holding area 3 pm, EKG with V3-6 0.5-1.5 mm STE unchanged from pre-procedure and ?sl more prominent V3, painfree with 2 SL TNG



CRF:      -HTN          +DM         +Chol         +FH Uncle MI 62        ex-tob X 32 yrs (avg 2 ppd X 35 yrs prior, pt states started age 6!)



Past Medical History	

asbestos exposure- no known pulm dx

arthritis- fingers

iritis



Past Surgical History	

s/p left thumb surgery

s/p skin Ca excision/cryotherapy (back, face)



Medications	

HOME: (Pts. family to bring meds in 3/11)

ASA 325 mg qd

Glipizide (?XL) 5 mg q AM

Guaifenesin 2 tabs bid

Metamucil q PM

Natural tears ou qid

Lubricating eye ointment hs

MVI 1 qd

Ibuprofen 600 mg prn joint pain, sleep (few times/week)

HOSP: IV Aggrastat 11 cc/hr

IV TNG 17 incr to 50 mcg/min





Allergies	

Tylenol-rash



Social History	

lives alone, divorced, 7 children (2 sons in same town), medical care at Rusk State Hospital



Habits	

-ETOH           Caffeine- tea        

Diet- lowfat, NAS, 8 glasses H2O/day            



Family History	

-HTN     ?DM      -CVA         Mo Aplastic anemia, Bro leukemia



Review of Systems	

intermittent right foot numbness +/- bilat elbow numbness, EMG 2 mos ago at RSH revealed "nerve damage" per pt, no etiology discussed or rx given per pt, URI 2 mos ago with small amt blood in nasal discharge attrib to dry nose- no signif nosebleeds, chronic nocturia X3-4 and recent nl PSA/prostate exam, occas constipation controlled with fiber; otherwise negative in detail



Physical Exam	  

T 99.8          SR 80-90 no ect        RR 18        BP 120-130/70-80   sat 92% 3L/95% 5L           Ht:6'             Wt:200# per pt

General Appearance	

elderly white male in bed NAD, fair historian

Neurological	

PERL left 3.5, right 4 mm, brisk, EOMI, no nystagmus, no droop or ptosis, MAE 4/4, slightly lethargic but easily arousable to voice, O X 3, speech clear and appropriate

Neck	

2+ carotids, no bruit, JVP 6

Cor/Cardiac	

RRR, S1S2, no murmur/rub/gallop

Chest	

Lungs clear anteriorly

Abdomen	

Large, soft, NT/ND, nl BS, no hepatomegaly/mass/bruit

Extremity	

right fem A/V sheaths in, no heme/ooze, left 2+ fem no bruit, feet warm 2+ DP/PT, no edema



External Labs	

Lab:







EKG: NSR, nl axis, bord 1AVB, 0.20/0.14/0.43, RB3, Q V1-3, ST-T changes (as described in HPI)



CXR: 3/10 RDC- "NAD"



Plan	

#1 CAD- 70 yo ruling in for MI s/p LAD intervention

-Ischemia- angina resolved with nitrates, reviewed EKG with Dr. Espinosa (in to examine pt) and discussed with Dr. Espinosa and Jessup, will keep sheaths in overnight, restart Hep no bolus when PTT down, con't Integrelin, ASA/Plavix (initiate Zantac prophylaxis and guiaic stools), NPO after midnight in case relook indicated, con't IV TNG 

-Pump- will obtain echo (no LV gram done), monitor I/O, diurese if CHF sx (sat lowish but no JVD/crackles, ?baseline pulm dz), con't post cath hydration and check creat in AM (375 cc dye), consider initiating Ace-I, hold on Ibuprofen for now

-Rhythm- suboptimal rate control, con't Lopressor 25 mg qid- change to bid dosing once tolerance better evaluated, watch for wheeze or ectopy



#2 DM- Accucheck bid, check HGbA1c, resume Glipizide in AM (unless relook cath), initiate Lipitor for LDL 126; defer PT/dietary consults for now



#3 ID- low grade temp and mild WBC elevation on admission, will check UA now, CXR in AM, initiate Ancef while sheaths in



#4 Neuro- transient confusion and ?visual halluc prob due to benzos/narcotics, neuro exam nonfocal, will maintain freq observation for pt safety, esp given sheaths overnight

Arushi Emerson, RNCS





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-07-13

 



Team 1b Medical Intern Admission Note



Pt:	Jasso, Stephen

MR#: 	 7990698

Date of Admission:  7/05/95

Attending: 	I. Ellsworth



CC:  Vertigo, EKG changes



HPI:  73   yo with h/o of DM, CAD s/p anteroseptal MI (2091) and stent placement presents with 2 days of vertigo, most prominent upon wakening in the a.m.  He reports feeling as if he is spinning while the room is stable; this sensation is worsened by changes in position or head movement.  It diminishes only slightly as the day progresses.  He denies any numbness, weakness, tingling, changes in vision or memory.  He denies any recent URI.  He does report tinnitus which has been present intermittently for years as well as bilateral sensorineural hearing secondary to gunshot exposure.  No NV. The sensation of vertigo is superimposed upon one week of gradually progressive loss of balance, described as not knowing where to put his limbs in relation to space.  He also reports ~7 days of mild diarrhea in a.m only, attributable to eating sorbitol ice cream as well as continuing to take Metamucil for the same 7 day period.  Diarrhea has been fully resolved for 2 days PTA. He does report good PO fluid intake, ~8 bottles of H20 per day.  He monitors his sugars regularly and reports they have been running in the 110-140s. He denies any fevers, chills, sweats or sick contacts.  The patient does have ptosis on the L and reports that this has been present less than one month.  He has had no changes in medications.



Additionally, the patient reports one episode of fleeting chest pain along the midaxillary line on 07/12 which was relieved immediately by NTG.  (Pt attributes the pain to gas as the belching coincident with the NTG also seemed to relieve the pain).  He does also report an increase in SOB after walking up one flight of stairs which has arisen over the past few months.



PMH: 

DM x 20 years, peripheral neuropathy

HTN

CAD

Anteroseptal MI in 03/91, PTCA and stent

EF 32% (last echo 2092)

Hemorrhoids (normal colo 2095)

Iritis, corneal dystrophy

Osteoporosis

Diverticulosis (?)



Meds:  	

Glipizide 2.5 QD

Asa  325 QD

Lisinopril 5mg QD

Lopressor  50 mg BID

Lipitor  10 mg QD

Amitryptilline  25 mg QHS

Prednisone gtt

Caltrate + D (CALCIUM Carbonate 1500 Mg (600 Mg Elem Ca)/ Vit D 200 Iu)  1 TAB PO BID











All:  	Acetaminophen--rash



SH:  	

	Tob:  	43 year pack hx, quit 2060	EtOH:	denies	Illicits:	 denies



FH:  	Mother:  pernicious anemia

Father:  died in accident at young age

Brother:  leukemia



ROS:	

As in HPI.  

-	General: no weight loss/gain, no fatigue, no fevers, no chills, no change in appetite

-	Respiratory: no cough, no SOB, no DOE, no hemoptysis, no wheezing

-	HEENT: no neck stiffness, no hoarseness, no hearing loss

-	Cardiac: chest pain/pressure as above, no palpitations, no orthopnea, no PND

-	Gastrointestinal: no nausea, no vomiting, no diarrhea, no constipation, no bleeding

-	Neurologic: diminished sensation in LLE bilaterally

-	Lymph nodes: no enlarged lymph nodes

-	Musculoskeletal: No back pain, no neck pain, no leg pain, no arm pain

-	Urologic: No hematuria, no dysuria, no polyuria, no nocturia 

-	Hematologic: No bruising, no bleeding

-	Exposures: No sick contacts, no recent travel  



Exam:  	 

	VS:  	97.7  74 18  98%  supine 108/54 standing 127/70

HEENT: NC/AT, PERRL, nonicteric.  EOMI, no nystagmus. MMM, w/o exudates.

Dicks Hall Pike maneuver elicited neither nystagmus nor symptoms

Neck:  	supple, NT, full ROM, 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no LAD. JVP 7cm

Lungs:  CTAB; no crackles, no wheezes

Cor:  	RRR; normal S1S2, no m/r/g appreciated

Abd:  	soft, non-tender, non-distended; NABS; no organomegaly

G/R: 	brown stool, guaiac neg in ER

Extr:  	no c/c/e; 2+ DP's, 1+ PTs bilaterally

Neuro: AOx3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact with exception of L ptosis, motor and sensory nonfocal; DTR's 2+ and symmetric throughout. Equivocal Babinskis bilaterally. F to N nl, H to S nl, FFM intact, Romberg neg.



LE 	Hip flex	Hip ext	Knee flex	Knee ext	Ankle flex	Ankle ext	

Right	5	5	5	5	5	5	

Left	5	5	5	5	5	5	



UE 	Shoulder abd	Elbow ext	Elbow flex	Wrist ext	Wrist flex	Finger abd	

Right	5	5	5	5	5	5	

Left	5	5	5	5	5	5	



Labs:  



Chemistry:	       	          	          	          

          	          	          	          

Chemistry

  Lytes/Renal/Glucose

    Sodium                 139   135-145 mmol/L     07/13/95 12:59    

    Potassium              3.7   3.4-4.8 mmol/L     07/13/95 12:59

    Chloride               107   100-108 mmol/L     07/13/95 12:59

    Carbon Dioxide        23.9   23.0-31.9 mmol/L   07/13/95 12:59    21.0(L) 03/12/92 

    BUN                     11   8-25 mg/dl         07/13/95 12:59

    Creatinine             0.9   0.6-1.5 mg/dl      07/13/95 12:59

    Glucose                111H  70-110 mg/dl       07/13/95 12:59     111(H) 07/13/95 



  

    CK-MB             NEGATIVE   NEG                07/13/95 12:08    15.6(H) 03/12/92 

    Troponin-I        NEGATIVE   NEG                07/13/95 12:08



  Lipid Tests

    Cholesterol            120   mg/dl              07/04/95 15:59

    Triglycerides          102   40-150 mg/dl       07/04/95 15:59

    HDL                     41   35-100 mg/dl       07/04/95 15:59

    LDL Cholesterol         59   mg/dl              07/04/95 15:59

    Chol/HDL Ratio         2.9                      07/04/95 15:5



    Hemoglobin A1C        4.40   3.80-6.40 %        07/09/95 11:31    6.50(H) 03/14/92 



Hematology

  Complete Blood Count

    WBC                    8.5   4.5-11.0 th/cmm    07/13/95 12:35    15.5(H) 03/12/92 

    RBC               NOT DONE   4.50-5.90 mil/cm   07/13/95 12:35

    Hgb               see detail                    07/13/95 12:35    13.0(L) 03/11/92 

    HCT               see detail                    07/13/95 12:35    40.5(L) 03/12/92 

    MicroHCT              31.5L  41.0-53.0 %        07/13/95 13:17    31.5(L) 07/13/95 

    MCV               NOT DONE   80-100 fl          07/13/95 12:35

    MCH               NOT DONE   26.0-34.0 pg/rbc   07/13/95 12:35

    MCHC              NOT DONE   31.0-37.0 g/dl     07/13/95 12:35

    PLT                    206   150-350 th/cumm    07/13/95 12:35

    RDW               NOT DONE   11.5-14.5 %        07/13/95 12:35



Coagulation

  Routine Coagulation

    PT                    12.8   11.1-13.1 sec      03/11/92 12:16    13.5(H) 03/11/92 

    PT-INR                 1.1                      03/11/92 12:16





Cardiac markers negative x 1:     		          	          

	          	          	          

UA:negative



Guaic: negative



EKG: Old anteroseptal infarct-Q and ST elevations in V2-4



CXR:	The lungs are well aerated. There are no focal areas of

	consolidation or effusion.  The cardiac silhouette is normal in

	size and configuration.  There are no mediastinal abnormalities.

	There are no osseous or soft tissue abnormalities.

	

CT:

	No evidence of acute intracranial pathology.

	Nonspecific periventricular white matter hypodensities most

	consistent with microangiopathic disease in a patient of this age



MRA:  pending

________________________________________________________________________



A/P:  73 yo with h/o HTN, DM, CAD presenting with 2 days of vertigo and one week of loss of balance. Symptoms of vertigo are most consistent with peripheral vertigo.  BPPV most likely as symptoms are worse in a.m and diminish over the day. Given tinnitus Meniers on the diiferential but less likely. Labarynthitis less likely as there is no antecedent infection or associated nausea.  Given multiple risk factors central process such as stroke will image brain.  Vertigo combined with loss of balance, although not elicited on exam, may represent vertebrobasilar insufficiency.  EKG changes concerning for ventricular aneurysm v. anteroseptal reinfarction if viable tissue still remains.  ROMI and Echo in a.m.



Vertigo:

--CT negative for acute process

--MRI pending

--Neurology consulted





CV:

Ischemia

-	ROMI by EKG, markers

-	Transthoracic echo in a.m.

-	continue ASA; titrate up Lopressor for goal HR = 60 as BP tolerates

-	check fasting lipids in AM, continue Lipitor

-	continue lisinopril

-	recent HbA1c 4.4



Pump

-	no signs/symptoms of failure on exam, CXR



Rhythm

-	currently NSR; titrate up BB as above

-	watch for ectopy; keep K = 4, Mg =2



Dispo:

-	code status: FULL

 









_______________________________

Virgie Giuliana Quintanar,  M.D. 

Pager #11591







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-06-11





Internal Medicine

LANCASTER MEMORIAL HOSPITAL



Personal data and overall health   Mr. Jacobs is a 73yoM with a history of NIDDM, CAD s/p anteroseptal MI (2092) w/ stent placement, AIHA, BPPV.



Reason for visit   Follow-up Visit



Problem List (reviewed)



Diabetes mellitus (adult onset) MAJOR 

Atherosclerotic coronary vascular disease MAJOR 

Health maintenance MAJOR 

Anemia MAJOR 

Smoking status: former smoker 



Major Problems



Diabetes mellitus (adult onset)

Aug 13

S: Has history of DM2 for 20(+)years c/b peripheral neuropathy for which Mr. Jacobs takes amytriptyline with good effect. He has a hx of iritis and retinitis recently treated with steroids.  He follows-up with the Rusk State opthamologists. For foot care he sees a podiatrist at the RSH as well. There is no history of diabetic ulcer or cellulitis. He is maintained on glyburide 2.5mg for several years and he checks his BS qd with range of 100-150 and occasional episodes of hypoglycemia. His last AIC was 4.4% in 9/95. At this time his UA showed no proteinuria and his renal function is within normal limits. He is on an ACEi. His diabetic care is well managed at the Diabetic clinic by Whitney Bullock. 

P: c/w glyburide and current endocrine/optho/podiatry care.



Atherosclerotic coronary vascular disease

S: Mr. Jacobs has a hx of anteroseptal MI in 2092 and is s/p left main stent placement. In July of 2095, he had a TTE which was remarkable for an EF of 23%, reduced from 31% in 2092. Also notable for anteroseptal AK and infero-posterior HK. AD-MIBI in 9/95 with anteroseptal scar, but no ischemia. Does about 30 minutes of aerobic physical activity each morning without issue. No CP or SOB. Denies orthopnea, PND, LE edema. 

P: DM (AIC 4.4) and lipid control (LDL 59) is optimal. Medical Regimen consists of  ASA, BB, ACEi, Statin. Is a patient of Dr. Dunham and plan to see him annually. I wonder if he should be anticoagulated given his diffuse HK and whether he should be considered for BiV pacing.





Health maintenance

CAD: please see problem list

Tob: quit 25 years ago

EtOH: neg 

Exercise: intensive exercise regimen, but limited as of late by neuropathy 

Diet: eats fruits/vegetables; minimal salt, fatty foods    

Colon CA: Spring 2095 with normal colonoscopy

Prostate CA: next due for prostate exam in 7/96. Documented more than once in recent inpatient stay as non-enlarged, no nodules. PSA checked at RSH and is nl per patient. Will request RSH records. 

Seatbelts: y 

Sunscreen: y 

Vaccines: gets tetanus/pneumo at RSH (2095) and flu shot in the fall.



Anemia

History of Warm Autoimmune Hemolytic Anemia. Had Hct checked in April and it was 37. Is not light-headed, short of breathe, and denies any chest pain.



Allergies

Allergy   Gets rash with acetaminophen



Active Medications



glipizide 2.5mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:4

lisinopril 5 mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:4

nitroglycerin 0.4 mg SL Q 5 minutes, x 3 prn chect pain QTY:100 Refills:12

metoprolol 50mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:4

atorvastatin 10 mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:4

psyllium powder 1 tsp po bid please give sugar free psyllium QTY:x15ounces Refills:12

aspirin 81 mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:1 yr

Muro 128 1 drop each eye bedtime apply to both eyes at bedtime. QTY:1 Refills:12

sodium chloride one drop each eye qid apply one drop to each eye four times a day. QTY:1 Refills:12

amitriptyline 25 mg po qhs QTY:90 Refills:4



Change in therapies and Renewals

glipizide 2.5mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:4 Start: 11/03/2092

lisinopril 5 mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:4 Start: 11/03/2092

nitroglycerin 0.4 mg SL Q 5 minutes, x 3 QTY:100 Refills:12 Start: 11/03/2092 prn chect pain

metoprolol 50mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:4 Start: 11/03/2092

atorvastatin 10 mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:4 Start: 11/03/2092

psyllium powder 1 tsp po bid QTY:x15ounces Refills:12 Start: 11/03/2092 please give sugar free psyllium

aspirin 81 mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:1 yr Start: 11/03/2092

Muro 128 1 drop each eye bedtime QTY:1 Refills:12 Start: 5/05/2093 apply to both eyes at bedtime.

sodium chloride one drop each eye qid QTY:1 Refills:12 Start: 5/05/2093 apply one drop to each eye four times a day.

amitriptyline 25 mg po qhs QTY:90 Refills:4 Start: 10/12/2094

Iron sulfate 325mg  PO QD QTY:30 Refills:3 Start: 1/11/2096 End: 6/11/2096 take with food once daily. - Inactivated

Colace 100 mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 1/11/2096 End: 6/11/2096 - Inactivated



Past medical history   DM x 20 years, peripheral neuropathy

HTN

CAD 

Anteroseptal MI in 03/09, PTCA and stent 

EF 23% (last echo 2095) 

S/P Hemorrhoidectomy 2096  

Iritis, corneal dystrophy 

Osteoporosis 

Rheumatoid arthritis - affecting small joints of hands and back.  Had iritis as well and told the two were linked. Has not been told has ank. spond. or psoriatic.  Not active at present. 

Basal Cell CA: removed in 2094

Warm autoimmune hemolytic anemia



Family history   NC



Social history   Divorced.  7 children, 15 grandchildren. Worked as abiological technologist.  Ex smoker, quit 25 years ago; (-) EtOH since 2078 but previously heavy drinking hx; minimal C2H5.  Lives in Dushanbe apartment community.



Review of systems   All other systems negative in detail.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 100/60  R=L

Pulse 60  on BB

Weight 194  

Height 194  

General appearance   Well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.

Heent   NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, O/P clear without erythema or exudates.

Neck   JVP flat; carotids brisk, 2+ bilaterally without bruits, no goiter.

Chest   Clear to auscultation bilaterally.

Cor   PMI at 5th ICS, MCL. RRR nl s1, s2 without m/r/g.

Abdomen   NT/ND, no HSM. Normal active bowel sounds.

Extrem   All pulses palpable, no loss of hair, cap refill excellent. Feet are warm, no trauma or infection

Musc skel   No bony deformities.



Assessment and plan   Recheck HCT today. Follow-up with Dr. Duarte re issue of anticoagulation and BiV pacing. RTC in 3-4 months for annual physical exam.



Disposition





Signed electronically by Fagan, Kory  on Jun 11, 2096     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-12-09



 

 





Team 2 Intern Admission Note

Name: Stephen Jasso

MR# 799 06 98

Date of Admission: 12/08/96

Cardiologist: Dr Dailey 



ID/CC:75 YO M with chest pain 	







HPI: 

This pleasant 75 YO M presents today after multiple episodes of sharp L anterior chest pain. The first episode started this AM (10AM). It was left sided with out radiation non positional or pleuritic. Denies any associated sx such as palpitations, SOB, n,v. Although he has had a mild cough with throat irratation over the past few days.  He was attributing this pain to gas but he took an aspirin and (expired) nitroglycerine SL just in case. He had an anteroseptal MI in 2092 and when questioned he does not feel this pain is similar to his prior attack.  Later that day he had another episode of pain for which he felt more worried about, called the EMS for evaluation of a cardiac cause of his pain. On route to the Hospital the EMS gave SL nitro which relieved the pain. He was evaluated in the ED where he had EKG, cardiac enzymes and was given his normal dose of beta blocker. His EKG when compared showed evidence of his old anterior septal MI, possibly slightly inverted T waves in I,AVL and deeper T wave  inversions in V1-3. 

First 2 sets of cardiac enzymes have been normal and he has remained CP free since the last nitro. 



ROS:   No F/C/NS.  No change in weight/appetite. No Palpitations/Orthopnea/PND/LE edema/Claudication. No SOB/cough/hemoptysis/wheezing/sore throat/rash.  No N/V/D/hematochezia/melena. No delta MS/LOC. No slurring of speech, unilateral weakness. No dysuria.  No exposures/ingestions/recent travel.  Otherwise negative in detail.



PMH:

DM type 2

HTN

CAD 

Anteroseptal MI in 03/09, PTCA and stent 

EF 23% (last echo 2095) 

S/P Hemorrhoidectomy 2096  

Iritis, corneal dystrophy 

Osteoporosis 

Rheumatoid arthritis - affecting small joints of hands and back.  Had iritis as well and told the two were linked. Has not been told has ank. spond. or psoriatic.  Not active at present. 

Basal Cell CA: removed in 2094

Warm autoimmune hemolytic anemia



Medications:

glipizide 2.5mg po qd

lisinopril 5 mg po QD

nitroglycerin 0.4 mg SL Q 5 minutes

metoprolol 50mg po bid 

atorvastatin 10 mg po qd 

psyllium powder 1 tsp po bid 

psyllium

aspirin 81 mg po qd 

Muro 128 1 drop each eye bedtime.

sodium chloride one drop each eye qid .

amitriptyline 25 mg po qhs 

Iron sulfate 325mg  PO QD daily. - Inactivated

Colace 100 mg po bid 







Allergies:  	

Tylenol



SH:  	

Divorced.  7 children, 15 grandchildren. Worked as biological technologist.  Ex smoker, quit 25 years ago; (-) EtOH since 2078 but previously heavy drinking hx; minimal C2H5.  Lives in Dushanbe apartment community.





FH:	

HTN     ?DM      -CVA         Mo Aplastic anemia, Bro leukemia



Phys Exam 

VS:	T=AfebHR=68	BP= 95/60	RR=18	SaO2 96%= 2L

General:  NAD

HEENT: NC/AT,  PERRL, anicteric. EOMI.  OP w/ MMM, no erythema or injection.

Skin:	No rashes

Neck:  	Supple, full ROM, JVP=7CM , 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no thyromegaly or nodules, no nodes

Chest: CTA&P bilaterally

CVS:  	RRR nl S1 S2, no m/r/g

Abd:  	nl BS, soft, non-tender, no HSM

Extr:  	no c/c/e 2+ DP's bilaterally

Neuro: AAOX3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact, Motor 5/5 UE and LE, Sensory intact including proprioception and vibratory in lower ext



DATA:

Labs 



NA        	136       	          	          	          	          

K         	4.1       	          	          	          	          

CL        	106       	          	          	          	          

CO2       	27.4      	          	          	          	          

BUN       	11        	          	          	          	          

CRE       	1.0       	          	          	          	          

GLU       	156(H)    	          	          	          	          



CK        	80        	77        	          	          	          

CK-MB     	PEND      	2.4       	Negative  	          	          

CKMBRI    	PEND      	see detail	          	          	          

TROP-I    	          	          	Negative  	          	          

TROP-T    	PEND      	<0.01     	          	          	          

 

WBC       	8.2       	          	          	          	          

RBC       	4.49(L)   	          	          	          	          

HGB       	13.6      	          	          	          	          

HCT       	38.1(L)   	          	          	          	          

MCV       	85        	          	          	          	          

MCH       	30.4      	          	          	          	          

MCHC      	35.8      	          	          	          	          

PLT       	201       	          	          	          	          

RDW       	12.7      	          	          	          	          

    

PT        	13.5(H)   	          	          	          	          

PTT       	30.7(T)   	          	          	          	          





CXR:12/08/96	

No acute cardiopulmonary process.

EKG:	

NSR, Q waves V1-3, TWI I, AVL V1-3. prwp

__________________________________________



Impression:



75 YOM with CP here for ROMI. Pt is CP free as of arrival to ED will contiue to RO and likely stress in the AM. Pt cardiac risk factors included age, prior history, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, DM.

Plan: 



1.Chest Pain- 

-ROMI enzymes cycled, EKG serial, ASA, BB, Nitro as needed

-Bruce protocol stress in the AM if enzymes rule out

-On cardiac telemetry



2. DM- On RISS

-Will check Hba1c



3.Prx nexium, fragmin









_________________________________

Eva Pearson, MD

Pager #45803



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-08-06



Reason for Visit

74 yo man with Type 2 DM x 20 yrs, here for f/u -- no longer eligible at RSH.



History of Present Illness

75 yo man with T2 DM and mild dementia here for f/u; glycemia has worsened over the past year. 



He checks his FS about weekly.  His FS was174 yesterday morning.  He has had DM x 20 yrs, now on glipizide 2.5 mg po qd for several years with worsening HbA1C, up to 7.6%.  His diabetes has improved since he lost about 40 lbs by dieting several years ago (max wt 235, today 186).  



He denies sx of hyperglycemia.  He has no hypoglycemia.  He still exercises and eats well.  



Podiatry now here.

Optho: hx of retinal detachment.  Needs optho here now that no longer at the RSH.

No microalbuminuria proteinuria.





Review of Systems

Allergic/Immunologic, Constitutional, Psychiatric, Eyes, Ears/Nose/Throat, Cardiovascular, Respiratory, Hematologic/Lymphatic, Gastrointestinal, Genitourinary, Musculoskeletal, Integumentary, Neurological, and Endocrine systems reviewed and negative except as otherwise noted.



Problems

      Diabetes mellitus

      Coronary artery disease

      Iritis    : and corneal dystrophy, followed at the RSH

      Peripheral neuropathy    : pain relieved on amitriptylene; sensation and pulses preserved



Medications

      GLIPIZIDE   5MG TABLET take 0.5 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days

      LISINOPRIL   5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days

      Nitroglycerin 1/150 (0.4 Mg)   1 TAB SL PRN  , q 5 min x 3

      Metoprolol Tartrate   50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID x 90 days

      ATORVASTATIN   10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days

      Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)   81MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

      Muro 128   1 DROP OU qhs 

      Amitriptyline Hcl   25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QHS x 90 days

      Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS)   1 TAB PO QD 

      Caltrate + D (CALCIUM Carbonate 1500 Mg (600 Mg Elem Ca)/ Vit D 200 Iu)   1 TAB PO BID 

      OXYCODONE   5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO Q4H PRN pain , Please do not drink and/or drive while taking narcotics.

      Colace (DOCUSATE Sodium)   100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO BID x 14 days



Allergies

      ACETAMINOPHEN    - Rash, 



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   130/72 

      PULSE   68 

      HEIGHT   70 in

      WEIGHT   198 lb

      BMI   28.5 



Physical Exam

      General Appearance

Well appearing elderly male, NAD

      HEENT

No scleral icterus.  Fundi background retinop

      Neck

No thyroid goiter.  No jugular venous distention.

      Chest

Clear to auscultation and percussion

      Cor/Cardiac

Regular rate and rhythm, no murmurs, rubs, or gallops

      Skin

No focal skin breakdown or ulceration in distal lower extremities

      Extremity

Distal dorsalis pedis and posterior tibialis pulses intact.  No clubbing, cyanosis, edema

      Neurological

Sensation to  Semmes-Weistein monofilament intact.  Decreased vibratory sense at toes.  



Results

06/17/2097 CHOL 128 [1],  TRIG 96,  HDL 45,  LDL 64 [2],  CHOL/HDL 2.8 [3]



06/17/2097 UCREAT 0.93,  MALB 0.4,  MALB/CRE 4.3



06/17/2097 HGBA1C 7.60 (H),  MEAN-GLU 167,  CCOM Fasting







Assessment

 73 yo man with type 2 DM and CAD, with worsening glycemic control over the last several months.  Nl bone density despite kyphosis.  



Plan

1. Diabetes

--Glycemia: I estimate his Cr clearance to be 73 cc/min.  Therefore, I recommended and wrote out for him:

a. Increase glipizide to 5 mg po qd

b. Start metformin 500 mg po bid, increase to 1000 mg po bid if no abd sx.  If he can tolerate this, woudl d/c glipizide.

--Pt education re above.

--Ophtho referral



2. Dyslipidemia: controlled on Lipitor



3. Hypertension: controlled, but on the border; may need another agent.



4. Cardiac disease:followed by Dr.Upton; to be referred for ICD eval given CAD and low EF.  On ASA.



5. Decreased vibratory sense: needs B12 on next lab draw.



F/U  December.

 

CC: Kory Fagan, MD via MTR email.







****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>