<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2092-03-11





NAME:     Hendrickson, Ora 

MRN:      7194334



This patient is here for a follow-up.  She was seen with a very complete evaluation 

by Ida Oquinn for her recurrent urinary tract infections.  She submitted a

urine sample initially that appeared fairly clean but then after straight cathing her

urine Ida was able to obtain cloudy foul smelling urine.  A fair amount retained

as postvoid residual.  Ms. Hendrickson completed her 14 days of Levaquin with

resolution of her symptoms but now over the past few days she has noticed an odor

and cloudiness to her urine again without fevers of dysuria or urinary urgency.  She

has anxiety associated with the possible reasons why she should have recurrent

infections.  She is most concerned about having cancer.  She is scheduled to see Dr.

Quezada March 24th.  The patient reports increased anxiety of late as there have

been issues going around the housing projects.  A 14-year-old girl was raped and

one week later an individual was climbing a tree to try to get into her apartment. 

She ended up combating him with a broom and he ran away.  She did not file a

police report.  As a result of this she has had more problems with her anxiety.  She

reports compliance with all her medications except that she ran out of her Lasix

approximately one week ago.  She had been taking 20 mg one-half to one tablet

sporadically but not on a regular basis.  She denies any chest pressure or

palpitations.  She denies any shortness of breath.  She denies any problems with

pain in her right foot or increased swelling of her left ankle.



PHYSICAL EXAM:  Blood pressure is 156/90.  Heart is regular rate and rhythm. 

No murmurs, gallops or rubs.  UA reveals positive nitrate and 2+ leukocytes.  Her

ankle reveals trace edema on the left.  Her right extremity is warm to palpation.  



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  



(1)  Hypertension.  Blood pressure has been high over the past two visits.  This

     may be due to the fact that she has not been taking her Lasix.  I have

     restarted her on the Lasix 20 mg to take one-half tablet q.d. on a regular

     basis.  



(2)  Anxiety.  I will write a letter for her to the Rupert Housing Council to try

     to get her moved out of this current housing project to a safer environment.



(3)  Recurrent urinary tract infections.  She had a urine culture submitted today. 

     She was given another prescription for Levaquin 150 mg one PO q.d.  She

     will stay on this until her appointment with Dr. Quezada.  I attempted to

     reassure her that it is unlikely that cancer is the cause for her current

     recurrent infections.  It is more likely due to her cystocele.



(4)  Peripheral vascular disease.  This appears stable.  She remains off the

     cigarettes.  



(5)  ASCVD.  She remains without symptoms.  



(6)  GERD.  She remains on the Prilosec.



(7)  Hyperlipidemia.  She remains on Lipitor.  She should have a repeat

     cholesterol obtained with a new primary care physician in the fall.



(8)  Borderline high sugar.  The patient should also have this rechecked with the

     new physician in the fall.



Mary Isham, M.D.



MI/ussery/echols





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-11-16



 





Team D Intern Admission Note

Date: 11/16/92

_______________________________________________________________________



CC/HPI:



Pt is 76 yo F with h/o CAD, HTN, hypercholesterolemia, COPD, many pack-years of smoking, and anxiety who presents with c/o SOB.



Pt was in her usual state of health about 1 week PTA, when she noticed gradually worsening SOB and developing cough productive of scant whitish sputum.  She had no fevers/chills, prior URI symptoms/sick contacts, CP/lightheadedness, N/V/abdominal pain, diaphoresis, increasing leg swelling, or orthopnea/PND symptoms.  She thought she might be developing    bronchitis,    discontinued smoking and called her PCP to ask for antibiotics.  She was told to come to the clinic but her SOB progressively worsened in the few hours PTA, and she called for EMS to go to the ED. 



In ED:  

a. Lasix 40 mg IV x2, NTG paste    initial SOB improvement, small UO;

b. Lasix 40 mg IV x 2    improved, ready for floor transfer but develops an episode of worsening SOB/flush pulmonary edema on CXR;

c. Lasix 160mg IV    Morphine 3mg IV + CPAP    Atrovent/Albuterol    Zaroxylin 5mg + Lasix 200mg IV     improved, on Hi-Flow O2; total UO: 1,100cc.



Also received: ASA, CTX 1gm IV, Azithromax 500mg po, Atrovent/Albuterol nebs.



PMHx:



1. HTN

2. CAD [old MI by EKG/imaging]

3. COPD 

4. Hypercholesterolemia 

5. DM, type II

6. Recurrent UTIs [cystocele/recurrent UTI]

7. Chronic LE edema [Doppler NEG]

8. Anxiety

9. GERD  

     



ALLERGIES:  



Penicillin/Cephalosporins - hives



MEDS:



Atenolol 100 mg PO qd

Lipitor 10 mg po qd

Cozaar 50 mg po qd

Furosemide 20 mg po qde

Prilosec 20 mg po qd

ECASA 325 mg po qd

Nifedipine XL 60 mg po bid

Klonazepam 0.5 mg po bid

 



SHx: lives alone, independent with ADLs PTA



FHx: no CAD, DM, stroke

 

VS:  	T 97 	   HR 84      BP  128/80    RR 22      Sat  97% O2 HF

PE:

GEN: slightly anxious, with O2 mask on

SKIN:	pale, no ecchymoses

HEENT: supple; JVP ~8cm; no carotid bruits	

CHEST: bibasilar crackles, few scattered wheezes	

HEART: RRR, (+) 2/6 SEM

ABD: soft, ND, active bowel sounds			

EXT: trace pitting edema bilat 		 		

NEURO: alert, appropriate; CNs intact. Strength/sensation symmetric.		



LABS:



Sodium (Stat Lab)       132       L              135-145        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)    4.0                      3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)     103                      100-108        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)          19.8      L              24.0-30.0      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)          26        H              8-25           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)   1.1                      0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)      262       H              70-110         mg/dl



Calcium                 9.0                      8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus              3.9                      2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium               1.9                      1.4-2.0        meq/L

Total Protein           8.6       H              6.0-8.0        g/dl

Albumin                 3.6                      3.1-4.3        g/dl

Globulin                5.0       H              2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin        0.0                      0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin         0.8                      0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase    319       H              30-100         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT       24                       7-30           U/L

Creatine Kinase Isoenzy 0.7                      0.0-6.9        ng/ml

Troponin-T              <0.01                    0.00-0.09      ng/ml

Transaminase-SGOT       60        H              9-25           U/L

Creatine Kinase         91                       40-150         U/L



WBC                     11.9      H              4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                     41.1                     36.0-46.0      %

HGB                     13.9                     12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                     4.81                     4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                     332                      150-350        th/cumm

MCV                     86                       80-100         fl

MCH                     28.8                     26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                    33.7                     31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                     14.3                     11.5-14.5      %

Superstat PT            12.4                     11.1-13.1      sec

Superstat PT-INR        1.1

Superstat APTT          29.3                     22.1-35.1      sec

Poly                    85        H              40-70          %

Lymphs                  11        L              22-44          %

Monos                   3         L              4-11           %

EOS                     1                        0-8            %

Basos                   0                        0-3            %

Absolute Neuts          10.05     H              1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs         1.33                     1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos          0.40                     0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS            0.10                     0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos          0.04                     0.0-0.3        th/cmm

RBC Morph on Smear      NORMAL                   NORMAL



EKG:	old LBBB, no acute ischemic changes 



CXR: cardiomegaly, bilateral pleural effusions



ADENOSINE MIBI (6/89): The ECG response to pharmacological stress was negative for

 ischemia. Images demonstrated a small posterobasal infarction

 associated with mild to moderate inferior ischemia.  Comparison to

 2084 is difficult due to the difference of technique.  However,

 septal ischemia is no longer present in the current study and

 inferior ischemia is still present.



ECHO (6/89): mild mitral regurgitation; LA dilated; 

- trans-aortic gradient ~13 mm HG/no stenosis; 

- LV imildly dilated, w/segmental LV dysfunction [inferior wall]; EF 68 %;

- trace tricuspid insufficiency

- trace pulmonary insufficiency; RV 34 mmHg/ not dilated







A/P: Pt is a 76 yo F with multiple cardiac risk factors who presents with CHF exacerbation. Ddx of precipitants include new myocardial ischemia, hypertensive crisis, medication non-compliance/misadministration, arrhythmia, or infection.  Even though MI would be the most worrisome to follow through with, a simple trigger such as COPD exacerbation cannot be excluded.  



-	continue HF O2, ASA, cardiac enzymes to r/o MI

-	tight BP control w/ CCB and ACEI as needed; may use TNG/Hydralazine

(will hold BB during the acute exacerbation)

-	Lasix IV prn; strict I/Os [admission wt 180#)

-	Low-sodium diet/consider fluid restriction

-	Repeat CXR/EKG

-	Azithromycin 250mg po/Albuterol/Atrovent nebs

-	ECHO in AM/consider ETT/Cardiology: Dr Garner









_________________________________________

EVELYN HOLCOMB, M.D.

X62950







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-01-13

Team X Intern Admission Note



Name:	Hendrickson, Ora

MR# 		7194334

Date:  	01/13/93

PCP:		Oliveira, Keith MD



CC/RFA:  SOB.



HPI: Pt is a 76 yo F with a h/o CAD, HTN, hypercholesterolemia, COPD, CHF who developed acute SOB while at home PM of admission. Pt reports no dietary discretions and excellent adherence to medications. She was out evening of admission at a social gathering and noticed symptoms when she returned home and had difficulty climbing an internal staircase in her home She ascended the staircase and was unable to regain her breath. She reports she developed profound dyspnea and tachycardia. She denies chest pain, diaphoresis, dizziness or LOC. She has had a cough productive of clear sputum x 1 week with no fever, night sweats, rigors or chills during this time. She has had no vomiting or diarrhea. She does not recall wheezing, and asserts the only symptoms during the episode consisted in SOB and tachypnea.



Of note, pt had 2 vessel CABG in 11/92. Catheterization on 11/18/92 revealed 100% obstruction of the left proximal circ, 70% proximal LAD obstruction, and 100% obstruction of the mid RCA. 



Course in ED:

En route to BBH pt received Lasix 40 mg, TNG x 3. She was described as pale, cool, and diaphoretic. She was unable to complete full sentences. She received Lasix 40 mg IV and 20 mg IV 2 hours later, ASA 325 x 1, Zofran 8 mg IV, and 0.5     nitropaste. Initial vitals were T 98 P 93 BP 148/67  RR 24  93 % on 6 L and 100% on BiPap (brief).



PMHx: 

1. HTN

2. CAD [old MI by EKG/imaging]

3. COPD 

4. Hypercholesterolemia 

5. DM, type II

6. Recurrent UTIs [cystocele/recurrent UTI]

7. Chronic LE edema [Doppler NEG]

8. Anxiety

9. GERD  

   



ALLERGIES:  

Penicillin/Cephalosporins - hives



MEDS:

Atenolol 100 mg PO qd

Lipitor 10 mg po qd

Cozaar 50 mg po qd

Furosemide 20 mg po qde

Prilosec 20 mg po qd

ECASA 325 mg po qd

Nifedipine XL 60 mg po bid

Klonazepam 0.5 mg po bid

 



SHx: lives alone, independent with ADLs PTA



FHx: no CAD, DM, stroke

 

PHYSICAL EXAM:

Gen:	Supine, c/o nausea.

	Vitals: T  96.8 P 87 BP 132/64 RR 20 SaO2 93% 6 L NC.

HEENT: PERRL. Sclerae anicteric, conj pale. MMM, no exudates. JVP 7 cm.

Chest: Fine inspiratory crackles inf    of lung field; anterior end-expiratory wheeze.

Heart: RRR. Nl S1/S2, I/VI SM. Carotid bruit on left, right clear. Left pedal pulses 1 + uniformly; right not palpable. 

Abd:  NABS, obese, NT, no organomegaly.

Extr: Trace pretib edema. DJD hands. 

Skin: No lesions.

Neuro: No gross deficits.



LABS:  

Calcium                 9.0                      8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus              3.7                      2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium               1.6                      1.4-2.0        meq/L

Total Protein           7.9                      6.0-8.0        g/dl

Albumin                 3.1                      3.1-4.3        g/dl

Globulin                4.8       H              2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin        0.1                      0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin         0.4                      0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase    293       H              30-100         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT       17                       7-30           U/L

Amylase                 29                       3-100          units/L

Lipase                  1.8                      1.3-6.0        U/dl



Creatine Kinase Isoenzy 2.4                      0.0-6.9        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                             0.0-3.5        %

  Result Text:

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T              0.01                     0.00-0.09      ng/ml

Transaminase-SGOT       33        H              9-25           U/L

Creatine Kinase         40                       40-150         U/L



Sodium (Stat Lab)       138                      135-145        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)    3.8                      3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)     109       H              100-108        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)          25.0                     24.0-30.0      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)          14                       8-25           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)   0.8                      0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)      222       H              70-110         mg/dl





WBC                     11.1      H              4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                     36.7                     36.0-46.0      %

HGB                     11.2      L              12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                     4.68                     4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                     313                      150-350        th/cumm

MCV                     78        L              80-100         fl

MCH                     23.8      L              26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                    30.4      L              31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                     15.8      H              11.5-14.5      %

Superstat PT            12.6                     11.1-13.1      sec

Superstat APTT          29.4                     22.1-35.1      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST    RECEIVED

Diff Method             Auto

Poly                    73        H              40-70          %

Lymphs                  23                       22-44          %

Monos                   2         L              4-11           %

EOS                     1                        0-8            %

Basos                   1                        0-3            %

Absolute Neuts          8.19      H              1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs         2.48                     1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos          0.26                     0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS            0.09      L              0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos          0.06                     0.0-0.3        th/cmm

Aniso                   None                     NORMAL

Hypo                    3+                       NORMAL

Macrocytes              None

Microcytes              1+



CXR: 

Bilateral effusions, left > right. Pulmonary edema.



Cardiac US: 11/17/92

ANATOMIC REGION   STATUS ROUTINE DIMENSIONS       REGIONAL WALL MOTION

                                    (normal)     (completed only if abn.)

MITRAL VALVE      ABN                            SEGMENT   BASE  MID  APEX

LEFT ATRIUM       ABN    LA    39  (25-38mm)

AV. A0. LVOT      ABN    AO    33  (24-39mm)     anterior

LEFT VENT.        ABN    LVIDd 50  (37-53mm)     ant.sep.

TV. RA. VC.       NORM   LVIDs 39                mid.sep.               H

PV. INF. PA.      NORM   PWT   13  ( 7-11mm)     inf.sep.    H    H

RIGHT VENT.       NORM   IVS   13  ( 7-11mm)     inferior    A    A     A

IAS. IVS.         ABN                            inf.pos.    A    A

COMPLEX CHD       NORM   EF    33 % ( >50 %)     pos.lat.         H

CORONARIES        UV                             lateral

PERICARDIUM       ABN



Wall Motion Abbreviations: N=Normal H=Hypokinetic A=Akinetic D=Dyskinetic



MITRAL VALVE

There is calcification of the posterior mitral annulus.  There is no evidence

of mitral valve prolapse.  There is mild mitral regurgitation by color and

spectral Doppler.



LEFT ATRIUM

The left atrium is dilated.



AORTIC VALVE, AORTA, LVOT

There is thickening of the bases of multiple aortic leaflets.  The aortic

valve is tricuspid.  There is no evidence of aortic insufficiency by color or

spectral Doppler.  There are irregular echoes along the aortic wall c/w

atheroma.



LEFT VENTRICLE

The left ventricular cavity size is normal.  The left ventricular systolic

function is impaired.  There is symmetric left ventricular hypertrophy.  There

is segmental left ventricular dysfunction (see wall motion plot).  This

involves the lateral,inferior and apical territory.  There is a false tendon

within the LV cavity which is a normal variant.  The estimated ejection

fraction is 33 %.



TRICUSPID VALVE - IVC, SVC

There is color and spectral Doppler evidence of trace tricuspid insufficiency.



PULMONARY VALVE, INFUND., P.A.

There is evidence of trace pulmonary insufficiency by color and spectral

Doppler.



RIGHT VENTRICLE

The right ventricle is not dilated.  The right ventricular systolic function

is within normal limits.



PERICARDIAL DISEASE AND EXTRACARDIAC MASSES

There is a small circumferential pericardial effusion.  There is increased

intrapericardial pressure without evidence of frank tamponade.  There is

diffuse fibrin deposition on the visceral pericardium.  There is evidence of a

pleural effusion.



CONCLUSIONS

Compared to the report of 6/5/2089,the left ventricular systolic function is

impaired with new wall motion abnormalities. Also a new pericardial effusion

is visualized.



EKG: 

NSR, 90 bpm. ST elevations V1-V6.

_______________________________________

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:



76 yo F with PVD, CAD, s/p CABG, CHF, with acute onset SOB, likely CHF exacerbation.



CV:

Pt has diffuse CAD with propensity for failure, most likely etiology for SOB being CHF.

  	Pump 33%. Continue beta blocker, CCB. 

Daily weights, Is and Os, diurese with goal of -0.5 liters QD.

PT/OT for chronic deconditioning 2/2 failure.

  	Ischemia. H/o CABG, PVD. Cont ASA, statin. 

Cycle enzymes.

Serial EKGs.

AdenoMIBI to identify ischemia, assess CABG grafts, risk for failure.

  	Rhythm: sinus. 

Place pt on monitor given hx.



DM:

Sliding scale insulin.



HTN:

Beta blockade.



Anxiety:

Uses Klonopin 0.5 mg BID.



 GERD:

Prilosec.



FEN:

Cardiac diet; follow electrolytes given active diuresis.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-01-25



Problems

coronary artery disease 

hypertension 

hyperlipidemia 

chronic obstructive pulmonary disease 

peripheral vascular disease 

peripheral edema : left ankle, doppler negative

anxiety 

borderline diabetes mellitus 

urinary tract infection : Reoccurrent

S/P cardiac bypass graft surgery : 100% obstr of LPC and mid RCA, 70% obstr LAD on cath 11/92. 





Medications

Ecotrin (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Ntg 1/150 (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 Mg)) 1 TAB SL x1 : USE AS DIRECTED

Nystatin Powder TOPICAL TOP BID

Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO Q12H : Take as directed 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Procardia Xl (NIFEDIPINE (SUSTAINED Relea... 60 MG PO BID

FUROSEMIDE 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50MG, 0.5 Tablet(s) PO BID

Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD

Macrobid (NITROFURANTOIN Sr) 100MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD

Acetaminophen W/codeine 30mg 1 TAB PO Q4H PRN pain : Take as directed 

CLONAZEPAM 0.5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

CLARITHROMYCIN 500MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID x 10 day(s) 



Pt developed infection in a bunion approx 2 weeks ago, seen here 2 days ago, placed on biaxin (allergic to penicillin).  Pt notes no improvement in pain in foot and cannot lie on bed at night due to worsening pain, needs to sleep in chair with foot down.  Hx CAD, PVD, glucose intolerance.



PE:  NAD

right foot- distal one third of foot is swollen, erythematous with digital tinea all toes.  The bunion area is swollen, erythematous, tender, with central ulceration draining yellow pus (small amt)



IMP:  Cellulitis RLE with ulcer over bunion in pt with PVD, possibly diabetes.  Foot has worsened on oral antibiotics.  Sx with elevation worrisome for arterial insuff.  Pt sent to EW for eval, admission for IV antibiotics.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-07-02



Problems

coronary artery disease 

hypertension 

hyperlipidemia 

chronic obstructive pulmonary disease 

peripheral vascular disease 

peripheral edema : left ankle, doppler negative

anxiety 

borderline diabetes mellitus 

urinary tract infection : Reoccurrent

S/P cardiac bypass graft surgery : 100% obstr of LPC and mid RCA, 70% obstr LAD on cath 11/92. 





Medications

Ecotrin (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED) 325MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take as directed 

Ntg 1/150 (NITROGLYCERIN 1/150 (0.4 MG)) 1 TAB SL x1 , USE AS DIRECTED

Nystatin POWDER TOPICAL TOP BID 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take as directed 

Acetaminophen W/CODEINE 30MG 1 TAB PO Q4H PRN pain , Take as directed 

Bactroban (MUPIROCIN) TOPICAL TOP BID 

Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD 

Lopressor (METOPROLOL TARTRATE) 50MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 

Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 40MG CAPSULE EC take 1 Capsule(s) PO QD 

Avapro (IRBESARTAN) 150MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Clonazepam 0.5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID PRN anxiety  

Procardia XL (NIFEDIPINE (SUSTAINED RELEA... 60 MG (60MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Furosemide 40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 

Kcl SUSTAINED RELEASE ( 20MEQ TABLET CR take 2 Tablet(s) PO QD , take 2 tabs in am and 2 tab in pm 



Follow up visit.  Doing well, lives alone, independent with ADL's.  Has nocturia X 5, urinates 3-4 X during the day.  Has 1 c tea qd, no coffee or ETOH.  Drinks 5 bottles of water qd, 16 oz cranberry juice.  Never started macrobid.  Denies CP, SOB, GI sx.  Quit smoking 11/92.  Walks 30 min qd.



PE:  NAD P 60 reg  BP 148/70 after rest 154/70

Throat- neg

Neck- no adenopathy or thyromegaly

Lungs- Clear to P and a

cor- reg S1S2 no m,r,g

Breasts- no mass bilat

Abd- soft, active BS, no mass, tenderness, organomegaly

Ext- no edema



IMP:  1.  HT- uncontrolled.  Will increase procardia to 90 mg qd, recheck BP in 1 month. Check K, glu.

      2.  Chronic urinary sx- will check u/a, urine culture, start macrobid 100mg qd. Decrease lasix to 40 mg in am, decrease KCL to 40 meq q am.

      3.  Hx anemia, check CBC.

      4.  HM- schedule mammogram, pt declines colonscopy.

RV 7/23.

      



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>