<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2157-08-27

History of Present Illness	

ID:Admitted from cardiac cath lab. 



HPI:Mr. Doty is a  80 y.o. male with h/o HTN, DM, PVD, elevated cholesterol who presents with 6 month h/o chest and upper extremity discomfort on exertion along with SOB. He has limited his activities to prevent symptoms. He also has had a few episodes at rest in bed. 



Stress test at BII showed inferoposterior ischemia at low workload---3:18 minutes HR 101 (72%) and b/p 220/80. LV EF 48%. He presents today for cardiac cath. 



Full cath report not available but d/w Dr. Diamond states no intervention needed. Case complicated by back discomfort and urge to void-- Foley insertion requiring Coude. He will stay overnight and receive Abx. prophylaxis. He is pain free currently. 

Son with patient. 



CRF:    +  HTN        +  DM         +Chol        + FH         

Tob: none over 45 years 



Past Medical History	

DM 

HTN

High cholesterol

PVD- L SFA disease, + claudication at 1/4 mile. 

CNIS- no significant obstruction, plague. 



Past Surgical History	

Denies



Medications	

At home:



Atenolol 100 qd

Lipitor 5 qd

Avandia 4 qd

Lisinopril 40 qd

Omeprazole 20 qd

Metformin 500 qid

Imdur 60 qd

Vit E, C, B12

ASA 325 x 2 weeks



Allergies	

NKDA



Social History	

Lives alone in St. Michael. Cooks for self. Family supportive

Retired-had catering business- 2 sons running now. Helps out occasionally.

Wife deceased from cancer 



Habits	

ETOH: one drink weekly          Caffeine:  1 cup qd        

Diet:  cooks well balanced meals daily             

Exercise: golf daily



Family History	

n/a



Review of Systems	

Negatvie in detail except as above



Physical Exam	  

SR: 79          BP:   176/80        

Ht: 5'8"             Wt:165#

General Appearance	

Lying in bed, NAD, conversing appropriately with staff. Good historian. 

Neurological	

CN II- XII intact, speech clear

Neck	

Supple, no JVP, 2+ carotid pulse with bruits.

Cor/Cardiac	

RRR S1, S2 2/6 murmur

Chest	



Clear anteriorly b/l

Abdomen	

+ bowel sounds x 4, abd. soft NT/ND, no guarding/masses/HSM

Extremity	

Femoral: Right no hematoma, + bruit.

Left: + brout

DP: trace left, 1+ right, no edema. 



External Labs	

Lab

EKG:



Plan	

80 y.o. male with c/o angina, + stress test s/p cath with no intervention needed. + PVD with claudication. 



CV: Continue home medications. Speak with Dr. Diamond regarding ASA- he has only taken x 2 weeks. 



PV: to return in a few weeks for PV intervention. 



Endo: Hold glucophage. Start avandia  in am. Follow bid finger sticks and use sliding scale insulin prn. 



Further plans per Dr. Diamond. 







Adriana Buckley, NP

b. 69162





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2159-05-12

CARDIOLOGY

WISNER FAMILY PRACTICE



Floyd R Shaw M.D. 

Mariners Hospital Internists

6293 Brookside Terrace, Suite 626

Grayling, ME 78726



Dear Fitzgerald:



  I had the pleasure of seeing your patient, Haden Doty, in consultation today regarding his peripheral arterial disease and generalized vascular disease.  As you know, he is a patient that has known coronary artery disease, for which I ended up doing a catheterization on 08/27/2157, and that was done because of an abnormal stress test and chest pain.  At that time, he had been evaluated by Dr. Morgan Thayer, who performed a stress MIBI and demonstrated an inferoposterior ischemia, a low workload of 3 minutes and 18 seconds, and a heart rate of only 72% of predicted.  The LV chamber was dilated, and the ejection fraction was estimated at 48%, and there was a suggestion of global ischemia.  The catheterization demonstrated the presence of moderate diffuse coronary artery disease, plaque distributed throughout much of the coronary tree, some calcification, and narrow caliber vessels overall, but no focal high-grade stenoses.  There was some disease in the distal left main coronary artery, but his angina or ischemia was felt to be on the basis of excess demand in the phase of globally diminished supply.



He was treated medically for the coronary artery disease.  At the time of his cath, he also underwent an angiography of his abdominal aorta and selective angiogram of his left leg, because he was complaining of claudication predominantly on the left calf at that time.  That study demonstrated the presence of two renal arteries of the left side, a small superior one that was narrowed by about 50%, and a larger inferior left renal artery that was narrowed by about 60%.  The right side was patent.  With respect to the abdominal aorta, there was an ulcerated plaque just below the superior renal artery, narrowing the channel in the aorta by about 30% or 40%.  The iliac vessels were patent, and the left common femoral artery had some irregularity that was patent.  The left SFA, a diffusely diseased vessel, had a high-grade stenosis of about 80% in the adductor canal.  Then, at the trifurcation, there was occlusion or high-grade stenosis of all three trifurcation vessels on the left side.  There was reconstitution at the level of the ankle.



The decision at that time was made to treat him conservatively, at least for the present, since he was still playing golf three to four times a week.  He also apparently had some other issues, so I never saw him again in followup.  The original plan had been to bring him back for revascularization of his left renal artery and the left SFA.



He did have back surgery about a year ago when he became significantly crippled by his lumbar spinal stenosis.  Dr. Anders Sykes performed an L3-L4, L4-L5 decompressive laminectomy.  This had a dramatically positive effect on his back pain.



The biggest problem now is that he feels that he cannot walk as far and his exercise tolerance has decreased.  He has been an avid golfer in the past, but is now having some more difficulty with that.  Even when I saw him two years ago, he was using a cart to play three or four times a week.  He still is able to play golf, but if he walks about 100 yards, he starts feeling his calves, and now the symptoms are bilateral and equal.  He also has some numbness in his toes, which is constant, and his feet feel cold much of the time.  The symptoms of claudication have increased over the past couple of years.



His blood pressure has been reasonably stable.  He tells me that you get pressures of 120-130.  He has not been taking his blood pressure at home, but he does take a fair amount of medication, see below.



Of note, his son says that when he was in Michigan, he was playing 18 holes of golf regularly, sometimes a couple of times per day, but Haas notes that he was indeed limited by claudication even though he was able to play the golf down in Michigan.  He seems to be more limited up here since returning just a short time ago.  He also says that he feels like he has got to stay on the move, and if he does not play any golf at all, he will really deteriorate.  Of note, the discomfort is not only limited to the calves, but also there is some discomfort in the hips, though not nearly as bad and not as limiting.



Of note, he has been seeing Dr. Youngman for his legs and has been told to "walk walk walk."  At this point, he feels that he cannot walk as well or enough to follow through on his instructions.



Past medical history:

   As above.

Others include the following:

1.  Diabetes, type 2.

2.  Hypertension, with blood pressures as high as 220 at times in the past.

3.  Carotid bruits, though I do not have any readings from a Duplex ultrasound that was done a couple of years ago or so.

4.  Hyperlipidemia.

5.  Remote history of smoking, quit 40 years ago or so after 20 years of smoking.

6.  Peripheral neuropathy.

7.  Coronary artery disease, as described.

8.  Renal artery stenosis and PVD.



Current Medications:

  Avandia 4 mg QD

 Prilosec 20 mg QD

 atenolol 150 mg QD

 Imdur 60 mg QD

 lisinopril 40 mg QD

 Lipitor 5 mg QD

 metformin hydrochloride 500 mg 4 tabs qd

 glyburide 5 mg 2 tabs qd

 aspirin 325 mg QD

 Tricor 54 mg 1 tab qd

 Norvasc 5 mg QD

 Plavix 75 mg QD

 nitroglycerin PRN

 Lasix 40 mg QD



Social history:

   He used to run a catering company.  Currently retired.  Plays golf a lot.  Likes to maintain a high level of activity.  Has two sons, one in Lake Wildwood, another in Baldwin City.  He has a daughter in Michigan.  Grandchildren - several.  He also has a great grandchild.



No smoking currently and only drinks occasional beer.  Occasional cup of coffee.



Review of systems:

   Positive for edema, 1+ in both legs.  He denies neurologic symptoms, sweats, fever, chills, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, bloody stools, or hemoptysis.  He does have night cramps and frequent urination at night.  He says he has some problems with vision with some intermittent blurring of his vision, but no monocular blindness.  He is set up to see an ophthalmologist soon.



Physical examination:

-Pulse:   64 and regular

-BP: 160/65    by my nurse, but I retook it at 130/60

-General:   He is a well-appearing gentleman, looks younger than his age of 82 years

-Heent:   Normal.  EOMI.  PERRL

-Neck:   Carotid upstrokes normal.  Bilateral bruits present, soft.  No JVD

-Chest:   Clear

-Cardiac:   Normal S1 and S2, soft S4, and a grade 1-2/6 murmur in the left lower sternal border

-Abdomen:   Soft, positive bruit, no organomegaly, and no enlargements of the aorta

-Extremities:   Femoral pulses 2+, bilateral bruits.  Below this, feet are warm and well perfused, with 1+ edema bilaterally.  Trace pulses in the dorsalis pedis on both sides, not sure how well I am feeling them.  Popliteal pulses are trace to 1+.  No ulcers or gangrene.  No tissue loss



EKG:

    - normal sinus rhythm at 64.  Normal axis and intervals, very minor nonspecific ST-T wave abnormality, essentially normal tracing.



Other Data:

   Date of Birth:  01/22/2077



Assessment and plan:

   1.  Obtain MRA of abdominal aorta, renal, and run-off arteries down to the ankle.  This will help give us a road map as to how we can approach revascularization of his legs to make him feel better.  I already know that I can open up his left SFA and probably his left trifurcation vessels below the knee, but I would like to see the right side and also get another look at the aortoiliac vessels, since it has been a full two years.

2.  Continue appropriate risk factor modification as you are doing.

3.  We will obtain blood work today in preparation for revascularization.

4.  I need to get carotid noninvasive studies, since it has been a couple of years anyway.



Impression:

   1.  Peripheral arterial disease - progressive claudication, now involving both legs at an equal amount and limiting him in terms of daily activities.  We know that he has high-grade disease in the left leg, below the groin, which can be treated.  Right leg has not been examined in the past.  Also has an ulcerative plaque in the aorta, which might be best left alone.

2.  Renal vascular disease - known moderately severe stenosis left main and accessory renal arteries.  Blood pressure is under reasonable control.  Need to check his creatinine and BUN.  If they are okay, then we would leave him alone.  He is however on a total of six antihypertensive medications, so consideration of renal artery revascularization is certainly something to entertain.

3.  Coronary artery disease - stable.

4.  Diabetes.

5.  Spinal stenosis - better since back surgery.



Changes to Medications this visit

Avandia 4 mg   QD

Prilosec 20 mg   QD

atenolol 150 mg   QD

Imdur 60 mg   QD

lisinopril 40 mg   QD

Lipitor 5 mg   QD

metformin hydrochloride 500 mg 4 tabs  qd

glyburide 5 mg 2 tabs  qd

aspirin 325 mg   QD

Tricor 54 mg 1 tab  qd

Norvasc 5 mg   QD

Plavix 75 mg   QD

nitroglycerin     PRN

Lasix 40 mg   QD



Thank you so much for allowing me to participate in the care of this nice gentleman.  I will certainly keep you updated as to his clinical course.



Sincerely,







Mark Diamond MDCC: ; Morgan F Thayer M.D.



Signed electronically by   Mark  Diamond MD  on  Jun 6, 2159     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2164-06-26


















 
 



WFP Gastroenterology                                                                     K. Yash Ugarte, M.D., PhD.


ER 8                                                                                                                         Gastroenterology Fellow


85 Kim Drive


New London, Maine  45498-9493








Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology Fellow Consult Note 







DATE: 6/26/64, evaluated at 6:25pm



Name: DOTY, Haden

MR#: 9238369

DOB: 1/24/2077

GI CONSULT ATTENDING: Dr. F. Mcfarland

IN-PATIENT ATTENDING: unassigned

LOCATION: WFP ED



REASON FOR CONSULT:





      1.  Request for ERCP for further management of choledocholithiasis



HPI: 



87M h/o CAD (3VD), RAS, PVD, DM, HLP, HTN, b/l carotid artery stenosis who is referred to the ED in the setting of a dilated CBD and choledocholithiasis noted on CTA from 6/25/64.



      The pt reports bloating+nausea after eating as well as occasional RUQ pain over the preceding 3 months.  He also reports an ~10 lb wt loss over this period.



ROS: 




denies: fever, vomiting, diarrhea, blood PR, constipation, sob, headache, focal weakness, rashes, dysuria, hematuria, jaundice, acholic stools




Reports: occasional chills



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:



PAD, PCI left SFA popliteal 2159

HTN

CAD w/ mod/borderline 3VD on cath this month

Hyperlipidemia

DMT2

RAS

Carotid artery disease, mod to mod-severe disease b/l

Distal abdominal aortic dissection

Hernia repair



ALLERGIES:

Sulfa




HOME MEDICATIONS:



Per Billy Ulysses Graves&#8217;s consult note today:



AMLODIPINE (NORVASC) 10 MG PO DAILYATENOLOL 150 MG PO DAILY (TAKES IN AFTERNOON)FENOFIBRATE (TRICOR) 145 MG PO DAILYFUROSEMIDE (LASIX) 20 MG PO DAILY LISINOPRIL 40 MG PO DAILYPRAVASTATIN 40 MG PO QHSOMEPRAZOLE 20 MG PO DAILY CLOPIDOGREL (PLAVIX) 75 MG PO DAILY ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID (ASPIRIN) 325 MG PO DAILYGLYBURIDE 5 MG PO QPM BEFORE SUPPERASCORBIC ACID (VITAMIN C) 500 MG PO DAILYCYANOCOBALAMIN (VITAMIN B12) 500 mcgs PO DAILYCLONIDINE 0.1 MG PO BIDINSULIN GLARGINE (LANTUS ) 14 UNITS SC QHSISOSORBIDE MONONITRATE (IMDUR ER ) 30 MG PO DAILY



CURRENT INPATIENT MEDICATIONS:




Ciprofloxacin 400mg IV x1

Metronidazole 500mg IV q6h

Insulin 4 units sc x1 




FAMILY HISTORY:




Father &#8211; rectal ca at age 87

Mother &#8211; CVA

Brother &#8211; dementia



Denied: any other cancer history including CRC



PERSONAL / SOCIAL HISTORY:




EtOH: occasional

TOBACCO: prev, quit 45 yrs ago




OCCUPATION(s): retired catering comany owner

LIVING SITUATION: 
widowed, lives alone



VITAL SIGNS:

TEMP 98 HR 53 BP 161/72 RR 20 O2 Sat @@




PHYSICAL EXAM:




GEN: nad, examined in room 4O in Urgent Care 

HEENT: op clear, mmm, anicteric sclera, upper dentures noted

NECK: supple, nil lad, b/l soft murmurs

CV: rrr s1s2 no m/r/g

LUNG: ctab

ABDO: soft, nt, bs nl, nil hsm, nil cva tenderness

SPINE: nil deformity, nil tenderness to palpation

EXT: warm well perfused, dp+ b/l, nil c/c/e

SKIN: nil rashes/excoriations 

NEURO: a, ox3, nil focal findings, PERRL

RECTAL: small single external non-thrombosed hemorrhoid, vault empty w/ minimal light brown tinged fluid on gloved finger that was guaiac negative, nil masses




LABS:




Test Name   WFP         WFP         WFP       

            06/26/64    06/21/64    06/20/64  

            13:41       05:30       16:15     



NA          131(L)      137                                           

K           4.5         4.6         4.3                               

CL          100         105                                           

CO2         25.0        24.4                                          

BUN         32(H)       26(H)       29(H)                             

CRE         2.07(H)     1.66(H)     1.67(H)                           

EGFR        32(T)       42(T)       42(T)                             

GLU         276(H)      173(H)      62(L)                             

ANION       6           8                                             



Test Name   WFP         WFP       

            06/26/64    06/21/64  

            13:41       05:30     



CA          8.6         8.4(L)                                        

PHOS                    3.2                                           

MG                      1.7                                           

TBILI       0.7         0.6                                           

DBILI       0.3         0.2                                           

TP          6.1         5.7(L)                                        

ALB         3.5         3.3                                           

GLOB        2.6         2.4                                           

AMY         71          94                                            

LIPS        22          23                                            



Test Name   WFP         WFP       

            06/26/64    06/21/64  

            13:41       05:30     



ALT/SGPT    69(H)       42                                            

AST/SGOT    88(H)       25                                            

ALKP        146(H)      96                                            

TBILI       0.7         0.6                                           

DBILI       0.3         0.2                                           



Test Name   WFP         WFP         WFP       

            06/26/64    06/21/64    06/20/64 


            13:41       05:30       16:15     



WBC         8.4         5.7         5.9                               

RBC         3.07(L)     2.98(L)     3.28(L)                           

HGB         9.4(L)      9.2(L)      9.9(L)                            

HCT         28.7(L)     28.1(L)     30.4(L)                           

MCV         93          94          93                                

MCH         30.6        30.9        30.2                              

MCHC        32.8        32.8        32.5                              

PLT         246         259         269                               

RDW         13.9        14.0        14.1                              

METHOD      see detail  Auto                                          

%NEUT       81(H)       79(H)                                         

%LYMPH      15(L)       15(L)                                         

%MONO       4           4                                             

%EOS        0           1                                             

%BASO       0           1                                
            

ANEUT       6.80        4.51                                          

ALYMP       1.21        0.84(L)                                       

AMONS       0.37        0.22                                          

AEOSN       0.01(L)     0.04(L)                 
                     

ABASOP      0.01        0.03                                          

ANISO       None        None                                          

HYPO        None        None                                          

MACRO       None        None                                          

MICRO       None        None                                          



Test Name   WFP         WFP       

            06/26/64    06/21/64  

            14:22       05:30     



PT          14.0(HT)    14.0(HT)                                      

PT-INR      1.2         1.2                                           

PTT         25.7        26.0                                          



Test Name   WFP         WFP       

            06/26/64    06/21/64  

            14:18       16:30     



UA-COLOR    Yellow      Yellow                                        

UA-APP      Clear       Clear                                         

UA-GLUC     1+(T)       Trace(T)                                      

UA-BILI     Negative    Negative                                      

UA-KET   
  Negative    Negative                                      

UR-SPGR     1.010(T)    1.018                                         

UA-BLD      Negative    Negative                                      

UA-PH       5.5         5.5                                           

UA-PROT     Negative    Trace                                         

UA-UROBI    Negative    Negative                                      

UA-NIT      Negative    Negative                                      

UA-WBC      Negative    Negative                                      



MICROBIOLOGY:



Nil current.




RADIOLOGY:



6/25/64 CT ABDO:

There is mild to moderate stenosis of the origins of the celiac and 

     SMA.  The IMA is occluded.  There is a moderate stenosis of the right 

     renal artery origin.  There are two left renal arteries.  The upper 

     renal artery is an accessory muscle and has a mild to moderate 

     stenosis at its origin.  The left renal artery has a high-grade 

     stenosis at its origin.  There is a circumaortic left renal vein.

      

     There is a chronic penetrating ulcer with focal aortic dissection of 

     the visceral segment of the abdominal aorta.  There is a moderate 

     stenosis of the left common iliac artery origin.

      

     The kidneys are unremarkable.

      

     The liver, pancreas, spleen, and adrenal glands are unremarkable. 

     There is no intra-abdominal or retroperitoneal adenopathy.

      

     There is cholelithiasis.  The common bile duct is 2.1 cm in diameter 

     with a probable common duct stone.

      

     There are no bony lytic or blastic lesions.

      

     The visualized lungs are clear. There is centrilobular emphysema, 

     mild.  There are no pleural effusions.

      

     

     IMPRESSION:

      

     1.  Cholelithiasis with a dilated common bile duct and a common duct 

     stone.

      

     2.  No significant mesenteric arterial compromise.  The IMA is 

     occluded.

      

     3.  Stenosis of both left renal arteries, with the larger left renal 

     artery severely stenotic.

      

     4.  Mild to moderate stenosis of the right renal artery.

      

     5.  Chronic penetrating ulcer with focal dissection of the distal 

     segment of the abdominal aorta.

      


5/30/63 CAROTID US:

IMPRESSION


1. Bilateral moderate 50-69% stenosis of the internal carotid arteries.


2. &lt; 50% stenosis noted in the distal left common carotid artery.


3. No significant stenosis in the left external carotid artery.


4. Probable hemodynamically significant stenosis in the right external carotid

  artery.


4. Antegrade flow in both vertebral arteries.


5. Normal flow in both subclavian arteries.




PREVIOUS ENDOSCOPIC EVALUATIONS:



Per the patient and his sons he was evalueated &gt;10 yrs ago w/ a colonoscopy which noted a single small benign polyp.



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN:




87M h/o CAD (3vd), PVD, DM, HTN moderate b/l carotid stenosis, chronic ulcer in the distal ulcer w/ dissection, w/ a dilated CBD and choledocholithiasis for which we are consulted.



We will plan for further evaluation of the patient&#8217;s biliary system with an ERCP. 
Given the location of the largest stone i.e. not impacted with very slight LFT derangement I am concerned for alternative sources of the patient&#8217;s biliary dilation (e.g. pancreatic ca).



I have spoke to the patient and his 2 sons that given his numerous comorbidities in particular his cardiac status and carotid disease that he is at higher risk for complications which they all appreciate.






Recommendations:



-cont cipro/flagyl, if any concerns for decompsenation would add ampicillin also

-IVF

-clear liquids ok until midnight

-NPO from midnight

-neurology consult for risk of GA given carotid artery disease burden

-please confirm with vascular surg ERCP/GA safe given dissection/aortic ulcer present

-patient waitlisted for ERCP w/ GA on 6/27/64










_______________________

Yash Ugarte, MD, PhD

GI Fellow, pager 47860





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>