<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2063-10-04


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	GRETNA COUNTY CENTER
	


	Reason for visit:
   STEMI


	Interval History:
   This is a 56 year old female veterinarian who works for Calista Corporation in Wrightwood, AL who has been complaining of right shoulder pain for some time and was admitted to the GCC yesterday for same day arthroscopic surgery to treat adhesive capsulitis of the right shoulder.  The surgery went well without complications, but the patient awoke at home today with 3/10 chest pain and diaphoresis.  She called 911 and was found with inferior ST elevation and 8/10 CP that continued to worsen to 10/10 chest pain in the West Memorial Infirmary ER.  The ECG began to evolve reciprical changes, but the RV leads were negative for infarction.  The patient was transferred emergently directly to the GCC catheterization lab.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:
Adhesive capsulitis of the right shoulder
Calcific tendonitis of R supraspinatus 
GERD

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:
PROCEDURE:
Right shoulder arthroscopic acromioplasty, debridement, and resection of calcific mass on 10/3/63 at GCC.
Partial hysterectomy
SBO 

ALLERGIES: Augmentin

HOME MEDICATIONS:
Prilosec 10 mg bid
estrogen patch TOP qweek

TRANSFER MEDICATIONS:
ASA 325 mg x 1
Morphine 
Integrilin gtt
Nitroglycerine gtt
Heparin gtt

FAMILY HISTORY:  Positive for colonic CA on mother's side. 

SOCIAL HISTORY:
Lives in Lodi with her children.  Veterinarian at Calista Corporation.
Smokes about 3/4 of a pack a day and has done so for over thirty years. Denies 
alcohol abuse. 


	Review of systems:
   General: No F/C/Sweats/Weakness/Fatigue/Weight loss
HEENT: No vision problems/hearing problems/nose bleed/teeth or gum problems
Card: No DOE/Orthopnea/PND/LE edema/Palpitations; + CP and diaphoresis
Pulm:  No SOB/Pleursy/Wheezing/Cough/COPD/Asthma
Abd: No pain/N/V/D/C/hematemasis/hematochezia/melena
M/S: No decreased ROM/joint aches/muscle aches
PVS: No claudication/cold extremities/varicose veins
Hemo: No anemia/easy bruising or bleeding
Urinary: No increased frequency/urgency/burning of urination
Endo: No heat/cold sensitivity/polyuria/polydipsia/polyphagia
Neuro: No loss of sensation/numbness/tingling/weak muscle strength
Psych: No anxiety/depression 

Physical examination:
	
-BMI: 23.8  Normal, low risk
-Pulse:   
-resp. rate:   
-height: 68  in.
-weight: 71  kg.
-General appearance:   No acute distress.
-HEENT:   Unremarkable
-Neck:   JVP no jugular venous distention
-Chest:   Clear to auscultation bilaterally by anterior exam.
-Cardiac:   Left ventricular impulse discrete and nondisplaced. Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 and S2, with no S3 or S4. There were no murmurs, clicks or rubs.
-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds, soft and nontender, with no hepatosplenomegaly or masses appreciated.
-Extremities:   No cyanosis, clubbing or edema. 2+ pedal pulses.
-Neuro:   A&amp;O x3
-BP:   

Selected recent labs:

	 Bainbridge State Hospital ER:
K 4.2, BUN 19, Cr 0.9, Glu 177
WBC 170, Hct 44.3, Hgb 15.1, Plt 261
PT 9.9, PTT 25.2
	


	Assessment and plan:
   This is a 56 yo WF with no cardiac history and only the risk factor of cigarette smoking presenting to the GCC cath lab emergently today with an STEMI while recovering at home from arthroscopic surgery on the right shoulder yesterday.  
PLAN:
- NPO for urgent cardiac catheterization
- Admit to the service of Dr. Salas
- Prehydration
- Preprocedural labs: Lytes, CBC, coags, LFTs, cardiac enzymes to be drawn in cath lab.
- Continue current transfer medications for ACS.
- Anxiolytic x 1 prn anxiety
- Smoking cessation consult
- Further plans per Dr. Salas



	
Pablo Mendez, MPH, MS, PA-C
Pager: 48125
Phone: 03533

	
Pablo Y. Mendez, PA

	
Signed electronically by  Pablo Y. Mendez, PA
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-02-16


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	GRETNA COUNTYHIROPRACTIC CENTER
	


	Reason for visit:
   S/p PFO closure using a 25 mm Crybiform Amplatzer device on 12/05/63


	Interval History:
   It is a pleasure seeing Mrs. Xuereb in f/u s/p her PFO closure on 12/05/63 using a 25 mm Crybiform Amplatzer device.  
Her history is also signigicant for s/p STEMI the morning after arthroscopic shoulder surgery for adhesive capsulitis in 10/63, Protein S deficiency, COPD, HTN and dyslipidemia. 

She is doing well from the cardiac perspective-reporting that her PAC's have decreased in intensity and occurance-now happening 2-3x/day, and denies any further neurological events. 

She does, however, c/o a constant HA (feels as though her head is in a 'vice'), did not have pre-procedure. She does have a hx. of migraines, and reports that she has not had one since her closure. She is using Tylenol w/ good relief.  Thinks it is d/t the Toprol XL.  


	Past medical history:
   1. CAD-s/p IMI following shoulder surgery with evidence of acute thrombotic occlusion of her RCA; no other atherosclerotic lesions identified.  ? paradoxical emboli.  s/p thrombectomy with Export catheter - 10/04/2063
2. PFO with large right to left shunting
3. Protein S deficiency (? secondary to estrogen replacement)
4. Adhesive capsulitis R shoulder; s/p arthroscopic surgical repair 10/3/2063
5. May Thurner Syndrome- seen by Dr. Jones - no intervention needed
6. GERD
7. Dyslipidemia
8. HTN
9.  DM2 (diet controlled) - HgbA1C elevated for about 3 yrs
10. S/p Partial hysterectomy
11. h/o small bowel obstruction
12. COPD

Allergies: Augmentin - rash




	Medications (Confirmed):

	
Advair HFA 
aspirin 
Chantix  po bid
Coumadin 
Lipitor  40 mg daily
Prilosec  po daily
Toprol XL  25 mg daily
Ventolin HFA  PRN


	Family history:
   Mother: died at 72 - colon CA
Father: died at 82 - ? PNA. Hx of DM, COPD
Siblings: 12 siblings - all alive and well


	Social history:
   Divorced.  3 grown children. Works at Calista Co., veterinarian for exotic animals.
Tobacco: 40 pack yr hx, quit before shoulder surgery-taking Chantix
ETOH: none
Exercise: no formal exercise
Diet: no particular diet
Caffeine: 2 cups/day


	Review of systems:
   No lightheadedness, dizziness, presyncope or syncope. 
No hx of TIA/CVA/migraines/seizures

Physical examination:
	
-BMI: 24.4  Normal, low risk
-Pulse: 66  NSR
-height: 68  in.
-weight: 160  lbs.
-General:   Healthy, in NAD
-Neck:   Supple.  JVP &lt;5cm.  Carotids 2+ with good upstroke and no bruits.
-Chest:   Lungs are clear to auscultation anteriorly
-Cardiac:   Apical impulse is nondisplaced.  Rate and rhythm regular.  S1 S2 without murmur/rub/gallop.
-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds.  Nontender.  No hepatosplenomegaly or aortic enlargement appreciated.
-Extremities:   LE: warm, dry, no edema

-BP: 112/72  mmHg


	EKG:
   NSR-66bpm.  


	Other Data:
   1/26/64-TTE:
MITRAL VALVE 
There is no evidence of mitral valve prolapse. There is mild mitral regurgitation by color and spectral Doppler. 
LEFT ATRIUM 
There is no evidence of left atrial dilatation. 
AORTIC VALVE, AORTA, LVOT 
There is no evidence of valvular aortic stenosis. The aortic valve is tricuspid. There is no evidence of aortic insufficiency by color or spectral Doppler. 
LEFT VENTRICLE 
The left ventricular cavity size is normal. The left ventricular systolic function is within normal limits. There are no obvious segmental wall motion abnormalities. There is a false tendon within the LV cavity which is a normal variant. The estimated ejection fraction is 65 %. 
TRICUSPID VALVE - IVC, SVC 
There is color and spectral Doppler evidence of mild tricuspid insufficiency. 
PULMONARY VALVE, INFUND., P.A. 
There is evidence of trace pulmonary insufficiency by color and spectral Doppler. The RV systolic pressure was estimated from the regurgitant tricuspid velocity (assuming an RA pressure of 10mmHg). The estimated RV systolic pressure is 33 mmHg. 
RIGHT VENTRICLE 
The right ventricle is not dilated. The right ventricular systolic function is within normal limits. 
INTERATRIAL SEPTUM, INTERVENTRICULAR SEPTUM 
There are increased echoes along the interatrial septum c/w a closure device. The appearance of the device is most c/w an Amplatzer device. There is evidence of a patent foramen ovale by agitated saline contrast after Valsalva maneuver. 
PERICARDIAL DISEASE AND EXTRACARDIAC MASSES 
There is no evidence of pericardial effusion. 
CONCLUSIONS 
Compared to the report of 12/06/2063, there is residual shunt with the valsalva manuever. 




	Assessment and plan:
   In summary, Xian is a 56-year-old female s/p myocardial infarction, likely the result of paradoxical emboli via a large PFO, and s/p closure of her PFO on 12/05/63 using a 25 mm Crybiform Amplatzer device.  She is doing well from the cardiac perspective, and denies any further neurological events.  Upon our review of the echocardiogram there is a trace shunt across the device (7 beats, only after Valsalva) consistent w/ intra-pulmonary shunting.  We are willing to try decreasing her Toprol XL to 12.5mg qd, in an attempt to alleviate her HA's.  If this proves unsucessful, we will trial a course of Atenolol.  We agree with continuation of her ASA therapy and will see her in f/u for her 6 month appointment in June w/ an Echo w/ bubbles.  




Changes to Medications this visit
	
Coumadin     as directed End: 2/19/2064 held for cath lab - Inactivated
Advair HFA 250   bid
Toprol XL 12.5 mg   daily
aspirin 325 mg   daily

	
Floyd Fong, MD pager #81895

	
Transcribed by: Clara D Quilici

	
cc: Paulette Yancy (PCP)

	
Signed electronically by  Floyd Fong, MD
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2065-12-29


	CARDIOLOGY
	

	GRETNA CHIROPRACTIC CENTER
	

RE:  S/p PFO closure using a 25 mm Cribiform Amplatzer device on 12/05/63

Dear Dr. Yancy: 

  It is a pleasure seeing Mrs. Xuereb in follow up s/p her PFO closure on 12/05/63 using a 25 mm Cribriform Amplatzer device. 
Her history is also significant for inferior STEMI the morning after arthroscopic shoulder surgery for adhesive capsulitis in 10/63, Protein S deficiency, COPD, HTN and dyslipidemia. 
She is doing well from the cardiac perspective. She continues to note a rare, short-lived palpitation but states that these have definitely lessened in nature over the years. She does report, however, that she began to note non-exertional, short-lived episodes of chest pain which started about 1 month ago. She says that by the time she "thinks about taking a SL NTG", the pain has resolved. Her catheterization revealed non-significant CAD. Significant spasm in the ostium of the RCA. The distal RCA at the prior intervention site looks normal. 
She denies any further neurological events or headaches. 
Of note, she reveals that a few weeks prior to onset of chest pain she began smoking again. She was smoking 5 cigs/day, and has stopped since Saturday when she resumed her Chantix treatment plan. 
Our last recorded lipid profile drawn on 5/2/2064: CHOL: 135, HDL: 50. No TG or LDL noted. She has had this repeated since and is being followed by Dr. Yelton. We concur with LDL goal of &amp;lt;100.


	Past medical history:
   CAD-s/p IMI following shoulder surgery with evidence of acute thrombotic occlusion of her RCA; no other atherosclerotic lesions identified. ? paradoxical emboli. s/p thrombectomy with Export catheter - 10/04/2063 
PFO with large right to left shunting 
Protein S deficiency (? secondary to estrogen replacement) 
Adhesive capsulitis R shoulder; s/p arthroscopic surgical repair 10/3/2063 
May Thurner Syndrome- seen by Dr. Jones - no intervention needed 
GERD 
Dyslipidemia 
HTN 
DM2 (diet controlled) - HgbA1C elevated for about 3 yrs 
S/p Partial hysterectomy 
h/o small bowel obstruction 
COPD

	

	Changes to Allergies
	
Penicillins - reaction: Rash [reviewed]


	Family history:
   Mother: died at 72 - colon CA 
Father: died at 82 - ? PNA. Hx of DM, COPD 
Siblings: 12 siblings - all alive and well


	Social history:
   Divorced. 3 grown children. Works at Calista Co., veterinarian for exotic animals. 
Tobacco: 40 pack yr hx, quit before shoulder surgery-taking Chantix 
ETOH: none 
Exercise: no formal exercise 
Diet: no particular diet 
Caffeine: 2 cups/day


	Review of systems:
   No lightheadedness, dizziness, presyncope or syncope. 
Rest of review of systems is negative in detail.

Physical examination:
	
-BMI: 26.1  Overweight, moderate risk
-Pulse: 8667  NSR
-weight: 171  lbs.
-Neuro:   A&amp;amp;O x3
-Extremities:   LE: no edema
-Abdomen:   Normal bowel sounds. Nontender. No hepatosplenomegaly or aortic enlargement appreciated.
-Cardiac:   Apical impulse is nondisplaced. Rate and rhythm regular. S1 S2 without murmur/rub/gallop.
-Chest:   Lungs are clear to auscultation anteriorly
-Neck:   Supple. JVP &amp;lt;5cm. Carotids 2+ with good upstroke and no bruits.
-Heent:   Normocephalic, atraumatic.
-General:   Healthy, in NAD
-BP: 130/68  mmHg
-Skin:   Warm, anicteric, without rashes. 


	EKG:
   NSR, 67bpm. 


	Assessment and plan:
   In summary, Xian is a 59-year-old female s/p myocardial infarction, likely the result of paradoxical emboli via a large PFO, and s/p closure of her PFO on 12/05/63 using a 25 mm Cribriform Amplatzer device. She remains stable from the cardiac perspective, and denies any further neurological events. Given her new onset of chest pain, and recent return to smoking, we have asked her to stop smoking and call us in 2 weeks to report any change in her chest pain. If at that time, the pain has persisted we will obtain an ETT without imaging; if her pain has resolved with smoking cessation we will ask her to follow up with her PCP to continue with smoking cessation plan. We have asked that she have Dr. Paulette Yancy fax us a copy of her most recent lipid profile for our records and have reiterated the LDL goal of less than 100 for secondary prevention of strokes. We have asked her to obtain a TTE without bubbles for our annual review, and will call her once these results are available to us. We agree with continuation of her ASA therapy and will see her in follow up appointment in 1 year with another TTE without bubbles. 
		Medication List (confirmed)

				CONFIRMED

		- Advair HFA  250 bid

		- aspirin  325 mg daily

		- Prilosec  po daily take one hour before the first meal of the day

		- simvastatin  80mg po qpm

		- Ventolin HFA  PRN

			------------------------------------------------------------

				REMOVED

		- Lipitor  40 mg daily


	
	


	DX Tests Ordered:
   TTE without bubbles

It was a pleasure seeing Ms. Xuereb in followup today. Please do not hesitate to call with any further questions/concerns. 

Sincerely, 

	

	

	
Floyd Fong MD

	
Transcribed by: Clara D Decker

	
Signed electronically by  Floyd Fong, MD pager #81895
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>