<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2097-10-20




EHLERS, ULYSSES
28735364
10/20/2097


DATE OF ADMISSION:  

PRIMARY CARE PHYSICIAN:
Noah E. Galvan, M.D.
Saint John River District Hospital
699 Kingston Drive
Caro, MO  12151

REFERRING PHYSICIAN:
Richard L. Mckenzie, M.D.
San Luis Obispo County General Hospital
123 Pittsburg Street, Euite 598
Baxter Springs, MO  64715

HISTORY:  Mr. Ehlers is referred for evaluation of extensive coronary disease status.  He has history of several risk factors and a history of hypertension, hypercholesterolemia and a history of cigarette smoking. He has a prior history of peripheral arterial disease with a known abdominal aortic aneurysm.  He also has a history of bicuspid aortic valve with mild-to-moderate stenosis on recent echos and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation.  

He is status post a posterolateral MI in 2084 and had an adenosine MIBI in January 2097 with an old inferior MI and peri-infarct ischemia.  He presented with increasing angina with exertion where he is able to do most activities and climb stairs and walk his dog, but does have about one episode of angina a week while raking leaves that last about 5 minutes and resolves with rest.  He has not had any rest pain.  For his increasing angina, he had an attempted cardiac catheterization done last month, but they are unable to advance the guidewire pass the iliac artery and an MRI was able to determine that he has an occluded aorta.  He then had a left brachial artery.  Cardiac catheterization that revealed extensive coronary disease with a 70-80% distal left main stenosis and severe disease of the LAD and circumflex with minimal flow and a subtotal occlusion of the proximal right coronary with collateralization from the LAD territory.  There was an anomalous circumflex that appeared to emerge from the right coronary and there was a question of his anomalus LAD with a separate ostium superior to the left main, but the documentation of this was not clear.  With the complexity of his anatomy, he is referred for further evaluation.  He has otherwise a history of cigarette smoking and quit three months ago, does not drink alcohol.  He is married and lives in Missouri.

MEDICATIONS:  His baseline medicines include aspirin 81 mg a day, has included warfarin, ramipril 10 mg a day, Lopressor 50 mg twice a day, Lipitor 80 mg a day and Zetia 10 mg a day.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  A well-appearing man in no acute distress.  Blood pressure of 128/60, pulse of 60-70 and room air sat of 99%.  He had no jugular venous distention.  Chest was clear.  Heart had normal S1 and S2.  No S3 or S4.  There is a 2/6 systolic ejection murmur along the left sternal border.  His abdomen was benign.  Extremities showed no peripheral edema, but very faint distal pulses that were audible by Doppler.

IMAGING STUDIES:  His electrocardiogram showed sinus rhythm with left anterior fascicular block and was otherwise unremarkable.  His labs showed a BUN/creatinine of 21/1.3, glucose 145 and hematocrit of 40%.

IMPRESSION:  Mr. Ehlers presents with extensive vascular disease including left main and three-vessel disease.  We will try and define better his actual anatomy and likely do act angiogram to try and identify the locations of any anomalus vessels and then have a surgical consults regarding bypass surgery for his left main extensive disease.  We will also get an echocardiogram to reevaluate carefully the aortic valve.  We will also likely consult the vascular surgeons to discuss management of the occluded aorta.


______________________________
Edward L Echevarria, M.D.





eScription document:1-0864568 SFFocus



DD: 10/20/97
DT: 10/20/97
DV: 10/20/97



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-11-06



History of Present Illness

Asked by Dr. Ehlers to consult on glycemic management for Mr. Ulysses Ehlers who has no history of DM but was noted to be hyperglycemic postop. Mr. Ehlers is POD 1, s/p C4. His family history is positive for diabetes (mother diagnosed in her 80s).  He has required a regular insulin gtt protocol intermittently postop. He is now on a full liquid diet.



Max BG: 197

Current BG: 145

Insulin gtt off at present

 

Mr. Ehlers is a 69 yo M h/o CAD s/p MI 2084 (posterolateral), HTN, hyperlipidemia, a-fib, AAA, PVD, smoking (50 pk yr) who presents for CABG. Initially presented to Bonner General Hospital 9/97 for w/u of exertional chest pain. Cardiac cath was unsuccessful via femoral approach due to presumed aortoiliac occlusion. Subsequent cath 10/18/97 revealed left main stenosis with distal occlusion, RCA proximal occlusion and diffuse LAD stenosis. Pt was transferred to BHCC on 10/19 for further evaluation by the cardiology service. On 10/21 he underwent echo which revealed EF 55% with mild AS. On 10/22, cardiac cath revealed 3 V disease. Cardiac surgery was consulted and recommended CABG after medical optimization. His anginal symptoms remained stable and he was subsequently discharged home on 10/23. He now returns for surgical revascularization. Since his discharge on 10/23, he has not experienced any new or worsening chest pain or SOB. Denies orthopnea, PND. 

 

Preoperative Cardiac Status: Myocardial infarction 2084, requiring hospitalization. Myocardial infarction 2084, requiring hospitalization. The patient has a history of class I angina (no limitation of ordinary physical activity). There has been no recent angina. The patient does not have symptomatic heart failure. The patient is in normal sinus rhythm. The patient has a history of AF/flutter 

 

Previous Cardiovascular Interventions: None. 

 

Past Medical History: Hypertension. Peripheral vascular disease 3.6cm abdominal aortic aneurysm . Dyslipidemia. CAD Atrial fibrillation BPH Chronic back pain PVD Bicuspid aortic valve, mild AS/AI /Creatinine Clearance (estimate): 77.31 cc/min

 

Past Surgical History: s/p R inguinal hernia repair 

 

Family History: Coronary artery disease. Father died of CAD at age 88 

 

Social History: History of tobacco use. 50 pack year cigarette smoking history. Used within the last year. History of alcohol use. 1/month. The patient is a Cardiology Technologist. 

 

Allergies: Flecanide - unknown 

 

Medications: lopressor 50 po bid/ ramipril 10 po daily/ aspirin 325 po daily/ atorvastatin 80 po daily/ ezetimbe 10 po daily/ 





Physical Exam

100.3-107-18   99% on 4L   155/65

Neuro: A&O x3

Edema: +BLE edema



Lab Tests

A1c 6.6

Cr 1.2

WBC 10.5



Assessment and Plan

Hyperglycemia uncontrolled in the setting of surgery/stress/inactivity with no history of DM and c/w impaired glucose tolerance. Regardless of etiology this pt will benefit from tight glycemic control. 



Suggest:

1. Nutrition consult for carbohydrate consistent diet when eating.

2. Insulin gtt protocol until POD #3 or eating AND POD 2 then can trial 

    Novolog SS as below.  Restart insulin gtt protocol for BG>150.

3. Novolog SS ac

    Give when meal in front of pt.

4.  We will follow.



Thank you, please call with any questions, Diabetes Center beeper # 51158.



  



______________________________

Joyce R. Barton,N.P.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-06-04

 RENAL CONSULTATION SERVICE
LOUISIANA AVENUE MEDICAL CENTER


Patient:  Ehlers, Ulysses	MR: 28735364
Renal Attending: Dr. Judge
Admission Date: 4/24/2098			Consultation Date: 4/24/2098

Reason for Consultation: 
Progressive renal impairment.
Creat rose from 1.6 (Nov 97) to 4.07 (may 98)

History of Present Illness:
This is a 69 year old male with a hx of CAD s/p CABG 10/2097, who was referred on 6/03 from renal Dr. Turk, Elvis at the Central Buffalo Hospital to Dr. Judge at BHCC for rapidly progressive renal impairment.  He is an arteriopath with occluded aorta beneath the levels of renal arteries as revealed in recent MRA. In the past an attempted femoral artery cannulation was proved unsuccessful due to above reason. Subsequently he underwent two cardiac angiograms thro' left brachial and Rt radial arterial route.

 His creatinine has risen from baseline of 1.6 (Nov 97, post CABG) to 4.07 (may 98). He denies taking any NSAIDS. He thinks that he was started on Altace post surgery, but was not sure about that fact.

Dr. Turk did an duplex scan to assess his renal arteries which was suggestive of high grade stenosis of renal arteries on both sides. Since IR doctors at CentralBuffalo were not keen to do renal agniogram/angioplasty thro' radial artery route, Dr.Turk refered Mr. Ehlers to BHCC for consideration of renal angioplasty. He has also asked him to discontinue Altace and to withold coumadin (Indn: AF) inview of potential angioplasty.

He complains of claudication pains in both legs with left leg>Rt leg. He experiences pain on exertion on left calf, thigh and buttock. He complains of long term pedal swelling which extends upto upper knee level. He is SOB on moderate exertion and sleeps with 3 pillows. He also has some prostatic symptoms with poor urinary stream, frequency etc.


Past Medical History:
CAD s/p CABG on 10/97
Paroxysmal AF
DM2
HTN
Hyperlipidemia
PVD (occluded aorta)
AS (aortic bicapsid) 
BPH

Medications: NKDA
Amiodarone 200mg daily
Atenolol 100mg BID
Metformin HCL 500mg daily
ASA 81mg daily 
Lasix 40mg daily,
lipitor 40mg daily prn
Zetia 10mg daily prn

Family History: no history of renal disease in family

Social History: married.      PPD for 50 years.

Review of Systems: as above. No chest pain, discomfort, palpitation, SOB, BM changes, abdominal pain. He notes mild occasional back pain.

Vital Signs: 98.4 50 132/78 20 97% on RAUrine output: 600 ml (6/04 0-12am)

Physical Examination:General: well appearing
HEENT: PERRLA, EOMI
Neck: no bruit 
Skin: no rash, normal turgor
Chest: CTAB
Heart: RRR, no mrg 
Abd: nontender, distended, normal active bowel sounds, no HSM
Ext: 2+ edema in lower extremities upto knee level.
Bilateral distal femoral, popliteal , dorsalis pedis and posterior tibial pulses not palpable.
Toes appear discolored and dusky in appearance with slight delay in capillary refill.



Results
Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            
06/04/2098        136            5.3 (*)        102            27             
06/04/2098        141            5.5 (*)        108            24             
06/03/2098        137            4.9            103            27             

Date/Time         BUN            CRE            EGFR           GLU            
06/04/2098        83 (*)         4.23 (*)       14 [1]         130 (*)        
06/04/2098        80 (*)         3.92 (*)       15 [2]         108            
06/03/2098        75 (*#)        4.07 (*#)      15 [3]         165 (*)        

Date/Time         ANION          
06/04/2098        7              
06/04/2098        9              
06/03/2098        7              

Date/Time         CA             MG             TBILI          TP             
06/04/2098        9.0                                                         
06/04/2098        9.1            2.2                                          
06/03/2098        8.8                           0.7            6.4            

Date/Time         ALB            GLOB           
06/03/2098        3.8            2.6            

Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          
06/03/2098        30             23             80             0.7            

Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            
06/04/2098        6.84           2.77 (*)       9.1 (*)        28.7 (*)       
06/03/2098        6.76           2.65 (*#)      8.7 (*#)       27.2 (*)       

Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            
06/04/2098        103.4 (*)      32.8 (*)       31.8 (*)       164            
06/03/2098        102.4 (*#)     32.9 (*)       32.1           179 (#)        

Date/Time         RDW            
06/04/2098        17.8 (*)       
06/03/2098        18.0 (*#)      


ASSESSMENT:
Progressive renal dysfunction in the setting of severe bilateral renal artery stenosis for consideration of reno-vascular disease.

PLAN:
1. His MRA of abdomen was reviewed with Dr.Quilici, BHCC IR department. Aorta is fully occluded beneath the level of both kidneys. Tight renal artery stenosis noted in both kidneys. Both proximal and distal stenosis noted in the Rt renal artery. Both kidneys appeared normal in size 11.2 and 11.4 cm. Dr.Quilici is confident that renal angioplasty could be done relatively safely through radial artery approach.

2. We have requested Dr.Xi, Vascular surgeon to get his opinon on the need for surgical revascularisation of feet to save his legs from critical ischemia in the future. If so, whether he would benefit from surgical revascularisation of the kidneys. We are awaiting his expert opinion.

3. Patient realises that renal angiogram + angioplasty thro' radial artery carries its own risk. Risks of Cholesterol emboli, Contrast nephropathy, arterial injury, risk of further deterioration of his kidney function leading to early initiation of dialysis are explained. However patient feels that it worth taking a choice to prevent the kidneys from worsening rapidly by attempted angiopalsty.

4. We will obtain renal ultrasound to again measure his kidneys and to rule out any obstructive uropathy as the cause of renal dysfunction.

5. If patient is going for IR renal angiogram/plasty, then he will need Contrast prophylaxis.

We will review him tomorrow with Dr.Xi's opinon.

_________________________________
DONNIE YOUNGMAN MB MRCP(ENG)
P43903



Renal Staff

I have seen and examined the patient twice today, and have reviewed his MR studies with radiology
In essence I agree with Dr Youngman's recs.

Patient has normal sized kidneys with insidious rise in Cr without obvious identifiable remediable causes.
He has severe aortic disease with occlusion of the aortia, mod severe bilateral claudication in LL.
His renal arteries have ostial stenoses bilaterally.

His options are:
1) conservative approach, and likely ESRD in the coming weeks
2) Radiological placements of bilateral stents via L brachial artery
3) Surgical bypass as a part of larger repair for LL claudication

We are in discussions with Radiology and Surgery to come up with a final recommendation which we will d/w patient tomorrow.

Uriah Judge
MD PhD




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-06-11

 


Cardiovascular Medicine Consult Service Consult Note
X. R. Xi, MD, PhD
Vascular Medicine Fellow, #45811

Date of Consultation: June 11, 2098

ID: 70 year old male from Missouri
Reason for Consult: Perioperative consultation prior to aorto-bifemoral bypass surgery

History of Present Illness:
	This 70 year old gentleman was diagnosed with an occluded distal aorta in mid-2097 after an attempt at cardiac catheterization via the femoral artery.  
	Over the last several months, he has had exercise limiting lower extremity pain     he describes primarily left leg burning (thigh, calf) when he walks, coming on over about 150 yards.  If he pushes further, he will also get right leg burning in a similar distribution. 
	He also has had a marked increase in CR over the past 8 monts (1.1 -> >4).  Based on non-invasive imaging, this has been attributed to renal artery stenosis.  His ACE-I (?ramipril) has  been held, without improvement.  A referral was recently made to rule out bilateral RAS, and he had an invasive aortogram yesterday.  There was an 85% proximal right RA stenosis, and a 40% left RA stenosis, perhaps only partially explaining the elevated Cr.  The angiogram also confirmed the occluded distal aorta (below the renal arteries, the SMA is patent).  An aortobifem plus right RA revascularization is planned.
	He has had reduced functional capacity for some time.  He gets claudication within 150 yards, but he also has been limited by exertional dyspnea.  He complains also of orthopnea (3 pillows), PND, as well as bilateral LE edema.  He also has noticed his weight continuing to creep up which he attributes to fluid retention.  He is avoiding salt, but not fluid restricting.  His lasix dose has not changed.  He has been angina free since his CABG surgery.  He has not had palpitations or AF since the immediate post-op period.  A ROS is otherwise unremarkable.

Past Medical History:
Coronary artery disease
MI 2084
Developed limiting angina in late 2096, early 2097
CABGx4 on November 05, 2097 (Dr. Ehlers)
CABG x 4 (LIMA - LAD/ Sequential graft: SVG1 connects Aorta to D1 then OM1/ SVG2 - LVB2
Incidental anomalous circumflex off the right coronary artery
Pre-op EF 50-55% with infero-posterior hypokineses (?post-op)
Bicuspid aortic valve (not replaced with CABG according to notes)
Mild AS, Mild AI only on pre-CABG echo 2097
Hypertension
Dyslipidemia
Diabetes Type II
Perioperative hyperglycemia post CABG
Exsmoker
Quit 2097, >50 pack years
Peripheral arterial disease
Occluded distal aorta (diagnosed after cardiac catheterization attempt in 2097)
Small infrarenal abdominal aortic aneurysm 3.6cm
Paroxysmal atrial fibrillation (x2 years at least)
On coumadin for stroke prevention and amiodarone from maintenance of NSR
Currently in NSR
BPH
Chronic back pain
Renal insufficiency (Creatinine 4.1) non-oliguric - ?cause
Cr normal November 2097
Gradually increased over November from 1.1-1.6, ang then was ~4 when recently checked
Attributed to Renal artery stenosis based on non-invasive imaging (duplex, MRI), though 
Right inguinal hernia repair

Denies VTE, denies pulmonary problems.

Current Medications:
ECASA 81 mg daily
Amiodarone 200 mg daily
atenolol 75 mg bid
colace 100 mg bid
heparin 5000 units sc q8h
insulin sliding scale q4h
simvastatin 40 mg at HS
ezetimibe 10 mg daily
albuterol/ipratropium 3/0.5 mg via neb q4h

Medications at Home:
Amiodarone 200mg daily
Atenolol 100mg BID
Metformin HCL 500mg daily
ASA 81mg daily 
Lasix 40mg daily,
lipitor 40mg daily prn
Zetia 10mg daily prn
Coumadin 5mg qd	

Allergies:
Flecainide (arrhythmia).

Family History:
Noncontributory.

Social History:
Married, lives at home with his wife.  Exsmoker.  Minimal alcohol, no other substance abuse.

Review of Systems:
Noncontributary.

Physical Examination:
Mildly tachypnic RR 24.  BP 160/90 right arm.  HR 60 reg.  Afebrile.
Head and neck examination unremarkable.  No bruits heard.
JVP markedly elevated at the angle of the jaw.  The CP is delayed in upstroke, and mildly reduced in volume.  There is S1 S2 and a II/VI SEM that is high pitched and peaks in mid to late systole.  The Apex is hard to feel, but slight diffuse and sustained.  The abdomen is obese, distended, nontender, and there is no organomegaly or masses.  The patent   s distal pulses are difficult to feel, and despite the bilateral TEDS there is bilateral lower extremity edema.


Investigations:

EKG: Normal sinus rhythm
Note: Aortogram report is not on LMR

Na 140		WBC 6.59
K 4.3		HgB 8.0
Cl 104		Plt 165
CO2 25		Hct 25.8
BUN 80		INR 1.2 (coumadin held)
Cr 4.45		PTT 30.8
EGFR 13
Glu 74
Ca 8.3
Mg 2.4

Impression and Plan:

This gentleman is currently mild fluid overloaded (CHF) and hypertensive; this should be improved prior to any proposed surgery.  The issues include:
Congestive heart failure     I suspect there is worsening fluid retention primarily due to his worsening renal function.  I would consider:
increasing his diuretic (eg. Lasix 80 mg iv bid) to improve diuresis and get him euvolemic.  Hopefully this will work; if not, he should have ultrafiltration so that he is not in heart failure for his operation.  He will be at high risk of CHF post-op, and likely will need an ICU bed
consider starting hydralazine/nitroglycerin combination in lieu of ACE-inhibitor for afterload reduction
consider a pre-op echo     we probably should check his EF and bicuspid aortic valve to exclude severe AI and severe AS
Prevention of periperative MI
He should continue his ASA, atenolol, statins/zetia peri-operatively
No further testing for ischemia necessary unless is LV function on echo is markedly reduced (recent CABG, no angina)
Even with best medical care, for his proposed surgery and his comorbidities he carries a substantial risk for perioperative cardiac complications (roughly 5-10%)
Prevention of perioperative AF
Continue his atenolol and amiodarone perioperatively
Restart coumadin post-op for stroke prevention long term
Endocarditis prophylaxis
He will need perioperative antibiotics given his bicuspid aortic valve

We will follow with you     he may need a couple of days to treat his heart failure/fluid overload prior to surgery.


XIN Xi, MD, PhD


Staff Notes:



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>