<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2095-01-16

                                                   Heritage Of Bridgeport    

                                                      Preadmission Testing Area  

                                                   History & Physical Examination

                                                     and Anesthesia Assessment   





                                                                                   

                                                                                                                         Willean Gabriella Yamamoto, N.P.

                                                                                                                               Idamae Elliot, N.P.

                                                                                                                              Lisa Carter,N.P.     

                                                                                                                              Diane Younce, N.P.





                                                                                                                       Michael Voorhees, M.D.

                                                                                                                               Medical Director



       Date: 16 January 2095



       Procedure: This 73 year old male with Cervical Herniation is scheduled for a Cervical Laminectomy with Fusion on Jan. 21, 2095 by Dr. Noah Blanchard



       Chief Complaint & History of Present Illness: This 73 year old gentleman has been  disabled assistance and wheelchair bound since 2066 when he suffered a compression fracture in a fall from a ladder at an amusement park.  He has been disabled but  has managed to stand  and get himself in and out of the wheelchair.  He began noticing cramps and tingling of both his upper extremities and they felt the same as before he had his cervical laminectomy in 2081. He was unable to grip his cup and began dropping objects. Nerve conduction studies were done in September 2094 the conclusion is that he has bilateral evidence of cervical polyradiculopathy right greater than the left.  evidence of sensory poly neuropathy there is also evidence to suggest a mild mean neuropathy at the wrists bilaterally





        Past Medical History:  

1.  Paraplegia secondary to Compression fracture in Amusement Park accident in 2066

2.  cervical spondylosis

3.  COPD uses prn Albuterol MDI

4.  CAD S/P CABG X3 in 2087 catheterization done in March 2090.  Recent stress done in May 2094

History of CABG, known hypercholesterolemia, hypertension, dyspnea on exertion, cancer, smoking. S/P B/L CEA, Cath '90 - occluded SVG to Cx, patent LIMA. patent SVG to RCA. Admitted with (L) sided chest pain, ruled out for MI by enzymes. Ruled out for aortic dissection by CT. Last Adeno-MIBI 3/2092 - posterior wall MI, Negative for ischemia. PURPOSE(S): Diagnosis of ischemia. DIAGNOSES: Primary diagnosis is chestpain. Additional diagnoses include hypercholesterolemia, coronary artery disease, hypertension, diabetes, hyperlipidemia. MEDICATIONS: Albuterol, ECASA, Furosemide, Lopressor, Losartan. PROCEDURE: The patient underwent an adenosine stress test with exercise. Maximum adenosine dose: 140 ucg/kg/min. Supplemental arm exercise x 0:00 (min:sec). 1 lb hand held weight 1097MBq 99mTc sestamibi were injected intravenously following infusion of adenosine with exercise and tomographic imaging data acquired. Additional data were acquired following intravenous injection of another 406MBq 99mTc sestamibi at rest on the same day. Global LVEF was computed and qualitative assessment of regional systolic function was made. STRESS TEST RESULTS: DURATION @ MAX DOSE (min:sec) 5:00 HR (REST=>MAX) 56 => 74 (50% PREDICTED) BP (INITIAL=>PEAK) 150/60 => 150/60 (MINIMUM = 130/x) PEAK DOUBLE PRODUCT: 11100 ENDPOINT(S): The protocol was completed. Chest pain did not occur. REST ECG: The rest electrocardiogram revealed nonspecific ST segment and T-wave abnormalities. Sinus bradycardia 56/min. First degree AVB STRESS ECG: No ST segment changes were observed during this test. Arrhythmias: None STRESS TEST COMMENTS Negative for ischemia. However, the sensitivity of Adenosine-induced ST segment changes for detecting significant CAD is limited. SCAN RESULTS: The left ventricle is normal in size. There is a moderate reduction in tracer activity in the posterobasal wall of the left ventricle which persists after reinjection at rest. The left ventricular ejection fraction was 50% on the stress study. Regional wall motion abnormalities were noted in the posterior wall on the stress study. CONCLUSIONS: The ECG response to pharmacological stress was negative for ischemia. The myocardial scans show posterobasal infarction without ischemia--LVEF=50%. 



5.  Ileoloop complicated by pyelo X7 2079-2082 + neurogenic bladder

6.  TIA 's did have bilateral Carotid endarterectomies

7.  Hypercholesterolemia

8. IDDM now on Glyburide 5 mgm po bid and bid dosing of NPH 33 units in am and 45 units in the pm.  his blood sugars can range from 100-480 and HgA1C is approx 9

9.  Disc Herniation L4-5 L5 S1

10  Decreased hearing and tinnitus

11. UGI bleed  in 2089 ( 2 unit PRBC's ) negative endoscopy in  September. 2092

12.  Hemorrhoids

13.  Candida Infection Ileal Conduit 2/92

14.  Fx. left Tibia

15.  Acute depression.. after his injury he was very depressed and self destructive sought counseling and was hospitalized after cutting his wrists and trying to inhale gas.  He has been on various antidepressants and currently lives with his wife on no medication.   His sx's have improved since becoming sober in 2087.

  



                                              

        Past Surgical History:

C5-6,C6-7 Right Foraminectomy in Mar. 2081

Debredement of the cervical surgical area in July 2088 ( right arm weakness)

CABG X3 May 2087

cardiac catheterization in March 2090

Bilateral carotid Endartercetomies in 8/2091

Laminectomy L4-5 and L5-S1  in 2081

ORIF left tibia Mar. 2092



         

        Medications:

1.  ASA 81 mgm po qd

2.  Lopressor 50 mgm po bid

3.  Norvasc 10 mgm po qd

4.  Lasix 40 mgm po qd

5.  Lescol 20 mgm po (2) at hs

6.  Albuterol MDI 2 puffs qid

7.   Glyburide 5 mgm po bid

8.  NPH Insulin 35 units q am and 45 units qpm







        Allergies: No Known drug allergies although "muscle relaxants" and amitriptyline caused increased muscle weakness, no allergies to foods, environmental or Latex



        Social history:



               Smoking: discontinued in 2087 after smoking 2PPD for 50 years

               Alcohol Use: remote use in the past quite all alcohol in 2087

               Allergen Exposure: none known no blood transfusions in the past three months

               Exercise:  wheelchair bound             

               Occupation: retired

               Marital status:Married

         

        Review of Systems

                

                General: wheelchair dependent

                HEENT:  + tinnitus and hard of hearing full ROM neck

                Cardiovascular:+CAD,+HTN, +Hyperlipidemia,IDDM, Has had symptomatic bradycardia episodic nature secondary to stimulation of the carotid sinus with neck brace

                Respiratory: +COPD

                Neurologic: Sensation decreased below nipple line

                Gastrointestinal: + UGI bleeding in  duodenal ulcers X22089 (transfused 2 units PRBC's), + abdominal wall hernia, uses Dulcolax suppository every other day for rectal  bowel evacuation

                Hepatobiliary: remote history of alcohol abuse

                Renal/Genitourinary: + ileal conduit  complicated with frequent pyelonephritis from 2079-2082 recurrent nephrotomy tube with left nephrolithiasis removed in 2083, + neurogenic bladder

                LMP: N/A

                Peripheral Vascular: denies blood clot , + occasional dependant edema edema               

                Musculoskeletal:+ Paraparesis secondary to T4 compression + cervical spondylosis,+ lumbar fusion,+ left tibia fracture after a fall in 2092

                Heme/Onc: denies blood disorders, or cancer, radiation or chemotherapy                

                Psychiatric:  + depression ( see notes in old chart  2066 he had self destructive behavior "cutting wrists" and "gas inhalation' he was hospitalized at Texas Medical Center

                Skin: + acute candida around ileal conduit stoma uses lotrisone( now resolved)

           Vital signs:



                     Bp: 165/64   mm Hg

                     P:62  bpm

                     SaO2: 95  %

                     Temp: 96.3  degrees F

                     Resp:18

                     Ht: 69  inches

                     Wt:172   pounds



           Exam:

                     General: well developed, well nourished obese male sitting in wheelchair good trunk balance

                     HEENT:  good range of motion, no masses, neck veins flat,  no bruits, bilateral carotid surgery scars

                     Airway: Mallampatti: Class II

                     Teeth: lower rigfht lateral "loose" and obvious gum recession

                     Lungs:  Clear to auscultation

                     Heart:  regular rhythm,  no  murmurs, S1=S2, no gallop

                     Abdomen:  soft, non tender,non distended,normal bowel sounds, no organomegaly or palpable                       masses                                          

                     GU/Rectal:ileal conduit right upper quad no rash noted

                     Extremities: no clubbing or cyanosis

                     Skin: no ulcers or rashes

                      Lymphatics:  no lymphadenopathy

                      Neurological:

                          Cranial Nerves;  II-XII grossly intact

                          Sensory:diminished     

                          Motor:    lower extremity atrophy

                          Reflexes: diminished

                          Gait:  wheelchair bound

                          Speech: articulates well clear and focused, hard of hearing





          Assessment:   ASA Physical Status:3 





               73 year old male with cervical disc herniation scheduled for Cervical  Laminectomy with fusion on Jan. 24, 2094 by Dr Blanchard.  He has co morbid diseases IDDM, HTN, Hyperlipidemia, COPD, Paraplegia, Hx of uti and depression. His last surgery was in 2092 ORIF left Tibia IV sedation with spinal anesthesia no complication noted in anesthesai record..  There has been difficulty placing the IV ( pt said this happens a lot). According to note from 3/07/81 anesthesia for previous cervical Laminectomy  Rapid sequence induction MAC #3 8.0 ETT easy intubation. Pt was a smoker for 50 years occasionally uses Albuterol with a spacer suggested he use it pre op .  He had a stress test done in May 2094 and it was negative for ischemia and a LVEF was 50%.  Report in this note under Medical Problems.  He was admitted for "chest pain " in May 2094 and he no longer is using the NTG sl or the Nitropace.  He was told the "pains" he feels is most likely from his CABG ( CABG X3)- Grafts to RCA patent,occluded at circumflex, LIMA patent and the post sternal pain. The stress test was done during this admission as well as a CAT scan to r/o aortic dissection. ( also negative)  his biggest problem seems to be his "not very well controlled diabetes".  There is a note from the May 2094 admission that he was to receive a trial of Nexium to see if his "chest pain" was epigastric" but pt and wife said he never received this medication.  He denies any GERD or "chest pain" since may 2094.  He recognizes his hypoglycemia sx's and  also his hyper glycemia sx's ( blurred vision) when his blood sugar is 480.  He will not take his Glyburide the night before surgery and the morning of.. He will take 1/2 dose of Insulin the morning of 15 untis NPH.    He denies any medication allergies but staes that "muscle relaxants" cause his legs to become flaccid.





            Plan:



                 Proposed Anesthetic: general endotracheal

                 Monitors:  standard, arterial line

                 Pain Management: IVPCA

                 Autologous Blood:none

                 Premedication: none

                 Usual Medications: Lopressor, Norvasc

                 Medications to be held before surgery: Glyburide

                 Diabetic Medications: 15 units of NPH Insulin morning of surgery

                 NSAIDS:  avoid for three days prior to surgery

                 Aspirin:  avoid for one week prior to surgery

                  NPO:  after midnight



     Ancillary Studies:

          Labs Pending:

          EKG: formal reading pending

          CXR: pending





     ____________________________________________________

     Willean Gabriella Yamamoto, MSN, RN,C-NP



     PATA Medical director/staff anesthesiologist:



     I have reviewed this preanesthetic assessment and concur with the assessment and recommended plan with      the following exceptions:





     signed:  ______________________________________________



     Attending Surgeon Reassessment Note:





     I have reviewed the above history and physical exam and agree with the findings.  Additional comments:



     signed:_______________________________________________

   

  

        













****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-12-13

TEAM 2 ACCEPT NOTE

Patient's name: Frank Keatering	
MRN: 	4832978
Date of Admission to MICU: 	12/11/95
Date of transfer to Internal Medicine: 	12/13/95

ID/CC:  acute loss of motor/sensation at level of T8

History Obtained From: Pt, old charts, transfer note.

History of Present Illness:  74 y/o man with h/o paraplegia 2/2 compression fracture and wheelchair bound, vascular dz, with recent bilateral ileofemoral and renal artery stent (11/24/95) and recent cardiac cath stent to the circumflex (11/28/95). Pt presented to OSH 12/10 with c/o abdominal pain onset the PM prior to admission, diffuse in nature, localized in the mid-epigastric region, RUQ, and LUQ with a pain scale of 8-10/10 pain. Per charts he reported decreased pain in the am with ability to tolerate PO's and then increasing pain that afternoon. Also associated with diaphoresis, + nausea, no vomiting, no sob. During placement of a central line at OSH ED, pt experienced shaking during procedure and had acute loss of motor and sensory strength in the LE's. Per Nursing chart at OSH ED, pt given Morphine for abd pain (around 4p-8p) with coffee ground emesis at 8pm with subsequent decrease in BP to 76/49 and started on dopamine for pressure support. At the same time, pt c/o numbness in feet. Per charts he was reported to be bending forward coughing and vomiting and experienced acute loss of sensation/motor function in the abdomen and lower extremities.

Course at the outside hospital- 
1.Neuro- acute loss of sensation/motor at the level of T8. Per Neurology, had paraplegic legs, no sphincter tone, no anal wink, Sx were concerning for aortic dissection. Abd US unrevealing but was reported as a poor study. CT of T8-T10 did not show gross deviations of spine, no soft tissue masses or disk bulging.  
2.GI- Coffee ground emesis at OSH, with no fresh blood- with dropping HCT 44-40-35 and transfused 1 U pRBC on 12/11.  Also guiac +.  Etiology thought to be 2/2 ASA and plavix.  No egd was performed and amlyase and lipase, and LFTs were nl per report.  
3.ID- Pt was hypotensive with SBP in the 70's on presentation with good response to fluids, In setting of elevated WBC to 22 pt was empirically treated with Abx (zosyn, flagyl and vanc). BCx were sent and CXR appeared clear.
4.CARDIAC- Cardiac enzymes were followed with increasing Troponins: 0.04    0.07    0.08    0.09, CK index: 3.0    3.7. No complaints of chest pain during his stay. And no report of signifigant EKG changes. 
5.Renal- Creatinine increase from 2.6 to 3.1 thought to be 2/2 Acute on chronic RF.

Pt transferred to HOB for further eval of r/o dissection, r/o cord compression, GIB, poss abd ischemia, ARI/CRI

Review of System on admission: 
CV: no orthopnea, no PND
Resp: sob, no cough, no sputum production 
GI: abdominal pain as above, no melena, no BRBPR, able to have BM
GU: per OSH ED report of dark urine in ileostomy bag x2d with decreased UOP
Musculoskeletal: baseline decreased to minimal movement in the LLE, min-mod movement in right leg, able to transfer to and from wheelchair
Neuro/Psych: alert and oriented x3.

MICU Course:
1.Paraplegia:  Has baseline deficits (wheelchair bound), but unclear how they compare to current exam--> level at T5/T6.  
- first MRI showed low T2 signal collections from T6--> L1 with displacement of thoracic cord anteriorly from T7-T10. 
-no cord compression on repeat study, however ddx still includes cord infarction vs demyelinating disease
-neurosurg, neuro consulted, following
2.Respiratory status: Acute desaturation 2/2 methemoglobinemia as consequence of topical anesthetic
- s/p methylene blue (80 mg x 1, 40 mg x 1) with resolution of methemoglobin from 35% to 1%. 
3.Renal failure:  Possibilities raised include cholesterol emboli from recent interventions, relative hypoperfusion with normalization of blood pressure. 
- urine eos negative
- Cr 2.9-->2.5 today
4.Abdominal pain: mild-moderate stenosis just beyond origin of SMA seen on MRA; considered mesenteric ischemia a/w low flow state. However, lactic acid 1.3, and pH wnl 
- have liberalized bp parameters now that dissection ruled out
5.GI bleed: coffee ground emesis-- unclear if this reflects enteric ischemia vs. sentinel bleeding
-GI team consulted
6.Coronary artery disease:
- troponin 0.14 on admission, but subsequently all wnl, likely troponin leak in setting of GIB prior to admission
- taken off ASA, plavix in context of suspected UGIB
- cont lopressor 
- hydral, isordil, goal SBP 140-150
7.Hemodynamics:
- TEE with no dissection
- TTE with EF 54%, no SWMA, no tamponade
- metoprolol +/- isordil/hydral
8.Diabetes mellitus
- on MICU insulin protocol, will switch to sliding scale

Past Medical History: 
1.  Paraplegia secondary to Compression fracture in Amusement Park accident in 2066
2.  cervical spondylosis
3.  COPD uses prn Albuterol MDI
4.  CAD S/P CABG X3 in 2087 catheterization done in March 2090: patent SVG to RCA, patent LIMA to LAD, occluded SVG to Circ; stress 5/94 /o ischemia; Cath with stent in circumflex 11/28/95
5.  Ileoloop complicated by pyelo X7 2079-2082 + neurogenic bladder (ostomy for urine)
6.  TIA 's, s/p bilateral Carotid endarterectomies
7.  Hypercholesterolemia
8. IDDM 
9.  Disc Herniation L4-5 L5 S1
10  Decreased hearing and tinnitus
11. UGI bleed in 2089 (2 unit PRBC's) negative endoscopy in 9/92
12.  Hemorrhoids
13.  Candida Infection Ileal Conduit 2/92
14.  Fx. left Tibia c rod placement in 2/92
15.  Acute depression: after his injury he was very depressed and self destructive sought counseling and was hospitalized after cutting his wrists and trying to inhale gas.  He has been on various antidepressants and currently lives with his wife on no medication.   His sx's have improved since becoming sober in 2087.
16. Bilateral ileo-femoral bypass, renal artery stent 11/24/95
17. Known discrepancy of 30 mmHg in BP between L, R arms

Medications:  prior to admission at OSH
ASA 325 mg po qd
Plavix 75 mg 
Lopressor 50 mg po bid
Losartan 50 mg po qd
Furosemide 40 mg po qd
NTG SL prn
Fluvastatin 40 mg po qd
APAP 500 mg po 2 tid prn
Glyburide 5 mg qam,qpm
NPH insulin 12U qam, 18 U qpm
Lortisone cream to stoma tid prn
Atrovent MDI 2 puffs bid
Pulmicort MID 2 puffs bid
Albuterol MDI 2 puffs prn up to qid

Allergies: hurricane spray    methemoglobinemia

Family History: 
Non contributory

Social history: 
Smoking: discontinued in 2087 after smoking 2PPD for 50 years    
Alcohol Use: quit all alcohol in 2087
Exercise:  wheelchair bound
Occupation: retired
Family: Married, daughter nearby, son (estranged) in GA

Physical Exam:
	VITALS: T=97.3   BP=166/58   HR=84   RR=28   O2=95%4L
	GEN: Lying in bed in NAD slouched over eating ice cream
	HEENT: nasal cannula in place
	NECK: supple, JVP < 8cm; carotid bruit on R
	CHEST: slight crackles at R base, otherwise CTAB w/good air mvt
	CV: RRR, nlS1S2, 2/6 SEM LUSB
	ABD: ostomy intact; soft, ND, NT
	EXT: warm, no edema
	NEURO: alert, oriented to person, HOB, late-Nov, 2095; remembers most of events of past 2 wks; CN II-XII intact; mass, tone in UE nl bilat, LE atrophied bilat; strength 4/5 bilat in UE, 0/5 LE; 1+ DTRs UE, 0 DTRs LE; sensation grossly intact UE, absent in LE's below umbilicus.

Labs:
   HOB  BLOOD          13-Dec-2095 04:45  Accession# 3084A07688
Sodium (Stat Lab)        144                         (135-145)        mmol/L
Potassium (Stat Lab)     4.0                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L
Chloride (Stat Lab)      119                H        (100-108)        mmol/L
CO2 (Stat Lab)           19.7               L        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L
BUN (Stat Lab)           51                 H        (8-25)           mg/dl
Creatinine (Stat Lab)    2.5                H        (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl
Glucose (Stat Lab)       165                H        (70-110)         mg/dl
Calcium                  7.9                L        (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl
Phosphorus               2.4                L        (2.6-4.5)        mg/dl
Magnesium                1.9                         (1.4-2.0)        meq/L
Total Protein            5.8                L        (6.0-8.3)        g/dl
Albumin                  2.7                L        (3.3-5.0)        g/dl
Globulin                 3.1                         (2.6-4.1)        g/dl
Direct Bilirubin         0.2                         (0-0.4)          mg/dl
Total Bilirubin          0.3                         (0-1.0)          mg/dl
Alkaline Phosphatase     53                          (45-115)         U/L
Transaminase-SGPT        10                          (10-55)          U/L
Amylase                  44                          (3-100)          units/L
Lipase                   2.2                         (1.3-6.0)        U/dl
Creatine Kinase Isoenz   4.1                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml
CPK Isoenzymes Index                                 (0.0-3.5)        %
     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.
Troponin-T               0.07                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml
Transaminase-SGOT        13                          (10-40)          U/L
Creatine Kinase          313                         (60-400)         U/L
Vancomycin,Unspecified   12.0                                         mcg/ml
       PEAK: 15.0-35.0
          TROUGH:    0-10.0

   HOB  BLOOD          13-Dec-2095 05:07  Accession# 8446G98130
WBC                      14.6               H        (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm
HCT                      28.1               L        (41.0-53.0)      %
HGB                      9.6                L        (13.5-17.5)      gm/dl
RBC                      3.14               L        (4.50-5.90)      mil/cmm
PLT                      320                         (150-350)        th/cumm
MCV                      90                          (80-100)         fl
MCH                      30.7                        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc
MCHC                     34.3                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl
RDW                      14.2                        (11.5-14.5)      %
PT                       14.0               H        (11.1-13.1)      sec
PT-INR                   1.3
     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.
APTT                     19.9               L        (22.1-35.1)      sec
DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST     RECEIVED
Diff Method              Auto
Poly                     82                 H        (40-70)          %
Lymphs                   10                 L        (22-44)          %
Monos                    3                  L        (4-11)           %
EOS                      5                           (0-8)            %
Basos                    0                           (0-3)            %
Absolute Neuts           11.98              H        (1.8-7.7)        th/cmm
Absolute Lymphs          1.46                        (1.0-4.8)        th/cmm
Absolute Monos           0.41               H        (0.2-0.4)        th/cmm
Absolute EOS             0.70               H        (0.1-0.3)        th/cmm
Absolute Basos           0.03                        (0.0-0.3)        th/cmm
Aniso                    None                        (NORMAL)
Hypo                     None                        (NORMAL)
Macrocytes               None
Microcytes               None

MICRO: Urine, blood cx x 2 NGTD at HOB; VRE neg x1; MRSA nasal swab neg x1

EKG: NSR at 80, nl axis, old ST depressions in V4-5

CXR (12/13):  Stable chest without new or enlarging infiltrates or pneumonias.
	Cardiac size normal, no signs of edema or decompensation.
	Operative changes as before and right subclavian central line as
	before without apparent pneumothorax or complication.

MRI (12/12): 
EXAMINATION: MRI of the cervical, thoracic, lumbar spine.
	EXAMINATION DATE: 12/12/95.
	Comparison films: The prior films are available for comparison to
	due PACS technical difficulties. Comparison is made with the
	report of prior C-spine CT from January 2095.
	History:72 year old man with history of paraplegia from traumatic
	injury in 2066 with new sensation loss and motor loss below T8.
	Technique:Sagittal T2 images were obtained of the cervical,
	thoracic, lumbar spine.  The Axial T2 images are obtained from T10
	through L1. The images are moderately motion degraded in the
	thoracic and lumbar spine.  The cervical spine MRI was repeated
	three times due to motion. No contrast was used.
	Findings:
	CERVICAL SPINE:
	Straightening of the cervical lordosis is noted from C2 through
	C6. Bone marrow signal demonstrates patchy areas of T2 high signal
	within the C4 and C5 vertebral body.  Posterior disc osteophyte
	complexes are present at C2/C3, C3/C4, C4/C5, C5/C6, C6/C7.
	The patient is status post posterior laminectomy and fusion which
	causes susceptibility artifact. The laminectomy from C3 through
	C7, previously noted, is not well visualized due to motion
	artifact and susceptibility.
	THORACIC SPINE:
	There is partial fusion of T4 to T5 with loss of height of T4 and
	focal kyphosis at this area. Myelomalacia is noted from T1 through
	T5. There is focal T2 high signal within the cord substance at the
	T4 level.
	T2 low signal collections are noted posterior to the cord at T6
	through T12.  A high signal septation is present through this
	collection at T7 and extending from T11 through L1. This low T2
	signal collection displaces the cord anteriorly from T7 through
	T10.
	The cord is small from T7 through T10 consistent with myelomalacia
	and high T2 signal.
	High signal is also present in the cord substance of the distal
	thoracic cord and at the conus.
	Small amount of T2 high signal is noted in encircling the distal
	thoracic cord and the spinal roots.
	LUMBAR SPINE:
	Straightening of the lumbar spine is noted with grade 1
	retrolisthesis of L4 on L5. There is a levoscoliosis with apex at
	L4/L5.
	Disc demonstrates T2 shortening within several lumbar discs and
	disc height loss at L4/L5, L5/S1.
	T2 high signal at the endplates are noted around the L4/L5 and
	L5/S1 disc levels.   Moderate to severe stenosis of the bilateral
	neural foramen at L5/S1 facet osteoarthritis and disc height loss
	of L5/S1 is noted. The patient has had prior surgery of the
	spinous processes of L4 and L5.
	The conus terminates at L1/L2. The spinal roots appear clumped
	centrally and there is T2 high signal around the upper spinal
	roots. T2 high signal is noted at the distal aspect of the thecal
	sac.
IMPRESSION:
	 1.  Low T2 signal collections from T6 through L1 with
	displacement of the thoracic cord anteriorly from T7 through T10.
	The differential diagnosis for this collection includes unusual
	flow artifact or multiloculated septations or epidural
	collections.  Recommend dedicated thoracic and lumbar spine MRI
	with contrast and T2 axials through the L spine and C spine. If
	clinically indicated, consider repeat C spine MRI with contrast.
	Dr. Winters was informed of this at 2:15 PM on 12/12/95.
	2.  Myelomalacia of the thoracic cord from T4-T5 level and at
	T7-10.
	3.  The spinal roots are incompletely imaged but have a clumped in
	appearance suggesting arachnoiditis. Repeat axial images through
	the entire spinal roots could better evaluate this.
	4. Degenerative disc disease of the lumbar spine at L4/L5 and
	L5/S1. degenerative disc disease of the cervical spine at C3/C4
	C4/C5 C5/C6.
	5.  Prior surgical fusion of the cervical spine and laminectomies
	are incompletely evaluated on the study due to motion.  Please see
	prior CT report for the details.
	6.  Mild focal kyphosis with height loss at T4 appears subacute
	and may be from prior trauma.

MRI (12/13):	
MRI THORACIC AND LUMBAR SPINE WITHOUT AND WITH GADOLINIUM
	History: History of previous cord compression. Status post recent
	aorto-bifemoral bypass. Now with sudden onset of loss of lower
	extremity motor function and sensation.
	Comparison: MRI spine dated 12/12/95.
	Procedure: Multiplanar MR imaging of the entire spine was
	performed without and with Gadolinium.
	Findings:
	There is an old compression fracture at T5.  There is exaggeration
	of the normal kyphosis at this level.  There is no evidence of
	marrow edema to suggest acute fracture in the spine.  There is
	straightening of the normal lumbar lordosis.  There is grade 1
	retrolisthesis of L4 on L5.  There is degenerative change in the
	L4-5 and L5-S1 end plates.  There is increased T2 signal in the
	L4-5 and L5-S1 discs however the adjacent endplates are well
	preserved, and although infection cannot be completely excluded,
	it is considered very unlikely.  There is a small central disc
	protrusion at T8-9.
	There is no evidence of significant canal stenosis in the thoracic
	or lumbar spine.
	Examination of the cord demonstrates myelomalacia extending from
	the T5 level inferiorly.  There is prominent flow artifact in the
	CSF surrounding the myelomalacic cord.  The conus is expanded and
	demonstrates hyperintensity on T2 weighted sequences.  There is no
	associated enhancement.  No vascular flow voids are identified.
	There is a small right pleural effusion.  There is consolidation
	at the right lung base.  This may represent atelectasis or
	infiltrate and correlation with chest x-ray is recommended.
IMPRESSION:
	Expansion and signal abnormality in the conus superimposed on
	chronic myelomalacia. The differential diagnosis includes cord
	infarction, and demyelinating disease.  Vascular malformation and
	neoplasm are considered less likely due to the absence of vascular
	flow voids and abnormal enhancement.


MRA:  MRA of the aorta with runoff was conducted as per departmental
	protocol.
	FINDINGS:
	Due to the nature of MRI imaging, dedicated sequences were
	performed to evaluate the vasculature. The remainder of the
	abdominal organs are not fully evaluated and if clinically
	indicated, directed sequences could be performed.
	This was a technically limited study due to suboptimal contrast
	bolus and movement.  The patient was agitated and unable to
	cooperate .
	No evidence for an aortic dissection is identified.
	There is moderate stenosis of the left subclavian artery just
	beyond its origin.
	The celiac trunk is patent.
	There is mild/moderate stenosis just beyond the origin of the
	superior mesenteric artery.
	The renal arteries cannot be assessed on this study.
IMPRESSION:
	1.  Limited study due to technical factors and patient movement
	however no evidence of an aortic dissection is identified.  A
	repeat MRI with better contrast bolus and sedation may be obtained
	if clinically indicated.
	2.  Moderate stenosis is noted just distal to the origin of the
	left subclavian artery.
3.	Mild/moderate stenosis just beyond the origin of the SMA.

CT Spine (12/13): report pending
_____________________________________________________________________
Assessment/Plan: 74 y/o vasculopath presenting with new neurological deficits, abdominal pain, UGI bleed, progressive renal failure, initially worrisome for aortic dissection. Unifying diagnosis remains obscure- ? occlusive atheroemboli vs epidural hematoma.

1.Paraplegia: Has baseline deficits (wheelchair bound), but unclear how they compare to current exam--> level at T5/T6. First MRI showed low T2 signal collections from T6--> L1 with displacement of thoracic cord anteriorly from T7-T10; no cord compression on repeat study, however ddx still includes cord infarction vs demyelinating disease
-neurology and neurosurgery following
-awaiting spinal CT to evaluate for epidural hematoma
-in addition, neurology has asked for MRI with line diffusion and MPGR sequence to r/o infarction, which has been ordered

2.Respiratory status: Acute desaturation 2/2 methemoglobinemia as consequence of topical anesthetic; s/p methylene blue (80 mg x 1, 40 mg x 1) with resolution of methemoglobin from 35% to 1%, now on 4L NC sats are 95%.
-cont O2 and wean as tolerated
-enter hurricane spray as allergy

3.Renal failure:  Possibilities raised include cholesterol emboli from recent interventions, relative hypoperfusion with normalization of blood pressure. No contrast at OSH; urine eos negative; FENa= 0.94%; Cr 3.1    2.5 today
-follow Cr

4.Abdominal pain: mild-moderate stenosis just beyond origin of SMA seen on MRA; considered mesenteric ischemia a/w low flow state. However, lactic acid 1.3, and pH wnl 
- will follow acid/base status, lytes, pain

5.GI bleed: coffee ground emesis-- unclear if this reflects enteric ischemia vs. ulcer in setting of plavix, ASA
-GI team following, planning on probable EGD 12/15
-holding ASA, plavix for now

6.Cards- ISCHEMIA: troponin 0.14 on admission, but subsequently all wnl, likely troponin leak in setting of GIB prior to admission
- off ASA, plavix in context of suspected UGIB
- maintain Hct > 30
- cont lopressor 
PUMP: TEE with no dissection; TTE with EF 54%, no SWMA, no tamponade
- metoprolol, isordil/hydral goal SBP 140-150
RHYTHM - NSR

7.Diabetes mellitus: sliding scale QID
- will convert to NPH once requirements determined

8.FEN: resume diet as EGD likely on Monday

9.Prophylaxis: cont nexium, holding fragmin given concern for bleeding

10.Dispo: Will need rehab once stable; PT/OT

11.CODE: FULL




______________
Karen V. Barajas, M.D.
Internal Medicine Intern 18412




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-09-03

      



Belleview Convalescent Hospital

Consult for Surgery



Keating,Frank D

4832978 





CC/ID: 74 yo male with Abdomainal pain



HPI:  74 yo who was in 11/96 HOB for abdominal pain and worsening of this incomplete paraplegia.  For more details please see HOB d/c summary 12-11-95 and his Lakeland Hospital d/c summary from 5-19-2096.  As an inpatient he developed a sacral decubitus ulcer which became large.  During his rehab stay at LH, he was being followed by they HOB wound clinic for management of his sacral ulcer with a vac dressing.  The wound progressed until he presented to the EW 8/96 with frank fecal contamination of a stage 4 ulcer.  He thus had a diverting colostomy on 8/23/96 to allow his ulcer to heal.  he presented to the EW today with one day of abdominal pain, distention and nausea.



PMH: 

      Paraplegia, secondary to compression fracture in 2066;

     Cervical spondylosis;

     Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease;

     Coronary artery disease, status post coronary artery bypass graft times 3

     in 2087;

     Ileal loop, complicated by recurrent pyleonephritis;

     History of transient ischemic attack, status post bilateral carotid

     endarterectomies;

     Hypercholesterolemia;

     Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus;

     Disc herniation at the L4-5, L5-S1 levels;

     History of peptic ulcer disease with upper gastrointestinal bleed in 2089,

     requiring packed red blood cells transfusion;

     Hemorrhoids;

     History of candida infection involving his ileal conduit;

     Status post left tibia fracture;

     Depression;

     Peripheral vascular disease, status post bilateral iliofemoral bypass.

     H/o Acute renal failure after cardiac catheterization

  Spinal cord infarction from embolic event

     



PSH:

   1.    C5-6 and C6-7 right foraminotomy in 2081

2.	Laminectomy at L4-5 and L5-S1 in 2081

3.	Bilateral carotid endarterectomies in 2081

4.    Coronary artery bypass grafting in 2087

5.	11/24/95 underwent bilateral iliofemoral and renal artery stent placement

6.	11/28/95 cardiac catheterization with a stent placed in the left circumflex artery 

   7.   Diverting colostomy 8/23/96



Meds:Zocor  20mg qhs, Ambien 10mg qhs, Nexium 20mg BID, NPH 10u AM, 16u PM, Ducolax  BI, Vit C 500mg TID, Cozar 50mg qd, Paroxetine 30mg qd, Plavix 75mg qd, Lescol 40mg qhs, Isosorbide 20mg TID, Metroprolol 25mg TID, Neurontin 100mg qhs, Nefedical XL 60mg qd, Fragmin 500 U SC QD



All: 

     Patient notes that muscle relaxants and Amitriptyline increase patient's weakness.  Otherwise no known drug allergies.





SH: Notable for history of prior tobacco use.  The patient quit smoking in 2087, after    approximately 100 pack years.  He reported a history of remote alcohol use, but none since 2087.  Otherwise notable for the fact that the patient was married, and he is retired.





PE:   T 97.5  Hr 83  BP 119/60  RR22  O2 Sat 97%



Gen:  Comfortable appearing gentleman 

Cards RRR nlS1, S2  No R/M/G appreciated

Resp:  Decreased breath sounds at RML

ABD:  distended, soft, nontender, stool in colostomy bag, urine in urostomy bag

incision with open are, no surrounding cellulitis, no purulent drainage

Skin:  Deep decubitus sacral ulcer 0.5cm superior to the anus measuring 3cm deep and 2cm in circumference with 4

Labs:

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            

09/03/2096        142            3.8            106            25.7           



Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            

09/03/2096        14             1.1            131 (H)        



Date/Time         CK-MB          TROP-I         

09/03/2096        NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       



Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HCT            PLT            

09/03/2096        12.9 (H)       4.56           40.8 (L)       529 (H)        



Date/Time         %NEUT          %LYMPH         %MONO          %EOS           

09/03/2096        85 (H)         12 (L)         3 (L)          0              



Date/Time         PT             PTT            

09/03/2096        13.2 (H)       23.8           



Date/Time         UA-BLD         UA-ALB         UA-NIT         UA-WBC         

09/03/2096         [1]            [2]           NEGATIVE        [3]           



Date/Time         UAS-RBC        UAS-WBC        UAS-BACT       UAS-YEAS       

09/03/2096        10-20          >100           Few            Few            



Date/Time         UAS-SQHI       

09/03/2096        Moderate       



Radiology



KUB/upright:

IMPRESSION

      Dilated small bowel with air fluid levels suspicious for small

     bowel obstruction.



CT Abd/pelvis:dilated loops of small bowel , small amout of free fluid, 8x5 cm collection in pelvis



Other studies EKG NSR with TWI V1-V4 TW flat in V5-V6





Impression/Plan: 74 y.o. M with SBO s/p diverting colostomy and pelvic fluid collection.



1) Admit to Ward Surgery

2) IR drain in AM

3) Ancef

4) NPO, NGT, IV fluid.



Youssef M. Noe III, MD



                                            _____________________________

Emergency Ward Surgical Department

Pager: 60382     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-01-17

                                                       Patient Name: KEATING,FRANK [ MRN: 4832978HOB ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 1/17/2097



BCH SURGERY EW EVALUATION



HPI: Mr. Keating is a 75 year-old male with a complex medical history which includes a history of a stage 4 sacral decubitus ulcer, secondary to being bedridden due to paraplegia (due to injury in 2066).  His ulcer was eroding into his rectum and therefore he underwent sigmoid colostomy 8/96 for diversion.  He is also s/p ileal loop urostomy in the distant past.  Was seen in plastics clinic today, decub progressing well, but poor POs, referred for admission.  Denies N/V, has had normal ostomy output, denies abd pain, though he did have some cramping several days ago.  His main complaint is long-standing back pain.  Of note, he had been readmitted about 2 weeks postop with distention and pain, CT showing partial SBO and a pelvic fluid collection, which was drained, cultures were sterile.  Wife noted some discharge from midline wound several days ago, but this has ceased. 



PMH:      Paraplegia, secondary to compression fracture in 2066;

     Cervical spondylosis;

     Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease;

     Coronary artery disease, status post coronary artery bypass graft times 3

     in 2087;

     Ileal loop, complicated by recurrent pyleonephritis;

     History of transient ischemic attack, status post bilateral carotid

     endarterectomies;

     Hypercholesterolemia;

     Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus;

     Disc herniation at the L4-5, L5-S1 levels;

     History of peptic ulcer disease with upper gastrointestinal bleed in 2089,

     requiring packed red blood cells transfusion;

     Hemorrhoids;

     History of candida infection involving his ileal conduit;

     Status post left tibia fracture;

     Depression;

     Peripheral vascular disease, status post bilateral iliofemoral bypass.

     H/o Acute renal failure after cardiac catheterization

  Spinal cord infarction from embolic event



PSH:

   1.    C5-6 and C6-7 right foraminotomy in 2081

2.	Laminectomy at L4-5 and L5-S1 in 2081

3.	Bilateral carotid endarterectomies in 2081

4.    Coronary artery bypass grafting in 2087

5.	11/24/95 underwent bilateral iliofemoral and renal artery stent placement

6.	11/28/95 cardiac catheterization with a stent placed in the left circumflex artery 

   7.   Diverting colostomy 8/23/96



Meds:

o SIMVASTATIN (ZOCOR )  20 MG PO  QHS    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o CLOPIDOGREL (PLAVIX )  75 MG PO  QD    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o ESOMEPRAZOLE (NEXIUM )  40 MG PO  QD    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o ZOLPIDEM TARTRATE (AMBIEN )  10 MG PO  QHS   PRN: insomnia 



o PAROXETINE (PAXIL )  30 MG PO  QD    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o INSULIN NPH HUMAN  10 UNITS SC  QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o INSULIN NPH HUMAN  16 UNITS SC  QPM BEFORE SUPPER  10/21/2096 (Thu) Routine x1    Last Dose Given:  10/23/96 at 08:00 am 



o INSULIN REGULAR HUMAN  Sliding Scale  If BS <=    200 give 0 Units ;  For BS from 201  to 250 give 4 Units ;  For BS from 251  to 300 give 6 Units ;  For BS from 301  to 350 give 8 Units ;  For BS from 351  to 400 give 10 Units ;  For BS > 400 give 12 Units and Call House MD ;   SC  QID (AC + HS)    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 12:00 pm 



o OXYCODONE 5 MG/ACETAMINOPHEN 325 MG (PERCOCET 5 MG/325 MG )  1-2 TAB PO  Q4-6H   PRN: pain  Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 03:00 pm 



o AMLODIPINE (NORVASC )  5 MG PO  QD    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o LISINOPRIL (ZESTRIL )  40 MG PO  QD    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o DALTEPARIN SODIUM (FRAGMIN )  5000 UNITS SC  QD  <DI>   



o METOPROLOL SUCCINATE EXTENDED RELEASE (TOPROL XL )  400 MG PO  QD  <DI>   



o ISOSORBIDE MONONITRATE (SR) (IMDUR )  60 MG PO  QD    Last Dose Given:  10/24/96 at 08:00 am 



o GABAPENTIN (NEURONTIN )  100 MG PO  QHS   



All: benzocaine spray -> methgbemia



ROS: no neuro changes, weakness, slurred speech, etc

no cough, SOB

no chest pain, DOE

has been seen for penile d/c by Dr Regan, who did not think he had any active lower urinary infection

no diarrhea, vomiting



PE: 97.1   129/51   58  18  99ra

comfortable, NAD

Abd soft, NT, ND, well-healed midline incis with small dark scab, no fluctuance, no erythema, no discahrge

urostomy clean, pink; ostomy pink, viable, thin tan stool, guiaic neg



Labs: 

WBC                              15.3             H        (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              26.2             L        (41.0-53.0)    %

PLT                              375              H        (150-350)      th/cumm

Poly                             87               H        (40-70)        %



Sodium (Stat Lab)                128              L        (135-145)      mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)             5.0              H        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)              110              H        (100-108)      mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)                   13.8             L        (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)                   148              H        (8-25)         mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)            3.2              H        (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)               109                       (70-110)       mg/dl

LFTs, amylase, lipase, Lactic Acid all normal



Arterial pH                      7.27             L        (7.35-7.45)

Arterial PCO2                    23               L        (35-42)        mm/Hg

Arterial PO2                     113              H        (80-100)       mm/Hg

Osmolality                       324              H        (280-296)      mOsm/kg



Urine Sodium                     28                        (NOTDEF)       mmol/L

Urine Creatinine                 0.39                                     mg/ml

FENA 1.73%



UA-SED-RBC                       5-10                      (0-2)          /hpf

UA-SED-WBC                       20-50                     (0-2)          /hpf

UA-SED-Bacteria                  Moderate                  (NEG)          /hpf



CXR: clear lungs

CT (I-O+): mild R and moderate L hydro, mild perinephric fat stranding R>L, no abnormal pelvic fluid collections, no bowel thickening or abscess, some thickened distal sigmoid colon



A/P:  75yr man s/p sig colostomy for diversion, s/p IR drainage of postop collection, now with FTT, acute renal failure with FENA>1% and possible UTI, non-gap metabolic acidodis

--Check C-dif

--UTI Rx, directed towards the gram negatives he has grown in the past

--Agree with transfusion given CAD hx

--Routine ostomy care, ostomy nurse consult for any ostomy related questions. The ostomy itself appears very healthy, so I doubt the thickening represents hypoperfusion to the distal bowel

--Please contact BCH Surgical Service with any questions





______________________________                              

Earl N. Morrow, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-03-20

Date  3/20/98
Time 6:30am
Team B Admission Note

Patient: Keating, Frank
Medical Record Number: 483 29 78
Room: T123
Date of Admission: 3/19/98
Attending Physician: Peter Floyd (Pullman rounder)
Admitting Intern: Nathanael Guidry
Code Status: full

Source: Patient, Medical Record

ID/CC:
76yoM h/o CAD, COPD, DM, paraplegia p/w fever, SOB.

History of Present Illness:  
Patient reports that over the past 3-4d, he has had the constellation of Fever (to 101F), chills/shivers/myalgias/arthralgias/anorexia.  He has had a cough productive of white sputum.  He has also had nausea/dry heaves, unclear if there have been aspiration events.  

In the ED, VS: T98.5 BP80/40  150/106.  The patient was initially hypotensive, initially responded to IVF, but BPs dipped back to SBP<100.  WBC 14.0; he was Flu A +.  CXR showed a possible R mid-lung opacity.  He was given 4L IVF, ceftriaxone, azithromycin, 

Review of Systems:
Admits to SSCP-radiating to L side and back, nonpleuritc, nonpositional, similar to anginal equivalent; multiple episodes beginning at rest, lasting minutes.  Chronic palpitations, LH   dness, +/- nausea.  + PND, LE edema stable.  Chronic abdominal pain associated with colostomy.  
Patient denies the following symptoms.
CONSTIUTIONAL: f/c/r/sweats, anorexia/weight-loss 
HEENT: h/a/ear pain/sore throat/rhinorrhea
PULM:cough/SOB/DOE
CV:LOC
ABD: constipation/diarrhea/melena/BPR/ bloating
GU: dysuria/frequency/urgency
SKIN: rash
NEURO: unilateral weakness/paresthesia/dysphasia/dysphagia/visual change.

Past Medical/Surgical History:
Paraplegia
	2066 Thrown from amusement park ride     partial T4 paraplegia (confined to wheelchair, able to stand/xfer)
		ruptured bladder, S/p ileal loop conduit (2066)
			recurrent pyelonephritis, candidal infections
Complete laminectomy c3-c7, C5-6, c6-7 R foraminotomy in 2081
	Laminectomy L4-5, L5-s2 in 2081
11/2095 paraplegia at T8 after spinal cord infarction from cholesterol emboli after cardiac cath

CAD	
	2087 CABG x3
	2095: Cath     stent in L Cx artery
	1/96 NSTEMI
PVD
	S/p bilateral iliofemoral and renal artery stent 11/95
H/o TIA
	Bilateral CEA in 2081
CRI
	2/2 DM, bilateral RAS
Hypercholesterolemia
DM2
PUD
	12/95 EGD w/ nonbleeding gastric ulcers
COPD
Depression
Sacral decubitus ulcer
	2095 eroding into rectum
2096 c/b osteomyelitis requiring diverting colostomy
Chronic RTA
H/o significant epistaxis
Hearing loss
Insomnia

Received flu shot 11/97

H/o VRE, MRSA

S/p rod repair of tibial fx in 092

Allergies:
Amitryptiline 
Benzocaine

Medications:
Percocet 1tab 


Social History:
Lives with wife who is his primary care-taker.  Requires help w/ almost all ADLs, including transfers. 
TOB: remote 2ppdx60y
ETOH: remote, social
ILLICITS: none
Denies sick contacts, no travel.

Family History:
NC

Physical Examination:
GEN: 	appropriate, WA, NAD
VS: 
T
96
P
50
BP
90/40
RR
14
O2SAT
97%2L
	
HEENT: 	MMM, JVP 8cm.  
PULM: 	no focal dullness/consolidation.  Wheezes w/ moderate air movement.
BACK: 	stage 3 decub over sacrum, did NOT probe to bone. Granulation tissue, no infection/drainage.
CV: 	brady, reg, S1 and S2 normal, no murmurs
ABD: 	soft, NT/ND/NM/NHSM. BS active. Colostomy/ileostomy bags in place.
EXT: 	1+ edema 
NEURO:   
MS 	A&Ox3
SENS	up to T4 level.
SKIN:		no rash, good skin turgor

Data: 
NA        	133(L)    	134(L)    	135       	          	          
K         	4.1       	4.1       	4.8(T)    	          	          
CL        	107       	111(H)    	112(H)    	          	          
CO2       	17.7(L)   	15.6(L)   	14.8(L)   	          	          
BUN       	62(H)     	69(H)     	71(H)     	          	          
CRE       	2.3(H)    	2.2(H)    	2.2(H)    	          	          
GLU       	85        	137(H)    	106       	          	          

CA        	          	8.5       	          	          	          
PHOS      	          	4.3       	          	          	          
MG        	1.8       	1.9       	          	          	          
TBILI     	          	0.4       	          	          	          
DBILI     	          	0.0       	          	          	          
TP        	          	7.9       	          	          	          
ALB       	          	4.0       	          	          	          
GLOB      	          	3.9       	          	          	          
AMY       	          	43        	          	          	          
LIPS      	          	2.6       	          	          	          

ALT/SGPT  	19        	          	          	          	          
AST/SGOT  	55(H)     	          	          	          	          
ALKP      	142(H)    	          	          	          	          
TBILI     	0.4       	          	          	          	          
DBILI     	0.0       	          	          	          	          

CK        	711(H)    	          	          	          	          
CK-MB     	11.8(H)   	Negative  	Negative  	          	          
CKMBRI    	1.7       	          	          	          	          
TROP-I    	          	Negative  	Negative  	          	          
TROP-T    	0.41(H)   	          	          	          	          

WBC       	6.2       	14.0(H)   	          	          	          
RBC       	3.20(L)   	3.31(L)   	          	          	          
HGB       	9.9(L)    	10.2(L)   	          	          	          
HCT       	30.7(L)   	31.6(L)   	          	          	          
MCV       	96        	95        	          	          	          
MCH       	30.9      	30.9      	          	          	          
MCHC      	32.2      	32.4      	          	          	          
PLT       	275       	313       	          	          	          
RDW       	14.8(H)   	14.7(H)   	          	          	          
DIFFR     	          	Received  	          	          	          
METHOD    	          	Auto      	          	          	          
%NEUT     	          	87(H)     	          	          	          
%LYMPH    	          	10(L)     	          	          	          
%MONO     	          	3(L)      	          	          	          
%EOS      	          	0         	          	          	          
%BASO     	          	0         	          	          	          
ANEUT     	          	12.30(H)  	          	          	          
ALYMP     	          	1.34      	          	          	          
AMONS     	          	0.37      	          	          	          
AEOSN     	          	0.01(L)   	          	          	          
ABASOP    	          	0.02      	          	          	          
ANISO     	          	None      	          	          	          
HYPO      	          	1+(H)     	          	          	          
MACRO     	          	None      	          	          	          
MICRO     	          	None      	          	          	          

PT        	14.7(H)   	          	          	          	          
PT-INR    	1.4       	          	          	          	          

UA-GLUC   	Negative  	          	          	          	          
UA-KET    	Negative  	          	          	          	          
UA-SPGR   	1.015     	          	          	          	          
UA-BLD    	2+        	          	          	          	          
UA-PH     	6.5       	          	          	          	          
UA-PROT   	3+        	          	          	          	          
UA-NIT    	Negative  	          	          	          	          
UA-WBC    	2+        	          	          	          	          
MIC-SED   	Completed 	          	          	          	          
HCAST     	None      	          	          	          	          
UAS-RBC   	5-10      	          	          	          	          
UAS-WBC   	50-100    	          	          	          	          
UAS-BACT  	Many      	          	          	          	          
UAS-SQHI  	Few       	          	          	          	          

EKG Sinus brady, TWI aVL. No change from previous.
CXR patchy opacity in the R mid-lung.


Impression/Plan: 
76yoM h/o paraplegia, p/w fever, cough.  Likely flu, +/- PNA (CXR not that impressive).  COPD flare on top of flu.  Will cover with antibiotics, treat for COPD flare.  Patient has been complaining of recent C/P, similar to anginal equivalent.  Small troponin leak, likely in setting of hypovolemic hypotension.

HoTN: c/w aggressive fluid resuscitation.  Patient clinically appears well.
	-IVF for now.
	-hold norvasc, imdur. Low dose lopressor for now.
	-if persistent hypotension, cort stim, consider more aggressive intervention.
COUGH: flu + COPD +/- PNA.  5d into flu symptoms, will not treat w/ anti-viral medication.  Will treat for COPD flare, as well as CAP coverage.
	-ceftriaxone/azithromycin x 7 days
	-prednisone taper 40mg  0mg over 12 days. Standing nebs.
CHEST PAIN: small troponin leak, likely demand in setting of hypovolemic hypotension.
	-keep O2 sats 100%, HCT>30 (T&S to be sent)
	-ASA, lopressor, statin, plavix
ARF: baseline Cr 1.5, now >2.  suspect some amount of ATN.
	-did not correct after volume resuscitation
	-urine lytes, spin urine.
NON-AG ACIDOSIS: related to ileostomy?
	-correcting w/ IVF.
	-if not back to baseline after resuscitation, initate work-up.
PAIN: 
	-home percocet, neurontin.
DECUBITIS ULCER: stage 3
	-CNS for appropriate therapeutic surface.
FEN: low fat/cholesterol, no added salt, potassium 2g.
PROPHY: nexium, heparin sc.
CODE: FULL 
DISPO: to home when ready.
									
							Nathanael Guidry, MD
Pager: #32564




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>