<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2078-12-13

 
Vascular Surgery Admit H+P

Name:  Nathan Vieira
Medical Record:  #0666729
Date of Evaluation:  12/13/78
Attending:  Dr. Atwood

CC:  L leg/foot pain

History of Present Illness: Pt is a 71 yo M s/p bilateral fem-pop BPG   s by Dr. Atwood who had been previously asymptomatic walking up to five miles without claudication, after his R BPG in Feb and L BPG in April of this year.  He in fact saw Dr. Atwood on 11/10 and had a good DP pulse at that time on the left.  However, one week ago he sat on the floor for ~3 hours doing electrical work, flexed at the hip and slightly flexed at the knee, and that night he began to have calf and dorsal foot pain on the L side.  This lasted for ~24 hours.  He went to his PCP who was concerned that he may have compromised his graft given he had a diminished DP pulse on the L, and also had developed an area of erythema on the L lateral calf which the PCP suspected to be cellulitis.  He was prescribed keflex by his PCP which he started on 12/10, and the patient reports his erythema has improved since starting the abx.  He then revisited Dr. Atwood who found diminished trace DP pulse on the L, possibly secondary to graft kinking and/or thrombosis, and advised the patient to be admitted today for likely angiogram and possible thrombolysis in the AM.  On ROS he has had no F/C/N/V/D/abd pain/back pain.

Past Medical History: 	
Diabetes, PVD, CAD s/p PTCA ,HTN, Dyslipidemia, Urinary retention from hypotonic bladder ( self cath's) and abx prophylaxis, Former smoker, GERD, psoriasis s/p phototx 
 
Past Surgical History: 	
    	Bilateral femoral Endarterectomies
	L fem-pop BPG PTFE 4/8/78 	
    	SFA Angioplasty -  Dr Atwood  1/15/78  
 	Right Fem pop BPG  with 6mm TFE Ring  2/9/78 Dr Henry Atwood 
	Left Shoulder surg  
          	Cystoscopy TUR	 

Allergies: 	NKDA
Medications:  
	Lipitor 20 qpm
Zetia 10mg qpm
ASA 81 qam
Altace 10 qam
Atenolol 50 qam
Glyburide 2.5mg BID
Nitrofurantoin 50mg qd
Taclonex 60mg cream
Keflex 500 qid x 7 days (12/10- )

Physical Exam: T=98.5 P=72 SR  Bp=117/61 RR=  97% RA
 
General: 	WDWN NAD
Neck: 	supple	Carotids:	no bruits
Lungs: 		CTAB
CV:		RRR S1 S2
Abd:	soft NTND +BS, no masses	Bruits: none
Pulses: 		
		Carotids	L: 2+	R: 2+
Radial 		L: 2+	R: 2+	
		Femoral	L: 2+	R: 2+
		Pop		L: NP	R: NP
DP 		L: Dopplerable	R: Dopplerable
		PT 		L: Not Dopplerable	R: Dopplerable	 
		Grafts		L: Dopplerable	R: Dopplerable
Wound:	L lateral thigh small 3x4 area of erythema, mildly tender, nonindurated.

Recent studies:
Labs:  
Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units

Plasma Sodium                    140                       (135-145)      mmol/L
Plasma Potassium                 4.1                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L
Plasma Chloride                  105                       (100-108)      mmol/L
Plasma Carbon Dioxide            27.2                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L
Calcium                          9.3                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       3.0                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        1.5                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L
Plasma Urea Nitrogen             16                        (8-25)         mg/dl
Plasma Creatinine                1.0                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl
Plasma Glucose                   278              H        (70-110)       mg/dl
Total Protein                    7.4                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl
Albumin                          4.0                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl
Globulin                         3.4                       (2.6-4.1)      g/dl
Direct Bilirubin                 0.1                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl
Total Bilirubin                  0.4                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl
Alkaline Phosphatase             122              H        (45-115)       U/L
Transaminase-SGPT                32                        (10-55)        U/L
Amylase                          46                        (3-100)        units/L
Lipase                           2.3                       (1.3-6.0)      U/dl
Transaminase-SGOT                28                        (10-40)        U/L

WBC                              7.0                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              36.6             L        (41.0-53.0)    %
HGB                              13.8                      (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl
RBC                              4.12             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm
PLT                              238                       (150-350)      th/cumm
MCV                              89                        (80-100)       fl
MCH                              33.5                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc
MCHC                             37.7             H        (31.0-37.0)    g/dl
RDW                              13.1                      (11.5-14.5)    %
DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED
Diff Method                      PEND

PT                               12.8                      (10.3-13.2)    sec
PT-INR                           1.1
APTT                             27.0                      (22.1-34.0)    sec


Impression:  71 yo M s/p bilateral fem-pop BPG   s who now presents with new LLE pain likely secondary to graft kinking and/or thrombosis.

Recommendations:
OR in AM for angiogram and possible LLE thrombolysis.
Unasyn IV for ?cellulitis
Preop labs as above, U/A pending.
EKG: 12/13 WNL, L axis deviation.
CXR: 12/13 clear BL.
Type and Screen: 12/13 BB sample received.
NPO p MN, IVF p MN
Pt consented for procedure, consent in chart.
Mucomyst/bicarb protocol for renal protection prior to angio.
Patient discussed with Dr. Vernon Barrera, vascular fellow.


_________________________________________
Deborah Ash, Vascular Surgery Junior Resident, Pager 07747





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-05-21





Vascular Surgery Admission Note


Patient Name:  Vieira, Nathan
MRN:  0666729
Date and Time: 5/21/2080 8:15 PM
Attending: Dr. Atwood
Fellow: Dr. Godfrey
Senior Resident: Dr. Sanders
Junior Resident: Dr. Alford 48167


Reason for consult: 
Preadmit for angio 5/22/80


HPI:  Pt is a 73yo M known to Dr. Atwood s/p multiple LE revascularization procedures. He presented to Dr. Atwood c/o new onset RLE pain, numbness, and color change, similar to previous episodes of graft thrombosis. He was evaluated at the time and a plan made for angiography and intervention. His INR was 2.9, so it was allowed to drift down and he was scheduled for a procedure on 5/22/80. He is admitted today for preoperative evaluation, anticoagulation, and renal protection.


PMHx/PSHx:
DM
PVD
LLE angio, thrombectomy 12/78
L fem-pop BPG 4/78
R fem-pop BPG 2/78
RLE angio 1/78
CAD s/p PTCA
HTN
Hyperlipidemia
Urinary retention from hypotonic bladder &#8211; self caths, abx prophylaxis, s/p cytstoscopy/TUR
GERD
Psoriasis
L shoulder surgery


Meds: 
Lipitor 20 qpm
Zetia 10mg qpm
ASA 81 qam
Altace 10 qam
Atenolol 50 qam
Glyburide 2.5mg BID
Nitrofurantoin 50mg qd
Taclonex 60mg cream


All:  
NKDA


PE:   
NAD
CTAB
RRR
Soft, ND, NT, no abdominal bruits
LE: no edema bilaterally
Foot:      R: White great toe with dry gangrene through the first interphalangeal joint.  Mild erethema proximally.
                L: erythema and mild color change of distal toes, a change from pt&#8217;s baseline, (+) cap refill, no palpable pulses


                Rad        Fem        Pop         DP           PT
R             2+           2+           none       none       none                                       
L             2+           2+           none       1+           1+           


LABS:  
WBC                              9.2                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              39.2             L        (41.0-53.0)    %
HGB                              13.4             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl
PLT                              222                       (150-400)      th/cumm


PT                               12.4                      (10.3-13.2)    sec
PT-INR                           1.1
APTT                             25.3                      (22.1-34.0)    sec


Plasma Sodium                    142                       (135-145)      mmol/L
Plasma Potassium                 4.5                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L
Plasma Chloride                  104                       (100-108)      mmol/L
Plasma Carbon Dioxide            26.8                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L
Plasma Urea Nitrogen             17                        (8-25)         mg/dl
Plasma Creatinine                1.19                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl     
Plasma Glucose                   147              H        (70-110)       mg/dl


Calcium                          9.8                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       2.6                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        1.4                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L


STUDIES:
CXR: Low lung volumes.  No evidence of acute cardiopulmonary disease.


A/P:
73yo M preadmission for renal protection and OR for angio 5/22
-          NPO p MN, IVF
-          Renal protection protocol
-          Heparin gtt
-          Consent in chart


________________________________
Tessa Alford, MD, PhD 48167
RCH Surgery





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-07-11


Vascular Surgery Admission Note
 




Patient Name: Vieira, Nathan
MRN: 0666729
Date and Time: 7/11/2080 8:00 PM
Attending: Henry C. Atwood, M.D.
Fellow: Vincent Gregory, M.D.
Junior: Donovan J. Betty Barber, M.D.


Admitted for Left Leg Wound debridement 


HPI: 
Mr. Nathan Vieira is a 73yo M with PMH significant for DM2,  CAD, HTN, hyperlipidemia, hypotonic bladder GERD, psoriasis,  well known in the vascular service for PVD, s/p  LLE angio, thrombectomy 12/78, L fem-pop BPG 4/78, R fem-pop BPG 2/78, RLE angio 1/78 most recently on may LE revascularization procedures,  Popliteal exploration with graft thrombectomy, aortoiliac angiogram, left lower extremity angiogram, angioplasty of posterior tibial artery, angioplasty tibioperoneal trunk and distal anastomosis of bypass graft, stent placement for stenosis of proximal graft. 
Mr. Vieira presented to Dr. Atwood clinic 
today with persistent wound collection in the below knee popliteal incision. He noticed a lump approximately 3 weeks ago, underwent incision and drainage with wick placement and started a course of PO antibiotics. This has continued to drain serosanguinous fluid, apparently the overall induration and erythema with some additional fluid under moderate pressure was released. He has been seen daily by a visiting nurse and she can do the dressing, replacing the wick, and putting a sterile absorbent dressing on top of this. We will see him again in another week.
  He is on coumadin, last dose 3.5 last night. 

Denies fevers chills, SOB, cough.


PMHx/PSHx:
DM
PVD
LLE angio, thrombectomy 12/78
L fem-pop BPG 4/78
R fem-pop BPG 2/78
RLE angio 1/78
CAD s/p PTCA
HTN
Hyperlipidemia
Urinary retention from hypotonic bladder - self caths, abx prophylaxis, s/p cytstoscopy/TUR
GERD
Psoriasis
L shoulder surgery


Meds: 
Lipitor 20 qpm
Zetia 10mg qpm
ASA 81 qam
Altace 10 qam
Atenolol 50 qam
Glyburide 10 mg BID
Nitrofurantoin 50mg qd
coumadin 3.5 mg QD


All: 
NKDA


PE: 
Temp:  97.7      HR  76        BP  150/62       RR  16        100^% O2 Sat  
Gen: Awake, alet, oriented, NAD
Resp: CTAB
CV: RRR
Adomen-Soft, ND, NT, no abdominal bruits
Ext no edema bilaterally
LLE wound collection  in the below knee popliteal incision, draining purulent fluid. surrounding erythema. The overall 

Foot: R: Mild erethema proximally.
L: erythema and mild color change of distal toes, a change from pt's baseline, (+) cap refill, no palpable pulses
Rad Fem Pop DP PT
R 2+ 2+ none none none 
L 2+ 2+ none 1+ 1+ 


A/P:
73yo M with PMH significant for DM2,  CAD, HTN, hyperlipidemia, hypotonic bladder GERD, psoriasis,  well known in the vascular service for PVD, s/p  LLE angio, thrombectomy 12/78, L fem-pop BPG 4/78, R fem-pop BPG 2/78, RLE angio 1/78 most recently on may LE revascularization procedures,  Popliteal exploration with graft thrombectomy, aortoiliac angiogram, left lower extremity angiogram, angioplasty of posterior tibial artery, angioplasty tibioperoneal trunk and distal anastomosis of bypass graft, stent placement for stenosis of proximal graft.  
Mr. Vieira presented to Dr. Atwood clinic 
today with persistent wound collection in the below knee popliteal incision.
Admitted for  Left Leg Wound debridement.


- NPO p MN, IVF
-CBC/INR, PTT
-EKG
-Electrolytes
-CXR 
-UA
- Consent obtained an placed in chart


Plan has been discussed with Vascular Fellow Dr. Gregory.


Donovan J. Betty Barber, M.D.
PGY-2
Vascular Surgery.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-03-08


















                
 


Vascular Surgery

History and Physical

________________________________________________________________________


Attending: Godfrey, Kelley
Fellow: Godfrey, Stanley
Junior: Orosco, Vincent I.
  
Patient: Vieira, Nathan B.
MRN: 0666729
Date: 3/8/2081


HPI: This is a 74 y.o. M with h.o CAD and PVD s/p bilateral lower extremity bypass grafting procedures complicated by a thrombus in the L side of the iliac portion of the graft for which he has been on coumadin. In anticipation for a follow-up cardiac catheterization (recent episodes of shortness of breath), his coumadin was held since Thursday (3/6/2081). Then on 3/7/2081, he was noted by medical staff to have a slightly cool L lower extremity. The patient states that it has felt this way with some intermittent pain at rest for the last several weeks. He complained of both numbness and pain, and he was started on a heparin drip when his INR fell to less than 2.0. Dr. Atwood who did his initial operation was contacted and he was arranged for transfer to RCH. He arrives today (3/8/2081) on a heparin drip.



PHMx: 


DM (insulin-dependent)
CAD (recent echo showed EF 55-60% but inferior wall infarct in 9/2080; stress test in 11/2080 showed no reversible ischemia)
PVD
Bladder atony
Psoriasis
HTN
HL


PSHx: 


R femoral to below-knee popliteal bypass graft with 6-mm PTFE ring (2/2078)
L femoral below-knee popliteal bypass graft with 6-mm PTFE (4/2078)
Open thrombectomy femoral-popliteal bypass graft (12/2078)
Left femoral artery cutdown, graft thrombectomy, patch angioplasty of common femoral artery, patch angioplasty of proximal bypass graft, angiogram of left lower extremity, balloon angioplasty of posterior tibial artery, balloon angioplasty of peroneal artery, balloon angioplasty of tibioperoneal artery with placement of balloon expandable stent (5/2080)
Popliteal exploration with graft thrombectomy. stent placement for stenosis of proximal graft (5/2080)
Incision and drainage and VAC dressing to left lower extremity wound x 2 (7/2080)


Medications:

Lasix 40 IV BID
Coumadin 3 mg QD
Enalapril 5 mg BID
Coreg 3.125 BID
ASA 81 QD
Lipitor 20 QD
Glyburide 10 BID
Zocor 40 QHS
Lantus insulin 30 U QHS and sliding scale
MVI
Clonazepam PRN
Tylenol PRN
Colace 100 BID PRN
Soriatane CK 250 mg TID (for psoriasis)
Bactroban ointment to LLE


Allergies: Adhesive tape


Family Hx: Noncontributory


Social Hx: Lives at home.


ROS: As per HPI.


Physical Exam:

Vitals:             T 99.4, HR 87, BP 117/59, RR 18, 100% on RA
GEN:              Well-appearing in NAD, A&amp;Ox3
HEENT:         NC/AT, PERRL, EOMI, no jaundice
CV:                 RRR, no M/R/G
PULM:           CTAB
ABD:              Soft, NT/ND, +BS
EXT:              L foot slightly cooler than R foot, well-healed medial knee incision on LLE, no open wounds
NEURO:        Non-focal, moving all extremities
PULSES:       Carotids 2+, no bruits
                        Radials 2+
                        Femorals 2+
                        Politeals NP
                        PTs NP
                        DPs NP
                                                                                    
Laboratory Studies: Pending


Imaging: CXR pending


EKG: Pending


Impression: 74 y.o. M with HTN, PVD, HL, DM who presents several days after stopping coumadin for a planned cardiac catheterization with cold, pulseless LLE consistent with acute on chronic thrombosis of L femoral to below-the-knee bypass graft.



Plan:


Routine admission labs
Continue heparin gtt (PTT goal 60-80)
F/U INR/creatinine
Mucomyst
Gentle fluids
CTA angiogram with distal runoff of B/L lower extremities






______________________________
Vincent I. Orosco, M.D.  
PGY2 General Surgery
Pager #46717


Case discussed with Stanley Godfrey, M.D., vascular fellow.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-03-21


















 





Plastic Surgery Consult Note


Chief PRS:  Dr. Anthony Giles
Senior PRS:  Dr. Dawn Julian
Junior resident: Dr. Oneida Norwood


Date: 3/21/2081


Patient Name:  Vieira, Nathan
MRN: 0666729



CC: 
Consult for radial artery harvest



HPI:  74 RHD M with coronary artery disease, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, Type II DM, peripheral arterial disease and prior cigarette abuse  admitted to the Vascular Surgery service on 3/8 with critical limb ischemia. On 03/09/2081, he underwent peroneal and popliteal angioplasty with thrombolysis of the femoral-popliteal bypass graft and stenting of the proximal anastomosis by Dr. Godfrey.  This was complicated by a postoperative MI. 03/15/2081, cardiac catheterization 
is significant for left main and multivessel coronary artery disease, and CABG was planned.  Of note, his cath was complicated by pseudoaneurysm of the right brachial artery at the point of access.   He was evaluated by SonoSite by the cardiac surgical PA, and was found to have no available venous conduit secondary to his multiple lower extremity procedures.  We are therefore consulted for radial artery harvest. 



PMH:  
CAD-remote, silent myocardial infarction 

Hypertension

Hyperlipidemia

Diabetes Mellitus Type II

Peripheral Neuropathy

Peripheral Arterial Disease-S/P (R) femoral to below knee popliteal BPG with PTFE, 02/2078

-S/P (L) femoral to below knee popliteal BPG with PTFE, 04/2078 

-S/P (L) open thrombectomy femoral-popliteal BPG, 12/2078

-S/P (L) femoral artery cutdown, graft thrombecomy, patch angioplasty of CFA, patch angioplasty of proximal BPG, angiogram of LLE, balloon angioplasty of posterior tibial artery, balloon angioplasty of peronral artery, balloon angioplasty of tibioperoneal artery with placement of stent, 05/2080

-S/P (L) popliteal exploration with graft thrombectomy and stent placement of proximal graft, 05/2080

-precedure c/b LLE MRSA requiring I&amp;D and VAC dressing x 2, 07/2080

Prostate Cancer

Neurogenic Bladder

Psoriasis

Shoulder Surgery-S/P (L)

Tonsillectomy





MEDS: 
Acetaminophen (tylenol )  325-650 MG PO Q6H

Acetylcysteine 20%(200 mg/ml) 1200 MG PO BID

Acetylsalicylic acid (aspirin)  325 MG PO DAILY

Captopril 6.25 MG PO TID

Carvedilol (coreg)  3.125 MG PO BID

Collagenase (santyl ) 1 APPLICATION TOP TID

Digoxin 0.25 MG IV Q6H

Docusate sodium (colace ) 100 MG PO BID

Furosemide (lasix ) 60 MG PO BID

Heparin cardiac sliding scale iv 500-1500 Units/Hr IV CONTINUOUS INFUSION 

Insulin aspart (novolog ) 14 UNITS     SC QPM BEFORE SUPPER

Insulin aspart (novolog ) 15 UNITS     SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST

Insulin aspart (novolog ) Sliding Scale SC TID AC

Insulin nph human 20 UNITS     SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST

Nitroglycerin paste 2% (nitrol paste ) 1 INCHES TOP Q4H

Sennosides (senna tablets ) 2 TAB PO Q12H

Simvastatin (zocor ) 40 MG PO DAILY

Vancomycin hcl (vancocin hcl ) 1000 MG IV BID





ALL:  Adhesive tape (Rash)
  
Physical Exam:
General:  
Alert, pleasant, NAD
RUE:  Palpable 2+ radial pulse, weakly dopplerable ulnar pulse.  Allen&#8217;s test: prior to compression of radial artery, SpO2 100%.  During compression, signal lost by probe within seconds.  Upon release, signal regained, SpO2 again 100%.   Localized edema of upper arm,  no obvious pulsatile mass.
LUE:  Well-healed scar anterior shoulder from prior surgery.  Palpable 2+ radial, 1+  ulnar pulses.  Allen&#8217;s test:  prior to compression of radial artery, SpO2 99%.  Remained 99% with compression of radial artery X2 minutes.  Clinical Allen&#8217;s test:  somewhat sluggish (5-6 seconds) pinking up of the exsanguinated hand upon release of the ulnar artery.




Labs/studies:



WBC                              6.3                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              32.4             L        (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              10.7             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              4.04             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              245                       (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              80                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              26.5                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             33.0                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              16.1             H        (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               14.3             H        (10.3-13.2)    sec

PT-INR                           1.3

APTT                             75.4             H        (21.0-33.0)    sec





Plasma Sodium                    137                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.3                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  103                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            22.9             L        (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 11                        (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          9.1                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       4.2                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             11                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.05                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             &gt;60                                      mL/min/1.73m2



Assessment: 74 M with PVD and recent MI, preop for CABG sometime next week.  His left radial artery may be safe to use for conduit. His right is not usable. 


Recs:
-          Preop per Cardiac Surgery Service
-          Patient to be seen by Dr. Queen Olivares, Plastic Surgery Fellow.  She will not be available for radial artery harvest on Thursday of next week.




Discussed with Dr. Queen Olivares, Plastic Surgery Fellow. 

__________________________

Oneida Norwood MD, PGY-2

Resident in General Surgery

Pager-56956

 
Patient seen and examined. Addendum to above note on 3/22/81:
 
ROS: 
Denies HA, visual change
Denies CP, SOB, palpitations
Denies n/v, GI upset
Denies h/o seizures
Currently has LLE wound (from recent procedure)
States is R. handed, likes to golf, states hands are always cold and sometimes turn "blue"-no pain associatd w/ symptoms
Denies new onset of UE/LE weakness
 
Plan:
Allen's test on RUE is abnormal and is consistent with a dominant radial artery, however, left appears to be fine.
Will likely attempt harvest of LUE radial artery-will retest Allen's test intraop as welll
Please avoid any additional needle sticks or blood draws from the LUE
Please let the plastic team know ASAP of the surgery date so that our schedule can be coordinated with the CABG surgery



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>