<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2092-12-27

MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
039 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                12-27-92
 
 
HPI: Kadeem Vicente comes in today for a follow-up office visit.  The 
patient was seen by me approximately one month ago as a new patient and 
whose primary medical concerns a history of coronary artery disease, for 
which he suffered a "silent heart attack" many years ago, a history of 
benign prostatic hypertrophy, as well as hypertension and GERD.  As it 
turns out, the patient had been on Zantac for many, many years, the 
beneficial effects of which were unknown.  We had decided as of our last 
meeting to stop this drug and find out if he became symptomatic.  The 
patient reports today that he is not symptomatic, and thus we will 
continue to discontinue this medicine.  At this point, the patient does 
not need the addition of a proton pump inhibitor, such as Prilosec.  
With regard to the patient's symptoms of benign prostatic hypertrophy, 
the patient said that he only has taken one dose of the Hytrin, since he 
wanted to use up all his Minipress, which he tool up until 2 nights ago.  
Thus it is too early to assess the efficacy of this medication.  It is 
noted that his blood pressure was 152/74, which is better than it was 
the last time he was here, which the systolic range was 160-170 and 
diastolic was 80-90.  The patient reports no new symptomatology other 
than occasional fatigue, from which he will have to rest.  The patient 
has no symptoms of congestive heart failure, no shortness of breath, no 
ankle edema, no JVD by observation, and his laboratory results are 
remarkably normal, given his medical complaints.  The patient's 
cholesterol is 190 with a slightly above average triglycerides.  Review 
of systems otherwise negative.
 
Physical exam is not performed at this time.  Blood pressure was 152/76 
on the right, 152/76 on the left, temperature was 96.8, respirations 20 
and unlabored, and pulse was 70.
 
ASSESSMENT/PLAN: This is a 75 year old man with multiple medical 
problems coming in for follow-up.
1.   Hypertension - the patient will stay on his Zestril and will use 
     Hytrin now, both for his hypertension, as well as benign prostatic 
     hypertrophy.  The patient does speak of some nocturnal dribbling, 
     and he said he also has urge incontinence, particularly while 
     standing.  The patient was told that after a trial of Hytrin, which 
     hopefully can help with his symptoms of benign prostatic 
     hypertrophy, that this urge incontinency will also be helped.  If 
     the patient's symptoms continue beyond this, he will be referred to 
     Urology for possible TUNA procedure.
 
2.   BPH - please see above.  The patient will stay on Hytrin for now.
 
3.   ? coronary artery disease - the patient's cholesterol is 190 with a 
     slightly above average triglycerides, which is more than acceptable 
     for this gentleman.  I do not have an HDL in which to judge his 
     ratio, but I was by the patient before that it runs in the high 40s 
     MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
476 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                12-27-92
PAGE 2
 
     or low 50s.  Therefore this will be an acceptable ratio without 
     therapy.  I will get a fasting lipid on the patient probably in 
     about 6 months, and if there is any derangement in his profile, he 
     will be put on an antilipid drug.
 
4.   GI - at this point his GERD symptoms have not returned, and what I 
     will attempt to do is to keep him off his H2 blockers at this 
     point.  Should his symptoms return, the patient most likely will be 
     placed on Prilosec.
 
I will seen him in one month for follow-up, primarily for evaluation of 
his use of Hytrin.
 
 
______________________________
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
 
KT:TR:9254
DD:12-27-92  
DT:01-01-93
DV:12-27-92
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-03-07

MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
593 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                3-6-93
 
 
 
HPI:  Kadeem Vicente comes in today for follow up office visit.  The patient 
is seen primarily for follow up regarding his history of hypertension, 
coronary artery disease (the patient is status post inferior wall MI), 
benign prostatic hypertrophy and to a much lesser extent osteoarthritis.  
The patient is also followed GERD-like symptoms.  With regard to the 
latter, the patient notes that since he has been off the Zantac, he 
initially saw no change in his ability to handle foods; however, he now 
notes that he is starting to get some reflux and feels slightly 
uncomfortable with this.  He denies chest pain per se and any symptoms 
pertinent to cardiovascular disease, such as chest heaviness, shortness 
of breath, diaphoresis, nausea.  The patient knows the foods that give 
him this type of reaction, such as tomato based sauces and tries to 
avoid them as much as possible.  The patient is asking me about Prilosec 
which he recently read in the Journal and was wandering whether this 
would be a suitable alternative to H2 blockers (Patient had been on H2 
blockers for many years without a trial off of them, which a reason that 
we stopped his H2 blocker therapy recently).  
 
With regard to the patient's symptoms of benign prostatic hypertrophy, 
the patient says that these have almost completely resolved on the 4 mg 
of Hytrin and which he will continue taking.  The patient does remain on 
Zestril for his hypertension as well as the Hytrin and the blood 
pressure gotten by the nurse today was 150/80 and repeated by me 20 
minutes later was 130/74. 
 
The patient reports being otherwise well, no new symptoms.  No positive 
review of systems.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAM:  Was not performed.  Vitals:  Blood pressure taken by me 
was 130/74 in the right, 130/74 in the left, temperature was 98.8, 
respirations 20, unlabored and pulse was 80.  
 
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  75 year old man with multiple medical concerns 
comes in for follow up.
1.   Hypertension.  The patient will stay on his Zestril, once a day as 
     well as his Hytrin, which he uses also for BPH.  His blood pressure 
     appears to be well controlled on this regimen.  One of the issues 
     would be whether or not the patient should be on a beta-blocker.  
     The patient verbally has a history of "a silent heart attack"  and 
     there is evidence of an inferior wall MI and this is certainly an 
     option we will consider in the future, although I would not add a 
     third anti-hypertensive regimen and would most likely replace his 
     Zestril with a beta-blocker.
2.   GERD.  The patient will be given a prescription for Prilosec 20 mg 
     to be taken at bedtime.  The patient was told that this would not 
     MARTHA JEFFERSON HOSPITAL
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
004 Will St                           Vicente, Kadeem
Sandpoint, MI 58543                             CK759182
(033) 250-1408                                3-6-93
Page 2
 
 
     be long term therapy but that we can do this for the next 2-3 
     months, although he should be able to experience relief almost 
     immediately.  The patient does have a known hiatal hernia, which 
     may also contribute to his symptoms of chronic reflux.
3.   BPH - The patient will stay on his 4 mg of Hytrin, which appears to 
     be working quite well.  The patient notes that there is less 
     dribbling, less nocturnal urination.  The patient does take Lasix 
     20 mg once a day for congestive heart failure and did not have any 
     difficulty with urination after he takes the diuretic.  
4.   Insomnia.  The patient will stay on his Ambien 10 mg which he takes 
     on a q.h.s. basis.  The patient was formerly on Amitriptyline but 
     was told that the secondary side effects which can include EKG 
     changes and at this point tells me that the Ambien works and he 
     would like to stay on this.  Patient has enough to last until I see 
     him next time.
 
I will thus see the patient in 3 months for a fasting lipid (The 
patient's lipid profile thus far has been acceptable.   The cholesterol 
is 190 and an acceptable triglyceride; however, I do want to assess the 
patient's LDL and HDL before making any decisions with regard to 
treatment.  
 
 
 
______________________________
Stephen A.N. Xayachack, M.D.
 
JG:WQ:6672
DD:3-7-93 
DT:3-7-93 
DV:3-6-93
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-12-12

SPENCER STATE HOSPITAL
SPENCER Internal Medicine Associates
100 Burrit St                             Vicente, Kadeem
Fayetteville, MI  31474                             94859580
                                              12-18-93
 
 
 
HPI:  Mr. Vicente returns for follow-up.  He is status post TURP by Dr. 
Nixon.  He is having a little bit of incontinence, but Dr. Nixon 
thinks that this should get better.
 
We will have to recheck his platelets, which have been in the 120 to 145 
range.  We also will look back at his echocardiogram, which is showing 
that he had slight mitral and tricuspid regurgitation as well as mildly 
dilated LV with inferior hypokinesis.  He has remained on digoxin status 
post his myocardial infarction.
 
We want to recheck his cholesterol today.  We also have been concerned 
that he has been a little depressed but mostly because he is concerned 
about his wife's situation with breast cancer.  We had a long discussion 
about this.
 
Physical Examination:  On physical examination, his weight is 250 lbs.  
His blood pressure was 178/80.  The follow-up was 170/80.  His neck was 
supple.  Chest was clear to both percussion and auscultation.  Cardiac 
exam was regularly regular with no murmurs, gallops or rubs.  Abdomen 
was soft and nontender with no hepatosplenomegaly.  Extremities were 
clear of cyanosis, clubbing or edema.  Rectal tone was normal and guaiac 
negative.
 
Laboratory Data:  His hematocrit was 39.9.  Platelets were within normal 
limits.  White count is 8.3.  Digoxin is 0.9.  Lytes are within normal 
limits.  
 
Assessment and Plan:
1.   Status post TURP.  He appears to be recovering well.  He has had 
     slight incontinence, but I suspect this will pass.
2.   Thrombocytopenia.  This was very relative.  It now appears to have 
     resolved.
3.   Coronary artery disease.  As he recovers from his TURP, I question 
     whether it might be reasonable to go ahead and reexercise him.  At 
     the present time, he is quite stable on an aspirin, digoxin and 
     Lasix.  However, it may be that he would benefit from further 
     treatment with anti-anginals.
4.   Hypercholesterolemia.  This has been well-controlled recently.  His 
     last cholesterol was 168 in August of 2093.
5.   Depression.  He continues on Ambien.  He has some discretion about 
     his wife's breast cancer, and he appears to have some of his 
     uncertainty resolved.    
 
_________________________
Miles Echeverria, M.D.                                                      
 
GH:VO:0860/DD:12-18-93/DT:12-20-93/DV:12-18-93                          
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-06-12

June 12, 2094
 
 
Miles Echeverria, M.D.
Spencer Internal Medicine Associates
Spencer State Hospital
16 Burrit St
Fayetteville, MI  31474
 
RE:  Vicente, Kadeem F.
     MRN: 948-59-58-0
 
Dear Miles:
 
I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Vicente in Cardiovascular Care today.  This lovely 77-year old man has had past medical
history notable for coronary artery disease, hypertension, benign
prostatic hypertrophy, depression, insomnia, osteoarthritis status
post total knee replacement.
 
He presents today because of a recent exacerbation of symptomatic
coronary artery disease.  His history of coronary artery disease
begins with his presentation following his total knee replacement
in June of 2091.  In 10/91 he had an episode of profound weakness
and sat down.  He had no clear substernal chest pressure, loss of
consciousness or edema.  Workup at that time included a thallium
test which did not clearly demonstrate ischemia and an
echocardiogram with an ejection fraction of 50%.  He began therapy
at that point in time with aspirin, niacin, vitamin E, Lasix,
Zestril, Zantac, Minipress, Amitriptyline, and Digoxin.  He had
been free of exertional neck, chest, arm and jaw pain, paroxysmal
nocturnal dyspnea, orthopnea, palpitations, claudication and TIA
until this past spring.  He actually had done very well with risk
factor reduction including completing cardiac rehab at MJH and
following a stringent weight reduction program and decreasing his
weight.  In March of 2094 he began noticing that when he was going
up the 19 steps in his house he began having mid-sternal chest
discomfort and some dyspnea at the top of the stairs.  He stopped
working with the physiotherapist at that point and was initiated on
nitrate therapy.  Since that time he has noted that he has had
significant decrease in symptoms and over the past week has
actually had no need to take sublingual nitroglycerine and has been
taking the full flight of stairs without difficulty.  He does note
fatigue and insomnia such that he is sleeping only 2 to 3 hours a
night.  He does continue to be free of paroxysmal nocturnal
dyspnea, orthopnea, palpitations or lightheadedness.
 
Medical regimen includes Ambien, Paxil, Isordil 20 t.i.d.,
Atenolol, Digoxin, Zantac and aspirin.  He has no known drug
allergies.
 
On physical exam blood pressure when he first arrived at Clinic was
noted to be 220/100.  At the present time it is 180/100 with a
Vicente, Kadeem F.
MRN: 948-59-58-0
June 12, 2094
Page Two
 
heart rate of 55 and a respiratory rate of 10.  There is no
increase in jugular venous pressure.  His carotids are free of
bruits.  His lungs are entirely clear to auscultation throughout,
and cardiac exam is notable for a non-displaced PMI, S1 and
physiologically-split S2 with no murmur, rub or gallop.  Abdominal
exam is notable for a ventral hernia.  There is no organomegaly and
neither are there bruits present.  Lower extremities are notable
for 2+ femoral, popliteal, dorsalis pedis and posterior tibial
pulses with no edema.  Skin exam is notable only for the senile
angioma.
 
Electrocardiogram is notable for a left bundle branch block which
is new since prior tracing available here of 4/03/94.  MIBI was
notable only for a potential fixed anteroseptal defect and no
significant ischemia on 5/6/94.  The ejection fraction on a gated
spect was 57%.  
 
In summary, it appears that Mr. Vicente may have experienced a new
myocardial infarction resulting in a left bundle branch block in
March of 2094.  He could, however, also have developed his
progressive conduction system disease and have the fixed defect on
his MIBI attributable only to a left bundle branch block.  I will
be reviewing the primary images to make my final decision.  In
either regard he is now free of symptoms on his current medical
regimen despite his increased weight and his increased blood
pressure.  I certainly agree with further assistance from nutrition
and weight loss and proceeding with Imdur therapy which I would
increase to 60 mg p.o. q.d.  I also would consider further decrease
of his LDL with statin therapy but would only consider this after
assessing his response to re-initiation his nutrition program. 
Given his lack of symptoms at the present time with his usual daily
activity, I would prefer to proceed on the medical therapy route. 
I think that he could be reintroduced to rehab at MJH with the
hopes that further education can get him back on line in terms of
risk factor reduction.  
 
I certainly look forward to discussing this case further with you. 
It's certainly a pleasure to participate in his care.
 
Sincerely,
 
 
 
Gwen K. Xique, M.D.
DD: 06/12/94
DT: 06/17/94
DV: 06/12/94
/jackman
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-09-30

                     SPENCER EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

VICENTE,KADEEM FRANCIS   948-59-58-0              VISIT DATE: 09/30/95

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest discomfort. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 78-year-old gentleman 

who had a stuttering course of chest discomfort throughout the 

night, last night, and into today.  He finally took nitroglycerin 

tablets at about 9 or 10:00 a.m. and this abated his chest 

discomfort.  The patient has known history of coronary artery 

disease and recently had gone back on his coronary rehab program, 

however, yesterday after a workout, he became extremely tired, more 

tire than usual.  He thought he might have pushed it a bit and he 

rested throughout the rest of the day.  Then last night, he had 

some chest discomfort, which he initially did not think much of. 

Then was then associated with some shortness of breath in the early 

morning hours.  He felt he was wheezing.  This resolved after he 

got up and walked around.  He took the nitroglycerin tablets this 

morning.  These were fresh nitroglycerin tablets he had just 

obtained and this, in fact, resolved his symptoms.  He then came in 

to see Dr. Echeverria, his physician, in clinic and was sent to the 

emergency department for evaluation.  Please see the handwritten 

emergency department record for additional details. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Coronary artery disease 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  See handwritten emergency 

department record. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is presently comfortable, not 

tachypneic.  His blood pressure is 160/80.  His heart rate is in 

the 50s.  There is no evidence of congestive heart failure on 

examination.  There is no jugular venous distention and his lungs 

are clear to auscultation.  His heart examination is distant, with 

no murmurs or gallops appreciated.  His extremities have trace 

edema.  Abdomen in soft and non-tender.  Pulses are equal. 

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  His electrocardiogram shows a left bundle 

branch pattern with no change in configuration from previous 

tracings.  His other laboratory studies are pending. 

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The case was discussed with his 

physician, Dr. Echeverria.  We both agree that the patient has 

probably had a progression of his coronary syndrome with possible 

unstable plaque, given his episode of shortness of breath and 

paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.  It is possible that he has silent 

ischemia, which is not evident because of the left bundle branch 

pattern.  Pending the other evaluation and studies, which are being 

sent at this time, the patient will require hospitalization for 

further medical management. 

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Acute coronary insufficiency, coronary artery 

disease. 

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted to the hospital in stable condition. 

___________________________________                    BR445/05178 

STEPHEN HENDERSON, M.D.   SH44                             D:09/30/95 

                                                       T:09/30/95 

Dictated by:  STEPHEN HENDERSON, M.D.   SH44 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>