<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2080-12-12

FREDERICK JEFFERSON

KRMC Unit No: 887-09-86



ZUCKER HILLSIDE HOSPITAL



ADULT MEDICINE





Date: December 12, 2080

84-year-old male for follow up of a recent hospitalization last weekend.  Apparently, had some mild congestive heart failure, after eating some pizza.  Apparently he ruled out, he was only in the hospital for 24 hours.  Since discharge, he has been doing well.  He feels perhaps a slight tickle in his throat and occasional cough but no PND, orthopnea, dyspnea on exertion or chest pain.  There were no changes of his medication.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  

(1)	CAD with CHF: EF of 25%.

(2)	Hypertension.

(3)	Peripheral vascular disease.

(4)	Gout.

(5)	DJD.

(6)	Renal insufficiency.

(7)	Hyperlipidemia.

(8)	BPH.

MEDICATIONS: Lasix 40 mg b.i.d., digoxin .125 mg q.o.d., Colchicine .6 mg q.o.d., Metoprolol 50 mg twice a day, prednisone 5 mg q.d., Coumadin as per Anticoag Clinic, hydralazine 10 mg q.i.d., Isordil 20 mg t.i.d., K-DUR 20 meq q.d., Hydroxychloroquine 200 mg q.d., calcium and vitamin D twice a day, allopurinol 100 mg q.d., Celebrex 200 mg q.d. and Azulfidine 500 mg taken 3 x per week.



PHYSICAL EXAM: Weight: 197, down 6 pounds from November.  His blood pressure today is 130/70.  His pulse is in the 80's and slightly irregular.  Neck: 8 cm JVD.  Lungs: Although diminished breath sounds, clear.  Cardiac: Regularly irregular, S1, S2.  Abdomen: Soft and nontender.  Extremities: No edema on the right.  Trace ankle edema on the left.



A/P:	Status post episode of congestive heart failure due to dietary noncompliance: Appears to be stable now with decrease in his weight. Continue present medical regimen.  We had a discussion on the importance of diet compliance.  Avoid salt products.  Will otherwise see Mrs. Kang later this month in December and I will see him again in January.

David Hale, M.D.

DH/quiggle/nielsen





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-07-17

FREDERICK JEFFERSON

KRMC Unit No:  887-09-86



ZUCKER HILLSIDE HOSPITAL



ADULT MEDICINE





Date:  July 17, 2081



Weight 204 lb, up 15 lb. 



Patient accompanied by wife who gives meds to patient. 



Patient states does not eat much. Wife disagrees. States frequent sweets in diet, cake, doughnuts, pie a la mode, 1    cups of coffee - will have cookie with it. 



MEDICATIONS:  Lasix 40 mg 1.5 tabs q.d., calcium tablet 500 mg q.d., colchicine 0.6 mg q.o.d., digoxin 0.125 mg q.o.d., isosorbide 20 mg t.i.d., Hydralazine 10 mg q.i.d., Metoprolol 50 mg b.i.d., Prednisone 5 mg q.d., Coumadin 3 mg per anticoag. 

CHF/CAD. Rare cough productive of clear sputum. Denies SOB, DOE, PND, although awakens 2-3 x per night. Walks around, sits in recliner for about an hour, then back to sleep. Per wife, patient naps in chair during day. Also frequently drinks coffee at night. Patient denies CP or palpitations or difficulty with breathing. 



PHYSICAL EXAM:  Weight up 15 lb. BP, RA 120/70. Chest - Clear with decreased sounds bilateral bases, decreased breath sounds. Cardiac - Regular rhythm with premature beats at 84. No murmur. Extremities - No edema on right, trace on left. 



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  

(1)	CHF/CAD. No new symptoms. However, 15 lb weight gain of concern. Consult with Dr. Hale. Check chest x-ray today, BUN and creatinine, lytes. 

(2)	Obesity. Counselled patient and wife regarding d/c sweets in diet, need to focus on reducing weight. 

(3)	Wife mentions patient frequently forgets things, days of week, etc. Discussed with patient mild dementia. RTC in 2 months to Dr. Hale. Continue current meds.



ADDENDUM: Patient at end of visit mentioned bitter taste, acid, after eating. Apparently never got prescription for ranitidine filled. Ranitidine 150 mg, #60, 1 tab b.i.d. refilled x 3. Pt. ed. regarding decrease coffee in diet. Advised decaffeinated at h.s.





Odessa Kang, RNC, ANP

OK/quiggle/urie





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-02-03

85 yo male for follow up.

c/o mainly of arthritis pain in hands.  no redness or swelling.  

Sleeping well at night with no pnd or orthopnea.   sleeping in bed as opposed to couch/chair.



finds reflux of small amount of food every three meals if he eats quickly.  sometimes gets rushed by family members.

no dysphagia or odynophagia.





PROBLEMS



Congestive heart failure  

Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease  

Hypertension  

Gout  

DJD  

Benign prostatic hypertrophy  

Hyperlipidemia  

Chronic renal dysfunction  

Peripheral vascular disease  s/p right fem-tib bypass 1/78

Prostatic nodule  psa 1.6 09/81.  seen by dr. hoover in 11/81 who recommended yearly follow up.





MEDICATIONS



PREDNISONE   5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  Take as directed 

COUMADIN (WARFARIN SODIUM)      1 Tablet(s) PO QPM  Take as directed per anticoag

HYDRALAZINE HCL   10MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QID  Take as directed 

ISORDIL (ISOSORBIDE DINITRATE)   20MG  1 Tablet(s) PO TID  Take as directed 

ALLOPURINOL   100MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  Take as directed 

K-DUR (KCL SLOW REL.)   20MEQ  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  Take as directed 

CALCIUM CARBONATE (500 MG ELEMENTAL CA  )   500MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  Take as directed 

DIGOXIN   0.125MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QOD  Take as directed 

COLCHICINE   0.6MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QOD  Take as directed 

PRILOSEC (OMEPRAZOLE)   20MG  1 Capsule(s) PO QD 

METOPROLOL TARTRATE   50MG  1 Tablet(s) PO BID  Take as directed 

LASIX (FUROSEMIDE)   40MG  1 Tablet(s) PO BID  Take as directed 

CELEBREX (CELECOXIB)   200MG  1 Capsule(s) PO QD  Take as directed 





ALLERGY



Penicillins  Unknown  



exam: weight 192(down 8 lbs)

bp 130/70

pulse  72

appears well

lungs:slight rales at bases with diminished sounds throughout but no wheeze.

abd: obese soft and nontender

ext: no edema.  hands: no redness or swelling 



a/p

chf: stable.   lung exam at baseline.   follow  present management.



copd: stable.



htn: stable.



Gerd:   tertiary contractions on barium swallow in october.  advised to eat slowly, taking his time and cutting food in small pieces.



prostatic nodule:   seen by dr. hoover on 11/27/81 and found asymmetry with left > right.   his plan is yearly exam.



guaiac positive stool:   Will be having colonoscopy in the next month.



arthritis:   asked him to call arthritis clinic: dr. quijada for follow up. continue with prednisone. 



HEALTH MAINTENANCE



Influenza 10/02/2081   

Cholesterol 10/03/2081 217  DESIRABLE: less then 200

Rectal exam 10/02/2081   

Stool Guaiac 12/05/2081 one trace postiive out of three Done - positive 

Pneumovax 11/07/75  Done 

Smoking status 10/02/2081  Never a smoker 

UA-Protein 08/31/2081 1+  

check tsh

follow up in three months. 

______________________________________________



David S. Hale, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-01-12

86 yo male for follow up.  his main complaint is of ongoing left shoulder discomfort especially when raising arm over his head. some discomfort at night when he sleeps on it.

also c/o intermittent regurgitation of food contents after meals.  no dysphagia or odynophagia.  

ros; negative for chest pain, pressure, dyspnea,  edema or cold symptoms. 

Problems

Congestive heart failure 

Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease 

Hypertension 

Gout 

DJD 

Benign prostatic hypertrophy 

Hyperlipidemia 

Chronic renal dysfunction 

Peripheral vascular disease : s/p right fem-tib bypass 1/78

Prostatic nodule : psa 1.6 09/81. seen by dr. hoover in 11/81 who recommended yearly follow up.

Coronary artery disease : ett exam: 2080The ECG response to pharmacological stress was uninterpretable for ischemia. The myocardial perfusion images reveal no evidence of ischemia. The images are suggestive of possible prior inferior infarction although soft tissue attenuation prevents a definitive evaluation of this territory.

sigmoid colorectal cancer : s/p sigmoid colectomy and sigmoidoscopy 04/82

rs3PE 





Medications

Calcium Carbonate (500 Mg Elemental Ca ) 500MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID : Take as directed 

Celebrex (CELECOXIB) 200MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

PREDNISONE 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Hydralazine Hcl 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QID x 60 day(s) : Take as directed 

Isordil (ISOSORBIDE Dinitrate) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO TID : Take as directed 

Coumadin (WARFARIN Sodium) 3MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QPM : Take as directed per anticoag

COLCHICINE 0.6MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QOD : Take as directed 

Metoprolol Tartrate 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID : Take as directed 

ALLOPURINOL 100MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

DIGOXIN 0.125MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QOD : Take as directed 





Allergies

Penicillins - Unknown 



exam

weight 188(down 6lbs)

120/70

76

appears well

left shoulder:  able to abduct up to 110 degrees before discomfort.

no subacromial or anterior biceps tendon tenderness.

cor;RRRs1s2

lungs: clear

ext: no edema



a/p

gerd:  no dysphagia but i notice he has lost six lbs since last visit.  will send him for ugi series to investigate further.   continue with prilosec



left shoulder tendinitis:  continue with celebrex.  he is followed by rheumatology. 



b12 deficiency:  lvl 222.  b12 1000mcg im to left deltoid.  follow up in six weeks. 



hypertriglyceridemia:   chol 210 but trig of 497 and hdl 32: begin lopid  600 mg po bid. 

cad: stable with no angina or failure.



htn; stable. 

Health maintenance

Influenza Vaccine 10/06/2082 

Cholesterol 10/15/2082 210 DESIRABLE: less then 200

Rectal exam 10/02/2081 

Stool Guaiac 12/05/2081 one trace postiive out of three Done - positive 

Pneumovax 11/07/75 

Smoking status 10/02/2081 Never a smoker 

UA-Protein 08/31/2081 1+ 









_____________________________________________

David S. Hale, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-12-15

f/u visit for multiple chronic medical probs





Problems

Congestive heart failure 

Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease 

Hypertension 

Gout 

DJD 

Benign prostatic hypertrophy 

Hyperlipidemia 

Chronic renal dysfunction 

Peripheral vascular disease : s/p right fem-tib bypass 1/78

Prostatic nodule : psa 1.6 09/81. seen by dr. hoover in 11/81 who recommended yearly follow up.

Coronary artery disease : ett exam: 2080The ECG response to pharmacological stress was uninterpretable for ischemia. The myocardial perfusion images reveal no evidence of ischemia. The images are suggestive of possible prior inferior infarction although soft tissue attenuation prevents a definitive evaluation of this territory.

sigmoid colorectal cancer : s/p sigmoid colectomy and sigmoidoscopy 04/82

rs3PE 

Diabetes mellitus 





Medications

Calcium Carbonate (500 Mg Elemental Ca ) 500MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD

Celebrex (CELECOXIB) 200MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

COLCHICINE 0.6MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QOD : Take as directed 

Lopid (GEMFIBROZIL) 600MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

DIGOXIN 0.125MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QOD : Take as directed 

PREDNISONE 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Coumadin (WARFARIN Sodium) 3MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QPM : Take as directed per anticoag

Isordil (ISOSORBIDE Dinitrate) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO TID : Take as directed 

Kenalog 0.1% (TRIAMCINOLONE Acetonide 0.1%) 0.1%, 1 application TOP BID

ALLOPURINOL 100MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD : Take as directed 

Hydralazine Hcl 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QID x 60 day(s) : Take as directed 

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Metoprolol Tartrate 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

GLYBURIDE 1.25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 



CAD/ HTN no cp, sob or palpitations no doe  or nocturnal sx knows not to shovel snow     overdue  for bp med which he will take when he gets home

DM  brings in home record  fbs range: 116,115,107, 117, 98, 99, 136  4PM bs  151, 146, 155, 144, 145, 114, 211(ate candy)  per son  pt still on half tab glucotrol until bottle finished then will change to glyburide

pt feels he is eating less now  no hypo sx

prostate nodule  no gu sx

pvd  denies leg pains  

had nodules  L arm excised

concerned re lump around navel  occ tender  denies pain  no increase in size

O: 

Vital signs

BP 160/80 Right Arm ,P 72 Regular ,Wt 183 lb 

chest clear  decreased sounds at base cor rr at 72 no m/g

abdo  sm ventral hernia  above umbilicus  reducible  nontender

Labs  Psa 3  freepsa 0.97  pct free 32.3

hgbA1c  6.4 (127)

path report  = palisading granulomatous tissue reaction  

A: htn borderline  ? re to med overdue  

cad stable

pvd stable

dM  at goal  to change to glyburide soon  monitor bs  on new meds

psa  f/u Dr Hoover

sm abdo hernia  pt ed re prob  monitor

L arm nodules  unclear path  dx  

rtc as sched to  Dr Hale   to me April  call earlier prn





_____________________________________________

Ottilie Kang,RNC,ANP















****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>