<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2061-01-15

                     ST LUCIA EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
VUONG,XOCHILT R   515-31-23-5                  VISIT DATE: 01/15/61
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Bleeding. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This 71 year old female status 
post cardiac cath stent placement and then later EP study states 
that she was doing well until last night when she started to ooze 
from the groin site.  She did not apply any pressure.  She states 
that she was bleeding through the night, did not want to bother her 
brother, called Dr. Aponte today who told her to come in.  She 
states that she did not know where the site was.  She could not see 
it and she did not apply pressure.  She has no chest pain, no 
shortness of breath.  She is not dizzy.  She is on Lovenox and 
Coumadin both.  She has not had her PT checked.  The rest of the 
systems were reviewed and are negative. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Depression, cardiac cath, hypothyroidism. 
MEDICATIONS:  Taken from the chart. 
ALLERGIES:  Taken from the chart. 
SOCIAL HISTORY:  She lives with her brother. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her heart rate was 81, her temperature is 
96.5 degrees, blood pressure is 123/64.  This is a well-developed 
female, alert, oriented.  HEENT exam is atraumatic, normocephalic. 
Neck is soft and supple.  Mouth and throat are normal. 
Well-hydrated moist mucosa.  Conjunctiva are clear.  Sclerae are 
non-icteric.  There is no jugular venous distention.  Heart had a 
regular rate and rhythm.  The lungs were clear to auscultation 
bilaterally.  The abdomen was soft, nontender.  No guarding.  No 
hepatosplenomegaly.  There is a hematoma at the right groin.  The 
cath site was about 1 cm and closed but there was some small oozing 
from the site.  It stopped with pressure.  The patient was covered 
in blood and blood clots.  The old dressing was removed.  All the 
dried blood and blood clots were removed.  The patient was cleaned 
up by myself.  Then, the nurses put her in the hospital gown. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  PT, PTT, CBC were obtained. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  After speaking with the patient at 
length, it seems that she lives with her older brother.  She is 
caring for him and is a bit overwhelmed with this.  Obviously, her 
medical knowledge base is not adequately prepared to deal with this 
problem.  She will be admitted to the Observation Area through the 
day for nurse training.  Social Services will be consulted to 
arrange for a home visiting nurse.  Dr. Aponte was called. 
CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Social Services and Dr. Aponte. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Bleeding from cath site and knowledge deficit. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  See the chart 
for disposition. 
___________________________________                    OO412/09605 
NATHAN PLATT, M.D.       NP27                           D:01/15/61 
                                                       T:01/15/61 
Dictated by:  NATHAN PLATT, M.D.       NP27 
cc:  OWEN R. APONTE, M.D.   OA0 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2063-09-29

Reason for Visit	

Comprehensive physical.



Problems	  

Hyperlipidemia	      

She is now on Lipitor per Dr. Qu.

diabetes mellitus	      

Blood sugars nl on Glucophage and Avandia.  I will check labs today.

S/P Herpetic Neuralgia	      

Still has itchiness on her chin but no pain.  

Colon cancer	      

Still sees Dr. Aragon Q3mos, doing well. 

Coronary artery disease	      

s/p right coronary stent 1/2061 after non-Q wave MI.  She had an arrest in the field on 9/05/2062 and was taken to SLH, after intubation in the field.  Emergency catheterization showed 30% LAD. 40% diagonal and a ejection fraction of 25% with antero-septal akinesis.  CPKs were neg.  Of note, a recent stress test at DCGH had shown LBBB but nl LV function, so she was diagnosed with new cardiomyopathy.  She was disch on 9/10 to Dr. Qu's care.  It is not clear that she has followed-up recently, though a echo from 09/24/62 shows an ejection fraction of 58% with no definite segmental wall motion abnormality.  She has been pain free and is able to walk a few blocks without difficulty since then.  

hypothyroidism	      

Continues on Synthroid.

Lung cancer	      

Now 5 yrs out from left lobectomy and is followed by Dr. Aragon.

depression	      

Seems to be doing extremely well despite her multiple med problems in recent yrs.  Remains on Paxil and also takes Ativan nightly.  



Vital Signs	  

Blood Pressure:	 100/50   Left Arm

Pulse:	 64   Regular

Weight:	 143   Pounds



Physical Exam	  

General Appearance	

Well appearing.

HEENT	

No thyromegaly, no adenopathy.

Breast	

Without masses, good carotid upstrokes.

Cor/Cardiac	

Nl S1-S2.

Abdomen	

Benign.

Rectal Exam	

Heme neg brown stool, no masses.

Extremity	

Full pulses, no edema.

Pelvis	

Nl.



Medications	  

LORAZEPAM	 0.5MG  1 qd

Synthroid	 0.05MG  QD

AVANDIA (ROSIGLITAZONE)	 4MG 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

LASIX (FUROSEMIDE)	 80MG 1 Tablet(s) PO 2 tabs BID

PRILOSEC (OMEPRAZOLE)	 20MG 1 Capsule(s) PO BID

LOPRESSOR (METOPROLOL TARTRATE)	 50MG 0.5 Tablet(s) PO BID

Paxil	 20.0MG PO QD

GLUCOPHAGE (METFORMIN)	 500MG 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

CALTRATE 600	 1TAB PO BID

FE GLUCONATE (FERROUS GLUCONATE)	 325MG 1 Tablet(s) PO TID

ECASA (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED)	 81MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ATROVENT INHALER (IPRATROPIUM INHALER)	 2PUFF NAS BID

SEREVENT (SALMETEROL)	 2PUFF NAS BID

CALCIUM GLUCONATE	 500MG 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

ACCUPRIL (QUINAPRIL)	 10MG PO QD

ONE TOUCH TEST STRIPS	 BLANK  

Multivitamins	 1TAB  QD

OCUVITE (MULTIVITAMINS)	 1TAB PO QD

Lipitor	 20MG PO 1 QD

Lopid	 600MG PO BID



Health Maintenance	  

Influenza Vaccine	 09/29/63   given today

Cholesterol	 09/29/2063 185  

Mammogram	 04/12/2063 BilScrMammo  

Pap Smear	 09/29/2063 See report in Results  

Stool Guaiac	 07/30/2062  Done - negative 

Pneumococcal Vaccine	 08/02/2060   Given today.

UA-Protein	 09/06/2062 2+  

HBA1C	 09/30/2063 5.40  

Bone Density	 09/29/63   ordered



Disposition and Plans	

Return 1 yr physical.

Breast Exam	 07/30/2062    Without masses. 

Rectal exam	 07/30/2062    Heme negative brown stool, no masses. 

Pneumovax	 08/02/2060   

BSE instruction	 07/31/2061 BSE instruction reviewed today  





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-05-05



Medications

Lipitor 40 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Paxil 20.0 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Synthroid 0.05 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Multivitamins 1 TAB QD

One Touch Test Strips : As directed.

LORAZEPAM 0.5 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Accupril (QUINAPRIL) 10 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Calcium Gluconate 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Serevent (SALMETEROL) 2 PUFFS NAS BID

Atrovent Inhaler (IPRATROPIUM Inhaler) 2 PUFFS NAS BID

Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 81MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO 1 TAQD

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 80MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50MG, 0.5 Tablet(s) PO BID

Fe Gluconate (FERROUS Gluconate) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO TID

Glucophage (METFORMIN) 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO : 2 tabs po qam, 2 tabs po qpm.

Caltrate 600 1 TAB PO BID

Avandia (ROSIGLITAZONE) 4MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

Ocuvite (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 TAB PO QD

Fosamax (ALENDRONATE) 70MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO BID 





Problems

Pernicious anemia : In 3/64 HCT was 28 with B12 195. All other parameters nl. Has been getting monthly IM B12. Still feels tired. Will check HCT today. 



Hyperlipidemia : Dr. Qu recently changes lipitor to lopid. Dietary non-compliance and poor DM control not helping lipids. 5/05/64: Recently increased to 40 mg qd and fasting chol checked today.



Diabetes mellitus : Good control. Check A1c today.



Depression : Her brother died recently and he was her main companion. She seems to be grieving appropriately but is somewhat isolated without much in the way of social or other activities. Has lost about 9# since 10/63 due to poor appetite. Does not wish to take any more meds. I will see her more frequently.



Vital signs

BP 100/60 , P 72 , Wt 132 lb

 



3 mos f/u





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-07-17







Name:  Xochilt Vuong

MRN:  6398353





REASON FOR VISIT:  Xochilt Vuong is a 74-year-old patient of Dr. Wanda Yeomans, and is sent because of rising serum creatinine.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Vuong has a history of diabetes mellitus 

going back more than 10 years.  She also has had hypertension and elevated lipids 

over approximately the same period of time.  She has a complicated history 

including lung cancer and colon cancer, both treated and in remission.  Her 

creatinine has been rising gradually over recent years with a value of 1.0 in 2062, 

1.2 in May 2063, 2.1 and 1.8 in early 2064 with 2.3 in May 2064, and recently 3.1 

obtained on July 06, 2064.



She has been quite anemic in the recent months with a hematocrit level of 24.9.  

Her serum folate, B12, and iron and are not particularly low, and MCV is normal 

at 81.  Urinalysis showed 3+ albumin in September 2062 and persisting 

proteinuria since that time.  Dr. Yeomans obtained an ultrasound examination in 

March, which showed diffusely thinned renal cortices, but no evidence of 

obstruction, stones, or masses.



She has visited an ophthalmologist regularly for macular degeneration.  She does 

not know whether signs of diabetes are present, but she has had no laser treatment 

for any proliferative retinopathy.



Recently, she has been feeling unusually fatigued with diminished appetite and 

almost constant nausea.  She vomits rarely.  Her weight has fallen by about 20 

pounds.  She is slightly constipated.  She is moderately dyspneic on exertion.  She 

is not troubled by muscle cramps or by unusual itching of her skin.



Her medications continue as listed with ACE inhibitors, "statins," and a rather 

large dose of Lasix at 80 mg twice a day.



Medications

Paxil 20.0 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Synthroid 0.05 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Multivitamins 1 TAB QD

One Touch Test Strips : As directed.

LORAZEPAM 0.5 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Accupril (QUINAPRIL) 10 MG PO 1 TAB QD

Calcium Gluconate 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Serevent (SALMETEROL) 2 PUFFS NAS BID

Atrovent Inhaler (IPRATROPIUM Inhaler) 2 PUFFS NAS BID

Ecasa (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 81MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO 1 TAQD

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 80MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO BID

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50MG, 0.5 Tablet(s) PO BID

Fe Gluconate (FERROUS Gluconate) 325MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO TID

Glucophage (METFORMIN) 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO : 2 tabs po qam, 2 tabs po qpm.

Caltrate 600 1 TAB PO BID

Avandia (ROSIGLITAZONE) 4MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

Ocuvite (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 TAB PO QD

Fosamax (ALENDRONATE) 70MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK

Prilosec (OMEPRAZOLE) 20MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO BID

Lipitor 40 MG PO 1 TAB QD 





PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On examination today, she looks tired but 

reasonably comfortable.  She speaks in a high-pitched somewhat hoarse voice, 

which has persisted since one of her surgical procedures.  Her blood pressure in 

the right arm, sitting, is 148/60 with regular pulse 72.  Her chest has a few basal 

crackles but in general is clear and air moves comfortably.  JVP fills below the 

sternal angle heart shows a grade 2 systolic murmur, loudest at the upper left 

sternal border.  Abdomen is soft and nontender.  There is no renal tenderness.  

Extremities have no edema.



IMPRESSION:  Progressive renal failure in a 74-year-old woman with more than 

10 years' history of diabetes as well has hypertension and hyperlipidemia.  The 

proteinuria, if confirmed, would support the diagnosis of diabetic nephropathy but 

this would be unusual in the absence of retinopathy.  It would be useful to know 

from her ophthalmologist whether retinopathy is present.  It is, of course, also 

possible that she has vascular disease involving the kidneys.  Their symmetry and 

the presence of proteinuria would argue against this possibility.  The ACE 

inhibitor in the presence of vascular disease might of course raise her serum 

creatinine by reducing renal blood flow somewhat.  Her loss of appetite and 

nausea may well be related to the degree of renal failure.



RECOMMENDATION:  I would suggest that she see Filomena Xia, RD, a renal 

dietitian, to learn a diet appropriate for renal failure as well as for her diabetes and 

hyperlipidemia.  This might succeed in reducing some of her nausea.  It think it 

would be worthwhile as an experiment to reduce or discontinue her Accupril and 

perhaps  her Lasix temporarily to see whether serum creatinine falls with 

less ACE inhibition and somewhat more fluid volume.  If, of course, shortness of 

breath worsens or edema appears, then returning to the Lasix would be 

reasonable.  It might be that a longer acting, milder diuretic, such as 5 mg of 

metolazone might help to control edema (and potassium) and reduce the 

requirement for Lasix.  If serum creatinine fell appreciably with less ACE and 

diuresis, it would reassure us that the damage was not all structural, and it might 

be then possible to return to these medicines with less worry.



Her anemia is no doubt related to lack of erythropoietin and would likely benefit 

from instituting therapy with Epogen (such as 4000 units twice a week) or 

Aranesp).



PLAN:  We will send a urine today for total protein to creatinine ratio, which may 

help us decide whether the problem is mainly diabetic nephropathy.  If so, the 

measures proposed would be appropriate.  We discussed the eventual probable 

need for dialysis (assuming no other intercurrent medical catastrophes).  It would 

be useful for her to visit the DCGH Renal Department (located here on our 

floor at 592G, along with Ms. Xia's office) to learn about modes of dialysis.  

We discussed construction of a forearm fistula, which should be done well before 

a need for it arises.  I would, in fact, recommend that she proceed to have this 

done in the next few months.  This could be arranged through Dr. Xaysana's office 

or perhaps by speaking with Dr. Najee Yuan.  I will, of course, help with any of 

these measures as necessary.









Xander Xie, M.D.





Wanda

Urine total protein/creatinine ratio is only 0.11 (corresponding to about 0.1 g/day or proteinuria).  This is a very small amount for diabetic nephropathy, and argues in favor of vascular disease.  I would suggest getting a MRA of renal arteries to look for any main artery obstruction.  If present it would account for the sensitivity of her creatinine to ACE or changes in hydration.



Kyle



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-08-11

DCGH Cancer Center



Diagnosis:  

1. Colon cancer

2. Lung Cancer



Reason for Visit: 

routine f/u



Main Symptoms/Side Effect of Treatment:   

 weight loss has stabilized

having more reflux

recently found to have worsening renal function and was seen by Dr Xie and felt to need dialysis in the near future. The cause of the RI is unclear but probably related to either diabetic or hypertensive disease.

  	  	

Past Oncologic History:  

1. T3 N3 adenocarcinoma of the left upper lobe diagnosed in 3/59 and s/p chemoradiation followed by resection

2. T2 N1 adenocarcioma of the sigmoid colon s/p adjuvant 5FU/LV completing therapy in 09/61

  

Social History: 

;nothing new to report



Review of Systems:  



All other systems are negative.

  



Physical Exam: deferred



Laboratory Data: CEA and CA19-9 normal



Chest abd pelvic CT without contrast: no evidence of metastatic disease



PET scan:  No definite evidence of metastatic disease



Impression:  

1. Stage 3 colon cancer:

2. Stage 2 lung cancer

3. Anemia

4. Renal Insufficiency



She has no evidence of metastatic disease and her main problem is her impending renal failure. We had a very blunt discussion about dialysis and her desire to not go on it. She understands that she would die from progressive renal dysfunction and she will talk more about this with Drs Yeomans and Xie.



Plan: 

1. as above



Counseling comprised the majority of today's visit which was 15 minutes







____________________________

Nunzio Kyle Aragon, M.D.





cc: 

Wanda Yeomans, MD DCGH

Edward Qu, MD DCGH

Nunzio Manning, MD DCGH

Xzavior Casey, MD DCGH

Nunzio Yockey, MD DCGH

Rusty Vincent, MD DCGH

Otis Xayasane, MD DCGH



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>