<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2087-09-18










CHIEF COMPLAINT:  BP CHECK



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: 



The patient presents to the office for follow-up of (#1) hypertension. 



The patient presents to the office for follow-up of (#2) anemia. He saw Dr willis and has an appt fdor colonoscopy in Nov.





PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:04/26/2086 

 

PMH significant for HTN. 





PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/02/2086 

 tonsillectomy.





FAMILY HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/02/2086 

Father deceaced Alsheimer's

Mother NIDDM, HTN, CVA, Nephrogenic DI.



SOCIAL HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/02/2086 

 

EtOH:  rare use.   

Drugs:  no drug abuse.   

Tobacco:  none.   

Family:  single.   

Work:     Senior Manager of Goods Production            .



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Constitution:  Constitution:  good general health, no fever, no change in weight . 

 Cardiovascular:  no palpitations, no chest pain or dyspnea. 

 Respiratory:  no cough, no wheezing or dyspnea. 

 Urinary:  no dysuria or frequent urination  

 Gastrointestinal:  no abdominal pain, no diarrhea, no constipation, no nausea or vomiting.

 Endocrine:  no temperature intolerance or weight changes. 

 





VITAL SIGNS: 

Date/Time: 09/18/2087  05:39 PM  - ostrowski

Pulse 1: 80 bpm 

Blood Pressure 1: 130 / 88 mmHg 

Weight: 302.00 lbs.







EXAMINATION: 



[Neck] - supple no lymphadenopathy or thyromegaly, 

[CV] - regular rate no murmurs, rubs or gallops, no heave; carotid and pedal pulses normal and 

[Respiratory] - clear breath sounds bilaterally, no accessory muscle use, normal percussion. 





CONSTITUTIONAL: The patient appears severely obese.  Appears properly developed for stated age, in no apparent distress.  





OTHER: HB 12.5





IMPRESSION: Hypertension

Obesity

Minimal anemia but with drop over past 4 months.





ALLERGIES: 

No Known Drug Allergies 05/21/2087 ostrowski





MEDICATIONS: 

Lidex cream No Match bid prn up to 2 week : 01/09/2087 - 02/02/2090 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 45 grams  Refill: 1 Date: 09/29/2089 : ostrowski



HCTZ 25mg qd : 05/02/2086 - 09/29/2089 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 100  Refill: 3 Date: 10/21/2088 : ostrowski



K-Dur 10MEQ qod : 05/02/2086 - 03/06/2092 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: #30  Refill: 11 Date: 08/03/2090 : ostrowski



Zestril 5MG qd : 05/02/2086 - 10/21/2088 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 30  Refill: 11 Date: 09/18/2087 : ostrowski







PROBLEMS - CARE PLANS: 

Problem: problem

Code: 285.9 Anemia, unspecified

Careplan: 

GI consult for endoscopy. Email sent to Dr Willis requesting expedite proceedure in view of lower HCT.

Problem: problem

Code: 401.9 Hypertension

Careplan: 



Diet:  low sodium and low cholesterol. weight loss increse exercise.

ASA QD

 Refill meds

FU 3 mo.



E/M Codes: 42789




THIS IS A COPY PRODUCED FOR THE LMR. THE ORGINAL IS STORED ON THE COMPENDIA SERVER AT SMI KESSEL GROUP HOME AND IN PRINT IN THE PATIENT'S SMI PAPER RECORD.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-12-01










CHIEF COMPLAINT:  F/U HOSP



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: FU SMI ER abdominal pain now  better. pain was periumbilical. 







PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/20/2088 

 

PMH significant for HTN. 

Colonic Poilyp SP LGI blled post colonoscopy 2087





PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/20/2088 

 tonsillectomy.





FAMILY HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/20/2088 

Father deceaced Alsheimer's

Mother NIDDM, HTN, CVA, Nephrogenic DI.



SOCIAL HISTORY: Entered By:ostrowski  On:05/20/2088 

 

EtOH:  rare use.   

Drugs:  no drug abuse.   

Tobacco:  none.   

Family:  single.   

Work:     Senior Manager of Goods Production            .



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Constitution:  Constitution:  good general health, no fever, no change in weight . 

 Respiratory:  no cough, no wheezing or dyspnea. 

 Cardiovascular:  no palpitations, no chest pain or dyspnea. 

 Gastrointestinal:  (denies) abdominal pain, decreased appetite, no change in bowel habits, (denies) diarrhea, (denies) dysphagia and (denies) hematemesis. 

 Gastrointestinal:  (denies) nausea, (denies) rectal bleeding, normal stools and (denies) vomiting. 

 Urinary:  (denies) dysuria, (denies) hematuria and (denies) frequent urination  

 





VITAL SIGNS: 

Date/Time: 12/01/2089  04:09 PM  - ostrowski

Pulse 1: 70 bpm 

Blood Pressure 1: 120 / 80 mmHg 

Weight: 299.00 lbs.







EXAMINATION: 



[Neck] - supple no lymphadenopathy or thyromegaly and 

[Respiratory] - clear breath sounds bilaterally, no accessory muscle use, normal percussion. 

[CV] - Heart: normal rate and regular rhythm. 

[GI] - Abdomen: no tenderness, (-) rebound, (-) guarding, normal bowel sounds, (-) hepatomegaly, (-) splenomegaly and no abdominal mass. 

Labs/Studies: _____. WBC 13.5 CT diverticulosis / Diverticulitis  w some bowel loops 





CONSTITUTIONAL: Appears properly developed for stated age, in no apparent distress.  The patient appears severely obese.  





IMPRESSION: Hypertension

Obesity

GI bleed SP polypectomy

Diverticulosis w ? diverticulitis  ? SBO resolved 

GERD.





ALLERGIES: 

No Known Drug Allergies 05/21/2087 ostrowski





MEDICATIONS: 

CIPRO 500MG PO bid : 12/01/2089 - 02/02/2090 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 20  Refill: 0 Date: 12/01/2089 : ostrowski



METAMUCIL 1Tablespoon twice daily w water : 12/01/2089 - 12/18/2093 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 1  Refill: 0 Date: 12/01/2089 : ostrowski



CETAPHIL   topically prn : 09/29/2089 - 12/18/2093 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 1  Refill: 0 Date: 09/29/2089 : ostrowski



Lipitor 10MG qd : 01/27/2089 - 08/23/2092 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 30  Refill: 11 Date: 08/29/2091 : ostrowski



Cormax 0.05% topically bid prn : 12/11/2087 - 02/02/2090 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 45 `gRAMS  Refill: 2 Date: 12/11/2087 : ostrowski



Lidex cream No Match bid prn up to 2 week : 01/09/2087 - 02/02/2090 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 45 grams  Refill: 1 Date: 09/29/2089 : ostrowski



K-Dur 10MEQ qod : 05/02/2086 - 03/06/2092 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: #30  Refill: 11 Date: 08/03/2090 : ostrowski



HCTZ 12.5mg qd : 05/02/2086 - 03/06/2092 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 100  Refill: 3 Date: 08/29/2091 : ostrowski



Zestril 10MG PO qd : 05/02/2086 - 01/02/2092 ACT : ostrowski

   Script:  Amt: 30  Refill: 11 Date: 12/12/2091 : ostrowski







IMMUNIZATIONS: 

Td 01/27/2089



PROBLEMS - CARE PLANS: 

Problem: problem

Code: 562.11 Diverticulitis

Careplan: 



Medications:  CIPRO - 500MG      - PO bid - 12/01/2089 - Script: Amt: 20 Refill: 0.

 

Diet:  clear liquid till better then low residue. W metamucil bid 

 

Problem: problem

Code: 562.10 Diverticulosis

Careplan: 



Diet:  Diverticulosis diet.

 

Follow Up:  prn f/u

 

Medications:  METAMUCIL - 1Tablespoon          - twice daily w water  - 12/01/2089 - Script: Amt: 1 Refill: 0.

 






THIS IS A COPY PRODUCED FOR THE LMR. THE ORGINAL IS STORED ON THE COMPENDIA SERVER AT SMI KESSEL GROUP HOME AND IN PRINT IN THE PATIENT'S SMI PAPER RECORD.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2091-08-24

Team B Sub-Intern Admission Note

Wood,Cade

MR# 6691247

Date of Admission: 8/24/91

GI:  Narvaez, Guy

PCP: Suzanne, Otto



ID/CC:	Weakness 



HPI:  Mr. Wood is a 58 yo M w/ Hx of colonic polyps and diverticulosis who presents with 1 day of weakness.  Mr. Wood was at work this morning and at 9 AM he started to feel weak.  He describes the weakness as lack of energy and has normal muscle strength.  He states he really didn't have any symptoms other than weakness, but when asked about chest pain, he notes that he had mild chest discomfort, which was analogous to catching his breath after exercise.  He also describes some mild lightheadedness.  He has 2 pillow orthopnea, but he denies any fever, chills, nausea, night sweats, unintentional weight loss, syncope, HA, dyspnea, chest pain, PND, diaphoresis, palpitations, or any other concerning symptoms.  He notes his last BM was on Friday morning and states his stools have not been black or tarry, bright red, pencil thin, or watery.  He denies any abdominal pain, constipation, or diarrhea.  He notes that rest and staying out of the heat improved his symptoms, while exertion worsened his symptoms.  He has had these symptoms before in March of this year, but his symptoms today are more mild than when he presented then.  At that time he had symptoms of weakness and lightheadedness especially when standing, and he was found to have a Hct of 24.9.  He was guiac positive and was sent for a colonoscopy and an upper GI endoscopy, where a he was found to have erosive esophagitis and two cecal polyps.  The bowel prep on the colonoscopy was poor and he was asked to follow up with a repeat colonoscopy.  He was sent home on iron supplements and a PPI.  Of note, his previous colonoscopies had shown tubulovillous adenomas including a 25 mm polyp that could not be fully resected and had been   Before this admission he was seen by his worksite nurse who sent him to his PCP.  Dr. David Napolitano at Kessel Group Home saw him and transferred him to SMI for workup of severe anemia (Hct 25.4 MCV 75), dizziness, and orthostasis. 

    

PMH:



1.	Diverticulosis (Dx by colonoscopy in 10/18/87

2.	Polyps - Single polyp 10/87 removed by colonoscopy (tubulovillous adenoma) with 11 day postpolypectomy bleed.  F/U colonscopy in 11/10/90 and 12/15/90 found 25 mm polyp in ascending colon that could not be completely removed (Tubulovillous adenoma by pathology).  

3.	Hyperlipidemia (medically controlled for 2 years) - Chol 100/TG 100/HDL 26/LDL 54/CardRR 3.8 (3/16/91)

4.	HTN (medically controlled for 6 years)



MEDICATIONS:



1.	HCTZ 12.5 mg poqd

2.	Zestril 10 mg poqd

3.	Lipitor 10 mg poqd

4.	FeSO4 325 mg poqd

5.	Omeprazole 20 mg poqd

6.	K-DUR 10 meq poqod



Allergies:  	Demerol - passes out



SH:  	Patient lives alone in De Witt.  He is a Performer at GEICO.  

	Tob:		Hx of 1 year of occasional smoking at age 14

	EtOH:  		Occasional in the past, but now rarely

	Illicits: 	Denies

	SEXUAL:	Currently no partner, and no Hx of STD



FH:	Sister in good health.  Father died at age 81 of aspiration pneumonia and had Alzheimer's disease.  Mother died at age 80 of uncertain cause.  



ROS:   	Const:  	  No fever, chills, night sweats, recent unintentional weight loss, or anorexia.      

HEENT:  No deficits in hearing, vision, or taste.  No head or neck lesions or masses.  No sinusitis or 

  rhinorrhea

CV:         See HPI

Pulm:	 No dyspnea, cough, sputum, pleurisy, or soar throat.

GI:	 See HPI

MSK:  	No muscle weakness, muscle or joint pain, or decreased ROM.  No lower extremity swelling. 

Neuro:  	No LOC, change in mentation, altered motor strength or coordination, or changes in sensation

Psych:    No depression or anxiety



Exam:  	VS:	T= 97.9    HR=84   RR=22  SaO2 = 99% RA

	Orhtostatics:   BP = 120/70 supine   105/60 Standing   (Done after

General:  Obese man who is resting in NAD

Skin:  Numerous skin tags and cherry angiomas on trunk.  

HEENT: NCAT,  PERRLA, EOMI.  OP w/ moist mucus membranes, no erythema, thrush, or injection.

Neck:  	Supple, full ROM.  JVP ~ 6.  2+/2+ carotids w/o bruits, no palpable nodes

Chest: 	Clear to auscultation bilaterally  

CVS:  	RRR, nl S1 S2.  No M/R/G.  No syncope upon standing

Abd:  	BS present; Soft, w/ no tenderness, rebound, guarding, distension, or HSM.  Guaic positive per ER.        

Extr:  	Left ankle tenderness with flexion.  No erythema, effusions, or induration.  Right distal lateral leg with diffuse erythematous macular rash ~ 5 cm in diameter  

Neuro: AOX3, Noted slightly delayed responses.  Mental status normal (Intact verbal language and comprehension), CN II through XII intact, no nystagmus, Motor 5/5 in handgrip, biceps, quads, gastrocnemius, ant. tibialis.  No deficits to touch bilaterally throughout.  DTR 2+/2+ in patella, achiles, biceps, and brachioradialis.  Toes going down bilaterally.  Patient was able to walk and had a normal gait      



DATA:



Chemistry:



Test Description        Result   Flags           Ref. Range     Ref. Units



Plasma Sodium          141                       135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium       4.2                       3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride        106                       100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide  26.6                      23.0-31.9      mmol/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen   27         H              8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine      1.7        H              0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose         93                        70-110         mg/dl

Calcium                9.2                       8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus             3.6                       2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium              1.5                       1.4-2.0        meq/L

Total Protein          7.3                       6.0-8.3        g/dl

Albumin                3.5                       3.3-5.0        g/dl

Globulin               3.8                       2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin       0.1                       0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin        0.3                       0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase   120        H              45-115         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT      10                        10-55          U/L

Amylase                47                        3-100          units/L

Lipase                 3.2                       1.3-6.0        U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT      16                        10-40          U/L

Creatine Kinase Isoenz NEGATIVE                  NEG

Troponin-I             NEGATIVE                  NEG



Hematology:



Test Description        Result   Flags           Ref. Range     Ref. Units



WBC                    7.8                       4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                    26.3       L              41.0-53.0      %

HGB                    8.4        L              13.5-17.5      gm/dl

RBC                    3.40       L              4.50-5.90      mil/cmm

PLT                    387        H              150-350        th/cumm

MCV                    77         L              80-100         fl

MCH                    24.7       L              26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                   32.0                      31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                    15.2       H              11.5-14.5      %

PT                     12.3                      11.1-13.1      sec

PT-INR                 1.0

APTT                   26.4                      22.1-35.1      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST   RECEIVED

Diff Method            Auto

Poly                   83         H              40-70          %

Lymphs                 12         L              22-44          %

Monos                  3          L              4-11           %

EOS                    2                         0-8            %

Basos                  0                         0-3            %

Absolute Neuts         6.40                      1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs        0.97       L              1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos         0.25                      0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS           0.17                      0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos         0.02                      0.0-0.3        th/cmm

Aniso                  None                      NORMAL

Hypo                   3+                        NORMAL

Macrocytes             None

Microcytes             1+



EKG:   Normal sinus rhythm.  Axis at 0.  No Q waves or ST changes



CXR:   Clear.  No PNA or edema



ER Course:  In the ER, he was started on IVFs and labs were sent.



Impression:  



Mr. Wood is a 58 yo M w/ Hx of colonic polyps and diverticulosis who presents with 1 day of weakness and lightheadedness secondary to a microcytic anemia.  His Hct stabilized at 26 since his transfer from his PCP's office.  His anemia is most likely due to lower GI bleeding from either his diverticulosis or from his polyposis given his guiac positive stool in the ER.  He is currently hemodynamically stable and he states he feels much better symptomatically.  Given that he hasn't had a follow up colonoscopy since the poorly prepped one in March of this year, he will probably need to be reevaluated by Dr. Narvaez.  Other possible attributing causes of his anemia could be hypothyroidism given his somewhat delayed response, but his DTR were normal.  Iron studies will be sent to confirm the probable diagnosis of chronic GI bleeding resulting in iron deficiency anemia.  He will not be transfused now given that he is asymptomatic currently and he prefers not to be transfused unless necessary.  His syncope could also have been exacerbated from his slight orthostatic hypotension as seen on PE and his high Cre and BUN indicating that he is volume depleted.  He will be adequately hydrated to correct his hypotension.  Given his chest pain and syncope, MI will be ruled out, but this is very unlikely given his clinical presentation.  His first enzymes were negative and his EKG showed no Q waves or ST changes.   



Plan: 

1)	GI Bleed

a.	Transfuse pRBCs if necessary - Consent and Type and Cross (O +)

b.	Two large bore IVs if rapid resuscitation is needed

c.	Follow Hct Q8H and watch HR and BP for signs of active bleeding

d.	Nexium 40 POQD

2)	Heme:  Anemia

a.	Send Iron Studies, TSH

b.	FeSO4 325 mg POTID

3)	CV:  

a.	Rule out MI:  Enzymes + Monitor

b.	Hypertensive:  Continue on HCTZ and Zestril

c.	Hyperlipidemia:  Continue Lipitor











_________________________________

David Napolitano, MS IV

Pager #57255





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-08-16

 

Eye Specialties Intern Admission H & P



Patient Name: Wood, Cade

MR# 6691247

Location: BIG99

PCP:	 Dr. Otto Suzanne



Date of Admission: 8/15/92



ID/CC:	59 y.o. male with SOB during a CT on the day of admission

HPI:  Pt. is a 59 y.o. male with DLBCL dx'ed with stage 4 DLBCL in 11/07, S/P CHOP-R (finished 3/08), HTN, GERD, and anemia who p/w acute onset of SOB while lying down during a f/u staging non-contrast CT on the day of admission. Pt. notes a 5lbs weight gain over the past week. He also reports a 1-2 week h/o increasing DOE when he performs his household chores or working in his backyard. At his baseline, can can walk    of a mile w/o dyspnea or CP. 4 days PTA, he had to    take it easy    during a picnic as he would easily develop DOE with minimal exertion.  2days PTA, pt. experienced coughing bouts when he tried to lie down for sleep. The patient acutely developed SOB after lying down for a few minutes during his CT. He felt 1/10 CP during this episode located in the R middle sub-sternum. The pain lasted for approximately 10 min, dull in quality, did not radiate, did not change with position, relieved after given NTG in the ED. He experienced a similar CP during an administration of his chemo several months PTA. This CP was determined not be be cardiogenic. + diaphoresis, - N/V, - lightheadedness, - palpitations. He reports eating a lot of salty foods. - recent URI/sick contacts.







Onc Hx

-59yo man with h/o 1y microcytic anemia (low Fe, low ferritin) 

Found to have ascending colon adenomatous polyp persistent despite several colonoscopic resections. Also noted anorexia, fatigue, bloody stools.

11/8/91 admitted to SMI with sudden RLQ pain. Ab CT notable for large mass arising out of the small bowel with liver lesions.

11/11/91 liver bx: DLBCL. 

11/16/91 seen in clinic. Discussed diagnosis. Arranged staging. Anemic.

11/28/91 BM bx -> negative for BM involvement, PAC placement

11/30/91 cycle #1 CHOP-R. Mild transfusion reaction with PRBC

12/02/91 PRBC successfully given. Neulasta.

12/7/91 In f/u, noted to be neutropenic despite Neulasta and with oral candidiasis. Tx diflucan, prophylactic Levoquin. Anemic -> 2U PRBC.

12/21/91 cycle #2 CHOP-R, c/b episode non-cardiac chest pain

completed CHOP/R x 6 cycles in 3/08





ED course:   

VS: HR=78 BP=178/108 Tc-96.6 RR=28 SaO2=96% RA

Given ASA 325 mg, NTG X1, Lasix 20mg IV X1, 500 ccNS. 





PMHx:

1.	Stage IV DLBCL 11/07. Likely intestinal origin Involvement of liver; no bone marrow or thoracic involvement. S/p 6 cycles CHOP-R chemotherapy. Last cycle 3/14/92.  Repeat CT 1/27/92 showed RLQ mass reduced in size to 9x5 cm. CT 4/04/92 showed considerable inflammatory reaction in the right lower quadrant engulfing loops of small bowel c/w a focal small bowel perforation.

2.	Microcytic anemia diagnosed 3/07. 

3.	Diverticulosis

4.	Colonic polyps - tubulovillous adenoma resected 10/87. Repeat excisions 06, 12/06. Cecal polyp  - tubular adenoma resected 3/07. Last colonoscopy 10/07 with resection of 10x3 mm polyp in ascending colon.

5.	GERD - endoscopy 3/07 revealed 3 linear esophageal ulcerations from 30cm to 40 cm with no evidence of gastric or duodenal ulceration.

6.	HTN

7.	Hyperlipidemia-Lipitor d/c'ed prior to chemotherapy regimen.

Allergies:  	

Demerol - syncope

Fluconazole - GI upset



Medications at home:

     

Omeprazole - 20mg QHS

Lisinopril 40 mg PO QD

Lopressor 50 mg PO BID



PSHx:

6/14/92 Resection of the terminal ileum and ascending colon for partial obstruction at the terminal ileum. Pathology showed small intestine with abscess formation, foreign body giant cell reaction, marked transmural fibrosis with foamy histiocytes and acute and organized serositis consistent with perforated viscus.  There was also tubular adenoma measuring 0.4 cm in the ascending colon- completely excised., no evidence of malignancy.  





SHx:  Pt. is single, lives by himself. He formerly worked in    goods production    but was laid off 1 yr. PTA. He has a supportive network of family and friends. He does not smoke, has 1 alcoholic beverage every few months, and denies illicit drug use. 



FHx: 

Father- DM, Alzheimer's

Mother - DM, HTN



ROS:   No F/C/NS.  + 5lbs weight gain in 2 weeks. No hemoptysis/wheezing/sore throat/rash.  No N/V/D/hematochezia/melena. No delta MS/LOC. No slurring of speech, unilateral weakness. No dysuria.  - polyuria/polydypsia, heat/cold intolerance. 



Exam:  	VS:	HR=65	BP=157/98 RR=20 SaO2=95% RA

General:  NAD 

HEENT: NC/AT,  PERRL,. EOMI,

Neck:  	Supple, full ROM, no LAD, no thyromegaly , 

Chest: 	CTA&P bilaterally, no wheezes, crackles, or ronchi

CVS:  	RRR nl S1 S2, no m/r/g, JVP= 7 , 2+ brisk carotids w/o bruits

Abd:  	soft, NT/ND, nl BS, no HSM

Extr:  	WWP, no c/c/e 2+ DP/PT bilaterally

Neuro:   A+OX3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact, Motor 5/5 UE and LE, Sensory intact. DTR's 2+ and symmetric in bilat LE and UE. Toes down bilaterally. F to N nl, RAM nl.  

Skin: -rash





DATA:

 

          	08/15/92  

          	12:19     



NA        	138       	          	          	          	          

K         	3.8       	          	          	          	          

CL        	108       	          	          	          	          

CO2       	25.6      	          	          	          	          

BUN       	16        	          	          	          	          

CRE       	1.0       	          	          	          	          

GLU       	104     

 

          	08/15/92  	08/15/92  

          	22:40     	13:09     



CK        	40(L)     	          	          	          	          

CK-MB     	1.9       	Negative  	          	          	          

CKMBRI    	see detail	          	          	          	          

TROP-I    	          	Negative  	          	          	          

TROP-T    	<0.01     	          	          	          	          

Lab Results for: 	WOOD, CADE H



Test Name 	SMI       

          	08/15/92  

          	12:13     



WBC       	8.5       	          	          	          	          

RBC       	4.11(L)   	          	          	          	          

HGB       	12.4(L)   	          	          	          	          

HCT       	34.8(L)   	          	          	          	          

MCV       	85        	          	          	          	          

MCH       	30.1      	          	          	          	          

MCHC      	35.5      	          	          	          	          

PLT       	185       	          	          	          	          

RDW       	14.3      	          	          	          	          

DIFFR     	Received  	          	          	          	          

METHOD    	see detail	          	          	          	          

%NEUT     	88(H)     	          	          	          	          

%LYMPH    	6(L)      	          	          	          	          

%MONO     	4         	          	          	          	          

%EOS      	2         	          	          	          	          

%BASO     	0         	          	          	          	          





CXR:	

New mild interstitial pulmonary edema.



EKG:	Nl sinus rhythm, L axis deviation, nl intervals, T wave inversions I, aVL, T wave flattening V3-V6, old inferior infarct.



Echo 11/07 - There is symmetric left ventricular hypertrophy.  There are no obvious segmental wall motion abnormalities.  Theestimated ejection fraction is 73 %.



___________________________________________



Impression: Pt. is a 59 y.o. male with DLBCL dx'ed 11/07 s/p CHOP-R, HTN, hyperlipidemia, GERD, and anemia who p/w acute onset SOB in the setting of a BP = 178/108 likely 2/2 flash pulmonary edema.





Plan: 

CHF - pt.'s PE resolved s/p 20 mg IV lasix, administration of lopressor, and NTG. He showed no signs of volume overload during the physical exam. Chest CT showed no acute hemorrhage, PTX, or lymphangitic spread (preliminary read). Follow-up official CT read. No contrast was given, therefore, acute SOB could not be secondary to contrast allergy. This pt.'s salty diet and uncontrolled HTN most likely led to the acute decompensation. No evidence of infection. Pt. will receive an Echo to evaluate for possible worsening LVEF s/p antrhacycline chemo vs. diastolic dysfunction with LV hypertrophy. F/U BNP. Will re-dose lasix only if necessitated by clinical signs of volume overload.

Angina - This pt. has EKG changes and pain that is possibly cardiogenic in origin. Will obtain serial enzymes to r/o MI. Begin ASA, increase lopressor to 50 TID, captopril instead of lisinopril for easier titration of BPs, 2LO2 via nasal canula. Consider stress test before d/c.

Prophylaxis - fragmin 5000 SC QD. SOB resolved after lasix + lopressor. Unlikely PE in this setting but pt. is hypercoagulable given malignancy. Low threshold for CT PE protocol.

GERD-Omeprazole.

Onc - Will check uric acid and LDH to eval. for possible TLS. Unlikely given normal electrolytes and good renal function. CT shows no lymphangitic spread but must f/u official read in the AM.



_________________________________

Henderson Xin, MD

Team 3 Intern

Department of Internal Medicine

Saint Marys Infirmary

Pager #44348








      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-07-10



Kaur, Xan G

Internal Medicine, Buite N

Victor Cullen State Hospital, 4th Hloor , Aoom 498

Cortland, IL, 75166-9513



		RE: CADE  WOOD

07/10/2093

Admission Note



			



BIGELOW U INTERN ADMISSION NOTE



PATIENT: WOOD, CADE

MRN: 6691247

ATTENDING: WEISS

PCP: OTTO, SUZANNE

CODE: FULL



			

CC: Testicular pain 



HPI:  60 yo male with a 5 day history of sharp testicular pain, increased frequency that would awake him 5-6 times a night, and burning on urination. Pt states that the pain would come and go, and was a 10/10. Pt began getting up so many times at night that he decreased his PO intake to decrease his urination. The pain continued to get worse and he went to his PCP who sent him to the EW



EW course: in the EW pt was found to have a CRE of 3, which is elevated from his baseline of 1.6. Pt was cathed and immediately put out 300ccs of dark yellow fluid. A UA was found to be positive and the pt was started on Levo. On presentation the pt denied any blood, d/c, penile pain, n/v/, f/c or dizziness, trouble starting or stopping stream.  Pt was stooling normally, and has not had any sexual contacts in the last 10 years.



ROS: Per HPI: No F/C/NS.  No CP/Palps.  No Orthopnea/PND/LE edema/Claudication. No SOB/cough/hemoptysis/wheezing/sore throat/rash.  No hematochezia/melena. No delta MS/LOC. No slurring of speech, unilateral weakness.  No exposures/ingestions/recent travel.



PMH:   

Hypertension

Hyperlipidemia

Colonic Poilyp / tubular adenoma  (repeat colonoscopy Q3 years)

LGI bleed

Diverticulitis

Lymphoma B cell treated w CHOP(2091)

CHF

Neuropathy (likely due to vincristine

Echo 8/08 EF 46 % Hypo kinetic LV esp. inf/posterior



Medications on admission (confirmed with patient):

Zestril 40MG PO qd 

lopressor 50MG bid

lasix 20MG qd

Omeprozole 20mg qd

HCTZ 12.5MG qd. 

PYRIDOXINE HCL 50MG PO qd. 

Proventil MDI 2PUFFS q4 prn.  

NIASPAN 500MG 1-2 QHS.

CETAPHIL  topically prn

CLOBETASOL PROPIONATE 0.05% cream topically bid prn.  

aspirin 81MG qd.



ALL:  Demerol

SH: 1 pack year history, - ETOH, -Drugs

FH:    Pt. Lives alone, no kids not married



Physical Exam:  

V:  98.1, HR 75, rr 18 O2 97% RA

Gen:  AAO x3 nad, obese well appearing gentleman

HEENT: PERRL, EOMI, sclera anicteric.    

Neck:  Supple, no thyromegaly, no carotid bruits, JVP 

Nodes: No cervical or supraclavicular LAN

Cor: (difficult exam, pt obease) RRR S1, S2 nl.  No m/r/g.  No S3, S4

Chest: CTAB  

Abdomen: +BS Soft, ND.  No HSM, slight tenderness in super pubic region. Midline ABD scar from SP to diaphragm. + CVA tenderness. 

Genital: Normal genital with some tenderness in the epydidimis of the right teste. No erthema.

Ext: No C/C/E . Diminished light touch sensation on hands and feet. Varicosities on L leg, painful to touch.

Skin: No rashes.        

Neuro: non-focal



Labs and Studies:

U/S:

IMPRESSION:

1.  Normal pulsed and color Doppler flow within both testes,

Without evidence for torsion.

2.  Bilateral hydroceles and a right varicocele.

3.  Bilateral renal cysts



Test Name SMI       

          07/09/93  

          10:21     



WBC       15.5(H)                                           

RBC       4.34(L)                                           

HGB       13.4(L)                                           

HCT       37.0(L)                                           

MCV       85                                                

MCH       30.9                                              

MCHC      36.2                                              

PLT       216                                               

RDW       14.4                                              



			

NA        138                                               

K         3.8                                               

CL        109(H)                                            

CO2       25.1                                              

BUN       40(H)                                             

CRE       3.0(H)                                            

GLU       136(H)   



			

          07/09/93  

          13:25     



UA-GLUC   Negative                                          

UA-KET    Negative                                          

UA-SPGR   1.010                                             

UA-BLD    Negative                                          

UA-PH     5.0                                               

UA-ALB    Negative                                          

UA-NIT    Positive                                          

UA-WBC    Trace                                             



			





A/P:

1.ARF: Possible Post-obstructive. Will hold ACE, hctz and lasix. Due to possibility of being pre-renal.

 Will get a UA, Urine sodium and CRE and will treat with levofloxicin adjusted for renal clearance at 250mg po qd. Will send urine for Culture and sensitivities. Will get urine sediment and osmols. Will not order PSA due to instrumentation. Must consider reoccurrence of lymphoma, new malignancy secondary to cancer chemo? Will consult renal in the AM, and consider getting UPEP, BJ protein, ANA. Part of ARF may be secondary to fluid restriction by the Pt. Will give NS at a rate of 150cc an hour x 1L. Pt with know CHF will watch fluid.

2. UTI: pt on Levo pending culture and sensitivities.

3. Varocele: Will consult urology in the Am. Pt is currently without pain.

4.HTN: Hold all meds but lopressor. Will watch BP.

5. Prophylaxis: Pt ambulatory. Will resume GI prophylaxis.



_______________________________________________________________________

Name: Xan Kaur M.D.                          

Pager #29827

PGY-1











Signed electronically by Kaur, Xan G on Jul 10, 2093     



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>