<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-10-01
Office Note   Bobbie Albert #7000963		     Tuesday, October 01, 2074





Reason for visit

Mr. Albert is a 39-year-old American man status post bilateral lung transplantation due to cystic fibrosis and a history of HCV. He now presents with rising creatinine over the past three months and is referred by Dr. Benjamin Earnest.



Previous History and HPI

1)	CKD     Normal renal function until transplantation in 8/03/73, Crea 0.9 (weight 280lb). ARF during transplant admission, peak Crea 2.9. Post-tx Creatinine 1.8    2.0. Slow rise to 2.5 in 6/74, then episode of low blood pressure and fatigue. Cellcept and Norvasc were stopped. Crea rise from 1.8 to 3.3, yesterday 3.0. No foamy urine noted. Since 12/73 receives Parmidronate IV q3months. Estimated creatinine clearance 50-65ml/min.

2)	Cystic fibrosis     h/o multiple pneumonia, also aspergillus pneumonia. During admission for transplantation  7/73 MRSA sinusitis. 10/73 pneumomedistinum.

3)	h/o HCV postive 60-68, since then negative x2

4)	Hypertension.

5)	Hypercholesterolemia

6)	Gout for several years, several attacks, responding to Colchizine

7)	Obstructive sleep apnea, on Bipap

8)	Obesity, 340 lb peak post transplant, now 326 lb

9)	AVN right knee and hip



Allergies

NKDA



Medications

Neoral 150/175 bid, Prednison 15 qod, Bactrim SS tiw, Acyclovir 200 bid, Lipitor 40, Atenolol 50, MgGluconate 500 tid, Ca 600 bid, Vit D 50,000, Reglan 10 tid. Pamidronate IV q3months



Social-, Work-, and Family- History

Married with other lung transplant recipient (tx 9 years ago). No family history of renal disease. Nonsmoker, Marketing Manager.



ROS:

Good appetite, no skin itching. Drinks little according to wife. Poor energy level. Heart, lung, GI system without abnormal finding. No renal stones, no recurrent UTIs, urine amount unchanged. Occasional cramping while walking. Exercises in fitness studio.



Physical Exam

BP     R 150/105  L  145/100		HR    	64	weight 327 lbs. 

FS limited due to cataract. Moon facies, short neck.

OC     moist tongue. JVP ~ 8 cm.

No bruit neck/abdomen. distant heart sounds. Lungs clear.

Abdomen soft, spleen not palpated, liver ~12cm. Trace edema.

Appeared oriented, appropriate concerns. Speaks slowly.



Laboratory Values

9/30/74	Na 142, K 3.8,  Cl 106, Co2 24, BUN 35, Crea 3.0, Glu 85. 

Alb/tProt 3.5/7.5, Ca 8.9, Phos 3.5, Mg 1.1. AP 175.

 	WBC 7.2, Hgb 10.8, PLT 217

 	CyA 236, TGL 323, Chol 175, LDL 81, HDL 29.			



Today	UA     1.015/5.0/1+P. 

	Sed     one cast with dense pigmented inclusion (?cells),otherwise bland.



Impression and Plan

Mr Albert has progressive renal insufficiency, he does currently not require renal replacement therapy. Contributors may be Cyclosporine toxicity and intermittent dehydration. However, the recent more rapid rise makes biphosphonate toxicity or HCV-associated renal disease a worthy consideration. Bobbie also has uncontrolled hypertension and anemia.



I took the liberty to order a 24-hour urine collection, a kidney US, as well as SPEP, UPEP, cryoglobulin level, Fe-studies. Norvasc 5mg PO qd was also returned to his regiment. For now, I suggest to hold further infusions of Parmidronate until more data is available.



Bobbie will have a blood pressure check in 2 weeks (when he is in Nappanee for another appointment), and I will see him in four weeks. At that point he will be evaluated for Epogen/Aranesp.









Thomas Yockey, MD. 

Renal Fellow

(for Dr. Yousef Pugh)







CC: Dr Benjamin Earnest





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-02-01

             				

 Critical care					 





TRANSPLANT FELLOW ADMIT NOTE





HPI: 42 year old man s/p bilateral lung transplantation for bronchiectasis in 7/73 transferred from Burlington Obstetrics Gynecology Center for further evaluation of N/V/D, fever and hypoxia.  Over the past six weeks he had reported a slow decline in respiratory function  prompting a recent admission here 1/23 -25/77 for elective bronchoscopy to rule out rejection.  He noted a slight spontaneous improvement a few days before that admission.  Bronchoscopy showed no rejection but washings did grow M. catarrhalis -levaquin was begun on 1/25/77.  Pt reports continued slow improvement in dyspnea following discharge.  Yesterday morning he developed watery diarrhea (no blood or mucus) soon followed by nausea and vomiting (no blood or coffee grounds).  He went to BOGC and describes feeling increased dyspnea.  Found to be febrile to 101F and hypoxic (SpO2 94%, PaO2 53) and started on supplemental oxygen.  GI symptoms have since improved and pt is tolerating PO.  Denies chest pain, palpitations, cough, rash, HA, rhinorrhea, sore throat at any point during this illness.  Currently no dyspnea at rest.  



PMH: OSA, obesity, osteoporosis, gout, HTN, CRI, avascular necrosis of R hip/knee, depression, psoriasis



Current Meds: 

Imm: neoral 125 mg po bid, cellcept 500 mg po bid, prednisone 30 mg po qd

Abx: levaquin 500 mg po qd (1/25), bactrim ss 1 po tiw, acyclovir 200 mg po tid

Other: atenolol 25 mg po qd, norvasc 5 mg po qd, nexium 20 mg po qd, MgGlu 500 mg po tid, Kdur 20 mEq po qd, lipitor 40 mg po qd, Ca citrate/vit D/MVI, lasix 40 mg po qd, cozaar 100 mg po qd



SH: Lives in Florida with wife.  Works at ion media networks.



FH: noncontributory



Objective:

Vitals:  Tm 96.5  HR 71  BP 145/91  RR 22  SpO2  97% on 2L NC

Gen: NAD, obese

HEENT/neck: OP clear, MMM

Lungs/chest: CTA bilat, reduced breath sounds

Heart: RRR w/o m/r/g

Abd: SNTND +BS

Extr: no c/c/e, 2+ pulses



Lab: significant for

BUN 36, Cr 2.1

WBC 3.4, Hct 39, Plt 115



Micro: 

Nasal swab 1/31/77 - negative viral panel

Lung washings 1/23/77 - moderate M. catarrhalis



Path: Transbrochial biopsy 1/23 - negative for tissue rejection



CXR 1/31: Unremarkable 



Impression: 

42 year old man s/p bilateral lung transplant 7/73 for bronchiectasis developed acute GI illness in setting of levaquin tx for recent respiratory infection.  Now afebrile and with resolution of GI symptoms.  Remains somewhat dyspneic with normal BP and HR.  Azotemia possibly attributable to dehydration though concern for other etiologies as per Dr. Reilly's note.  WBCs reduced from recent levels.



Recommendations: 

GI illness: Mostly asymptomatic now though some concerning abnormalities remain (O2 requirement, low plt, low WBC, high Cr).  Remains hemodynamically stable.  Await results of panculture including stool studies (including C diff, E coli, Camphylobacter) when available.  

Transplant: Continue current immunosuppression and prophylactic abx.  Will consider holding cellcept, valcyte if leukopenia persists/worsens.  Follow daily cyclosporin troughs.  No evidence of rejection on recent biopsy.

Dyspnea: Consider aspiration though CXR negative, will follow.  Hold abx for now.

Renal: Azotemia of unclear etiology, follow up labs pending.  Renal consult per Dr. Reilly.









 

___________________

Oscar B. Stanley, M.D.

Pulmonary Fellow

Pager: 34348







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-05-14

 

MEDICINE TEAM 4 ADMIT NOTE
Name: Albert, Bobbie
MRN: 7000963
Date of Admission: 5/14/79
Attending: Dr. Benjamin Earnest

CC/ID: pneumonia

HPI: 
44M s/p double lung transplant in 2073 for bronchiectasis (on 2L home O2), HTN, and CKD, who is directly admitted to team 4 for PNA.  Pt. was in USOH until about 3 weeks ago when he first noted a sore throat.  He had a sick contact at work.  Pt. saw his PCP, who prescribed 10 days of Levaquin.  Although the sore throat resolved after about one week, pt. developed a cough producing yellowish sputum and chest congestion.  Pt. called his pulmonologist   s office (Dr. Earnest) and was advised to have a sputum sample sent to a lab in Florida, where pt. lives.  He was also advised to complete his Levaquin course, which ended on 5/10.  Despite completing levaquin course, cough, congestion, and mild DOE (occasionally had to increase home O2 from 2L to 3L) persisted.  He noted a temperature to 100 on 5/8, no chills, no chest pain.  Pt. again called Dr. Earnest, who ordered chest CT, PFTs, and obtain sputum culture results from lab in Florida, which revealed a pathogen resistant to cipro (did not test susceptibility to levoflox) and susceptible to zosyn and cefepime.  Pt. is admitted for IV antibiotics.

ROS: 
Negative in detail, including no recent unintentional weight changes, HA, neck pain/stiffness, change in vision, palpitations, abd pain, N/V/D/C, blood in stool, dysuria, hematuria, joint/muscle pain, numbness, or weakness.

PMH:
S/p double lung transplant (7/73) for bronchiectasis
Hypertension
CKD (baseline Cr 1.8-2.4)
OSA
Obesity
Osteoporosis
Avascular necrosis of R hip/knee
Depression
Psoriasis

Meds on Admit: 
acyclovir  200mg po TID
albuterol inhaler  90mcg/spray inh q4-6h PRN
Albuterol Nebulizer  3ml (0.083%) neb q4h PRN
azithromycin  250mg tab po MWF
Bactrim  single strength 1 tab po MWF
calcium citrate  600 mg po bid
Cellcept  500mg po bid
colistin  150 mg inhaled qd
Cozaar  100mg po qd
doxycycline  100mg po bid
Lasix  40 mg po qd
Lipitor  40mg po qd
magnesium gluconate  1000mg po tid
multivitamins  1 tab po qd
Nexium  20mg po qd
Norvasc  5 mg po qd
pamidronate  60mg iv q 6 months
potassium chloride  20mEq po bid
prednisone  15mg po qd
Prograf  1mg 6 caps po bid
Reglan  5mg po qac, qhs
Toprol XL  50 mg po qd
vitamin d  50,000 IU po q week

Allergies:
NKDA

Family Hx: 
Breast cancer- relatives

Social Hx:
Lives in Florida w/ wife.  Never smoked.  No EtOH.

PE
Floor vitals: T 97.9, HR 77, BP 127/67, RR 20, Sat 93% on 2L
Gen: alert, in NAD
HEENT: NCAT, PERRLA, EOMI, MMM, OP clear
Neck: Supple, no cervical or supraclavicular LAN, 2+ carotids, no bruits, no appreciable JVD 
Chest: scattered course BS, expiratory wheezes 
Cor: RRR, distant heart sounds, no m/r/g 
Abd: soft, NT, ND, BS+
Extrem: trace LE edema, 2+ PT pulses bilat.
Neuro: alert and oriented x3, CN 2-12 intact, 5/5 motor strength and nl. sensation to light touch in all extremities

Data
Test Name 	MARY       
          	05/14/79  
          	08:18     

NA        	144       	          	          	          	          
K         	4.4       	          	          	          	          
CL        	106       	          	          	          	          
CO2       	28.3      	          	          	          	          
BUN       	36(H)     	          	          	          	          
CRE       	2.5(H)    	          	          	          	          
GLU       	80        	          	          	          	          

Test Name 	MARY       
          	05/14/79  
          	08:18     

CA        	9.9       	          	          	          	          
TBILI     	0.3       	          	          	          	          
TP        	7.1       	          	          	          	          
ALB       	4.0       	          	          	          	          
GLOB      	3.1       	          	          	          	          

Test Name 	MARY  
	05/14/79       
          	08:18     

ALT/SGPT  	13        	          	          	          	          
AST/SGOT  	10        	          	          	          	          
ALKP      	88        	          	          	          	          
TBILI     	0.3       	          	          	          	          

Test Name 	MARY       
          	05/14/79       
          	08:18     

CHOL      	115(T)    	          	          	          	          
TRIG      	89        	          	          	          	          
HDL       	51        	          	          	          	          
LDL       	46(T)     	          	          	          	          
CHOL/HDL  	2.3(T)    	          	          	          	          

Test Name 	MARY       
          	05/14/79       
          	08:18     

WBC       	10.9      	          	          	          	          
RBC       	4.36(L)   	          	          	          	          
HGB       	13.9      	          	          	          	          
HCT       	40.7(L)   	          	          	          	          
MCV       	94        	          	          	          	          
MCH       	31.9      	          	          	          	          
MCHC      	34.1      	          	          	          	          
PLT       	159       	          	          	          	          
RDW       	15.7(H)   	          	          	          	          
DIFFR     	Received  	          	          	          	          
METHOD    	Auto      	          	          	          	          
%NEUT     	79(H)     	          	          	          	          
%LYMPH    	11(L)     	          	          	          	          
%MONO     	7         	          	          	          	          
%EOS      	3         	          	          	          	          
%BASO     	0         	          	          	          	          
ANEUT     	8.63(H)   	          	          	          	          
ALYMP     	1.20      	          	          	          	          
AMONS     	0.71(H)   	          	          	          	          
AEOSN     	0.33(H)   	          	          	          	          
ABASOP    	0.04      	          	          	          	          
ANISO     	None      	          	          	          	          
HYPO      	None      	          	          	          	          
MACRO     	None      	          	          	          	          
MICRO     	None      	          	          	          	          

Test Name 	MARY       
          	05/14/79       
          	08:18     

TACRO     	11        	          	          	          	          

Chest CT: pending

PFTs: FEV1, FVC and FEV1/FVC are reduced. TLC is normal. FRC is normal. RV is
increased.  RV/TLC ratio is increased. Resistance is increased; specific
conductance is decreased. Single breath diffusion capacity is reduced.

Floor EKG: sinus at 75 bpm, nl. Axis, nl. Intervals, no significant ST-T abnormalities

Assessment/Plan:
44M s/p double lung transplant in 2073 for bronchiectasis, HTN, CKD, admitted w/ PNA.
PNA
Tx w/ Cefepime and Zosyn given susceptibilities from OSH sputum cx
Cont. colistin nebs, albuterol nebs
F/u chest CT
s/p Lung Transplant
Cont. Cellcept, tacrolimus, prednisone
Cont. bactrim, doxycycline, acyclovir, azithromycin
CV
Cont. cozaar, lasix, lipitor, norvasc, Toprol
CKD
Creatinine appears to be at baseline, will follow.
OSA
CPAP at night
Prophy
Heparin sc
Omeprazole



_________________
Garrett Albert, M.D.
PGY-3
#54644




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-10-31

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.


Team 4 Admission H&amp;P


Name: Bobbie Albert
MRN: 7000963
Date of Admission: 10/31/79
Admitting Physician: Dr. Atkinson
PCP: Benjamin Earnest, MD
Code Status: Full 
Source of Hx:   Patient and chart, pulmonary fellow evaluation


ID/CC: presumed lung rejection s/p lung transplant


HPI: 
Mr. Albert is a 44-year-old man with bronchiectasis who underwent bilateral lung transplantation in July 2073. He was seen in the post-transplant clinic on 10/29/2079 with complaints of worsening dyspnea on exertion over the preceding two weeks to the point that he has been symptomatic with ADLs and after walking 4-5 steps. He says that his prednisone dose was decreased from 12.5 to 10 mg daily approximately 1 month ago and that his tacrolimus dose had been decreased earlier this year. At baseline, he is on supplemental oxygen (2L NC at rest and 4L NC with exertion). He denied F/C/cough/chest pain/jaw or L arm pain/sick contacts. Recently had a treadmill ETT and TTE in Florida. Also some morning headaches for the past 5 days. Denies vision change, sinus pain or drainage. No recent leg pain/swelling or prolonged travel. No recent travel outside of Fountain Of The Four Rivers area. Has a puppy at home; no other recent animal contact. No recent falls. His PFTs demonstrated a worsening FEV1 and CT scan demonstrates evidence of worsening obstruction, likely related to rejection. He is being admitted for treatment of acute on chronic rejection.


ROS:   negative in detail except as noted above. 


PMH/Old Data
1.Bronchiectasis. Status post bilateral lung transplantation 8/02/2073. Acute and chronic rejection. Admitted with bronchietasis flare with Serratia in 5/79, tx with cefepime and pip/tazo.
2.History of PsA, Serratian in sputum.On colisitin nebs
3.OSA. On CPAP 14 cm H20 with 4L humidified oxygen
4.Osteoporosis
5.AVN Right hip and knee
6.Obesity
7.HCV
8.HTN
9.Depression
10.    Psoriasis
11.    CRI
12.    Gastroparesis
13.    Cataracts
14.    Hyperlipidemia


PSH
1.bilat lung transplant 7/73


Allergies/Adverse Reactions: NKDA


Outpatient Meds on Admit: 
1.Acyclovir 200 mg PO tid
2.Albuterol MDI 90mcg Q4-6H PRN
3.Albuterol neb Q4H PRN
4.Azithromycin 250 mg QMWF
5.Bactrim SS QMWF
6.Calcium citrate 600 mg BID
7.Cellcept 500 mg BID
8.Colistin neb 150 mg daily
9.Cozaar 100 mg daily
10.    Doxycycline 100 mg BID
11.    Flonase nasal spray BID
12.    Lasix 40 mg daily
13.    Lipitor 40 mg daily
14.    Magnesium gluconate 1000 mg TID
15.    MVIdaily
16.    Nexium 20 mg daily
17.    Norvasc 5 mg daily
18.    Pamidronate60 mg Q6 months
19.    KCl 20mEq BID
20.    Prednisone 10 mg daily
21.    Tacrolimus 5 mg PO BID
22.    Reglan 5 mg AC and at bedtime
23.    Toprol XL 50 mg daily
24.    Vitamin D50,000 units weekly


Soc Hx: Married to another transplant patient. No children. Lives in Florida. Works as a Electric Appliance Repairer. Lifelong non-smoker. No EtOH or illicits.


Fam Hx:   no bronchiectasis, no h/o CAD


Physical Exam
VS:       T 96.3, BP 124/74, HR 85, RR 25, O2 Sat 94 2L NC at rest; 273 lbs (124 kg)
Gen:        pleasant obese gentleman, speaking in full sentences with minimal pauses to breath
HEENT: EOMI, OP clear, MMM; no sinus tenderness or rhinorrhea
Neck:       supple, no JVD
Lungs:      limited inspiratory &amp; expiratory air movement , no wheezes/rhonci 
Cor:         RRR, nl S1-S2, no M/R/G
Abd:        obese, soft/NT/ND, + BS, no HSM; no midline spinal tenderness
Extr:        warm, no C/C/E, 2+ radial &amp; 1+ PT pulses 
Neuro: A+Ox3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact, motor 5/5 UE and LE, sensory intact


Labs
NA            143                                                               
K             4.7                                                               
CL            104                                                               
CO2           34.2(H)                                                           
BUN           28(H)                                                             
CRE           2.4(H)                                                            
GLU           103                                                               


CA            9.6                                                               
TBILI         0.3                                                              
TP            7.4                                                               
ALB           4.2                                                               
GLOB          3.2                                                               


ALT/SGPT    17                                                                
AST/SGOT    17                                                                
ALKP          98                                                                
TBILI         0.3                                                               


CHOL          131(T)                                                            
TRIG          164(H)                                                            
HDL           55                                                                
LDL           43(T)                                                           
CHOL/HDL    2.4(T)                                                            


HGBA1C        5.60                                                              
MEAN-GLU    101                                                               


WBC           12.3(H)                                                          
RBC           4.54                                                              
HGB           14.4                                                              
HCT           44.7                                                              
MCV           98                                                               
MCH           31.7                                                              
MCHC          32.2                                                              
PLT           162                                                               
RDW           15.2(H)                                                           
%NEUT         87(H)                                                             
%LYMPH        7(L)                                                              
%MONO         5                                                                 
%EOS          1                                                                 
%BASO         0                                                                 


TACRO         7                                                                 


Microbiology:
10/29/79 CMV antigenemia negative (was low-positive most recently in 7/74)


Imaging:
Chest CT 10/29/2079Scattered mosaic attenuation vs. GGO, bronchiectasis, mildly increased since 5/14/2079.No effusions or lymphadenopathy.


Studies
Floor EKG:NSR at 80, NL intervals &amp; ST-segments. No significant change from priors.


10/29/79 CXR:No evidence of anastomotic rupture. No signs of pneumonia, acute or chronic rejection, lymphoproliferative disease. Cardiomediastinal silhouette is within normal limits without signs of CHF.


10/29/79 chest CT: worsening airway obstruction per pulmonary fellow; official radiology read pending


Impression and Plan:
44y M with bronchiectasis s/p bilateral lung transplant, presenting with dyspnea. Concerning for acute-on-chronic rejection. PCP also a consideration with subacute dyspnea, but pt has been on appropriate prophylaxis and CXR/chest CT not suggestive of PCP. No other sx suggesting an infectious etiology, including sinusitis.


1.       Resp. Dyspnea, concerning for acute-on-chronic lung rejection.
-    methylprednisolone 500 IV qday x 3 days, then prednisone taper
-    continuing other outpatient immunosupressants; following daily tacrolimus levels
-    IV ganciclovir while on high-dose steroids
-    Check sputum gram stain + culture


2.       Renal: CRI at baseline (baseline Cr 1.9-2.3). Renal dosing for all medications.


3.       FEN
- no concentrated sweets, low saturated fat, low sodium; follow BID FSG while on pulse-dose steroids


4.       Prophy:   enoxaparin; omeprazole (on PPI as outpatient)


5.       Dispo:pending improvement in dyspnea &amp; functional status


Code: FULL


Discussed with transplant team and pulmonary team.




______________Craig Adams, M.D.
MARY Medicine PGY-3
Pager #70849




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-08-21



 
TEAM 4 ADMISSION NOTE 



PATIENT: Albert, Bobbie

MRN: 7000963   

ADMIT DATE:   8/21/82                TIME:  0515 AM

PCP:   Dr. Alexander Petersen

Attending: Dr. Atkinson, transplant    

Code status: 
Full

Source: Patient, patient record



CC: dyspnea, hypoxia 



HPI: 

47 yo man with long-standing bronchiectasis requiring double lung transplant in 2073 who states that for approximately the last month he has felt occasionally dyspneic and &#8220;dizzy&#8221; (which he more specifically describes as a sensation of unsteadiness, not vertigo-like), along with several discrete episodes of nausea with vomiting (maybe three days in the last month, the last time yesterday). 
He was visiting friends/family near The Woodlands, when on 8/20 he awoke feeling acutely dyspneic and weak.



He presented to Marion Memorial Hospital, where he was noted to be saturating in the high 90s on 2L, which is his baseline (4L with activity). Other notable labs were a Cr of 2.3, BNP 84, INR subtherapeutic at 1.4. CXR was read as no acute processHe was thought to be wheezy, and was given 10 mg of dexamethasone IV, nebulizers. He was empirically started on a heparin drip (800 unit bolus, 1800 units/hr) given his h/o DVT and a subtherapeutic INR. He was then transferred to MARY. 



In the ED here his INR was 2.4 (and his PTT was over 150). Upon interview here, he endorses the above history. Vitals upon arrival to the ED 97.3 79 141/95 24 100%2L.



He also notes that his INR had been stable recently (followed by his PCP) on his current dose of 4 Coumadin daily (except 2 on Mon/Fri). 



He denies cough, chest pain, GI symptoms, URI symptoms



15-point ROS negative except as in HPI with following additions: none.



MEDICAL HISTORY

Bronchiectasis, diagnosed as a toddler, with double lung transplant in 2073

Chronic renal insufficiency (baseline cr from 2.3-3)

Depression

Gout

Hyperlipidemia

Hypertension

Obesity

Sleep apnea, on bipap nocturnally at 18/12

Cataracts

Lung transplantation, status post

Chronic rejection

Deep venous thrombosis in October of 2081. Plan is for perpetual anticoagulation given risk factors.

Dizziness

Hypokalemia

Hypomagnesemia

Insomnia

Pseudomonas pulmonary infection

h/o suspected cute rejection



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:

  1. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)  81 MG PO QD

  2. Acyclovir    200 MG PO BID

  3. Albuterol Nebulizer Solution  2.5 MG NEB Q8H prn dypsnea

  4. Albuterol Inhaler Hfa  1 PUFF INH Q4H prn dyspnea, wheezing

  5. Amlodipine (Norvasc)  10 MG PO QD

  6. Amoxicillin  500 MG PO  

                takke 4 tabs 1 hour prior to dental procedures

  7. Atorvastatin (Lipitor)  40 MG PO QD

  9. Azithromycin  250 MG PO QMWF


10. Bupropion Hcl Sustained Release (12 Hr Tab) (Wellbutrin Sr)  150 MG PO BID


11. Bupropion Hcl (Wellbutrin)  150 MG PO BID


12. Calcium Citrate  Alternate PO BID

                                500 mg bid


13. Colchicine   0.6 MG PO QD for gout prophylaxis


14. Colistimethate (Colistin )  150 MG NEB QD


15. Doxycycline Monohydrate  100 MG PO BID


16. Ergocalciferol  50000 UNITS PO QWEEK


17. Escitalopram (Lexapro)  20 MG PO QD


18. Esomeprazole  40 MG PO QD


19. Fluticasone Propionate Nasal Spray (Flonase  )  1 SPRAY NAS QD


20. Fluticasone Prop/Salmeterol 250/50 (Advair Diskus 250/50)  1 INHALATION INH BID


21. Ipratropium Nebulizer (Atrovent Nebulizer)  0.5 MG NEB TID prn dyapnea


22. Magnesium Gluconate  1000 MG PO TID


23. Metoclopramide Hcl  10 MG PO QID (AC + HS)


24. Metoprolol Succinate Extended Release  100 MG PO QD


25. Multivitamins  1 TAB PO QD


26. Mycophenolate Mofetil (Cellcept)  500 MG PO BID


27. Prednisone  Alternate PO QD

                12.5 mg


28. Ranitidine Hcl  150 MG PO BID


29. Tacrolimus (Prograf)  Alternate PO BID

                6 mg


30. Trimethoprim /Sulfamethoxazole Single Strength (Bactrim Ss)  1 TAB PO QMONDAY, WEDNESDAY, FRIDAY


31. Warfarin Sodium (Coumadin)  Alternate PO 

                
4 mg daily, except 2 mg Mon/Fri

NOTE THAT LASIX WAS RECENTLY DISCONTINUED BY DR. ATKINSON



ALLERGIES:  

NKDA



FAMILY HISTORY 

Notable for maternal aunt with Cancer.



SOCIAL HISTORY

The patient lives in Earle, Florida. He doesn&#8217;t currently work, but used to be a Motion Picture Manager. He has never smoked. 



PHYSICAL EXAM

VITALS:  T:  97.9   HR:   74     BP: 162/96     O2Sat: 99% 2L Weight 304 lbs

GEN&#8217;L: pleasant, no acute distress, cushingoid body habitus        

SKIN: dry, no rashes noted               

HEENT: normocephalic, atraumatic, mucus membranes moist      

NECK: no cervical lymphadenopathy noted, supple      

HEART: RRR, no m/r/g     

LUNG: CTAB &#8211; unable to appreciate any wheezes       

ABD: NT/ND/+BS                      

EXT: no c/c/e bilaterally          

NEURO: CN 2-12 intact. Strength 5/5 in all extremities, major muscle groups   



LABORATORY STUDIES 

Creatinine 2.35, glucose 239
CK and troponin I negative in ED
WBC 8.1, Hct 35, platelets 128
INR 2.3, PTT over 150 in ED
1 am tacro level pending
CXR with no evidence of infiltrate, volume overload.



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN



47-year-old man with h/o double lung transplant admitted with one-month h/o subjective dyspnea (without hypoxia), weakness, and intermittent nausea. Workup relatively unremarkable so far. History not c/w PE, lungs clear on admission exam, no fever or leukocytosis or cough endorsed. 



Dyspnea/nausea/weakness: 

-check orthostatics

-continue heparin drip at reduced rate (units/hr), recheck INR this am, continue coumadin at home dose, lower extremity ultrasound to eval for DVT (as possible proxy for PE)

-continue rglan per home regimen

-transplant service to follow

-lung exam currently clear, little suspicion for COPD flare &#8211; will resume steroids at home dose (12.5 mg)

-schedule duonebs



s/p lung transplant: missed last night&#8217;s doses of mycophenolate and tacro, got them at 4 am today in ED

-discussed with pulm &#8211; hold am dose of mycophenolate/tacro today, restart this evening

-continue prophylactic meds/abx: colistin, azithro, bactrim, doxy



Renal insufficiency: at baseline. Seems relatively euvolemic

-will continue colchicine for gout proph as this has been long-standing

-lasix still on hold

-BNP was low at OSH; don&#8217;t suspect volume overload



Chronic hypomagnesemia and hypocalcemia:

-continue mag gluconate, substitute calcium carbonate for calcium citrate



FEN: 

-follow lytes

-no MIVF

-regular diet 





PPX:

-GI: ranitidine per home regimen       

-DVT: on heparin drip/coumadin          





Code Status:        FULL (presumed)





_________________________________

Yobany Aviles, MD

Team 4

Pager  #01440




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>