<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2082-07-04


Beaumont Hospital Physician Group
229 Crowley Avenue                                    Rhodes, Yajaira
Rutland, FL 94265                            97627182
(153) 636-7011                                           07/04/82
(584) 728-8734

SUBJECTIVE: The patient returns.  She has had three
operations on her back, finally ending with a fusion of
L2-L3 and a laminectomy in that area for recurrent disk
disease  at L2-L3.  She still is having severe pain going
down her right leg and anterior knee which is unchanged or
perhaps somewhat better.  She sees Dr. Herring with
regularity.  She has seen Dr. Oscar Riggs.  She has
nothing wrong with her hips and she has had multiple CT
scans showing the numerous operations and fusion.  

MEDICATIONS:  
1.  Lipitor 20 mg q.d. 
2.  Glynase 1.5 mg b.i.d. 
3.  Trandate 100 mg q.d.  
4.  Tegretol 300 mg in a.m., 200 mg in the p.m.  
5.  Premarin 0.625 mg 30 days a month.  
6.  Provera 5 mg 12 days a month.
7.  Enteric-coated aspirin 81 mg q.d. 
8.  Calcium 1200 mg q.d. 

She is in physiotherapy presently. She is not smoking nor
drinking.  She has been eating and has gained considerable
weight.

She has no cardiopulmonary, GI or GU complaints.  She is to
see Dr. Bruce Godfrey's replacement in August and to get a
mammogram at that time.  Hopefully, she will be able to lie
on the table when that occurs.  She is now able to drive a
car, but walks with a cane and cannot lie down with any
degree of ease.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She weighs 192 lbs stripped and her
blood pressure is 160/90 in the left arm standing, pulse is
72 and regular.  She appears as a well developed, overweight
white female in pain, having to hold on while standing,
easily weeping, but pleasant.  There is no icterus, cyanosis
or edema.  The eyes reveal 2+ arcus.  Pupils are round,
reactive and equal.  Nose and throat examination is
unremarkable.  Neck veins are flat.  Carotids are 2+ and
equal and without bruit.  Thyroid small and smooth.  Lungs
are clear to P&A. The heart is not enlarged.  There is a
regular sinus rhythm and no significant murmurs.  S1 and S2
are normal.  Liver and spleen cannot be felt.  She has good
peripheral pulses.

IMPRESSION:  
1.  Diabetes mellitus type 2.  She has had an eye exam at
Mitchel Memorial Hospital this past year, but her diabetes is poorly
controlled as her blood sugars have been in the 150-200
range.  I have told her to increase her Glynase to 3 mg
twice a day until she is able to diet.
2.  L2-L3 disk with fusion. 
3.  Mild hypertension, on no medication.  Will not start any
until she loses weight.


______________________________
Brett F. Rutherford, M.D.


CC:

eScription document:0-532059

DD: 07/04/82
DT: 07/05/82
DV: 07/04/82



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-04-03


Beaumont Hospital Physician Group
090 Crowley Avenue                                    Rhodes, Yajaira
Rutland, FL 94265                            97627182
(153) 636-7011                                           04/03/83
(584) 728-8734

SUBJECTIVE:  The patient returns having been in Maine for
the winter in the past five months.  Her husband visited
ever three weeks or so.  She is walking somewhat better with
less pain but moves very slowly.  She says that for the past
two weeks she first had some substernal pressure which moved
down into her abdomen and now instead of having one bowel
movement every one or two weeks she is having a bowel
movement three times a week which is formed and not bloody. 
 She put herself on Pepto-Bismol and is gradually getting
better.

She has not had any chest pain, tachycardia, palpitations,
cough or hemoptysis.  She has no visual signs.  She has not
been seen by the ophthalmologist recently.  Her hearing is
good.  She has mammograms yearly.  She sees her gynecologist
on a yearly basis, Dr. Giles, having changed from Dr. Godfrey.
 She is not sexually active.  

She is not dieting and has not lost any weight.  Her back
pain is somewhat better.  

MEDICATIONS:  She is on the following medications:  
1.  Lipitor 20 mg q.d. 
2.  Glynase 1.5 mg b.i.d. 
3.  Avandia 4 mg q.a.m. 
4.  Trandate 100 mg q.d. 
5.  Tegretol 300 mg in the a.m. and 200 the evening (changed
to 200 mg b.i.d.).  
6.  Neurontin 200 mg b.i.d. 
7.  Premarin 0.625 mg 30 days a month.  
8.  Provera 5 mg 12 days a month.  
9.  Enteric coated aspirin 81 mg q.d.
10. Calcium 1200 mg q.d. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Her diabetes has been poorly regulated
and hopefully the Avandia will make her feel better.  She
states that she takes the Avandia in the morning and she
feels very weak at lunchtime such that she has to get an
orange juice.  She says that her blood sugar has dropped but
when she checks it, it has been around 100 mg%  and I
explained to her that it is a normal blood sugar but it may
be that the drop causes her to have symptoms.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: She weighs 192 lbs stripped which is a
weight gain for her.  Her blood pressure is 122/76 in the
right arm sitting with a wide cuff.  She appears as a well
developed, pleasant white female, grossly overweight, moving
slowly and can only get up on the examining table with help
because of her back pain.  There is no icterus, cyanosis or
edema.  The pupils are round, reactive and equal and react
equally to light and accommodation.  Nose and throat
examination is unremarkable.  Neck veins are flat.  Carotids
are 2+ and equal and without bruit.  Lungs are clear to P&A.
 Breasts reveal no masses or discharge.  The heart is not
enlarged.  There is a regular sinus rhythm and no
significant murmurs.  S1 and S2 are of normal intensity. 
Liver and spleen are not felt.  Bowel sounds are normal. 
There are no abdominal masses or tenderness.  This is a
female escutcheon.  Rectal was deferred.  She has fair
peripheral pulses and decreased vibration sense in her feet.

IMPRESSION:
1.  Diabetes mellitus, poorly regulated.  Will check
glycohemoglobin today.  
2.  Diabetic neuropathy.  
3.  L2-L3 disk with fusion.  
4.  Hypercholesterolemia on Lipitor.
5.  Weight management problem.


______________________________
Brett F. Rutherford, M.D.


eScription document:6-015285 DOeScription

DD: 04/03/83
DT: 04/03/83
DV: 04/03/83



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-08-28


Beaumont Hospital Physician Group
131 Crowley Avenue                                    Rhodes, Yajaira
Rutland, FL 94265                            97627182
(153) 636-7011                                           
(584) 728-8734

SUBJECTIVE:  The patient comes in stating that she has had 5
days of substernal pain like a "ball pressing in on her
chest."  She has also had abdominal pain and has felt quite
poorly.  She did call this service this past weekend she
states and never received a call back.  She called me this
morning, and I saw her immediately.  The pain has not gone
down her arms and it is mostly located in her chest.  She
feels occasionally like she is going to throw up, and she
says that her blood sugars have been quite high.  She does
have diabetes.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her lungs are clear to P&A.  Her
blood pressure is 130/80 in the right arm sitting with a
pulse of 64.  Her neck veins are flat, carotids 2+ and equal
without bruit.  Heart is not enlarged.  There is a regular
sinus rhythm, and no significant murmurs.  Liver and spleen
are not felt.  EKG taken shows a possible old anterior
myocardial infarction, which is a distinct change from her
last EKG with poor progression of the R waves across the
precordium.

IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  Question myocardial infarction. 
Because of her prolonged pain and changes in the EKG, I
think that she should be observed in the BH emergency
ward and attend her there.


______________________________
Brett F. Rutherford, M.D.


eScription document:7-351769 RFFocus

DD: 08/28/83
DT: 08/28/83
DV: 08/28/83



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-04-03

Beaumont Hospital Physician Group
467 Crowley Avenue                                    RHODES, YAJAIRA
Rutland, FL 94265                            97627182
(153) 636-7011                                           04/03/84
(584) 728-8734

The patient returns not having been seen since last September by
me and at which time she had some chest pain which did not turn
out to be anything significant.  She is followed up by Dr. Horne
who felt that she had a lot of anxiety and she was at that time
on lisinopril as well as her other diabetic medications.  She
comes back from Maine.  She is on the following medications:
1.  Lipitor 20 mg q.d.
2.  Glynase 1.5 mg b.i.d.
3.  Glucophage 500 mg b.i.d.
4.  Cozaar 50 mg b.i.d.
5.  Avandia 4 mg q.a.m.
6.  Trandate 100 mg q.d.
7.  Tegretol 300 mg in the a.m. 150 mg in the p.m.
8.  Neurontin 200 mg b.i.d. (she was told she could discontinue
this)
9.  Premarin and Provera discontinued.
10.  Aspirin 81 mg q.d.
12.  Calcium 1200 mg q.d.

She states today that her abdomen has been distended for the past
5 days.  She has not had a bowel movement in 10 days.  She
ordinarily has a bowel movement once every 2 weeks.  She takes
nothing to move her bowels and she is extraordinarily upset about
her daughter who is homeless.  She has provided for her daughter,
helped her get a job, and the daughter is emotionally ill, and I
have advised the patient that she should be in a mental
institution.  The patient no longer care for her daughter and her
daughter cares nothing about her father and mother.  It is a
hopeless situation and 45 minutes were spent in discussion of the
daughter's illness and what the patient would do about this.  I
have told her to use some Dulcolax suppositories and Dulcolax by
mouth for probable impacted feces, although this is not an
uncommon thing for her and I have ordered a set of blood tests to
check on her diabetes, kidney function, etc.  She has a good
physician in Maine where she is planning to move in June and
she will return to me next week for a complete physical.  She
does have diabetic neuropathy mild and diabetic nephropathy mild.
 Her back has healed.  She no longer uses a cane to walk except
on climbing stairs.  She no longer has any chest pain or
shortness of breath.  She is extraordinarily anxious and
hopefully she will listen to the advice that I gave her.  Total
time spent during this visit was 45 minutes.


______________________________
Brett F. Rutherford, M.D.

eScription document:7-9689009 EMSSten Tel

DD: 04/03/84
DT: 04/03/84
DV: 04/03/84



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>