<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2061-08-26

 



MICU Intern Admit Note, Internal Medicine



name: Goins, Jacob
MR#:  

Transfer from Linden Health Care Center

Date of Admission: 08/25/61

Full code



Contact information: 



CC/HPI:  

27yo male from Cedar Hill Lakes, Nevada w/ history of insulin-requiring DM previously followed at Cottage Sanatorium, admitted to Linden Health Care Center after becoming unresponsive during a visit to his sister in Maryland. By report, patient was sitting on the couch at his sister's house, slumped to the floor and had seizure activity x 45seconds that was witnessed by EMS sevices. Accu-checks done at that time were >500 and attempts at intubation were unsuccessful. He was transported to ER, where additional attempts to secure his airway were also unsuccessful, by 2 physicians. There appeared to be some sot of stricture in the upper airway (not obvious on CT scan). However, pt had witnessed emesis, and was placed on 100% nonrebreather mask, with Versed and propofol for sedation with adequate O2 saturation. A x-ray confirmed dependent lung infiltrates consistent with aspiration pneumonia, and pt was started on Clindamycin.



On arrival to the ER, patient was also found to have a blood pressure of 248/146. He received 50mg dose of labetolol in the ER as well as several additional doses in the ICU. In the ICU, patient did not have any further witnessed seizure activity. A Head CT demonstrated no focal lesion, IC hemorrhage or other abnormality. Pt was treated with dilantin and IV insulin infusion. Serum ketones were negative. Additional workup revealed LVH by EKG criteria, as well as renal insufficiency Cr 2.6. Urine tox was positive for benzos, but was otherwise negative.



Patient also developed leukoytosis (WBC ?) with temp of 102 degrees. Although he had minimal neck stiffness by neurology consult exam, he underwent a lumbar puncture that demonstrated a colorless clear fluid, with glucose of 108, TP 44. Grams stain was negative. Tube #4 contained 21RBCs and 7 WBCs with a diff of 96% PMNs and 4% lymphs. CSF cultures and blood cultures were also done, and are pending.



During his hospital course, patient maintained adequate oxygenation with nasal trumpet in place. ABG on 08/25/61 am was 7.36/PCO2 45/ PO2 366, with bicarb of 25 and 100% sats. His FIO2 was subsequently weaned. He remained hemodynamically stable with BP 184/88 (MAP 114) HR100, RR23, 97% on cannula. Cardiac enzymes were negative. After patient's mother arrived from Georgia, she requested transfer to BMH.



Had no reported history of hypertension or seizure disorders. Mother reports patient having occasional spells in the past, lasting 5-10minutes where patient would become non communicative, associated with elevated glucose.



PMH:

1.	Insulin dependent DM, diagnosed age 12. Was followed at Cottage Sanatorium but has not had PCP or regular care for some time.



Medications On Admission:

1.	Labetolol 20mg IV q1hr PRN MAP>120

2.	Ativan 1-2mg IV q1h PRN

3.	Insulin gtt (currently 4u/hr)

4.	Clindamycin 600mg IV q6h for aspiration pneumonitis

5.	Pepcid 20mg IV QD

6.	Dilantin 100mg IV q8h

7.	IV NTG 5mcg/min during transfer



Allergies: NKDA per OSH



Soc Hx: Lives with Mother in Waycross, and works in a store (unclear type). He leaves home for He does not smoke, but does have drinking binges reported by his mother when he associates with several groups of friends. Mother is not aware of drug use, but also cannot rule it out.

 

FH:  HTN mother and father



Exam:  	VS:  T 99 HR 92   BP 182/80 RR  20 O2sat 95-98%FIO2 RA 

General:  Responds /localizes pain, moving all extremities.

HEENT: NCAT, pupils small but reactive, eyes conjugate

Chest: CTA B

CVS: S1 S2 +S3, no murmurs.

Abd:  +BS, soft, non-tender, non-distended. Subcutaneous indurated tissue mid Left upper abdomen, 4x5cm.

Extr:  Normal bulk/tone. Multiple round dark lesions right arm; indurated 3x4cm subcutaneous areas on bilateral thighs anteriorly. No edema BLE; 2+DP.



DATA (08/25/61):



Unspecified pH                   7.42                      (7.32-7.45)

Unspecified PCO2                 35                        (35-50)        mm/Hg

Unspecified PO2                  74                        (40-90)        mm/Hg



WBC                              22.6             H        (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              42.1                      (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              14.0                      (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              5.03                      (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              677              H        (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              84                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              27.8                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             33.3                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              12.2                      (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               13.4             H        (11.3-13.3)    sec

APTT                             26.1                      (22.1-35.1)    sec



Poly                             82               H        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           10               L        (22-44)        %

Monos                            7                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %

Absolute Neuts                   18.54            H        (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  2.31                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   1.56             H        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm

Absolute EOS                     0.12                      (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.07                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm

Aniso                            None                      (NORMAL)

Hypo                             None                      (NORMAL)

Macrocytes                       None

Microcytes                       None



Sodium (Stat Lab)                145                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)             3.2              L        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)              117              H        (100-108)      mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)                   25.5                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)                   21                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)            2.5              H        (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)               233              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



Calcium                          8.9                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       1.8              L        (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Plasma Lactic Acid               2.5              H        (0.5-2.2)      mmol/L

Magnesium                        2.1              H        (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Total Protein                    7.0                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl

Albumin                          2.7              L        (3.3-5.0)      g/dl

Globulin                         4.3              H        (2.6-4.1)      g/dl

Direct Bilirubin                 0.2                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl

Total Bilirubin                  1.1              H        (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl

Triglycerides                    118                       (40-150)       mg/dl

Cholesterol                      307                                      mg/dl

High Density Lipoprotein         85                        (35-100)       mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase             81                        (45-115)       U/L

Transaminase-SGPT                27                        (10-55)        U/L

Amylase                          222              H        (3-100)        units/L

Lipase                           1.4                       (1.3-6.0)      U/dl

Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       6.0                       (0.0-6.9)      ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index             0.1                       (0.0-3.5)      %

Troponin-T                       0.04                      (0.00-0.09)    ng/ml

Transaminase-SGOT                81               H        (10-40)        U/L

Creatine Kinase                  7511             H        (60-400)       U/L

Phenytoin (Dilantin)             9.1                       (5.0-20.0)     mcg/ml



UA-Color                         AMBER                     (YELLOW)

UA-Turbidity                     TURBID                    (CLEAR)

UA-Glucose                       3+                        (NEG)

UA-Bili                          NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Ketones                       Trace                     (NEG)

UA-Specific Gravity              1.027                     (1.001-1.035)

UA-Occult Blood                  3+                        (NEG)

UA-pH                            6.0                       (5.0-9.0)

UA-Albumin                       3+                        (NEG)

UA-Urobilinogen                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Nitrite                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-WBC Screen                    Trace                     (NEG)

UA-SED-RBC                       PACKED                    (0-2)          /hpf

UA-SED-WBC                       50-100                    (0-2)          /hpf

UA-SED-Bacteria                  Moderate                  (NEG)          /hpf

Hyaline Cast                     0-2                       (0-5)          /lpf

Squamous Cells                   Many                      (NEG)          /hpf

Uric Acid Crystals               Many                      (NEG)          /hpf

Microscopic Sediment             Completed



EKG: NSR, borderline LVH

CXR:  perihilar opacities, o/w clear.



Assessment and Plan:  27yo h/o insulin dependent DM, not medically followed, p/w witnessed seizure episode in context of severe hypertension.



1.	Neuro - seizure episode / unresponsiveness with non localizing neuro exam. Concern for hypertensive encephalopathy. Pt had LP at outside hospital which did not suggest meningitis. Other possibilities include infarct, encephalitis. Neurology consulted, with recommendations for:

n	EEG 

n	MRI w/ susceptibility  to evaluate for posterior leukoencephalopathy, MRA head/neck, MRV brain

n Dilantin (continued from OSH)

n	Check tox screen, ammonia. Mother has brought in some unknown pills which we will try to identify.

2.	ID - increased WBC, low grade temp s/p LP. No bacterial source for now, but CXR with opacities suspicious for pneumonia. Will start Vancomycin and cefepime empirically, and narrow per culture results. Concern for encephalitis, as HSV can present w/ HTN and seizures. Will ask Linden Health to add HSV PCR to CSF taken from LP prior to transfer. Start Acyclovir empirically in interim.

3.	Resp - s/p multiple attempted intubations at OSH, currently breathing adequately on RA, with audible obstructive physiology. Given need for MRI, may have to sedate and intubate. Will call anesthesia. Continue intubated until MS more alert, for airway protection. Will start ARDSnet for criteria meeting low PaO2/FIO2 ratio and bilateral pulmonary infiltrates.

4.	CV- severe hypertension w/ evidence of potential end organ damage (kidney/brain/cardiac). Will control BP w/ Nipride drip, with addition of labetalol for HR control. Target goal 25% decrease to SPB~160 today, and SBP 120 the following day. Check CK/TPNs. Continue IVF for potential rhabdo.

5.	Renal - Renal failure w/ Cr 2.6, unclear baseline. Suspect acute on chronic component given DM w/ poor follow-up. Will check Urine sediment, lytes to evaluate. Reading by me is +hyaline/waxy casts but no WBC or RBC casts. Kidney U/S pending, also with Doppler to evaluate for RAS. Also check urine renin/aldo and 24hr metanephrine for pheochromocytoma, serum metanephrine, and 24hr protein for nephritic syndrome in presence of HTN and hematuria.

6.	Endo - tight glucose control; CZI drip for DM. Has gap but No ketones at OSH; did not arrive in DKA. Will need reg insulin after drip DC'd in future.

7.	Access - PIV

8.	Prophylaxis - nexium, heparin SQ, peridex, HOB 30.









Infant Ledford

#12182

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2061-10-03

 

BMH Cancer Center

Hematology Note



Fellow: James Tyler

Attending:  Cole Morgan



Date of consultation:  October 04, 2061



Diagnosis:  thrombocytosis, reactive vs. essential thrombocytosis



HPI:

27 yo African American male with recent complicated hospital stay at BMH presents to hematology clinic for first time for follow up of his thrombocytosis.



This 27 yo male with history of type I DM who does not get regular medical care in late August was  visiting family in Maryland and had sudden witnessed seizure activity.  At the time, blood sugar was >500.  Upon initial arrival to the ER in Maryland, he has BP 248/146; plt count was in 800's.  The patient was intubated, treated for HTN with labetolol and placed on IV insulin and dilantin  and transferred to BMH for further care.  



At BMH, MRI showed several small areas of infarct read as concerning for embolic CVA- echo was done showing no vegetations, no PFO, NL EF with LVH; TEE without vegetations as well.  LP was done and sent for HSV which was negative.  He underent a renal workup which showed  nephrotic range proteinuria; labs also showed rhabdoymyolysis.   Renal doppler US showed no sign of RAS.  He was continued on abx for his  aspiration PNA.  Other parts of the secondary htn workup were done including evaluation for hyper aldo, pheo.



The vent was weaned and he was extubated on the 4th.  HTN was controlled with labetolol drip with additional oral agents being added.  He continued to have intermittent fevers and was on broad antibiotics which were originally weaned off.



Hematologically, the hct and wbc fell as he was hydrated.   Plt count stayed stable in the 600's for several days before increasing on the 3rd gradually up to the 1000's.   Retics were depressed at presentation and iron studies were c/w ACD and he was started on epogen.  Initially it was felt that his thrombocytosis was most certainly reactive; CRP was >150 with ESR >100.  He left the ICU and at this point his WBC trended down and he was afebrile and more clinically stable.  But his platelets kept climbing to nearly 1.5 million.  A bone marrow biopsy was done showing no cytogenetics to suggest CML and there were elevated megakaryocytes read as concerning for a myeloproliferative process.  As well, he suffered a DVT in his subclavian/IJ on the same side as a central venous catheter.  Given his thrombocytosis and elevated plt count, he was platelet pheresed twice in the hospital.  As well, hydrea was started at this time, initially at 500mg bid and then escalated to 1000mg bid when his counts were up to 800-900 despite the medication.  As well, he suffered a small GI bleed due to an ulcer.  For this reason he was not anticoagulated but placed upon daily ASA.



He was discharged from the hospital two weeks ago and has done fairly well since then.  His energy has been good.  He denies any fevers/chills/sweats.  No bleeding/bruising.  No further swelling in his arms/legs.  He does have some occasionally blurryness in eyes immediately after taking his anti-hypertensives but no numnbess/weakness/dizziness.





Problems/PMH:

DM type 1 since age 12

no recollection of any abnormal blood counts prior to this admit



New diagnoses on this admit

renal insufficiency

nephrotic proteinuria

malignant hypertension

thrombocytosis

GI bleed- upper with ulcer visualized on EGD

small embolic appearing CVA's



Medications:

Diovan

lisinopril

Hydrea 1000 bid

ASA 81 qod

lopressor

procardia

clonidine

nexium



insulin:  am 25 regular/34 NPH, pm  20 regular/28 NPH



Allergies:

nkda



Social History:

lives in waycross; single

works in Geologist

no tob

reports social etoh



Family History:

htn



Physical Examination:



Vital Signs

BP 101/63, P 64, RR 16, Temp 98.1 F, Wt 202 lb

gen:  well-appearing male, alert, conversant, nad

heent:  supple, non-icteric, no cervical/supraclav adenopathy

chest:  clear 

cv:  reg

abd;  benign with no hsm

ext:  trace LE edema, no upper edema

skin:  scattered ulcerations on his arms with granulation tissue,  scarred vesicular changes on his neck





Data:



10/03/2061 WBC 4.1 (L),  RBC 3.95 (L),  HGB 12.0 (L),  HCT 35.5 (L),  MCV 90,  MCH 30.4,  MCHC 33.8,  PLT 601 (H)



10/03/2061 RDW 17.2 (H)



10/03/2061 DIFFR RECEIVED,  METHOD ,  %NEUT 57,  %LYMPH 36,  %MONO 3 (L),  %EOS 3,  %BASO 1



10/03/2061 ANEUT 2.35,  ALYMP 1.48,  AMONS 0.10 (L),  AEOSN 0.10,  ABASOP 0.02



10/03/2061 RETIC 1.0





Assessment and Plan:



Interesting case of a 27 yo male with insulin dependent diabetes and apparent untreated HTN who presented with seizure in setting of hypertensive emergency and is found with nephrotic syndrome, renal insufficiency, several small embolic-appearing strokes and has developed marked thrombocytopenia to 1.5 million and had subsequent provoked DVT.  He was treated for concern of essential thrombocytosis in hospital with platelet pheresis then hydrea.  Today, he presents looking well and still has a thrombocytosis despite the hydrea.  It is still not possible to tell for sure if this is still a reactive thrombocytosis vs Essential thrombocytosis.



At the moment, we will continue to treat this as ET and will continue hydrea at the current dose and ask him to take aspirin 81 mg qd.  If this is a reactive process, time should be a good diagnostic test at this should improve after he is further from his complicated hospital/icu stay.



At his next visit with us next month we will recheck his C-reactive protein, ESR, iron studies/ferritin for some idea of whether his body could still be mounting an inflammatory response to drive a reactive thrombocytosis.  If his plt count comes down, we will be able to start tapering his hydrea at that time.



Of note, in the near future, we may be able to help determine between reactive and essential process with measurement of the JAK2 kinase level.  



In the meantime, he will be meeting with his new PCP and renal physician next week.    



_____________________________________________

James B. Tyler, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2062-03-27

Hematology Clinic Progress Note 

Fellow: Inge Logan, MD
Attending:  Cole Morgan, MD, PhD

Date of visit:  March 27, 2062

Diagnosis:  Mr. Goins is a 27 yoM with thrombocytosis here for interval follow-up on hydrea.

Hematologic History:
Mr. Goins is a 27 yo male with history of type I DM formally without regular medical care who was  visiting family in Maryland and had sudden witnessed seizure activity in late August.  At the time, blood sugar was >500.  Upon initial arrival to the ER in Maryland, he has BP 248/146; plt count was in 800's.  The patient was intubated, treated for HTN with labetolol and placed on IV insulin and dilantin  and transferred to BMH for further care.  

At BMH, brain MRI showed several small areas of infarct read as concerning for embolic CVA.  Embolic work-up included an echo which showed no vegetations, no PFO, NL EF with LVH; TEE without vegetations as well.  LP was done and sent for HSV which was negative.  He underwent a renal workup which showed nephrotic range proteinuria with labs also notable for rhabdoymyolysis.   Renal doppler US showed no sign of RAS.  He was continued on abx for his  aspiration PNA.  Other parts of the secondary hypertensive work-up were done including evaluation for hyperaldosteronism and pheochromocytoma.

The vent was weaned and he was extubated on the 4th.  HTN was controlled with labetolol drip with additional oral agents being added.  He continued to have intermittent fevers and was on broad antibiotics which were originally weaned off.

Hematologically, the hct and wbc fell as he was hydrated.   Plt count stayed stable in the 600's for several days before increasing on the 3rd gradually up to the 1000's.   Retics were depressed at presentation and iron studies were c/w ACD and he was started on epogen.  Initially it was felt that his thrombocytosis was most certainly reactive (CRP was >150 with ESR >100).  He left the ICU and at this point his WBC trended down and he was afebrile and more clinically stable.  But his platelets kept climbing to nearly 1.5 million.  A bone marrow biopsy was done showing normal cytogenetics and no evidence for CML.  His bone marrow did demonstrate elevated megakaryocytes, concerning for a myeloproliferative process.  As well, he suffered a DVT in his subclavian/IJ on the same side as a central venous catheter.  Given his thrombocytosis and elevated plt count, he was platelet pheresed twice in the hospital.  As well, hydrea was started at this time, initially at 500mg bid and then escalated to 1000mg bid when his counts were up to 800-900 despite the medication.  As well, he suffered a small GI bleed due to an ulcer.  For this reason he was not anticoagulated but placed upon daily ASA.  He was discharged from the hospital in September.   

Since then he has been followed in hematology clinic.  Initially, his platelets were still in the hi 500's despite hydrea at 1000 bid.  His hematocrit was mildly depressed at this point as well (29-31%). He was re-evaluated on 12/05/61.  His platelets were 502,000.  An epo level was drawn and his hydrea was increased to 1500/1000mg.  He was re-evaluated on 12/26/61 and found to have a hematocrit of 26.2%, WBC of 2.7K, and platelets of 508,000.  His hydrea was decreased to 500mg bid. 

Interval History:
Since his last visit, he left for Wynne for one month.  When he returned, his creatinine had increased to 4.0.  A renal biopsy performed last week showed diabetic nephropathy.  He is being evaluated by Dr. Xing for dialysis and renal transplant evaluation.  

In terms of his blood disorders, the patient has been at his baseline fatigue, slightly improving over the past few months.  He has no fevers, chills, night sweats, or unexplained weight loss.  He had one episode of transient global blurry vision 3 weeks ago which resolved on its own and has not recurred.  He has no headaches, other sensory deficits, or focal neurologic symptoms.  He has no oral ulcers or skin lesions from his Hydrea.  

Problems
Diabetes mellitus type 1 
Nephrotic syndrome 
malignant hypertension 
Thrombocytosis : unclear if secondary vs essential
Renal insufficiency 
Cerebrovascular accident : embolic, unclear source. In setting of high platelet count
Unspecified GI bleed 

Medications
Hydrea (HYDROXYUREA) 500 MG (500MG CAPSULE take 1) PO bid 
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 40 MG (40MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO BID 
Nifedipine (SUSTAINED RELEASE) 90 MG (90MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Humulin N (INSULIN NPH HUMAN) 40 UNITS SC QAM 
Humulin N (INSULIN NPH HUMAN) 36 UNITS SC QPM 
Insulin REGULAR HUMAN 25 UNITS SC QAM 
Insulin REGULAR HUMAN 20 UNITS SC QPM 
Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Lisinopril 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Toprol XL (METOPROLOL SUCCINATE EXTENDED RELEASE) 100 MG (100MG TAB.SR 24H take 1) PO BID 

Allergies:  NKDA

Social History:
Lives in Waycross; single
worked in Geologist; not working now

Tobacco: Denies
EtOH: Social
Illicits: Denies

Family History:
Hypertension in mother and father.  Father has severe HTN as well as renal disease, though not on dialysis. 

Review of Systems: 
Generalized weakness and fatigue, only able to walk short distances (stable).  Denies chills, night sweats.  Negative for shortness of breath, chest pain, palpitations.  No cough, sputum production, sore throat.  No epistaxis, gingival bleeding.  No nausea, vomiting, anorexia, diarrhea, constipation.  No hematochezia, melena. No hematuria or other urinary symptoms.  All other ROS are negative in detail. 

Physical Examination:


Vital Signs
BP 128/84, P 68, RR 16, Temp 98.6 F, Wt 218 lb 
Gen:  Thin male, alert, conversant, nad
Heent:  supple, anicteric, no cervical/supraclav adenopathy, mild proptosis
Chest:  CTAP without wheeze or rub
CV:  RRR S1/S2 +S4 no m/r/g
Abd:  benign with no hsm
Ext:  trace LE edema, no upper edema, no cyanosis/clubbing
Skin:  scattered ulcerations on his arms with granulation tissue-stable,  scarred vesicular changes on his neck
Neuro: AOx3, able to ambulate without difficulty

Data:  See LMR.

Assessment and Plan:
Mr. Goins is a 27 yo male with insulin dependent diabetes and apparent untreated HTN who presented with seizure in setting of hypertensive emergency, subsequently found to have nephrotic syndrome, renal insufficiency, and several small embolic-appearing strokes.  In this setting, he has developed marked thrombocytosis to 1.5 million and had subsequent provoked DVT.  He was treated with platelet pheresis, then hydrea.  It has been unclear if this is still a reactive thrombocytosis vs essential thrombocytosis.  We are following his CBC on hydrea.

His platelets are moderately elevated (757K).  He has no evidence of recurrent thrombosis.  His current hydrea dosing cannot be increased due to his anemia.  We would advise starting erythropoetin, monitoring his blood pressure closely.  At his current platelet count, his risk of thrombosis is not greatly increased, especially as his platelets are dysfunctional due to uremia.  We would advise continuing current hydrea. 

Continue current hydrea
Monitor counts monthly
Agree with starting erythropoetin in Internal Medicine. 
Return in 4 months for follow-up of counts

The patient was seen and discussed with Dr. Morgan. 




_____________________________________________
Inge J. Logan, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2062-05-30





Internal Medicine

BARTON MEMORIAL HOSPITAL



History of present illness

			

  This was a followup visit for this 28-year-old black man with the medical problems of type 1 diabetes mellitus, hypertension, thrombocytosis, and chronic renal insufficiency. The patient states that since I last saw him, he is being evaluated further for renal transplant. In addition, attempts were made to place an AV fistula for dialysis in his right arm and this did not work out. Given that this one did not work out, a decision was made to wait to see if there was a transplant candidate for him to get a renal transplant rather than put all of the pieces in place for hemodialysis if in fact he would need it. Most recently, the patient's creatinine was 6.4 and his BUN was 46 two weeks ago.



Major Problems





Diabetes mellitus

Type 1 diabetes mellitus.  The patient's diabetes is currently well controlled on his current regimen of NPH and Regular Insulin.  Most recently, his hemoglobin A1c was 6.6 on 02/27/2062.  The patient states that all of his fingersticks at home have been consistently between 70 and 110.



Chronic renal insufficiency

The patient is being evaluated for renal transplant and possible candidate that his family members and friends will be tested to see whether there are a match shortly.



Hypertension

The patient is on a tremendous amount of medication to treat his hypertension. Currently, he is on labetalol 600 mg PO BID, furosemide 20 mg PO QD, clonidine 0.3 mg PO QHS, lisinopril 40 mg PO QD, and nifedipine XL 90 mg PO QHS. BHypertension is currently well controlled on this regimen.



Erectile dysfunction

The patient was experiencing erectile dysfunction largely on Toprol.  For this reason, the Toprol was discontinued and the patient is having less of a problem with this issue currently.



Anemia

The patient's anemia is due to multiple different factors.  He has recently been started on erythropoietin, which he is getting via injection in the Internal Medicine three times a week.  Most recently, his hematocrit was 29.4% two weeks ago.



Thrombocytosis

The patient is on Hydria 500 mg PO QD for this problem and he is being followed by Hematology.



Hyperlipidemia

The patient's hyperlipidemia is new.  Most recently, his lipids were done on 02/27/2062 and at that time his total cholesterol was 294 and his LDL was 209.  This is a new problem for the patient, given that his lipids were fairly normal six months ago.  Given this, the patient was started on Lipitor 20 mg PO QD for hyperlipidemia.  We will repeat his lipid panel at the time of his next visit in eight weeks.



Active Medications



aspirin 81mg po qd

clonidine 0.3mg po 1 tabs po q pm

furosemide 20 mg po qd

Humulin n 40 units qam sc 36 units qpm take 30-60min before a meal or hs

Hydrea 500mg po bid

Insulin syringes (u 100) 

labetalol HCl tablets 600 mg po bid

Lancets 

Lipitor 20mg po qd

lisinopril 40mg po qd

Nexium 40mg po bid take 1h before meal

nifedipine xl 90mg sr po qhs do not cut/crush/chew

Onetouch test strips 

potassium chloride 10meq po qd

regular insulin 25 units qam  sc 20 units qpm give 30-60min before a meal



Change in therapies and Renewals



Hydrea 500mg po bid QTY:60 Refills:5 Start: 10/16/2061

Toprol xl 100 mg po bid QTY:30 Refills:5 Start: 10/16/2061 End: 5/30/2062 - Inactivated

furosemide 20 mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:5 Start: 10/16/2061

labetalol HCl tablets 600 mg po bid QTY:60 Refills:5 Start: 05/30/2062

Lipitor 20mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:5 Start: 05/30/2062



Physical examination

Blood pressure 120/88  

Weight   215 pounds

General appearance   This was a well-developed, well-nourished black man, in no distress

Chest   Lungs were clear throughout to AandP

Cor   Regular rate and rhythm with no murmurs, rubs, or gallops



Selected recent labs

			

  Fingerstick blood sugar 75.



Disposition

The patient will follow up with me again in six to eight weeks.



Note transcribed by outside service

			

  Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Ali, Felicia on Jun 6, 2062     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2062-08-30



 

CCU JAR Admit Note





Name:  Jacob Goins

MR #: 6850327 (Please note that pt also has MRN 4033790)

Date of admission: 8/30/2062

Resident: Addison Keefe

Attending: Angel Vail

PCP: Felicia Ali

Source: Medical Record and Family



CC: L Arm Weakness



HPI:  28 yo RH M h/o DM1, ESRD on HD, HTN, Stroke (thought to be due to thrombocytosis), GTC in setting of HTN one year ago (and in June per family), multiple HTN episodes on many anti-hypertensives, RIJ thrombosis, had transient L arm weakness at HD followed by some difficulty speaking and change in his mental status.  He was reportedly in good health the night prior to admission and the morning of admission per his family, with no sick contacts and no travel.  At HD he was hypertensive with SBP in 200s, had transient L arm weakness and paresthesias which then resolved and had difficulty speaking and following commands after being noted by his nephrologist at an OSH to be mentating well with normal speech.  No urinary/bowel incontinence, tonic-clonic movements or syncope was noted by his providers.  He was brought to BMH ED because of these problems. 



	In the ED, his initial VS were BP 211/120 HR 88 T 98 R 18 SaO2 100% RA.   he received a Head CT which showed  no acute infarct or ICH  , an MRI which showed  no acute infarct on  DWI, but he was agitated in the scanner and could not complete the study.  He received 5 mg hydralazine iv x 2 and was started first in a TNG gtt and then on a nitroprusside gtt to 100/min titrated to a goal of MAP 120.  His BP was 251/104 at 2315. and was  His L Arm Weakness resolved, but he was agitated and he transiently wanted to leave AMA, and was admitted to the CCU for further management.



ROS:  Per HPI. Other systems negative in detail



PMH:   

a.	Thrombocytosis

1.	Followed by Dr. Morgan at BMH 

1.	-ve JAK2 mutation and -ve myeloproliferative w/u

2.	Had high ferritin, low TIBC and high ESR levels when checked in the past.

3.	On Hydrea 

b.	ESRD due to DM1 and HTN

1.	Biopsy (3/62) with advanced diabetic glomerulopathy and secondary FSGS

2.	Had R AVG (7/04) , now on HD x 1 month 3/wk.

3.	Being evaluated for transplant

c.	DM1 since age 11

1.	HgbA1C 7.6 % in 7/62

2.	Repeated hypoglycemic episodes in the past

3.	Hx of DKA

d.	HTN has had 

e.	Hyperlipidemia

f.	Anemia

g.	GTC in August last year and per family report, in June of this year - attributed to HTN.  Was briefly on dilantin, but this was d/c'd due to side effects.

h.	MRI with embolic foci in August 2061

1.	w/u proved negative - attributed to thrombophilia



Medications on admission: 

aspirin 81mg po qd 

clonidine 0.3mg po 1 tabs po q pm 

Diovan 320mg po qd 

furosemide 20 mg po qd 

Humulin n 35 units qam sc 25 units qpm 

Hydrea 500mg po bid 

Insulin syringes (u 100) 

labetalol hcl tablets 600 mg po bid 

Lancets 

Lipitor 40mg po qd 

lisinopril 40mg po qd 

Nephrocaps 1 po q d 

Nexium 40mg po bid 

nifedipine xl 90mg sr po qhs 

Onetouch test strips 

potassium chloride 10meq po qd 

regular insulin 25 units qam sc 20 units qpm



ALL:  NKDA

SH: 

Lives with:  Mother. Used to work at Bebo in Geologist, currently unemployed.

No EtOH, Illicits, Tobacco.



FH:    HTN in parents, Mother with Stroke, Father on HD, DM1, DM2, CKD in other family members.



Physical Exam:  

V:  T     99.9        BP    210/90          P      110         R       20           SaO2  100% RA

Gen:  WDWN American male following commands intermittently.

HEENT: NCAT, PERRL, EOMF, sclera anicteric.    

Neck:  Supple, no thyromegaly, no carotid bruits, JVP flat

Nodes: No cervical or supraclavicular LAN

Cor: Tachy, RR S1, S2 nl.  No m/r/g.  + S3, prominent PMI.

Chest: CTAB  anteriorly

Abdomen: +BS Soft, NT, ND.  No HSM, No CVA tenderness. L para-umbilical bruit, no pulsatile mass.

Ext: No C/C/E, warm, well-perfused, subcutaneous mass on anterior R thigh, R AV fistula with thrill.  3+ DP and PT pulses b.l. Has indwelling L arterial line.

Skin: No rashes.        

Neuro: A, O x 1 , PERRL, EOMF, Smile symmetric, Sensation grossly intact to light touch, Strength 5/5 in flexion and extension in upper and lower extremities. Reflexes 2+, toes downgoing.



Labs and Studies:

Chemistry

  Lytes/Renal/Glucose

    Sodium                 136   135-145 mmol/L     08/29/62 17:13

    Potassium              3.5   3.4-4.8 mmol/L     08/29/62 17:13

    Chloride                99L  100-108 mmol/L     08/29/62 17:13      99(L) 08/29/62 17:13

    Carbon Dioxide        30.6   23.0-31.9 mmol/L   08/29/62 17:13

    BUN                     24   8-25 mg/dl         08/29/62 17:13

    Creatinine             5.0H  0.6-1.5 mg/dl      08/29/62 17:13     5.0(H) 08/29/62 17:13

    Glucose                 91   70-110 mg/dl       08/29/62 17:13

  General Chemistries

    Bilirubin (To...       0.8   0.0-1.0 mg/dl      08/29/62 17:45

    Bilirubin (Di...       0.3   0-0.4 mg/dl        08/29/62 17:45

    Total Protein          8.0   6.0-8.3 g/dl       08/29/62 17:45

    Albumin                3.8   3.3-5.0 g/dl       08/29/62 17:45

    Globulin               4.2H  2.6-4.1 g/dl       08/29/62 17:45     4.2(H) 08/29/62 17:45

  Liver Function Tests

    ALT (SGPT)              11   10-55 U/L          08/29/62 17:45

    AST (SGOT)              29   10-40 U/L          08/29/62 17:45

    Alk Phos                76   45-115 U/L         08/29/62 17:45

    Bilirubin (To...       0.8   0.0-1.0 mg/dl      08/29/62 17:45

    Bilirubin (Di...       0.3   0-0.4 mg/dl        08/29/62 17:45



Hematology

  Complete Blood Count

    WBC                   14.9H  4.5-11.0 th/cmm    08/29/62 17:12    14.9(H) 08/29/62 17:12

    RBC                   3.88L  4.50-5.90 mil/cm   08/29/62 17:12    3.88(L) 08/29/62 17:12

    Hgb                   14.3   13.5-17.5 gm/dl    08/29/62 17:12

    HCT                   41.2   41.0-53.0 %        08/29/62 17:12

    MCV                    106H  80-100 fl          08/29/62 17:12     106(H) 08/29/62 17:12

    MCH                   36.8H  26.0-34.0 pg/rbc   08/29/62 17:12    36.8(H) 08/29/62 17:12

    MCHC                  34.7   31.0-37.0 g/dl     08/29/62 17:12

    PLT                    839H  150-350 th/cumm    08/29/62 17:12     839(H) 08/29/62 17:12

    RDW                   17.1H  11.5-14.5 %        08/29/62 17:12    17.1(H) 08/29/62 17:12

  Blood Differential %

    Differential ...  RECEIVED                      08/29/62 17:09

    Diff Method           Auto                      08/29/62 17:13

    Neutrophils             88H  40-70 %            08/29/62 17:13      88(H) 08/29/62 17:13

    Lymphs                   8L  22-44 %            08/29/62 17:13       8(L) 08/29/62 17:13

    Monos                    3L  4-11 %             08/29/62 17:13       3(L) 08/29/62 17:13

    Eos                      1   0-8 %              08/29/62 17:13

    Basos                    0   0-3 %              08/29/62 17:13

  Blood Diff - Absolute

    Neutrophil #         13.14H  1.8-7.7 th/cmm     08/29/62 17:13   13.14(H) 08/29/62 17:13

    Lymph#                1.16   1.0-4.8 th/cmm     08/29/62 17:13

    Mono#                 0.45H  0.2-0.4 th/cmm     08/29/62 17:13    0.45(H) 08/29/62 17:13

    Eos#                  0.09L  0.1-0.3 th/cmm     08/29/62 17:13    0.09(L) 08/29/62 17:13

    Baso#                 0.03   0.0-0.3 th/cmm     08/29/62 17:13

  Smear Morphology

    Anisocytosis            1+H  None               08/29/62 17:13      1+(H) 08/29/62 17:13

    Hypochromia           None   None               08/29/62 17:13

    Macrocytes              3+H  None               08/29/62 17:13      3+(H) 08/29/62 17:13

    Microcytes            None   None               08/29/62 17:13



Coagulation

  Routine Coagulation

    PT                    12.1   11.1-13.6 sec      08/29/62 17:26

    PT-INR                 1.0                      08/29/62 17:26

    PTT                   24.9   22.1-34.0 sec      08/29/62 17:26



Toxicology

  +ve for Ephedrine.



Hypercoagulation Studies

    Act Prot C Re...       2.5   >2.0               09/12/61 14:20

    Protein S (Fu...       112   70-140 %           09/12/61 14:20

    Protein C (Fu...       160H  70-140 %           09/12/61 14:20      160(H) 09/12/61 14:20

    Homocyst(e)ine     REFUSED   0-12 umol/L        09/12/61 06:08

    AT3 (% NL Act...       108   80-130 %           09/12/61 14:20

    Interpretatio...  see detail                    9/14/61 18:31

  Antiphospholipid Antibodies

    Cardiolipin A...       4.7   0-15 GPL           07/25/62 12:34

    Cardiolipin A...      13.0   0-15 MPL           07/25/62 12:34



EKG

	Sinus Tachycardia @ 110, non-specific anterior ST abnormalities unchanged from 7/13/62.

	



Head CT - No evidence of acute intra-cranial process



MRI -  No acute infarct on DWI, pt did not complete study.



MRA Pelvis 8/28/62

     1. Patent abdominal aorta and visceral vessels as above.

     2. Patent aorto-iliac system

     3. On the right: Patent arterial tree

     4. On the left: Patent arterial tree



Renal Ultrasound Doppler 8/26/61

NO EVIDENCE OF HYDRONEPHROSIS.  SLIGHTLY ECHOGENIC KIDNEYS.  TRACE

     FREE FLUID.



A/P:  28 yo man with DM1, ESRD-HD, HTN, Hyperlipidemia, thrombocytosis, here with hypertensive emergency. His BP has remained high, so will attempt to reduce by 25% MAP for a few hours and then start an oral agent.  Nitroprusside will be used first but if he needs an extended treatment, will change to nicardipine (Bj Q Sugudoyta 1165 Glb;7(9 Kk 1):414-8) given his ESRD.  His change in mental status is likely due to hypertensive encephalopathy, but it is hard to exclude other sources of end-organ involvement such as the heart (especially considering his thrombocytosis) given his ongoing confusion.  Other sources of his confusion might include meningitis given his leukocytosis. 



1.	CV

a.	Pump

i.	Has an S3, but no signs of L or R heart failure.

ii.	Will reduce afterload prog

b.	Rhythm

i.	Sinus tachycardia, will give IVFs to reduce high-reninemic natriuretic state.

c.	Ischemia

i.	No EKG changes consistent with ischemia, will cycle cardiac biomarkers x 3, give ASA, Lipitor.

ii.	Will reduce afterload with Nitroprusside, IVFs, po anti-hypertensives.

2.	Neuro

a.	His mental status and leukocytosis are likely due to hypertensive encephalopathy but potentially concerning for possible meningitis. Will perform lumbar puncture, hold Abx since he has been in the hospital for more than 6h, give if CSF studies indicate it.

b.	Neuro following.

3.	HTN

a.	Will reduce MAP by 25% to ~100, will start with Nitroprusside, switch to Nicardipine. Will re-start some oral agents once reduced.

4.	DM1

a.	Will start half-dose of Insulin NPH, cover with RISS

5.	Renal

a.	Will need HD, will consult Renal.

6.	Thrombocytosis

a.	Stable, will consult Dr. Morgan's team re: continuing Hydroxyurea.

7.	Access

a.	L arterial line, peripheral iv.

8.	F/E/N

a.	IVFs, will start oral diet as mental status improves.

9.	Heme

a.	Has baseline anemia, likely currently hemoconcentrated, will montor Hct.

10.	Prophylaxis

a.	Senna, Colace, Nexium, Heparin.

_______________________________________________________________________

Name: Addison Keefe, MD PhD                              

Pager # 92783

PGY-2





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>