<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2115-11-24

 



Neurology Resident Admit Note



Date:	11/23/15 	          



Patient Name:  Travis, Peggy				

MRN:   0834010		

PCP name:  Richard Verlin-Urbina



Age:  54		Gender:   Female



Chief Complaint:  Confusion, ? Seizure



HPI:

           This is a 54 year old female with no known past medical history who was brought in via EMS presenting with confusion and right head deviation. According to mother, Peggy was " not acting right " all day. She appeared more confused about her surroundings and certain usual daily activities (such as using the remote control). At around 6: 30 PM, her mother reports that she appeared to be repeatedly bending down to pick up something that wasn't there and she was not responding to voice. However, when EMS arrived, she was responding to their questions and appeared alert. At some point during transit her right head deviation began and her left arm weakness was noted. 

         According to her mother and sister, she had not been complaining of a headache or dizziness. She awoke this morning with bilateral foot tingling that quickly resolved. Also no recent illnesses or falls.



Time of onset:  	Around 6:30 PM	

Witnessed onset: Yes  

Onset: acute

Mode of arrival:  ambulance	

Clinical Course: improving 

Pre-morbid neurological status: no disability   

Code status: full code 



Past Medical History:										

None, though she hasn't seen a physician in over 20 years according to family



Medications: 

None



Allergies: NKDA



Social and Family History:

Occupation:  			Marital status: Single

Tobacco - Never

EtOH - Never 

Illicit drugs: Never	

Home living situation:  Lives with mother	

Family medical history:  Mother with pacemaker, Sister with palpitations



Examination:



VS:  	Temp:     		HR:   88   reg 	 BP:    171/90 

RR:    		O2 Sat: 94% on 2 L/min nasal canula



General: 	Appearance: 	WDWN, Drowsy

HEENT: 	NCAT, MMM, OP clear

Neck: 		supple, no thyromegaly, no LAN, no bruits

Chest: 		CTAB	

CVS: 		RRR, no m/r/g

Abd: 		soft, NT, ND, +BS

Ext:		no c/c/e, bilateral distal pulses strong, severe acne on left upper back



MS: 	General: 	Drowsy, inattentive

Orientation: 	in tact x 4 (person, place, date, situation

Attention:	Unable to name days of week or spell world backwards	 

Speech/Lang: 	difficult to assess since not cooperating with exam and drowsy.

Memory: 	3/3 registered, 0/3 at 5 minutes

Calculations: 	Not tested

Neglect:	Left sensory neglect

Praxis: 	Not tested



CN:

I:  		Not tested

II,III: 		PERRLA 4 -> 2, VFFC

III,IV,V:	EOM full w/o nystagmus, no ptosis. Normal saccades/pursuits

V: 		sensation intact to LT/PP, corneal reflex intact

VII: 		face symmetric without weakness

VIII: 		hears finger rub bilaterally

IX,X: 	            voice normal, palate elevates symmetrically

XI: 		SCM/trapezii 5/5

XII: 		tongue protrudes midline, no atrophy or fasciculation



Motor:		Normal bulk and tone; no tremor, rigidity, or bradykinesia.



	Delt	Bi	Tri	Grip	IP	Quad	Hamst	TibAnt	EHL	Gastroc	

	C5	C6	C7	C8/T1	L2	L3	L4-S1	L4	L5	S1	

R	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	

L	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	



Coord: 	Unable to test

	

Reflex:		No abnormal reflexes.  Jaw jerk absent.  No Hoffman's.



  	Bi	Tri	Bra	Pat	An	Plantar	

	C6	C7	C6	L4	S1		

R	2	2	2	2	2	Flexor	

L	2	2	2	2	2	Flexor	



Sens:   Left arm extinction to LT and painful stimuli.  



Gait: Posture, stance, stride, and arm-swing normal. Tandem gait intact. Able to walk on heels and toes. Romberg negative.



NIHSS (stroke patients) 	Time of exam:



1a:	      1    	1b:		0	1c:	0	2:	0	3:	0	4:	0	5:4

6:	4	7:		x	8:	0	9:	0	10:	1	11:	1	



                     



Laboratory Studies:



Results

NA 134 ,K 3.8,CL 104,CO2 26.2,BUN 13,CRE 0.6,GLU 317 

CA 9.9,PHOS 4.6 (H),MG 1.6, TBILI 0.3,DBILI 0.1,TP 8.5 (H),ALB 4.1 

AMY 37,LIPS 2.5

ALT/SGPT 11,AST/SGOT 9,ALKP 88,TBILI 0.3,DBILI 0.1



WBC 10.5,HCT 43.5,PLT 317

%NEUT 74 (H),%LYMPH 19 (L),%MONO 3 (L),%EOS 4,%BASO 



CXR:     

IMPRESSION

     Normal portable chest radiograph.



Head CT/CTA:  

Patent vessels. Chronic left frontal/right frontal infarcts. Right parietal/ frontal infarcts.



Impression:

54 year old female with acute right parietal/frontal infarcts.

 

Plan:

1. CVR: Allow BP to autoregulate

        Heparin Started with goal PTT 50-70

        Stroke w/u including Holter and TTE

        Check cholesterol panel, homocysteine, lipoprotein a

2. Heme: Hypercoagulation panel

3. Speech/Swallow, OT, PT evaluation

4. Prophylaxis: Nexium, pneumoboots

 



________________________________

Hue Calhoun, MD #24104

Neurology Resident 



Patient is interested in hearing more about ongoing research protocols: Yes 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2115-12-14

Physical exam:



CC:





HPI: Accompanied by sister in law Amelia Travis 220-523-4413 (h); 199-683-8353 (cell).

54 y/o female with uncontrolled DM, HTN, hyperlipidemia, left breast suspicious masses, CVD, and recent hospitalization for CVA, here for follow up and adjustment of her meds.  She does not bring in her glucometer or log book.  She does bring in some of her meds.



Denies change in appetite, problems sleeping, night sweats, fevers, headaches, visual changes, dysphagia, shortness of breath, orthopnea, PND, cough, chest pain, lower extremity edema, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, blood in stool, black stool, dysuria, nocturia, urinary or fecal incontinence, rashes, joint pain, or depressed mood. no vaginal discharge, no pelvic pain. 





Problems

s/p left leg surgery 2097 

Diabetes mellitus type 2 

Cerebrovascular disease : Multiple strokes on MRI

Cerebrovascular accident : 11/15

Hypertension 

Hyperlipidemia 

knowlege deficits 

multiinfarct dementia? 

sedentary lifestyle 

poor dentition : multiple cavities 





Medications

Fragmin (DALTEPARIN SODIUM) 8500 UNITS SC Q12H , Anticoagulation as per Neurology- Thomas Javier MD. Stop on 12/17, 12/18,12/19, 12/20 for breast biopsy on 12/20.

Metformin 500 mg po BID

Lopressor 50 mg po BID



Allergies

NKA 





SOCIAL HX:

No tobacco, alcohol, or drug use.  Denies domestic violence.  Uses seat belts. Living with sister in law Amelia Travis and mother.



PE:



 

BP: 142/84    P-72



GEN: Pleasant female in NAD.

HEENT:  PERRL, no icterus or scleral injection

OP: clear, no erythema or exudate

Neck: supple, no lymph nodes, no thyromegaly, no thyroid nodules, no masses

Lungs: CTA bilaterally

LNs: no cervical lymphadenopathy.

Heart: RRR, no MRG.  

Abdomen: soft, non-tender, non-distended, BS present, no HSM, no Masses

Extremities: No C/C/E

Skin: no rashes, no irregular moles

Neuro: EOMI, visual fields intact, CN II-XII intact, UE and LE reflexes 2+ and symmetrical.  Nonfocal.



Labs:

None.   



Impression and Plan:



1) Uncontrolled DM: Add Glipizide 5 mg po BID. Cont. Metformin 500 mg po BID. Check microalbumin. Re-emphasized importance of bringing in glucometer and BG log book along with all meds to each and every visit.  Check on referrals to ophthalmologist, podiatry, diabetic teaching nurse, nutrition.



2) HTN: Add Lisinopril 5 mg po qd. 



3) CVD s/p CVA: Stable. Cont. Fragmin 8500 units SQ BID as per neurology.  Follow up with neurology.



4) Hyperlipidemia: Add lipitor 20 mg po qhs.



5) Left breast masses: Biopsy on 12/20/15.  She is to stop Fragmin on 12/17/15 for this. 



6)Poor dentition: Referral to dentistry.



7) HM:



Health Maintenance

Cholesterol 11/25/2115 207 DESIRABLE: <200

M-alb/creat ratio 12/14/2115 47.8 

Mammogram 11/27/2115 BilDigDxMamoAll 

Pap Smear 10/05/2115 2000

Smoking status 10/05/2115 as teen-once

UA-Protein 11/25/2115 NEGATIVE 

HBA1C 12/14/2115 11.80 

Urine Culture 11/25/2115 see report in Results 

Triglycerides 11/25/2115 131 

Cholesterol-LDL 11/25/2115 121 DESIRABLE: <130

Microalbumin 12/14/2115 6.5 

Bone Density 11/30/2115 BMD-Hip 

Hct (Hematocrit) 11/27/2115 37.3 

Domestic Violence Screening 10/05/2115 denies

Complete Physical Exam 10/05/2115 Unremarkable

Cholesterol-HDL 11/25/2115 60 

Hgb (Hemoglobin) 11/27/2115 12.9 



 

RTC 6 weeks





_____________________________________________

Richard A. Verlin-Urbina, M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2116-08-26

Physical exam:


CC:


HPI: 55 y/o caucasian female with hx as bellow here for follow up.


Denies weight loss or gain, change in appetite, problems sleeping, night sweats, fevers, headaches, visual changes, dysphagia, shortness of breath, orthopnea, PND, cough, chest pain, lower extremity edema, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, blood in stool, black stool, dysuria, nocturia, urinary or fecal incontinence, rashes, change in moles, joint pain, or depressed mood.   no vaginal discharge, no pelvic pain, no dyspareunia.  



Problems

Proteinuria 

Depression 

Osteoarthritis 

Noncompliance 

s/p left leg surgery 2097 

Diabetes mellitus type 2 

Cerebrovascular disease : Multiple strokes on MRI

Cerebrovascular accident : 11/15

Hypertension 

Hyperlipidemia 

knowlege deficits 

multiinfarct dementia? 

sedentary lifestyle 

poor dentition : multiple cavities 







Medications

Fragmin (DALTEPARIN SODIUM) 8500 UNITS SC Q12H , Anticoagulation as per Neurology- Thomas Javier MD. Stop on 12/17, 12/18,12/19, 12/20 for breast biopsy on 12/20.

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS , For high cholesterol. One pill every night.

Glucotrol (GLIPIZIDE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO BID , For diabetes. One pill twice per day.

Fluoxetine HCL 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , Take one pill per day. 

Metformin 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Ciprofloxacin 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO Q12H 

Lisinopril 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , For blood pressure. 





Allergies

NKA 



FAMILY HX:

No changes.



SOCIAL HX:

No tobacco, alcohol, or drug use.  Denies domestic violence.  Uses seat belts. 



PE:

Vital Signs



BP: 118/74    P-72

 

GEN: NAD

HEENT:  PERRL, no icterus or scleral injection

OP: clear, no erythema or exudate. poor dentition but no abscess noted.

Lungs: CTA bilaterally 

LNs: no  cervical lymphadenopathy.

Heart: RRR, no MRG.   radial,, DP pulses 2+.  No carotid, abdominal bruits.

Abdomen: soft, non-tender, non-distended, BS present

Extremities: No C/C/E

Skin: no rashes, no irregular moles

Neuro:  EOMI, CN II-XII intact, nonfocal.



Labs:

None.





Impression and Plan:



1) Uncontrolled DM:  Control improved over last 1 month.  However BG still markedly elevated. Given her h/o noncompliance I think this is a big step. Check HBA1c.



2) Proteinuria: recheck this.



3) Depression: Improved. Cont. fluoxetine for now. referral to MH again today.



4) HTN: Optimally controlled.



5) CVD :S/p CVA: Stable. Pt. very poor historian. Unclear how long ago she stopped fragmin. ASA qd for now.  follow up with neurology as scheduled on 9/02/16.



6) Hep B vaccine today first dose.



7) OA: Stable. Tylenol prn.



8) HM: Complete annual PE when above issues stable.





_____________________________________________

Richard A. Verlin-Urbina, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2117-08-19

Immanuel Medical Center

Emergency Department Record



Patient: TRAVIS, PEGGY             MRN: 0834010        DOB:  3/08/2061     Sex: F

Registration Date/Time: 8/19/2117 3:52:00 PM            Provider: NICHOLAS SINGH





Time Patient Seen

17:00

Chief Complaint

Swelling in the right foot.

HPI

56 yo f a known diabetic for past 3 yrs has come with complaints of swellin and redness of the R foot for one week,she hit her toe against a beaureu after wqhich she developed pain ,swelling and redness.There is loss of sensation.no h/o fever ,chills and rigor.

PMHx

Diabetes,hypertension,stroke

PSurHx

None

Meds

diabetic medications

Allergy

No Known Drug Allergies

Social Hx

No Etoh/drug



ROS

General

Negative

Constitutional

No major weight loss or gain, fatigue, fever, chills.

Head/Eyes

No visual changes, lesions, headaches

ENT/Neck

No hearing loss, tinnitus, vertigo, rhinorrhea, hoarseness, difficulty swallowing, oral lesions, stiffness

Chest/Respiratory

No coughing, wheezing, dyspnea

Cardiovascular

No chest pain, palpitations, PND, orthopnea

GI/Abdominal

No pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, melena, bleeding, heartburn

GU/Flank/CVA/Pelvic

No menstrual irregularity, vaginal discharge, frequency, urgency, dysuria, bleeding

Musculoskeletal/Extr/Back

bilateral pedal edema,ulcer in the right foot.

Skin

See HPI

Neuro

Slurred speech,weakness in the right lower limb

Psych

No depression, anxiety, unusual stress

Heme/Lymph/Imm

No bruising, adenopathy, chills, sweats, fevers

Endo

No polyuria, polydipsia



Physical Exam

Constitutional

Patient is a well developed, well nourished, healthy appearing, alert female, no acute distress, no obvious discomfort

Head/Eyes

NC/AT, pupils are equal, round and react normally to light, EOM's are full, no ocular discharge, conjunctiva normal

ENT

There is no nasal discharge. TM's clear, auditory canal without lesions, no intraoral lesions, good dentition, uvula midline, tonsils and pharynx without inflammation or exudates

Neck

Full range of motion, no stiffness or tenderness, thyroid normal size without nodularity.  Carotid pulses are intact bilaterally without bruits, no lymphadenopathy, no masses, no neck vein distention

Chest/Respiratory

Clear to auscultation and percussion, no crackles, wheezes or rhonchi

Cardiovascular

Regular rate and rhythm, normal S1 & S2, no murmurs, gallops or rubs

GI/Abdomen

Soft, normal bowel sounds, nontender, no intra-abdominal masses or hepatosplenomegaly

Genitourinary

Speculum and bimanual examination normal, no masses or tenderness

Musculoskeletal

No cyanosis, clubbing, or joint swelling

Skin

ulcer right foot,swelling of R foot,redness

Neurologic

Loss of sensation of b/l foot,slurring of speech,cn 1to12 normal ,power of lower limb muscle 4/5. UL POWER 5/5.

Psychiatric

No visual or auditory hallucination, not suicidal, not homicidal

X-ray Interpretation

X-ray right foot.

Impression/Plan

R Diabetic foot



ED Attending Physician Note

HPI

56 year-old female reports blunt trauma to right great toe one week ago now with increasing redness and swelling

ROS

Paste and the itching sensation, joint pain, fever,

Vitals

See Nursing Notes

PE

Gen: nontoxic HEENT MMM PERRLA EOMI neck NT supple heart s1s2 RRR -m lungs CTAx2 abd soft NT ND ext -c/c/e FROM all jts   neuro  sens symmetric to LT/PP distally, skin erythema of right great toe with soft tissue swelling and erythema extending into the forefoot with edema 



Medical Decision Making ED Course

ED IV antibiotics, check CBC and Chem-7; glucose normal; admit for diabetic foot infection/cellulitis

Condition on Discharge

Stable

Diagnoses

Right foot cellulitis

Review Comments

I have personally seen and examined the patient and confirmed the resident's examination, reviewed and agree with the resident's documentation of history, and discussed the evaluation, plan of care and disposition of the patient with the resident.



This note has been electronically signed by NICHOLAS SINGH, MD 8/25/2117 6:25:59 PM



Clinical staff documenting in the ED note include:



Attending/Nurse Practitioners(s)



NICHOLAS SINGH, MD

Other Providers



HEATHER HERNANDEZ, Medical Student



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>