<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2074-06-05

Mills returns with Urquiza and her husband.  He's been trying - cut way back on sodas, and chips.  He walks every day - really no complaints.  His HbA1C was up at 9.2.   No proteinuria.  No complaints of foot numbness , no visual sx.    Lipids were fair - 202, HDL 44, Trigs 461.  Cost has become an issue on meds as Mills has been denied state insurance for arcane reasons..  (his income is only 850.00/mo)


RoS: feels fine,  ROS neg. in detail.

Habits: no smoking or drinking.(sober for years)



Medications

Glucophage (METFORMIN) 500MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID x 90 days

Micronase (GLYBURIDE) 10 MG (5MG TABLET take 2) PO BID x 90 days

Tegretol (CARBAMAZEPINE) 200MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID x 90 days

Monopril (FOSINOPRIL SODIUM) 20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days

Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81MG TABLET CHEWABLE take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take as directed 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take as directed 

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days, Take as directed 



Allergies

NKA 


Vital Signs

Wt 202 lb  Looks well, though sunburnt.   BP: 160/80 p. 70's reg

clear RRR

 no edema, no neurop.


Problems

Diabetes mellitus - check FS glucose today.  Eventually we'll need to teach Mills/family how to do fingersticks, but we aren't there yet.  working hard on diet...    f/u 1mo.   He will need eye exam.  Adding statin and Aspirin today.

Hypertension - add HCTZ 25mg qd.

H/O Seizure disorder : Status post head trauma

H/O Alcohol abuse - sober now.



Health Maintenance

Influenza Vaccine 11/24/2072 

Cholesterol 04/03/2074 202 DESIRABLE: <200

M-alb/creat ratio 04/03/2074 6.5 

UA-Protein 10/01/62 NEG 

Triglycerides 04/03/2074 461 

Cholesterol-LDL 04/03/2074 -- "Calculated" LDL is inaccuratewhen triglycerides exceed 400 mg/dl.

Microalbumin 04/03/2074 0.6 

Hct (Hematocrit) 04/03/2074 41.0 

Cholesterol-HDL 04/03/2074 46 

MHCT (micro-Hematocrit) 07/15/62 30 

Hgb (Hemoglobin) 04/03/2074 14.3 

HbA1c 04/03/2074 9.50 


_____________________________________________

Yechiel Kidd, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-08-08



Reason for Visit

62 y.o. man, pt of Dr. Kidd, presents w/ c/o R hand pain x 1d.  Has sharp pain, starts in thumb, radiates proximally up arm to biceps area.   Pain lasts several minutes, resolves spontaneously.  Occurs several times a day, not reated to arm movement.  He denies trauma to area, recent falls, denies swelling, redness, rashes, weakness.



Problems

      Diabetes mellitus

      Hypertension

      H/O Seizure disorder    : Status post head trauma

      H/O Alcohol abuse



Medications

      Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid)   81MG TABLET CHEWABLE take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD ,  Take as directed 

      Glucophage (METFORMIN)   500MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID x 90 days

      Micronase (GLYBURIDE)   10 MG (5MG TABLET take 2) PO BID x 90 days

      Tegretol (CARBAMAZEPINE)   200MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID x 90 days

      Monopril (FOSINOPRIL Sodium)   20MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days

      Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN)   10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD ,  Take as directed 

      Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)   25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 90 days,  Take as directed 



Allergies

      NKA



Social History

legally blind, also has MR; lives w/ sister Urquiza who is his care taker.



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   118/74 

      PULSE   72 

      WEIGHT   192 lb



Physical Exam

Gen: WDWN man, NAD

Extrem: no edema; radial and p.t. pulses 2+ bilat; R UE - no deformity, no edema; well healed surgical scar over R bicpes area; non-tender in biceps/triceps, forearm area; mild tenderness in distal thumb; full ROM of elbow, wrist, fingers, shoulder w/out pain; motor 5/5 in all UE muscle groups. radial, brachial pulses 2+; hand warm, good cap refill.



Assessment and Plan

62 y.o. man w/ sharp intermitent pain in R UE - etiology unclear given lack of trauma and lack of physical findings on exam; will do hand film to assess for occult fracture or other abnormality; for now, ibuprofen prn.  I recommended pt f/u w/ Dr. Kidd in next few weeks (no showed 12/74 appt, next appt 10/75).  Sister Urquiza will call for appt.  RTC if pain persists.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-09-26

 

Neurology MEDIQUIK Senior Note



9/26/75

5:00AM

Patient Name: Percy Carrillo

MRN: 1668727



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: Please see neurology PGY2 note for full details. In brief the patient is a 62 yo man with mental retardation, HTN, hyperlipidemia, head trauma with SDH with evacuation, DM who presents with gait instability and difficulty with speaking and swallowing. Per guardian the patient was in his USOH until 9/24/75 evening at approximately 8:30pm he was found to have mumbled speech and having difficulty with ambulation with leaning to the left. On 9/25/75 in the morning he had a fall when getting out of bed and struck his head, and brought to the ED. No prior history of stroke or TIA. 



MEDS: ASA, Metformin, Glyberide, Tegretol, Fosinoperil, Lipitor, HCTZ

			

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION

VITALS: 	BP 130/85

MS:	AA&Ox3, speech fluent with slurring (unclear baseline), repeats and names well.  Comprehends simple commands.  Names president

CN: 	PERRL, VF full with BTT. EOMI but with nystagmus in all directions of gaze, even primary gaze. Facial sensation intact.  Face asymmetric. Tongue, palate symmetric.  SCM and traps 5/5. 

Motor:	UMN pattern weakness in RUE (4-/5), most notable in hands. Mild  proximal RLE weak (4+/5).  

Coord:	Impaired FTN in LUE, intact in RUE.   

Refl:	Deep tendon reflexes are 2+ at biceps, triceps, brachioradialis, patella, and ankles.  Plantar response is flexor on right and extensor on left.             

Sens:              Decreased PP but NOT LT in LUE and LLE 



Imaging: 

MRI Brain (9/25/75)     DWI bright ADC dark right lateral medullary pyramid with associated increased T2 signal.

MRA Head/Neck (9/25/75)     Narrowing of basilar artery with flow signal throughout and no thrombosis  

CTA Head/Neck (9/25/75)     Diffuse atherosclerotic disease, occluded R-ICA with good collateralization of right hemisphere, severe irregular narrowing through out bilateral vertebral arteries and basilar arteries. 



IMPRESSION: The patient has numerous risk factors for stroke with HTN, DM2, and HLP. His exam is consistent with lateral medullary pyramid lesion with involvement of spinalcortical tract prior to decussation explaining ipsilateral weakness and also involvement of the spinalthalamic tract explaining contralateral deficit in pain sensation. His vessel imaging is notable and concerning for diffuse atherosclerotic disease, specifically in posterior circulation in distribution of acute stroke. The patient was reportedly taking aspirin, though reports are mixed and this needs clarification. Vessel imaging did not implicate that the patient suffered from acute vertebro-basilar thrombo-embolism, but that his posterior circulation disease is a chronic issue and the stroke was more likely due to distal vessel thrombosis. Anticoagulation can be considered in acute setting of small sized posterior circulation stroke with vertebro-basilar disease, but in this case by the time the patient became known to neurology service and by the time it was known he had a stroke it was some 24hrs after initial symptoms, and in this interval he did not show any signs or symptoms of stroke progression making unstable plaque unlikely. Given the findings of the WASID study that anticoagulation did not significantly improve recurrent stroke prevention benefits over aspirin for symptomatic vertebro-basilar disease (because warfarin benefits were offset by higher hemorrhage rates), the decision to place this patient on aspirin is supported. The long term management of this patient requires aggressive control of atherosclerotic risk factors such as HTN, DM2, and HLP. The patient is significantly at risk of major ischemic stroke due to occluded right carotid artery and diffuse posterior circulation disease, and it is conceivable that if he continues to have persistent symptoms in the future that a revascularization procedure may be necessary.   



RECOMMENDATIONS:

1.	Aspirin 325 mg po qd

2.	Continue Lipitor 

3.	HTN management as an outpatient, autoregulate x 24hrs for SBP<180 mmHg  

4.	DM2 management 

5.	Check lipids, homocysteine, lipoprotein a, hba1c

6.	Check TCDs to obtain baseline data

7.	Consider TTE/Holter as outpatient as unlikely this was a cardioembolic event 

________________________________

Freddie V. Hickman MD

Mediquik Pager #02662





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-09-24

       
Team 4 Admit Note




Admission Date: 9/23/2076
Patient Name: Carrillo, Percy
MRN#: 1668727
Attending: Kidd, Yechiel
Historian: patient and ED report


Reason for admission: change in MS and placement issues 


HPI: Patient is a 63-year-old man with mental retardation, diabetes mellitus, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and s/p CVA in 2075 (subacute right medullary and
pontine strokes secondary to extensive atherosclerotic disease of the right
internal carotid artery).  He has been cared at home by his sister since his stroke last year and per his PCP&#8217;s notes earlier this year and per ED report his behavior and management has become steadily more difficult for his sister at home. Pt&#8217;s sister not with him on the floor however, per ED report pt supposedly found eating his own feces earlier and his sister expressing frustration and requesting a rehab placement for patient.  


Currently patient is alert an oriented x 3 and while denying any issues or complaints does express understanding that he is admitted with goal of being placed at a NH or rehab place.  


He denies any CP, SOB, n/v, f/c, HA, change in vision, worsening numbness, tingling, or parasthesia.  He does report decrease right-sided strength on his right side but reports improvement in strength since the CVA last year especially in the lower extremities. 


In ED CT of the head was performed and pt admitted for further w/u and possible placement.  

Past Medical History:  

HTN
Hyperlipidemia
seizure disorder ?since childhood (no seizure since childhood)
DM
H/o head trauma 13 years ago. Left subdural hematoma, right
ventriculomegaly secondary to obstructive hydrocephalus, right cerebellar contusion s/p right suboccipital craniotomy
mental retardation
s/p CVA in Sep-2075 (subacute right medullary and pontine strokes 
extensive atherosclerotic disease of the right internal carotid artery
   
Medications: (Per Dr. Kaufman&#8217;s note from July 14, 2076)



Glucophage (METFORMIN) 1000 MG (500MG TABLET take 2) PO BID 
Micronase (GLYBURIDE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 90 days
Percocet 5 MG/325 MG (OXYCODONE 5 MG/ACETAMINOPHEN 325 MG) 1 TAB PO Q6H PRN pain 
Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG (75MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 90 days
Simvastatin 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 
Tegretol (CARBAMAZEPINE) 200MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID x 30 days

Allergies: 

Hydrocodone 5 Mg + Apap 500mg - GI UPSET

Family History:  ?


Social History:  legally blind, lives w/ sister Urquiza who is his care taker.

Review of Systems: as noted above


Physical Examination
Vital Signs:  T 98.2         P 77          BP 146/74           RR 20           O2: 97% RA


General: sleeping comfortably, NAD
HEENT:   PERRLA, EOMI, nystagmus on lateral gaze bilaterally, oral mucosa moist, conjunctiva clear
Skin:    no rash or ulcers on the trunk or extrmities
Neck:  supple with full ROM, no jvd
Chest: CTA B
Heart: RRR, no r/g/m
Abdomen:    s, nt, nd, +BS
Extremities:  no c/c/e
Neurological: CNII-XII grossly intact.  Patient oriented to place and time and to person (president) with little help. About 4/5 strength on the LUE, LLE, RLE.  2-3/5 strength on the RUE.  
Diagnostic Studies: 
09/23/2076 NA 139,  K 4.0,  CL 104,  CO2 26.3,  BUN 15,  CRE 0.9,  GLU 199 (H)


09/23/2076 WBC 8.9,  RBC 4.46 (L),  HGB 14.4,  HCT 38.6 (L),  MCV 87,  MCH 32.3,  MCHC 37.4 (H),  PLT 201


09/23/2076 RDW 13.8


09/23/2076 PT 11.8,  PT-INR 1.0,  PTT 24.0


09/23/2076 UA-COLOR Yellow,  UA-APP Clear,  UA-GLUC 3+,  UA-BILI NEGATIVE,  UA-KET NEGATIVE,  UA-SPGR 1.020,  UA-BLD NEGATIVE,  UA-PH 6.0


09/23/2076 UA-PROT NEGATIVE,  UA-UROBI NEGATIVE,  UA-NIT NEGATIVE,  UA-WBC NEGATIVE


09/23/2076 TOX1 ,  TOX2 


09/23/2076 UR-ACETOM NEGATIVE,  UAMPH NEGATIVE,  UBARB NEGATIVE,  UBENZ NEGATIVE,  URCOCA NEGATIVE,  UMAMPH NEGATIVE,  UMETHD NEGATIVE,  UOPI NEGATIVE


09/23/2076 URPCP NEGATIVE,  UTHC NEGATIVE,  TRC-UG POSITIVE





CXR: 
      IMPRESSION:
      Normal Chest.
CT Head:
      IMPRESSION:
      1.  No acute intracranial hemorrhage.  No focal soft tissue
      swelling.
      2.  Evidence of prior intracranial injury and surgery as described
      above, stable compared to prior study.
      3.  Stable mild opacification of the right mastoid air cells.


                                  
Impression/Plan: 63-year-old man with mental retardation, diabetes mellitus, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and s/p CVA in 2075 who has been taken care of by his sister.  Steadily with worsening behavioral issues and more difficult to take care of by his sister.  Head CT is negative for a new CVA and labs are grossly normal and not suggestive of any major metabolic imbalance.  Patient also appears stable and NAD and fairly alert and oriented to the situation. He will likely benefit from a nursing home or rehab placement.
- Continue with out patient medications
- PT/OT consult
- Social services consult
- Regular diet
- Diabetic diet
- RISS and FS qid
- Lovenox 30 bid
- Full Code
_______________
Tito Quast, MD
Please page team 4 with questions.


****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>