<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2073-06-13

EDVISIT^98044905^WARE, VINCENT^06/13/73^ZORN, TYLER

The patient is a 65-year-old gentleman who presents complaining

of shortness of breath, weakness, and fatigue.  The patient was

seen in conjunction with resident physician, Ostrowski.  Please see

her note for details of the visit.  Resident's history was

reviewed by me.  The patient was interviewed and examined by me.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for non-Hodgkin lymphoma,

diabetes, and hypercholesterolemia.

MEDICATIONS:  Metformin, insulin, aspirin, and multivitamins.

ALLERGIES:  The patient has no allergies.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Negative for chronic diseases.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  No alcohol, tobacco, or illicit substances.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is followed by his

hematology-oncologist for unexplainable anemia.  The patient

presents complaining of dyspnea.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Significant for dyspnea on exertion,

weakness, fatigue, fever and shortness of breath, negative for

headache, blurred vision, chest pain.  Other systems were

reviewed and found to be negative, unless noted positive on

resident's note.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  I concur with documented resident's note. 

Specifically, abdomen was soft and nontender.  Rectal Exam: 

Guaiac negative, normal tone, and no masses.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  Laboratory studies remarkable for

hematocrit of 24.  EKG is unremarkable.  Chest x-ray is negative.

 The patient's management was discussed with Dr. Walsh,

oncology.

The patient will be admitted to oncology hematology for workup.

______________________________

ZORN, TYLER M.D.

D: 06/13/73

T: 06/13/73

Dictated By: ZORN, TYLER

eScription document:2-2004166 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-09-20

 MANAMANA nfectious Disease Consultation Note

Patient: Vincent Ware (71417347     2Y)
Student:  Casey Best, MS-4
ID Fellow: Tina Isaiah-Villagomez MD
ID Attending: Alexander Y Xian MD
Referring Physician: Webster MD
Date of Consult: September 20, 2073

Reason for consult:  cough, nightsweats and weightloss, two days prior to transplant

HPI: 66 yo M with h/o IDDM, large cell lymphoma in 2066, and now with myelodysplastic syndrome.  He was treated with CHOP in 2066 followed by radiotherapy, completed in Nov 2066.  He was free of disease since then until May 2073.  He sought primary care for a URI and was noted to be anemic (HCT 31).  His counts were followed and when his HCT dropped as low as 22 a Bone Marrow was done and showed myelodysplastic syndrome.  He was considered for a allogenic stem-cell transplant.  His major complaint is a dry cough that he has had since May 2073.   It is provoked by eating, drinking and lying down.  And only occasionally does he produce any sputum.  He has been on numerous antibiotics in the past four months for the cough and he also developed a periorbital cellulitis for which he was hospitalized at Educare-Fargo for which he received a 3 week course of Ceftriaxone, Nafcillin and flagyl (finished at the end of July).  In retrospect, he recognizes sinus pressure/congestion associated with periorbital cellulitis.  In August 2073 he had a questionable LLL PNA and was treated with cipro.  On pre-transplant work-up, CXR revealed increase    conspicuity of ill-defined LL zone opacity.      CT chest reviewed today revealed mutlifocal pneumonia with associated radiation-related changes.  

Throughout this time period he has only had a few days of fever for which he was at KCGH and given abx and defervesced.  He recalls    nightsweats    as the fevers broke.  He does admit to maybe a 10 lb weight loss in the past 4 months.  He denies SOB (unless he   s severely anemic), orthopnea, sore throat, dysphagia, odynophagia, CP, palpitations, angina-like symptoms, acid-reflux, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, BRBPR, dysuria, frequency, nocturia, joint or muscle pain.  He does have mild peripheral neuropathy in his feet bilaterally.

PMH:  
MDS
Peri-Orbital cellulitis, recent
Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus
Hypercholesterolemia
Non-hodgkin   s lymphoma (2066; tx w/ CHOP and radiation)
Pt:  RPR neg, CMV neg, HSV pos, TOXO pos, EBV pos, VZV pos, Hep Panel neg, HTLV neg and HIV neg, PPD neg 9/20/73 and 8/7/73
Donor:  RPR neg, CMV neg, Hep Panel neg, HIV neg, HTLV neg, PPD neg (traveled to Saudi Arabia, Cartersville, Newport)

Medications on admission:
Cipro (last dose 9/18/73)
Lantus and novolog
Procrit
Zetia, ASA, VitB/MVI

Inpatient medication:
Antimicrobials/immune booster:
Acyclovir
Bactrim (to d/c day 0)
Levaquin (to start day    1)
GCSF (start d+1)
Immunosuppressants:
Fludarabine, 
Vusulfan
Tacrolimus (start day    3)
Rapamycin (start day    3)
Other:  zoran, ativan/compazine, mvi/folate, ompeprazole, lantus, novolog, metformin, Demerol, oxycodone

Allergies: NKDA

Social History:  He is a programmer and works as a Industrial Engineering and Manufacturing Technologist at Activision Blizzard.  NO occupational exposures.  He is married with three children and 4 grandchildren.  He does not smoke or drink.  He has remote travel hx to the Rockefeller Centre, more recent global travel (Fernley, Cartersville, Iceland), and frequent travel to Muscat area.  He recently gave his indoor cat away as he hypothesized that she had something to do with his cough/MDS.  He does not recall tick bites and has infrequently visited Storting and Capitol.

Family hx:  Sister died of metastatic cancer     likely lung.  Father died of diabetes, Mother died at age 90.

ROS:  negative in detail except as outlined above in HPI

Physical Exam:
VS:  T 97.3 Tm 98.6  HR 88 BP 120/70 R 20 O2sat 98% RA
Gen:  WDWN male in NAD, AAOx3 doing extremely complex math at presentation
HEENT:  EOMI, conjunctiva pink, PERRLA, no oropharyngeal erythema, thrush or exudate
CV: S1 S2 nl, RRR, no M/R/G
Lungs:  mild coarse crackles at L base; R clear
Abd: soft, NT, ND, no organomegaly
Ext:  no C/C/E
Lines:  hickman, L subclavian, no erythema, warmth

Relevant Labs:  
09/20/2073 CRE 1.13
09/20/2073 LDH 113
09/20/2073 ALT/SGPT 15,  AST/SGOT 13,  ALKP 65,  TBILI 0.5,  DBILI 0.2
09/20/2073 1-3BGLUC PEND
09/20/2073 WBC 2.25 (*),  HGB 8.5 (*),  HCT 24.7 (*),  PLT 118 (*)
09/20/2073 %POLY-M 70,  %BAND-M 1,  %LYMPH-M 18,  %ATYPS 0,  %MONO-M 10 (*),  %EOS-M 0,  %BASO-M 1
09/20/2073 GALACT-AG 0.14 [1]

Microbiology

09/19/2073 Microbiology URINE:  Total Colony Count 100:  PROBABLE STAPHYLOCOCCI 
09/18/2073 NASAL (ASPERGILLUS SCREEN):  FUNGUS CULTURE: NO REPORT SO FAR 

Radiology

09/19/2073 CT SCAN CHEST W/O CONTRAST
REPORT NOT FINALIZED 

09/19/2073 Chest PA & Lateral  
      IMPRESSION: Chest PA and lateral views are compared to prior  done on 9/18/2073. Paramediastinal opacification is changed.  Cardiomediastinal silhoutte is stable. Nodular opacity in the  left perihilar region appears less apparent. No new consolidations are seen. There is a new left-sided Hickman catheter with its tip in the SVC. No pneumothorax is seen .
      
Impression:
66 yo M with h/o IDDM, large cell lymphoma in 2066, and now with myelodysplastic syndrome who presents with fourth months of cough of unclear etiology.

The differential diagnosis is broad and includes both infectious and non-infectious diagnoses.  Our leading diagnosis is either radiation fibrosis or a primary interstitial lung disease, such as COP.  However, we also think that several infectious etiologies should be considered.  Endemic mycoses (histo, blasto and crypto), cryptococcal pneumonia, nocardiasis, aspergillus, mucormycosis and MAC are some diseases to consider in this patient.  While the clinical picture of granulomas on chest CT and cough is consistent with the diagnosis of mycobacterial disease, the patient is very low risk for this infection and his lack of fevers, progressive weight loss and systemic illness argues against this diagnosis.  

I (AYX) have interviewed and examined Mr. Ware, and confirmed all of the findings documented in this note.   My highest suspicion is for an inflammatory process, such as radiation pneumonitis or BOOP/COP.  An occult infection is quite possible, such as pulmonary MAC or a mold (the lesion in his left lower lobe is especially suspicious).  Clinically he is unchanged over many months, so empiric antibiotics would not be indicated.    

 We recommend the following work-up:

-Expectorated sputum for gram stain and culture
-Induced sputum for
-PCP
-Modified AFB smear (looking for Nocardia)
-Fungal stain and culture
-Urine histo antigen
-Serum cryptococcal antigen
-Weekly monitoring of galactomannan and D-glucan
-Nasopharyngeal swab for respiratory viral panel (RSV, Adenovirus, Influenza A and B, paraflu A and B) and viral culture

If the above work-up is unrevealing, please consult pulmonology for a bronchoscopy -- sooner rather than later.

It is reasonable to start is levaquin 500 mg QD now to treat empirically for typical and atypical pathogens (this medication is scheduled to begin in two days, per protocol).

Our recommendations were communicated to Dr. Dalton and Dr. Robin Jeffery of the patient   s primary team.  Thank you for this consult.  Our team will follow with you





______________________________________
Tina Isaiah-Villagomez, MD; Fellow
Alexander Y. Xian, MD; Attending -- Pager 43486
Division of Infectious Diseases




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-12-21

EDVISIT^98044905^WARE, VINCENT^12/21/74^VILLA, SCOTT

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Dyspnea on exertion.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Ware is a 67-year-old man with

a history of diabetes and myelodysplastic syndrome, status post

stem cell transplant who presents to the Emergency Department

with a 2 to 3 week history of increasing exertional dyspnea.  The

patient denies chest pain, palpitations, or syncope but does

complain of bilateral lower extremity edema times several weeks. 

The patient has been worked up for the symptoms as an outpatient

and placed on Lasix for the past 2 weeks and had an

echocardiogram today, which was remarkable for atrial

fibrillation.  The patient was sent to the Emergency Department

for further evaluation.  Please see the written record for

further details.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Insulin-dependent diabetes,

myelodysplastic syndrome, status post stem cell transplant.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Basal cell resection.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient denies smoking, alcohol, or illicit

drug use.

MEDICATIONS:  Lasix, vitamin D, Lantus, and acyclovir.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  I have examined the patient and agree with

the physical as documented.  Of note, the patient is awake and

alert, in no acute distress.  Vitals:  Temperature is 96.9, pulse

is 100 to 128, respiratory rate of 18, blood pressure is 118/70,

and oxygen saturation is 96%.  Lungs:  Clear bilaterally with no

rales, rhonchi, or wheezing.  Cardiovascular exam:  Irregularly

irregular rhythm.  Normal S1 and S2.  No murmurs.  Abdomen:  Soft

with no tenderness, guarding, or rebound.  Extremity exam:  The

patient has bilateral lower extremity 2+ pitting edema, left

greater than right.  No calf tenderness.

MEDICAL DECISION MAKING AND EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Mr.

Ware is a 67-year-old man with diabetes and a 2-week history of

increasing dyspnea on exertion.  His chest x-ray did not

demonstrate pulmonary edema, but was significant for bilateral

pleural effusions.  The patient's EKG demonstrated a flutter with

a ventricular rate of 121 with inferolateral T-wave inversions. 

The patient was given IV and p.o. Cardizem with control of the

ventricular rate.  At the time of this dictation, the patient's

laboratory data are not available.  The plan is to admit the

patient to the hospital for further management.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  New onset AFib.

DISPOSITION:  Admission.

CONDITION UPON ADMISSION:  Good.

______________________________

VILLA, SCOTT M.D.

D: 12/21/74

T: 12/21/74

Dictated By: VILLA, SCOTT

eScription document:7-5753770 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-03-03



ID CONSULT NOTE 


PATIENT NAME:  Vincent Ware
MRN: 98044905

DATE OF ADMISSION: 3/02/75
DATE OF CONSULT: 3/03/75
ID ATTENDING: Haney


ID FELLOW: Riddle

SERVICE ATTENDING: Vann
REASON FOR CONSULT: Cough, dyspnea, fevers s/p HSCT off immune suppression


HPI:

Mr. Ware is a 67-year-old man with a history non-Hodgkins's lymphoma (spinal mass, s/p CHOP, radiation, in long term remission) and secondary MDS s/p reduced intensity allo-HSCT 12/73.  His post-tx course was unremarkable.  Peritransplant he devloped a multifocal PNA of unclear etiology. Pretransplant imaging showed peribronchial thickening, and post transplant a tree &amp; bud appearance with more focal areas of consolidation. Per the patient, he had a dry hacking cough with occaisional fevers and night sweats that lasted from April through November of 73 and resolved on their own.  He had several courses of quinolones (and other abx) during this period without significant relief, but ultimately his symptoms improved on their own.  His immune suppression was d/c'd 7/74.  He deveoloped iron overload (Ferritin 1356) and started phlebotomy 9/74.   


Mr. Ware did well from a respiratory standpoint until 11/74 when he noticed intermittent fevers approximately every 2 weeks.   At first they were in the 99 range and they would last 1-2days and be associated with malaise.  He also again experienced symptoms of a dry hacking cough that occurs with change in positioning (not necessarily lying flat).  By the end of November, the fevers were a bit higher (100.5).  He saw his PCP who thought he might have PNA.  He obtained a CXR and gave hime a course ofr azithromycin (5d). His fevers improved.  In early December, he began experienceing SOB with exertional dyspnea.  He saw his PCP again who rx avelox.  He got another CXR which showed some "fluid" and was strated on lasix.  He was also referred for echocardiogram, PFTs, and chest CT.  On arrival, he was found to be in AFB w/RVR. 


He was admitted from 12/21-01/02. He was rate controlled and had minimal diuresis.  Cardiac MRI suggested constrictive pericarditis and possible areas of active pericarditis.  Right &amp; left heart cath which showed no evidence of cosntriction hemodynamically. He had 1 temperature to 101.4, and given his history he was seen by our service.  Blood cultures were negative. Induced sputum was negative for AFB x 3. He and influenza/rsv/paraflu/adnevorus nasal swabs which were also negative. Sputum cultures grew oral flora. CMV VL, glucan, and galactomannan were also negative. 


He improved w/regard to SOB but cough persisted.  He was seen by Dr. Vann who was concerned for an immunologic process given his bilateral pleural effusions &amp; question of pericarditis. He had a URI syndrome in January that lasted 3 weeks then resolved.  On February 19th, he noticed the onset of low-grade temps (100.0-100.5) with malaise and mild chills.  These happened nightly through. He saw his PCP 2/23 who rx moxifloxacin. He had no change in his symptoms.  He had some mild rhinorrhea and mildly increased SOB.  He denies CP, abdominal pain, HA, N/V/D, joint pain, skin rashes, dysuria.  His son had a "head cold" prior to the onset of his symptoms.  No other sick contacts.  He was admitted for further workup. 



He is up tp date received influenza &amp; pneumococcal vaccines. 



ROS: as above, otherwise negative


PMH:

1. Lymphoma, non-Hodgkin's, large B-cell lymphoma status post CHOP in 2066 and radiation therapy for a T9 to T12 mass, in remission. 

2. Secondary MDS, newly diagnosed 06/73 s/p unrelated donor nonmyeloablative stem cell transplant 12/73

Pt: RPR neg, CMV neg, HSV pos, TOXO pos, EBV pos, VZV pos, Hep Panel neg, HTLV neg and HIV neg, PPD neg 9/20/73 and 8/7/73 
Donor: RPR neg, CMV neg, Hep Panel neg, HIV neg, HTLV neg, PPD neg (traveled to Saudi Arabia, Cartersville, Newport) 
3. Diabetes mellitus type 2. He is on insulin at home and his last hemoglobin A1C was around 8.
4. Hyperlipidemia on Zetia.

5. B12 deficiency.
7. History of basal cell cancer status post resection.
8. Tonsillectomy.
9. Orbital Cellulitis (7/73 tx with ceftriaxone/nafcillin/flagyl)


Home Medications: 
Actigall (URSODIOL) 300 MG (300MG CAPSULE Take 1) PO TID #90 Capsule(s) 
Aspirin (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD 
Folic Acid 1MG TABLET Take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , please ship to patients home- they are out of medication #30 Tablet(s) 
Lantus (INSULIN Glargine) 18 UNITS SC QHS 

Novolog (INSULIN Aspart) 6-8 UNITS SC tid 

Vitamin D 1000 U PO QD
Acyclovir 400mg PO TID
Lasix 20mg PO daily 



Current Medications:

Acyclovir 400mg po TID, ASA, Insulin, Pravaastatin, Sotalol, ASA, Vitamin D3




Allergies: NKDA 


FH: Mother lived to 90. Dad died of complications of diabetes/heart disease.  One sister w/metastatic lung CA. Younger brother with skin CA. No rheumatologic disease that he is aware of. 


Social History: He is a programmer and works as a Industrial Engineering and Manufacturing Technologist at Activision Blizzard. No occupational exposures. He is married with three children and 4 grandchildren. He does not smoke or drink. He has remote travel hx to the Rockefeller Centre, more recent global travel (Fernley, Cartersville, Iceland), and frequent travel to Muscat area. He recently gave away his indoor cat prior to transplant.  He does not recall tick bites and has infrequently visited Storting and Acropolis. He works on model planes. He has no TB exposures. 





PHYSICAL EXAM: 
VITALS: tmax 99.1 bp 120/62 hr 83 rr 20 sat 93% RA
GEN: NAD
HEENT: NC/AT, PERRLA, OP clear without lesions or thrush
NECK: supple
CHEST: mildly decreased BS bilateral bases 
CV: RRR, NO M/G/R
ABDOMEN: soft, NT/ND, normoactive BS, no HSM
EXTREMITIES: no clubbing or cyanosis, trace to 1+ bilateral LE edema
LYMPH NODES: no cervical, submandibular, axillary, or inguinal adenopathy
SKIN: no rashes


LABORATORY:
Na 135 K 5.1 CHL 103 CO2 26 BUN 16 Cr 1.03 GLU 259
AST 35 ALT 21 ALk Phos 265 TB 0.6
WBC 9.71 HCT 35.6 PLT 366 67%P, 17%L, 6%E
ESR 61
CMV 2/9 negative


MICROBIOLOGY:
BLOOD 3/02, 3/03 NGTD
URINE 3/02 1K probable enterococcus
STOOL 3/02 culture pending
3/03 FlU/Paraflu/RSV pending


RADIOLOGY:
CXR 3/02:
Increased moderate effusions since 1/29/2075.
CHEST CT 3/03: Pericardial effusion has resolved without apparent  change in bilateral pleural effusions since 12/14/2074. Prior granulomatous infection is evident. 



TTE:
The left ventricle is normal in size. Overall left ventricular function is mildly to moderately reduced. The estimated ejection fraction is 40-45%. There is global hypokinesis with regional  variation. There is septal ?bounce? raising the possibility of constrictive  physiology.
IMPRESSION &amp; RECOMMENDATIONS:
67yoM with h/o NHL in remission, secondary MDS s/p non myeloabaltive allo BMT now off all immune suppression since 7/74 presenting with fevers, SOB, and malaise.  He has not yet had documented fevers in the hospital, but his rhinorrhea after sick contact during this season is suggestive of a viral syndrome.  He has chronically mildly elevated LFTs which are stable.  He has a new mild eospinophila of unclear etiology. 
-nasopharyngeal swab AND pertussis IgM/IgG for pertussis given persistent cough and low grade temps
-f/u respiratory viral panel
-given mild eosinophilia, can check strongyloides antibody and stool for ova and parasites though no clear exposure history, would also check urinary histo Ag and cocciodes IgM/IgG (given old granulomatous disease on chest CT)
-would consider AM cortisol to r/o adrenal insufficiency 
-would repeat hepatitis serologies (HepB sAG, cAB, sAB, HepA AB, HepC Ab) given persistent mildly elevated LFTs
-would check toxoplasma DNA given risk of dz post-transplant




________________________________ 
Riley Riddle MD, MPH
Infectious Disease Fellow
pager 65296



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>