<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2062-10-30

54 yo male from Kazakhstan here for f/u of GI mucor.  Briefly, he was admitted 6/20/62 with DKA and MSSA bacteremia.  He was found to have perirectal abscess s/p CT-guided drains as well as L hip infected prosthesis and abscess s/p removal and drainage in OR on 7/07 and by IR 7/22, both sites positive for MSSA.  Hospital course c/b GIB and was found to have free air with perforated duodenum s/p ex-lap 6/22, gastrectomy with partial large bowel resection, splenectomy and primary anastamosis, with path positive for mucormycosis without clean margins.  He also had VRE/klebsiella LUQ abscess s/p IR drainage.  

He was initially treated with nafcillin and ambisome, but developed maculopapular rash on chest and arms thought to be secondary to nafcillin.  So he was switched to vanco/ambisome/linezolid/meropenem/amikacin for LUQ abscess.  After 6 weeks of high-dose ambisome, he was taken back to OR on 7/31 for re-exploration and was found to have some more necrosis around his esophageal-jejunostomy site that surgeons "scooped out" as much as they could, but were not able to get clean margins because of difficult anatomic restrictions. 
Given the inability to completely en-bloc resect Mr. Ethridge's GI mucor despite a long-trial of Ambisome, he was started on an investigational drug, posaconazole, provided by Emcor on a compassionate use basis.  This has had 50% success of curing mucor as salvage therapy in small trials.  He was started on this drug on 8/28/62 and has tolerated it well despite some nausea, diarrhea.  

He has been at EDUCARE-FARGO reports increase in strength and improved ability to bear weight on his hip.  He walks with a walker.  He had repeat CT abd/pelvix 10/26 which showed no intraabdominal collection and stable L hip collection.  He had abd drains removed 3 weeks ago but continues to have L hip drain, without much output.  He was started on TPN 1 week ago due to maltrition, despite po intake.  He has been trying to eat, but reports some nausea and diarrhea, especially after he eats and since starting posaconazole.  He reports good glycemic control.  He denies fevers/abd pain/nightsweats/chills/visual changes/HA/melena/cough/SOB.

PMHx:

DM

GI mucor

s/p total gastrectomy, esophagojejunostomy, distal pancreatectomy, transverse colectomy 6/62

s/p splenectomy

s/p L THR 3 years ago

L hip MSSA abscess s/p resection of arthroplasty and drainage

perirectal abscess

VRE/klebsiella LUQ (subdiaphragmatic and esophageal hiatal) abscess

CRI

HTN

anemia

neg HIV 7/62





Meds:

posaconazole 200 po QID (liquid)

amlodipine 5 qd

metoprolol 50 tid

clonidine 0.3 mg qweek

niferex

epogen 30,000U SQ qweek

insulin CZI



All: nafcillin-- rash



SH: immigrated to UKRAINE 10 years ago, no relatives here, all in Kazakhstan, single, lived in Alva previously



Habits: no EtOH/cig/IVDU



FHx: NC



PE: 96.3, 60, 102/60, 16

HEENT: o/p clear, no cervical LAD, neck FROM, mild icterus in sclera

Lungs: CTA

CV: rr, s1 and s2, no m/r/g

Abd: soft, NT/ND, +BS, abd incisions well-healed

Ext: L hip drain in place, limited ROM on L hip but improved

Skin: no rash



EKG: QT 363, no acute changes



Imp:

54 yo male with DM s/p long hospital course for DKA, multiple infections in hip and abd, and GI mucor s/p resection x2, but with residual disease.  Currently on posaconazole and tolerating well, but does have significant nausea, somewhat controlled with zofran.  Diarrhea can be a component posaconazole side effect, or due to dumping syndrome.



Plan:

1) continue posaconazole

2) need to have ortho f/u to evaluate L hip collection

3) RTC in 1 month 12/04/62 at 10am to f/u for posaconazole.  Will need EKG again at EDUCARE-FARGO before transfer here.



Mr. Ethridge seen and examined with Dr. Roberts.  He is very slowly improving in terms of strength, no doubt in part due to nocturnal TPN.  Hard to tease out the cause of his nausea, although anatomic reasons are as likely as medication side effects.  On balance, if his labs are ok, I'd favor continuing the posaconazole given most recent OR findings.  ECG without QTc prolongation.  Abdomen is bening.  Left hip still sore, but more and more stable.  



Brandon Gaines, MD





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-01-08

 

Internal Medicine - Team 3 Intern Admit Note



Patient Name: 	Ethridge, Clayton

Medical Record #: 	8381729

Date of Admission: 	01/08/64
Attending: 		Dr. Burton



CC/ID:	clotted AV fistula / renal failure



HPI: 	The patient is a 55 year old male with a past medical history significant for chronic renal failure (secondary to diabetes & hypertension) and gastrointestinal mucormycosis who underwent an arteriovenous graft placement ten days prior to admission. The patient was doing well until a few days prior to admission when he noticed a swelling in his new graft and a decrease in the degree of its pulse. Then on the morning of admission when he noticed his graft was without a palpable pulse or thrill. The patient then presented to the EDUCARE-PULLMAN ER for evaluation and treatment. 



	In the ER, the patient was found to have an engorged AV graft without dopplerable pulse or bruit. The patient was seen by surgery and an ultrasound of the upper extremity revealed a clotted graft and so the patient was admitted to the medical service for further evaluation and treatment.



Of note, the patient denies any pain  / numbness / coolness in his hand. He further denies any shortness of breath, increased swelling in his legs, or changes in his weight. He does indicate that he has suffered from decreased oral intake lately secondary to feeling tired and having a decreased appetite.



PMH: 	Diabetes mellitus

Diabetic neuropathy

Hypertension		

Chronic renal disease		- secondary to diabetes & hypertension, baseline Cr 4

Anemia				- baseline hematocrit mid 30s

Gastrointestinal mucormycosis	- s/p GI surgery (see below)



PSH: 	Hip replacement

Total gastrectomy, gastroesophagojejunostomy, distal pancreatectomy, transverse colectomy

Splenectomy

Left total hip replacement



Allergies:  	Nafcillin - rash



SH:  	Patient lives in Kemmerer at the Chestnut Lodge Sanitarium. He is from Kazakhstan originally, has no family nearby and works as a Glazier. 



	Tob:		Denies

	EtOH:  		Denies

	Illicits: 	Denies



FH:	Non-contributory.





Medications: 	procrit 10,000 U qthursday

catapres tts-3 qwednesday

oscal po tid

hydralazine 50 mg po tid

remeron 15 mg po qhs

colace 100 mg po bid

neurontin 100 mg po qd

folate 1 mg po qd

norvasc 10 mg po qd

trazadone 50 mg po qhs

nephrocaps daily

bumetanide 0.5 mg po qd

niferex 150 mg po qd

calcitrol 0.25 mg po qd



enulose prn

tramadol prn

nitroglycerin ointment prn

milk of magnesia prn

maalox prn

zofran prn

lopermide prn

tylenol prn



Exam:  	VS:  T=96.6       HR=62  	BP=125/61	RR=18	SaO2=99% on RA

General:  	no acute distress, calm, resting comfortably.

HEENT: 	pupils equal and reactive to light, anicteric sclera, extraocular movements intact.

Skin:		no rashes.

Neck:  		supple.

Chest: 		clear to auscultation bilaterally.

CVS:  		regular rate & rhythm, III/VI holosystolic murmurs, no rubs.

Abd:  		soft, non-distended, non-tender to palpation, normoactive bowel sounds.

Extr:  		+1 edema, no papable thrill or auscultatable bruit in AV graft.

MSK:		no joint swelling, no erythema, full range of motion.

Neuro: 	CN II through XII intact, motor strength 5/5 UE and LE, sensory intact.



DATA

Test Description       Result Ref. Range/Units Date/Time          Last Abnormal

Chemistry

  Lytes/Renal/Glucose

    Sodium                 136   135-145 mmol/L     01/08/64 13:51     133(L) 08/28/62 

    Potassium              4.9H  3.4-4.8 mmol/L     01/08/64 13:51     4.9(H) 01/08/64 

    Chloride               111H  100-108 mmol/L     01/08/64 13:51     111(H) 01/08/64 

    Carbon Dioxide        18.6L  23.0-31.9 mmol/L   01/08/64 13:51    18.6(L) 01/08/64 

    BUN                     82H  8-25 mg/dl         01/08/64 13:51      82(H) 01/08/64 

    Creatinine             5.9H  0.6-1.5 mg/dl      01/08/64 13:51     5.9(H) 01/08/64 

    Glucose                133H  70-100 mg/dl       01/08/64 17:54     133(H) 01/08/64 

Hematology

  Complete Blood Count

    WBC                    5.1   4.5-11.0 th/cmm    01/08/64 13:44     4.3(L) 04/29/63 

    RBC                   3.12L  4.50-5.90 mil/cm   01/08/64 13:44    3.12(L) 01/08/64 

    Hgb                   10.1L  13.5-17.5 gm/dl    01/08/64 13:44    10.1(L) 01/08/64 

    HCT                   31.1L  41.0-53.0 %        01/08/64 13:44    31.1(L) 01/08/64 

    MCV                    100   80-100 fl          01/08/64 13:44     101(H) 12/22/63 

    MCH                   32.5   26.0-34.0 pg/rbc   01/08/64 13:44

    MCHC                  32.6   31.0-37.0 g/dl     01/08/64 13:44    30.1(L) 07/09/62 

    PLT                    179   150-350 th/cumm    01/08/64 13:44     370(H) 08/27/62 

    RDW                   15.0H  11.5-14.5 %        01/08/64 13:44    15.0(H) 01/08/64 

  Blood Differential %

    Neutrophils             43   40-70 %            01/08/64 13:44      77(H) 08/27/62 

    Lymphs                  46H  22-44 %            01/08/64 13:44      46(H) 01/08/64 

    Monos                    5   4-11 %             01/08/64 13:44       2(L) 08/27/62 

    Eos                      5   0-8 %              01/08/64 13:44

    Basos                    1   0-3 %              01/08/64 13:44



Urinalysis

    GLUC - UA            Trace   NEG                01/08/64 15:20

    Ketones           NEGATIVE   NEG                01/08/64 15:20

    Specific Gravity     1.015   1.001-1.035        01/08/64 15:20   1.037(H) 07/16/59 

    Blood - UA        NEGATIVE   NEG                01/08/64 15:20

    pH                     5.0   5.0-9.0            01/08/64 15:20

    Nitrites          NEGATIVE   NEG                01/08/64 15:20

    WBC Screen        NEGATIVE   NEG                01/08/64 15:20

    Hyaline Cast          None   0-5 /lpf           01/08/64 16:19

    RBC - UA               3-5   0-2 /hpf           01/08/64 16:19

    WBC - UA               0-2   0-2 /hpf           01/08/64 16:19

    Bacteria          NEGATIVE   NEG /hpf           01/08/64 16:19

    Squamous Cells    NEGATIVE   NEG /hpf           01/08/64 16:19



Micro:		Blood & urine cultures pending



UpperExt U/S:	Clotted right upper extremity arteriovenous graft.



Impression:  	55 year old male with chronic renal failure, hypertension, diabetes and gastrointestinal mucormycosis who is s/p AV graft placement presents with clotted AV graft & renal failure.



AV Graft

   	Patient will undergo IR intervention on 01/09 in an attempt to restore flow to the AV graft

   	Will keep patient NPO after midnight

   	Will avoid systemic anticoagulants

   	Will obtain hypercoagulable labs



Renal Failure

   	Patient has chronic renal failure, secondary to diabetes and hypertension

   	Will need dialysis soon

   	Will continue nephrocaps, calcitrol, procrit



Hypertension

   	Will continue outpatient regimen



Anemia

   	Will continue iron supplementation / procrit weekly injections



Prophylaxis

   	DVT prophylaxis: 	will encourage ambulation 

   	GI prophylaxis: 	will initiate nexium & colace



Dispo

   	Patient will likely return to Chestnut Lodge Sanitarium on discharge





_________________________________

Uriel Q. Yarbrough, MD

Pager #89356



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-01-28

Patient Name: 	Ethridge, Clayton

Medical Record #: 	8381729

Attending: 		Dr. Burton



CC/ID:	fever post HD



HPI: 	The patient is a 55 year old male with a past medical history significant for chronic renal failure (secondary to diabetes & hypertension) and gastrointestinal mucormycosis who was recently admitted for a clotted AVF, s/p thrombectomy. Unfortunately, graft eventually reclotted and was deemed unsalvageable- the patient was then started on HD via a tunnelled catheter. Was tolerating this well, until day prior to admission noted a fever prior to going to HD. Blood cultures taken yesterday at HD, returned today with GPC in clusters, further speciation to follow. Admitted for fever workup.

Pt. currently complains of some generalized fatigue, malaise, nausea. Has a hx of abdominal mucormycosis resulting in chronic abdominal discomfort, which today is at baseline. No CP, SOB.





PMH: 	Diabetes mellitus

Diabetic neuropathy

Hypertension		

Chronic renal disease		- secondary to diabetes & hypertension, baseline Cr 4

Anemia				- baseline hematocrit mid 30s

Gastrointestinal mucormycosis	- s/p GI surgery (see below)



PSH: 	Hip replacement

Total gastrectomy, gastroesophagojejunostomy, distal pancreatectomy, transverse colectomy

Splenectomy

Left total hip replacement



Allergies:  	Nafcillin - rash



SH:  	Patient lives in Kemmerer at the Chestnut Lodge Sanitarium. He is from Kazakhstan originally, has no family nearby and works as a Glazier. 



	Tob:		Denies

	EtOH:  		Denies

	Illicits: 	Denies



FH:	Non-contributory.





Medications: 

1) Tylenol PRN 2) Remeron 15 mg at bedtime 3) Folic acid 1 mg PO daily 4) Trazodone 50 mg at bedtime 5) Nephrocaps 1 PO daily 6) Calcium carbonate with vitamin D 250 mg 3 x day 7) Nexium 20 mg PO daily 8) Hydralazine 50 mg 3 x day 9) Norvasc 10 mg PO daily 10) Clonidine 0.1 mg twice a day 11) Regular insulin sliding scale 12) Procrit 10K U weekly



Exam:  	VS:  T=999.9       HR=69  	BP=124/63	RR=18	SaO2=99% on RA

General:  	no acute distress, calm, resting comfortably.

HEENT: 	pupils equal and reactive to light, anicteric sclera, extraocular movements intact.

Skin:		no rashes.

Neck:  		supple. S subclavian HD catheter CDI

Chest: 		clear to auscultation bilaterally.

CVS:  		regular rate & rhythm, III/VI holosystolic murmurs, no rubs.

Abd:  		soft, non-distended, non-tender to palpation, normoactive bowel sounds.

Extr:  		+1 edema, no papable thrill or auscultatable bruit in AV graft.

MSK:		no joint swelling, no erythema, full range of motion.

Neuro: 	CN II through XII intact, motor strength 5/5 UE and LE, sensory intact.





Results

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            

01/23/2064        135            3.9            101            26.2           



Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            

01/23/2064        17             2.3 (H)                       

01/23/2064        49 (H)         5.1 (H)        159 (H)        



Date/Time         CA             PHOS           ALB            

01/23/2064        6.7 (L)        4.1            3.0 (L)        



Date/Time         CCOM           

01/25/2064         [1]           

01/23/2064         [2]           



Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            

01/28/2064        5.3            2.50 (L)       8.2 (L)        25.6 (L)       

01/25/2064        7.0            2.45 (L)       8.0 (L)        25.4 (L)       

01/23/2064        4.6            2.37 (L)       7.8 (L)        24.2 (L)       



Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            

01/28/2064        103 (H)        32.9           32.1           315            

01/25/2064        104 (H)        32.8           31.6           303            

01/23/2064        102 (H)        32.7           32.1           334            



Date/Time         RDW            

01/28/2064        14.1           

01/25/2064        14.6 (H)       

01/23/2064        14.1           



Date/Time         DIFFR          METHOD         %NEUT          %LYMPH         

01/28/2064        RECEIVED       Auto           46             45 (H)         



Date/Time         %MONO          %EOS           %BASO          

01/28/2064        6              3              0              



Date/Time         ANEUT          ALYMP          AMONS          AEOSN          

01/28/2064        2.48           2.34           0.31           0.14           



Date/Time         ABASOP         

01/28/2064        0.01           



Date/Time         ANISO          HYPO           MACRO          MICRO          

01/28/2064        None           1+             2+             None           



Date/Time         PROTSF         PROTCF         PROTCA         





[1] RESULT COMMENT:   PREDOMINANT GROWTH OF

[2] RESULT COMMENT:   Post dialysis







Microbiology



01/28/2064 21:47 EDUCARE-PULLMAN Microbiology

Specimen Type BLOOD CULTURE

Accession # 5856E7910







  Specimen: 5856E7910        Collected 28-Jan-64 21:47                     

                             Received  28-Jan-64 21:47                     

  Specimen Group:   BLOOD/SERUM

  Specimen Type:    BLOOD CULTURE

  Specimen Comment: PERIPHERAL IV  SET 2



  Blood Culture - Pending 







01/28/2064 21:46 EDUCARE-PULLMAN Microbiology

Specimen Type BLOOD CULTURE

Accession # 6934P2380







  Specimen: 6934P2380        Collected 28-Jan-64 20:00                     

                             Received  28-Jan-64 21:46                     

  Specimen Group:   BLOOD/SERUM

  Specimen Type:    BLOOD CULTURE

  Specimen Comment: SET 1



  Blood Culture - Pending 







01/27/2064 15:01 EDUCARE-PULLMAN Microbiology

Specimen Type BLOOD CULTURE

Accession # 6931L53151







  Specimen: 6931L53151       Collected 27-Jan-64 12:30                     

                             Received  27-Jan-64 15:01                     

  Specimen Group:   BLOOD/SERUM

  Specimen Type:    BLOOD CULTURE

  Specimen Comment: SET 2 DIALYSIS



  Blood Culture - Preliminary    Reported: 28-Jan-64 17:29

    Aerobic bottle: GRAM POSITIVE COCCI IN CLUSTERS Susceptibilities pending

    RESULT CALLED TO CARE UNIT AND/OR MD ON 1/28/64 







01/27/2064 14:59 EDUCARE-PULLMAN Microbiology

Specimen Type BLOOD CULTURE

Accession # 3194S62727







  Specimen: 3194S62727       Collected 27-Jan-64 12:30                     

                             Received  27-Jan-64 14:59                     

  Specimen Group:   BLOOD/SERUM

  Specimen Type:    BLOOD CULTURE

  Specimen Comment: SET 1 DIALYSIS



  Blood Culture - Preliminary    Reported: 28-Jan-64 07:24

    NO GROWTH 1 DAY 


Impression:  55 year old male with chronic renal failure, hypertension, diabetes and gastrointestinal mucormycosis who is s/p recent tunnelled catheter placement, now presenting with fever post HD, GPC in blood.

ID- Likely catheter related infection, will continue vanco for now, await speciation of GPC. Will recx if spikes above 101.5. FU urine cx. Vanco/Gent. Ultimately needs line out.

ESRD-continue dialysis schedule, will continue nephrocaps, calcitrol, procrit

Hypertension

Will continue outpatient regime

DM- Sliding scale insulin

Heme Protein C and S levels decreased on repeat testing. I believe protein C can be influenced by ESRD, but not protein S. This needs to be followed up further.

Prophylaxis

DVT prophylaxis: 	Fragmin 

GI prophylaxis: 	nexium


_____________________________________________

Herbert C. Guerrero, M. D.





      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-07-28

 



Team 2 Internal Medicine Intern Admission Note



Name:  Ethridge, Clayton

MR#:  8381729

Admit Date: 7/28/64

Attending:  Dr. Tomlin

Admitting intern: Ursula Quiles, MD

Code: Full



Source: Medical record, Patient



Chief Complaint: fistula clot



History of Present Illness:  Pt is a 59 yo Khazakhstani male, with h/o HTN, DM, mucormycosis, and ESRD on HD presenting with a thrombosed AVF in his left arm, established in April of 2064 by Dr. Jordon.  The patient has a history of multiple problems with access (clots, stenoses), requiring frequent thrombectomies and revisions.   The patient first noticed a problem on July 23, and by the 24th he said that "the access had collapsed." On July 25, interventional radiology attempted to thrombectomize the clot, with no success, requiring placement of a new tunneled catheter in left IJ to allow dialysis.  At present, patient is on the OR waiting list for tomorrow, for thrombectomy/revision.  



Of note, patient was admitted in April of 2064 after a nurse at the McLaren Hospital detected a new cardiac murmur.  Pt was found to have a RA thrombus by echo, presumed to be a complication from a prior catheter, started on a heparin gtt and transitioned to coumadin.  



ROS: No fever/chills, HA, SOB, CP, N/V/D (though states that stomach sometimes "sensitive").



Past Medical History: 

DM - Type 2

HTN

ESRD on HD MWF, with h/o multiple problems with access, Cr baseline 4

s/p extensive bowel resection for mucormycosis, June 2062 (gastrectomy, esophagojejunostomy, splenectomy, distal pancreatectomy, segmental transverse colectomy)	

s/p L THR    s/p resection arthroplasty of left femoral head and acetabulum for fungal infection (mucomycosis above, June 2062)

R atrial thrombus by echo in 4/63





Allergies: 

Nafcillin- rash

Penicillin- rash



Medications (upon admission)

      Remeron (MIRTAZAPINE)   15 MG (15MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 

      Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE)   20 MG (20MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO QD 

      TRAZODONE   50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 

      Colace (DOCUSATE Sodium)   100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO TID 

      Norvasc (AMLODIPINE)   10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      Diovan (VALSARTAN)   80 MG (80MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      Insulin Regular Human   SC  

      NEPHROCAPS   1 CAPSULE PO QD 

      Renagel (SEVELAMER)   806 MG (403MG CAPSULE take 2) PO TID 

      Folate (FOLIC Acid)   1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      Calcium Carbonate (500 Mg Elemental Ca++)   1250 MG PO AC 

      Warfarin Sodium   2.5 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 1) PO QPM



Social History:  Patient is a native of Kazakhstan, who moved to the UKRAINE to study Electrical Mechanics at OpenMarket Inc.  He is currently unable to pursue this field, due to his debilitated state, however he would like to try to intern, when he feels up to it.  He lives in the McLaren Hospital in Kemmerer (a facility for homeless individuals.)  No tobacco, EtOH, illicits. 



Family History: Non-contributory.



Exam: 

Vitals:  BP 121/62  HR 78 RR 16  T 97.5 O2 sat 100% RA

Gen:  

HEENT: PERL, OP without erythema, exudates; mucous membranes moist; no scleral icterus

Pulm: CTA with good air movement bilat.; no c/w/r

Cor/Cardiac: RRR nl. S1,S2; no m/g/r, neck veins flat

Abdomen: S/NT/ND; +BS throughout; no HSM, palpable/pulsatile masses

Extremity: no c/c/e; distal pulses 2+ bilat; left LE shorter than right and internally rotated

Neurological: CN II-XII grossly intact, strength 5/5 all major muscle groups; DTR's 2+ bilat. UE/LE, 



Laboratory

 

Hematology 

EDUCARE-PULLMAN  BLOOD          27-Jul-2064 16:10  Accession# 8911Z65654

WBC                              8.0                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              34.7             L        (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              11.0             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              3.55             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              255                       (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              98                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              31.1                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             31.8                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              15.3             H        (11.5-14.5)    %

Retic                            2.6              H        (0.5-2.5)      %





Chemistry

EDUCARE-PULLMAN  BLOOD          27-Jul-2064 16:10  Accession# 8911Z65654

Plasma Sodium                    135                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 5.0              H        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  100                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            19.4             L        (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Calcium                          7.7              L        (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       5.3              H        (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             74               H        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                7.7              H        (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Plasma Glucose                   113              H        (70-110)       mg/dl

Albumin                          3.7                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl

Parathyroid Hormone              187              H        (10-60)        pg/ml





EKG: NSR at 75-80, normal axis, normal intervals. No ST changes or TWIs compared to prior in April 2064 (J point elevation in V1-V3 in both). 



 

Cardiac Studies

Echo: 4/25/2064 

EF 65%, LVH, mobile mass (27x22mm) in RA, small pericardial effusion. 



Radiology

CXR July 27, 2064

IMPRESSION: Dual lumen dialysis catheter from the left jugular region to the right atrium without pneumothorax, hematoma, or pleural effusion. No new or enlarging infiltrates or masses.  Slight fullness in the region of the right thyroid gland.

	





Assessment and Plan: 59 yo Kazakhstani male, with HTN, DM, and ESRD on HD, and h/o access issues (multiple thromboses, stenoses requiring frequent revisions) and admitted with clotted left AVF for revision/thrombectomy in the OR.  

1.	Access: clotted L AVF, functional left IJ tunneled cath.

a.	On waiting list with Dr. Jordon for procedure tomorrow

i.	NPO p MN

ii.	Hold coumadin

b.	IV access for R arm. 

2.	ESRD on HD

a.	Patient for dialysis on Monday, if still inpatient.

b.	Contine nephrocaps, renagel, CaCarbonate, 

3.	DM: Pt reports well-controlled, rarely c FS>200

a.	FS qam, qpm before breakfast and dinner; reg ins sliding scale

b.	Diabetic diet

4.	HTN

a.	Continue outpatient regimen of norvasc and diovan

b.	Note: these meds are held on dialysis days (MWF)

5.	h/o R atrial clot

a.	INR goal 1.8-2.5

b.	Consider repeat echo, to evaluate clot stabilization and to better plan anticoagulation regimen

c.	Follow coags

6.	Elevated K to 5.8    5.0 on 7/27.

a.	Check pm labs, assess need for kayexalate. 

7.	Low Hct (lowest since 1/64)

a.	Anemia panel

8.	Prophylaxis

a.	Nexium, on coumadin tx (though held tonight)

9.	Code status: full code

 
Ursula Quiles, MD

Team 2 intern

#50684




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>