<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2059-06-19

PROMPTCARE INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Rutledge, Eva
                                              29195561
                                              6-19-59
 
 
 
HPI:  This is a regularly scheduled visit for this Eva Ruledge a 
44-year old woman with a history of hypertension and borderline obesity.  
She was last here in February with no complaints, but did have an elevated 
creatinine for which she was referred to the Internal Medicine for further 
evaluation.  The patient did not, however, present to the Internal Medicine as 
planned.  She states that she has been "too busy."  Her only complaint 
today is of some right leg pain, which she says is chronic and which is 
relieved to some extent by acetaminophen.  
 
Eva continues to take Procardia XL 30 mg. PO q.day.  A noted in her 
ambulatory record, the Procardia is prescribed as a b.i.d. drug, however, 
Eva believes it gives her headaches and refuses to take it other than 
on an almost p.r.n. basis.  
 
Review of systems is essentially normal.  Specifically, she denies any 
headaches, any chest pain, any shortness of breath.  She also denies any 
symptoms or signs referable to her urinary tract.  She has no history of 
dysuria, of frequent urinary tract infection, or of hematuria.
 
Physical Examination:  She is robust appearing.  Vital signs are 
significant for a blood pressure of 140/100.  HEENT exam is unremarkable.  
Lungs are clear.  Cardiac exam reveals a regular rate and rhythm, a normal 
S1, S2.  No S3 is appreciated.  There are no murmurs or rubs.  Abdomen is 
slightly obese, nontender, and with normal bowel sounds.  No masses are 
appreciated.  Lower extremities are without edema and joint exam does not 
suggest effusion or limitation of her range of motion.  Indeed, exam of 
her legs is entirely unremarkable.  
 
Laboratory:  Will include a repeat creatinine, a urinalysis and urine 
sediment and a urine creatinine.
 
Assessment and Plan:
 
1.   Hypertension:  Eva has had persistently elevated blood pressure 
     on her Procardia.  I have asked her to stop taking Procardia, which 
     she blames for headaches and to begin taking taking atenolol, 
     beginning at 50 mg. PO q.day.  I will see her in a few days in order 
     to make sure that she is not having any difficulties with this drug 
     and also to check her blood pressure once again.
 
2.   Right leg pain:  This would appear to be chronic and may well be 
     related to her work, which requires her to scuttle throughout the 
     hospital at fairly high speed (She is a Pulping Control Operator.)  I  have asked her to continue taking 
     Tylenol and we will re-evaluate her need for more powerful agents, 
     such as nonsteroidals if the need arises.
PROMPTCARE INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES          Rutledge, Eva
Page 2                                        29195561
                                              6-19-59
 
 
 
3.   Elevated creatinine:  Unfortunately, Eva has not kept her Renal 
     appointment.  In order to prevent this from recurring a third time, I 
     have called and made an appointment for her with Dr. Eileen Xayavong.  
     She is to see him on the 29th of this month at 1:00 p.m. and I have 
     also left a message on his E mail mentioning Eva to him.  
     Hopefully, he can help ultrasound identify the etiology of this 
     elevated creatinine before there is further loss of her kidney 
     function.  
 
4.   Health Maintenance:  The patient was scheduled to have a Pap smear 
     today, but again was "too busy to stay that long."  She is to see me 
     again shortly, and a Pap smear will be done at that time.  Her 
     February mammogram was essentially not suggestive of malignancy and 
     will not be repeated until next year.  
 
 
 
 
_________________________
Ulysses Quijano, M.D.
 
TD:PX:4740
DD:6-20-59
DT:6-19-59
DV:6-19-59
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Attending Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2066-10-08

                                                       Patient Name: RUTLEDGE,EVA [ MRN: 37947241ZGJ ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 10/08/2066


                                      PROMPTCAREIMA Clinic Note



Mrs. Rutledge is a former patient of Dr. Xia's who comes in today to establish a new PCP and for follow-up of her hypertension, diabetes, chronic renal insufficiency (baseline creatinine 2.2), and GERD.  She is currently on procardia xl, losartan, and atenolol for her hypertension.  She takes a baby aspirin qd for cardiac protection.  Her diabetes is controlled by diet alone, and her GERD by zantac 150 qd or bid prn.  Her last HbA1C was 6.9, with a malb/cr ratio of 222.2 and trace protein on U/A.  She has had a prior cardiac work-up for atypical chest pain with a negative ETT/SPECT in 2062 and a negative ETT in 2064.  An echo in 2062 showed an EF of 65% with no valvular abnormalities.



She is currently well with no complaints.  She is being followed in opthalmology for possible glaucoma.  She does not check her blood sugars at home, although she has a glucometer.  When asked if her sugars are ever low, she states that she has the same symptoms with hypoglycemia that she does with hyperglycemia: dizziness and hot flashes.  She's not had this recently.  She also does not check her BP at home.  She denies any numbness or tingling in her fingers, or any chest pain.  She did pull a muscle in her shoulder last night and still feels tender in that area.  She follows a diabetic diet (avoids sweets), gets no regular exercise, but works in Electrical and Avionics Mechanics so does have physical activity during the day.



PSHx: none

PGynHx: G7 P4 SAB1 TAB2, still menstruating q month, no hot flashes, heavy periods but no clots; LMP 10/01/66

Allergies: NKAD

Habits: never smoked, very rare EtOH, no illicit drugs



Medications:

ASA  81MG PO QD

ATENOLOL  100MG PO QD  (she has run out of this and did not take it today)

PROCARDIA XL  30MG PO QD

RANITIDINE HCL   150MG PO QD

LOSARTAN  50MG PO 2 qd



Physical Exam	

================ Vital signs ================

 Blood Pressure:  --  136/76

 Pulse:  --  76

Weight:  --  139  [Pounds]

General:  no acute distress

HEENT:   PERLA, anicteric, O/P clear

Neck:      no thyromegaly or LAN; no carotid bruits

Chest:     lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally with no crackles 

Heart:      regular rate and rhythm, S1 and S2 normal, no m/g/r  

Abd:        soft, NT/ND.  +BS.  No HSM or masses

Pelvic:     Pap done, with normal vaginal mucosa and cervix

Ext:  no edema, peripheral pulses present and feet without lesions.



Assessment:  51 yo woman with diabetes, hypertension, CRI from hypertension/diabetic nephropathy likely. 



Current Plan:

1.  Diabetes.  Checking A1C off medication.  Would like to have patient check FS when she's feeling ill or if A1C is elevated.  Will refer to NP for review glucometer use, diabetic diet.  She has been tried on glucotrol XL in the past and was hypoglycemia.  This is also probably not a good choice due to her renal insufficiency.  May try glyburide if A1C elevated.  Being followed by opthalmology with upcoming appt.  Podiatry referral deferred.  Consider repeat referral to nutrition.  Lipids very good (LDL 82) last check off medication.

2.  Hypertension.  BP borderline elevated today, but off atenolol.  HR also up.  Refilled all meds; will ask NP to check her pressure at next visit.  Will continue qd ASA for CAD/stroke prevention.

3.  GERD.  Continue zantac bid as needed.  Also recommended that patient start using Tums for calcium supplementation and relief of intermittent dyspepsia.  She will try this and get back to me about the effect.

4.  Chronic renal insufficiency.  Will get 24-hour urine to assess creatinine clearance and urine protein.  Checking chem 7 today for K and Creatinine.

5.  Health maintenance.  Patient due to dT shot, requested today.  Normal mammogram in 5/66.  Stool guaiac and flex sig can be done at next appt; will follow-up Pap.  


______________________________                              



Xena Danielle Elmore, M.D.



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



51 yo Puerto Rican woman with dm, htn, cri.  Cre last checked 2.2.  On procadia, losartan, atenolol.  Ran out of atenolol.   Does not check blood sugars.  No neuropathy.  She is active through her job (Electrical and Avionics Mechanics Technician ).  ETT was negative 10/64. 



136/76 pulse 76



Plan:  currently, on diet control.  Last A1c 6.9%.

Refilled Meds.

Pap done.  



______________________________                              



Xen Chris Emmons, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2069-11-18

HPI

54 yo F with h/o CRI, DM on insulin, HTN, obesity, GERD, glaucoma, anemia, p/f for f/u. 

She is generally doing well and has no complaints. She lost her glucometer and hasnt check her BS for 2 weeks. Last A1C after starting insulin down to 7.5, only on 5 glyburide bc of BS lows.

For her CRI, which is multifactorial (DM, HTN and L renal artery stenosis) she sees Dr Uriarte in Internal Medicine, saw him yesterday, Cr stable and PTH up a bit to 226. 

 

================ Problems ================

ESSENTIAL HYPERTENSION          

MODERATE OBESITY          

Diabetes mellitus          

Chronic renal dysfunction          cre cl estimate 23 in 12/67

Glaucoma          

Lactose intolerance          

Atypical chest pain          negative ETT 4/8/67, negative ETT 2064, ETT w/ SPECT 2062

Iron-deficiency anemia         

Gastritis          EGD 9/67, also GERD symptoms



================ Medications ================

Asa 81 MG PO QD 

Procardia XL 60 MG (60MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , may use adalat instead

Ranitidine HCL 150 MG PO QD 

Losartan 100 MG PO QD 

Glyburide 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Ferrous GLUCONATE 325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID , Take one tablet with every meal for iron deficiency

Hydrochlorothiazide 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take every day for blood pressure

Toprol XL (METOPROLOL SUCCINATE EXTENDED ... 50MG TABLET CR 24HR take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Calcitriol 0.25MCG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s) PO QD 

Zocor (SIMVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 

Lantus (INSULIN GLARGINE) 16 UNITS SC QHS , dose increase

Timolol XE 0.25% 1 DROP OU QD , must keep appt

Xalatan (LATANOPROST) 1 DROP OU QPM , must keep scheduled appt 





ALLERGIES   NKDA 



PHYSICAL EXAM

VS: BP 110/60  

Cor: RRR, nl S1S2, 1/6 sys M, no rubs, gallops

Lungs: CTA b/l, no rales, rhonchi or wheezes

Abd: Soft, NTND. Normal active bowel sounds. 

No c/c/e



A/P

54 yo F with h/o CRI, DM, HTN, obesity, GERD, glaucoma, anemia for f/u. 

1. DM: Last A1C 7.5 from 9.3 after starting insulin, still on  Lantus 16 and now Glyburide 5 qam. She sees Optho 2x/yr as she has glaucoma, saw them 2mos ago. 

--Prescribed glucometer

--Cont current regimen

--check A1C (pt left without getting labs, will get at next visit)

--2/69 urine mcalb/cr 200

--on statin



2. CRI: Multifactorial, followed by Dr Uriarte. Last Cr  2.8 on 5/69. She has 2ndary hyperparathyroidism as well, PTH yest 226. On Calcitriol. 

--Cont ARB. 

--F/u with Dr Uriarte. 



3. Anemia, h/o, Fe deficiency, on Fe supp. Last Hct 36.



4. H/o bowel ischemia but most recent CT wnl so more likely it was an infectious etiology.



5. HTN: Cont on ARB, Toprol, Procardia, HCTZ. Today somewhat high, increased Procardia to 60 qd. On ASA for 1ry prevention of CAD. Statin.



6.GERD: Cont Zantac, well controlled sx.



7. Galucoma: followed by Optho, cont eye drops



8. HM:

--lipids 8/69much improved with addition of statin TC 121, TG 309, HDL 28, LDL 31. Lfts ok. Will check again in Feb

--BMD 10/68 wnl

--colonoscopy 2/68 wnl

--Mammo will be scheduled for 12/69

--PAP overdue, will reschedule a PAP appt









______________________________                              



Quiana Gagnon, M.D.

      



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



I have discussed the evaluation and care of this patient with Dr. Gagnon.





______________________________                              



David R. Quintin, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-03-13

                                                       Patient Name: RUTLEDGE,EMMA [ MRN: 37947241ZGJ ]

                                                         Date of Visit:3/13/2072









HPI  DM, CRI, HTN-, with L5-S1 disc protrusion on MRI  , with normal Ct scan hip/leg





56 yo F with h/o CRI, DM on insulin, HTN, obesity, GERD, glaucoma, anemia, p/f for f/u. 

For her CRI, which is multifactorial (DM, HTN and L renal artery stenosis) she sees Dr Uriarte in Internal Medicine, w/ an appt on  next week and  unchanged Cr 4.5  



She had an AV fistula placed in anticipation for  future dialysis.



In March 2070, she was admitted for for ischemia colitis and had a colonoscopy revealing this. Underwent surgery for ischemia colitis in April 2070 with a right colectomy. 



She had a mammo in 2/13/2071 wnl.  Pap 9/27/2070 wnl.  separated from husband. Has children and granchildren. Needs refills of losartan, procardia, and toprol XL.



Main issues for her are her leg pain ( due to L5-S1 disc protrusion), and HTN which is elevated 171/94 ( sec to  leg pain)



Denies trauma, fall. Had PT at home briefly   but not at PROMPTCARE. She was supposed to have had an appt with ortho spine clinic per discharge summary, but she said they did not call  her.









================ Problems ================

ESSENTIAL HYPERTENSION          

MODERATE OBESITY          

Diabetes mellitus          

Chronic renal dysfunction          cre cl estimate 23 in 12/68

Glaucoma          

Lactose intolerance          

Atypical chest pain          negative ETT 4/8/67, negative ETT 2064, ETT w/ SPECT 2062

Iron-deficiency anemia         

Gastritis          EGD 9/67, also GERD symptoms



================ Medications ================

Asa 81 MG PO QD 

Procardia XL 60 MG (60MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , may use adalat instead

Ranitidine HCL 150 MG PO QD 

Losartan 100 MG PO QD 

Glyburide 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Ferrous GLUCONATE 325MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO TID , Take one tablet with every meal for iron deficiency

Hydrochlorothiazide 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD , Take every day for blood pressure

Toprol XL (METOPROLOL SUCCINATE EXTENDED ... 50MG TABLET CR 24HR take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Calcitriol 0.25MCG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s) PO QD 

Zocor (SIMVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 

Lantus (INSULIN GLARGINE) 16 UNITS SC QHS , dose increase

Timolol XE 0.25% 1 DROP OU QD , must keep appt

Xalatan (LATANOPROST) 1 DROP OU QPM , must keep scheduled appt 





ALLERGIES   NKDA 



PHYSICAL EXAM









Vital Signs

BP 171/94, P 90, Wt 125 lb

 











FS:  84 postprandial



HEENT: op clear,supple neck,no thyromegaly

HEART RR, S1S2

LUNGS CTA no r/r/w

ABD: +Bs, soft, nt,nd







LABS HGA1C



A/P

56 yo F with h/o CRI, DM, HTN, obesity, GERD, glaucoma, anemia for f/u s/p right colectomy for ischemia colitis, sciatica with L5-S1 disc protrusion on MRI  3 weeks ago

. 

1. DM: Last A1C 7.5 down from    9.3 previously after starting insulinTaking novulin 12 units QAM and novulog 4 units q OM. She sees Optho 2x/yr as she has glaucoma w/ an appt 3/28/2071. missed podiatry  again.

-check HGA1C; Cr increased to 4.5 per renal and  has app  with  renal next week



2. CRI: Multifactorial, followed by Dr Uriarte. Last Cr  2.5 on 4/2070. She has 2ndary hyperparathyroidism as well,  On Calcitriol. 

--Cont ARB. 

--F/u with Dr Uriarte. - Cr 4.5



3. Anemia, h/o, Fe deficiency, on Fe supp. Last Hct 33 in 4/2070.



4. H/o bowel ischemia s/p colectomy f/u with surgery.



5. HTN: Cont on ARB, Toprol, Procardia. Increase toprol XL to 100 mg poq d.  Cont losartan 100 mg qd, procardia 60 mg poq d. Has been off HCTZ. Pulse 90 and should tolerate inc toprol to 100



6.GERD: Cont Zantac, well controlled sx.



7. Glaucoma: followed by Optho, cont eye drops



8. HM:

--lipids recheck today

--BMD 10/68 wnl

--colonoscopy 3/2070 c/w ischemia colitis o/w unremarkable ( s/p surgery 4/8/2070)

--Mammo  wnl  2/2071. recsched next visit, because she is most concerned with her  leg/hip pain from sciatica

--PAP utd Breast exam done. SBE counseled.  



RTC 1 month for BP check; f/u HGA1C





______________________________                              



Betty Doris Hanna, MD



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>