<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2121-03-31

Kern Medical Center

Preadmission Testing Area

Department of Internal Medicine

Preanesthetic Assessment



Tina L. Purcell, M.D.

Associate Medical Director


March 31, 2121



Medical Record Number:  4698877 Isabella T. Valle



Procedure:  The patient is a 53 year old female scheduled for parathyroidectomy.  Surgery is scheduled on 4/03/21.



Chief Complaint & Present Illness:  hyperparathyroidism-parathormone level > 900-resulting in spontaneous fractures.  Patient had previous semi total parathyroidectomy in 2112.



Past Surgical History:  Prior surgery includes: ' 09 TAH-BSO;' 10 parathyroidectomy;' 13 renal transplant recipient; '18 left nephrectomy-easy mask and intubation; ventral hernia repair; AV fistulas x2-general anesthesia without any known problems



Family History:  There is no family history of adverse reactions to general anesthesia.



Medications:  Neoral, Lasix 40 mg, Norvasc 5 mg b.i.d., Lipitor 20 mg b.i.d., Cellcept 50 mg q.i.d., Bactrim, Estrotab, prednisone 10 mg, Epogen, iron, insulin NPH 45 units plus regular 10 units in a.m.

Allergies:  none



Social History:

	Smoking:  none

	Alcohol use:  rare

	Substance Abuse:  none

	Allergen Exposure within 3 Months(blood products/pregnancy): none



Review of Systems:  



HEENT:  negative

Cardiovascular:  hypertension; patient usually walks one mile per day and climbs one flight of stairs without any angina or shortness of breath

Respiratory: negative

Renal:  polycystic renal disease diagnosed 15 years ago resulting in renal transplant 2/13 and now renal failure with elevated creatinine 5.3-no dialysis at present

Hepatobiliary: negative

Neurological: negative

Gastrointestinal: no reflux

Hematological:  bruises easily, anemia-last hematocrit 31 percent but has been as low as 19 within the last year 

Endocrine/metabolic: diabetes treated with insulin-blood sugar 190

Musculoskeletal/Skin: recent infection in left foot fourth toe; left hip deterioration causing pain

Psychiatric: negative

Obstetrical:  negative



Vital Signs:



	BP:  152/87 mm Hg

	P:  88 bpm

	Resp:  20 rpm

	SaO2:  97%

	Temp:  97.7 degrees F

	Ht:  66 inches

	Wt:  158.8 pounds



Exam:



HEEN&T:  good range of motion, no bruits

Airway:  Mallampatti Class II

Teeth:  dentures

Lungs:  clear to auscultation bilaterally

Heart:  regular rhythm, no murmurs



Assessment:  

ASA Physical Status III-53 year old female with history of polycystic disease in renal failure status post renal transplant.  Patient has elevated parathormone level with resultant  spontaneous fractures.  EKG today shows normal sinus rhythm with biphasic T-wave in V4 and inverted T-wave in V5, V6.  Discussed patient with Dr. Uren-T-wave changes are new since 1/21. He will order a preoperative stress test.



Plan:



	Proposed Anesthetic: general endotracheal anesthesia

	Monitors:  standard

	Pain Management:  PCA

	Autologous blood:  none

	Premedication:  STRESS steroids

	Usual Medications:  in a.m. of surgery

	Medications to be held on day of surgery:  Lipitor D/C'd today

	Diabetic medications:  NPH 24 units in a.m.-no regular insulin

	NSAIDS:  D/C'd

	Aspirin:  none

	NPO: after midnight



Ancillary Studies:  EKG-normal sinus rhythm, possible lateral ischemia-official reading pending







________________________________________   

Tina Purcell, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2122-04-23

                                                       Patient Name: VALLE,ISABELLA [ MRN: 4698877KMC ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 4/23/2122, 10:45 p



Neurosurgery H & P:



CC/HPI: 54 yo F w/ h/o PCKD and HTN presents w/ worst H/A of her life.  The patient over-slept this morning because of a severe H/A and "groginess."  She awoke at 10 am by her Husband who was calling to check on her (given she usually awakens by 6 am).  She called 911 and was transferred to us for further care.  We were consulted at 10:40 pm for Head CT showing SAH.  She now only c/o mild H/A w/o any vertigo, tinnitus, weakness, nor numbness.



PMH: 	Polycystic kidney disease:

		- renal failure

		- s/p renal transplant in '13 

		- s/p nephrectomy in '18 

		- now on peritoneal dialysis



	Secondary Hyperparathyroidism

		- has had spont fractures

		- s/p semi total parathyroidectomy in 2112



	HTN

	Hypercholesteremia

	IDDM



PSH:	' 09 TAH-BSO

	' 10 parathyroidectomy

	' 18 left nephrectomy

	AV fistulas x2



Meds: 	Lasix 40 mg

	Norvasc 10 mg po qd

	Lipitor 40 mg po qd,

	prednisone 10 mg,

	Epogen 10kU 4x/week 

	Insulin NPH 38 units plus regular 8 units in a.m.



NKDA 



SH: non-contributory.



FH: Mother died of an aneurysm at KMC



PE: Afebrile, BP 160/80, P 80, R 16



Neuro:	AA & Ox3, speech clear

	PRL (L6 to 5, R 5 to 4), FOV full grossly, EOMI, FS, TML, SCM/TPZ 5/5 B

	MAE @ 5/5, mild RUE drift

	No gross sensory deficit

	DTR: 1+ B Bicep/BR/Patella

	NEG Babinski's

	No cerebellar signs



Head CTA: Fischer grade 1 SAH in B sylvian fissures.  Small amount of paramesencephalic SAH in the Right.  A 6 mm L MCA bifurcation aneurysm pointing latero-superiorly is seen.



LABS: Normal CBC,lytes, and coags except WBC = 12.6, K = 5.3, BUN/CR = 48 / 9.6, Trop = 0.25



A/P: 54 yo F w/ PCDK & HTN p/w Hunt Hess grade 2, Fischer grade 1 SAH from L MCA aneurysm. D/W Drs. Ashley & Dang:

	- D/W Dr. Uren and Dr. Quenton Vanburen who related that CTA and Angio could both be done for this patient safely.  A dialysis RN will be by soon to dialyse the patient.  CTA done.

	- Booked for OR Waitlist in AM

	- Pre-op labs done

	- EKG shows no ischemia w/ LVH

	- Vanc/Gent for open Peritoneal catheter noted on exam









______________________________                              

Michael Tomlinson, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2122-07-21

Valle, Isabella

KMC Neuro EW Consult

Date 7/21/22

MRN 4698877

DOB: 7/30/67



CC: Unresponsive this AM, with R sided deficit

HPI : 54 yo ?handedness WF with sig h/o PCKD on peritoneal dialysis, HTN, hypercholesterolemia, IDDM, s/p L MCA aneurysmal rupture and repair 4/22, who presents this AM found unresponsive by husband (All report given by EMS< cannot contact husband and he is not currently present.) Pt reportedly was last seen in USOH last night about 9pm when peritoneal dialysis was started. She was found this AM with her dialysate fluid half run through and it was on the floor, she was unresponsive.  Pt intermittenly responds to commands and is not speaking, so ROS is unabl to obtain at this point.



ALL: unknown if any allergies

Meds: Lipitor, Prednisone,Zestril, Norvasc, Calcitol, Phenytoin, Mesnest, Nephrocaps, Phoslo, Insulin NPH 37 and Reg 7

Med Hx:  as above, HTN, hypercholesterolemia, PCKD, IDDM, s/p L MCA aneurysm 4/22 

Soc Hx: unknown at this time



PE: T   96.6         P   101       R   20        BP    167/62         O2=100 RA

Gen: WF, appears older than stated age, withdrawing R side, looking to left

HEENT: normocephalic,atraumatic

Neck: supple, no bruits

Lungs: CTAB no w/r/c

Heart: RRR S1, S2, no m/r/g

Abd: soft, +BSs, slightly firm, peritoneal dialysate access in abdomen, abd bandaged, fluid exuding from abdomen

Ext: no c/c/e

Neuro: alert, cannot assess if pt is oriented to person, place, time, pt completely aphasic, follows verbal commands, cannot perform rest of MMSE at this time

CN: PERRLA, EOMI, eyes deviated to L, not roving, able to track and cross midline, no blink to threat on the L, visual acuity unable to assess, sensation face equal bilaterally, R sided NLF flattening, 

Motor: no PND on L, cannot lift R arm off bed to command, normal bulk on R, increased tone on R, atrophy of leg and arm on L, no tremors or fasiculations noted 

Strength unable to assess officially, moving L arm and leg spontaneously, no movement of R upper and lower extremities, only demonstrates flexor withraw to painful stimuli on R side

Sensation: unable to assess, pt does not respond to questions re:extinction or sensation but does respond to painful stimuli

Cerebellum: unable to assess

Gait: unable to assess

Reflexes: biceps, triceps, BR R 3+, L 2+

	Patellar, Achilles 3+ R, 2+ L, toes upgoing on R, downgoing on L

Labs: WBC sig for 17.5 w/ 90%N, chem 7 pending

Imaging: Pending CXR

A/P: 54 yo WF with sig medical problems, including L MCA stroke in 4/22, now with new R sided deficits ?stroke vs. sz

-CT no angio for now givenperitoneal dialysis

-likely for MRI/A of head and neck with diffusion as per acute stroke protocol 

-likely CMF admission/ stroke team unless suspicion for sz, infectious cause









Thelma Delarosa MD,PhD Neurology Resident Pager 04272





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2123-03-02

TEAM 2 INTERN ADMISSION NOTE

Name:  Isabella Valle 4698877

Date of Admission: 3/01/2123

Attending: Dr. L. Uren







HPI:  55 y/o female with multiple medical problems presents to ED after husban called EMS for seizure that lasted approximately 5 minutes. She has a known seizure disorder secondary to hemmorragic CVA in past. Pt. had recent reduction in Dilantin dose and has documented subtherapuetic levels since this change. Pt. denies any other complaints prior to or after seizure. In the ED waiting area-pt. Suffered another seizure and was transferred to the trauma section of the ER. Patient was given 2mg of Ativan with resolution of seizure and then was in an obvious post-ictal state. Foley was placed with drainage of pus and patient given 80mg IV gentamycin and 1 gram of Vancomycin. Head CT negative for any acute process and abd/pelvic CT performed-results pending. 



Past Med:



#1.  Subarachnoid hemorrhage, status post left MCA aneurysm clipped in 04/22.  #2.  Left MCA stroke in 07/22.  #3.  End stage renal disease from polycystic kidney disease status post left nephrectomy, status post renal transplant and hemodialysis.  #4.  Steroid induced diabetes mellitus.  #5.  Hypertension.  #6.  Status post parathyroidectomy.

#7.  Status post thyroid adenoma resection.  #8.  History of fungal

peritonitis in 07/22.  #9.  Hyperlipidemia.  #10.  Recent line sepsis with Enterococci 10/22.  #11.  Status post TAH/BSO for menorrhagia, and status post ventral hernia repair. #12 HD catheter infection



Meds:

Lopressor 25 Bid, Lactobacillus 1 packt PO bid, Ranitidine 50 IV qd, Colace 100 mg PO bid, Aggrenox 1 cap PO BID, Dulcolax prn, Celexa 40 po qd, CaCO3 1250 po tid, prednisone 5 mg po qam, Lipitor 20 po qd



Allergies: NKDA



Social History: no tobacco, or etoh, lives with husband who helps her with ADLs as she is hemiparetic



Family History: not obtained



Physical Exam:

T= 98.1, RR=20, P=63, BP=124/66, 97% 2L

GEN: NAD

HEENT: PERRL, no oral lesions visible

LUNGS: clear posteriorly crackles

HEART: S1, S2, +systolic murmer heard throughout

ABD: BS+, soft, NT

EXT: No edema except for RUE

NEURO: cannot move right side of body, upgoing toes on right



Labs:



WBC                     12.8      H              4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                     37.2                     36.0-46.0      %

HGB                     11.4      L              12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                     3.52      L              4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                     988       H              150-350        th/cumm

MCV                     106       H              80-100         fl

MCH                     32.3                     26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                    30.6      L              31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                     18.7      H              11.5-14.5      %

PT                      13.0                     11.1-13.1      sec

PT-INR                  1.1

  Result Text:

     PT-INR values are valid only for WARFARIN ANTI-COAG THERAPY.

APTT                    23.8                     22.1-35.1      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST    RECEIVED

Diff Method             Auto

Poly                    63                       40-70          %

Lymphs                  31                       22-44          %

Monos                   4                        4-11           %

EOS                     1                        0-8            %

Basos                   1                        0-3            %

Absolute Neuts          8.11      H              1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs         3.92                     1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos          0.54      H              0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS            0.18                     0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos          0.08                     0.0-0.3        th/cmm

Aniso                   2+                       NORMAL

Hypo                    3+                       NORMAL

Macrocytes              3+

Microcytes              None



Sodium (Stat Lab)       136                      135-145        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)    5.9       H              3.4-4.8        mmol/L

  Result Text:

     SPECIMEN NOT HEMOLYZED

Chloride (Stat Lab)     97        L              100-108        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)          34.2      H              24.0-30.0      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)          36        H              8-25           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)   4.4       H              0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)      100                      70-110         mg/dl





Calcium                 7.6       L              8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus              2.0       L              2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium               1.7                      1.4-2.0        meq/L

Dilantin,Chem           2.0       L              5.0-20.0       mcg/ml



UA-SED-RBC              50-100                   0-2            /hpf

UA-SED-WBC              PACKED                   0-2            /hpf

UA-SED-Bacteria         Few                      NEG            /hpf

Hyaline Cast            3-5                      0-5            /lpf

Squamous Cells          Few                      NEG            /hpf

Microscopic Sediment    Completed





EKG: NSR, prolonged QT-no change from prior-non specific ST/T wave abnormalities



CT Head-1.  No intracranial hemorrhage or CT evidence of acute stroke

	though MRI diffusion weighted imaging would be more sensitive.

	2. Stable encephalomalacia and Wallerian degeneration from left

	MCA stroke.

	3. Prior left pterional craniotomy and left MCA aneurysm 

      clipping.





Assessment/Plan:

1.	 Seizures-likely in setting of subtherapuetic Dilantin dose-will finish one gram load and start PO dilantin in am at 300 tid per neurology recommendations and check levels and await levels 10-15. Head CT negative for new process and no evidence of other reason for seizure. Patient on Keppra in past-needed now? Will ask neurology

2.	Pyuria-uncertian if significant due to the patient's likely minimal urine output-sent for culture-will await results-continue broad specrtrum coverage of potential pathogens with Vancomycin (1 gram given in ED) and ceftriaxone.

3.	High WBC-Abd CT reportedly negative as was CXR-will check final results and patient without symptoms-blood cultures pending-follow temp curve and WBC and continue abx until cultures negative

4.	Electrolyte abnormalities-patient on hemodialysis-will schedule for am-if not possible will have to treat for hyperkalemia.

5.	Renal transplant-continue Prednisone

6.	CVA-Will continue Aggrenox for now

7.	Other-continue home meds for now except lactobacillus as certain of purpose? 



Bradley Burch 69264

Team 2 Intern 





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>