<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2120-01-18

January 18, 2120

Freeman Faust, M.D.            
Evergreen Court Hospital
97 Factory Street
Haleyville, MN 78826   

RE: Jacob Rodriquez, M.D.
    MR #863-35-65-5

Dear Dr. Faust: 

Thank you for kindly referring your patient, Jacob Rodriquez, to the
Internal Medicine for evaluation of pulmonary hypertension.
Although I'm sure you are familiar with his history, I will review
it now for our records. Dr. Rodriquez is a 77-year-old retired Electrician
at Wells Fargo who by his report has enjoyed excellent
health until the past year. He denies any prior history of
hypertension, coronary artery disease, chest pains, significant
childhood illnesses or malignancy. He describes his usual baseline
health as excellent. He is a religious walker, walking multiple
times each week as well as a woodwind and singing enthusiast. Dr.
Rodriquez states that in approximately April or Mayof the past year he
was first diagnosed with hyperglycemia. This was treated with
Metformin. Subsequently Hydrochlorothiazide and Zestril were added
apparently for hypertension (although the patient does not believe
he has been diagnosed with hypertension). He subsequently developed
diarrhea which he felt was related to Glucophage which was
subsequently reduced in dose. In June of the past year the patient
was noted to be anemic which was felt to be related to sulfa in his
Hydrochlorothiazide. At that time he also was found to have lower
extremity edema which worsened with the discontinuation of the
Hydrochlorothiazide. The patient states in September of 2119 he
traveled to trinidad and tobago. While in trinidad and tobago he had a
marked increase in his lower extremity edema to the point that he
found it difficult to ambulate. He denied any difficulty with chest
pains or shortness of breath. He had no hemoptysis and no focal
unilateral leg swelling despite the long period of immobility
during the trip. He was seen by a Trinidad physician who prescribed an
ethacrynic acid which reduced his lower extremity edema
significantly. However, he subsequently developed diarrhea to this
medication and it was stopped. Subsequently his lower extremity has
once again worsened and has been treated with increasing doses of
Lasix and with the recent addition of Zaroxolyn. At the present
time Dr. Rodriquez states that he has no overt shortness of breath. He
still able to sing vigorously and to play woodwinds without any 

Page 2
Freeman Faust, M.D. 
RE: Jacob Rodriquez, M.D. 
January 18, 2120


limitation. He does find ambulating difficult due to the swelling
in his lower extremities. He has no chest pain, has no cough, no
sputum production, no hemoptysis. He has no fevers or chills. He
believes his weight is increased by 35 pounds in the past several
months. He believes this is entirely due to edema accumulation. He
denies any difficulties with disrupted sleep although he does note
that he's becoming increasingly fatigued during the day and is
often napping in the reclining chair which is new for him. He
denies any history of snoring. He has noted no new joint complaints
although he has had a pruritic eruption on the anterior surface of
his right lower extremity as well as on his left arm. This has been
present for approximately two or three months. Other than that he
believes his bowel and bladder function is normal. Review of
systems is otherwise unremarkable. 

His past medical history is significant for:
     1. Type II diabetes as above. 
     2. An apparent diagnosis of labile hypertension noted in his 
        chart. 
     3. Anemia thought secondary to Hydrochlorothiazide. 
     4. Past history of right bundle branch block. He has no      
        history of rheumatic fever. 

Current medications include Atenolol 25mg daily, folic acid,
Glucophage 850mg bid, Lasix 120mg daily, Lisinopril 15mg daily,
compression stockings, Metolazone 2.5mg daily was added recently. 

Drug allergies include possible hemolytic anemia due to
Hydrochlorothiazide. 

Family history is significant for diabetes mellitus. 

Social history is assuming for the fact that the patient is an
immigrant from trinidad and tobago. He has been living in Haleyville
since the early 2059's. He is a Electrician at Wells Fargo. He
has minimal exposure to chemicals in his research towards his
bachelor's degree but none since then. He is a non tobacco user. He
uses alcohol minimally. He's never had any blood transfusions. He
lives with his wife. They have no pets. He does not enjoy any
unusual hobbies not noted above. He has been exposed to
tuberculosis in the past and has a history of a positive PPD. 

On physical examination today Dr. Rodriquez weighs 193 pounds. Blood
pressure is 136/90. Pulse 83 and regular. Respiratory rate is 20.
Temperature is 96.8. Resting oxygen saturation is 98-99% with
ambulation in the hallway. This fell to a minimum of 97% with an
increase in his heart rate to 100. HEENT exam is significant for a
clear oropharynx. Sclera are white. Conjunctiva are minimally pale.
Page 3
Freeman Faust, M.D. 
RE: Jacob Rodriquez, M.D. 
January 18, 2120


The thyroid gland is normal. Jugular venous distention to
approximately 10 cm. was noted. Neck was supple. Examination of the
chest revealed diminished breath sounds bilaterally with dullness
at both bases. There was no egophony and no wheezes. Otherwise the
lungs were clear. Cardiac exam with a regular rate in rhythm,
normal S1 and S2, an intermittent S4 was appreciated. No RV heave
or lift was appreciated. No pulmonary artery tap was appreciated.
The pontic component of S2 was moderately enhanced. No appreciable
murmurs were detected. The point of maximum impulse was in the
anterior axillary line. Examination of the abdomen revealed a
nontender abdomen with a palpable liver edge, three fingerbreadths
below the right costal margin. This was nontender and smooth.
Minimal splenomegaly was also appreciated as well. Normal bowel
sounds were present. Examination of the extremities reveal three
plus symmetric edema to the top of the thigh in the lower
extremities, one plus edema was also present in both upper
extremities. No clubbing was noted. There were no skin changes
consistent with collagen vascular disease. Multiple follicular
lesions were noted on the anterior aspect of the right thigh as
well as on the left arm. Neurological exam was grossly nonfocal. 

Objective data include a CBC which most recently demonstrated a
white count of 11.8, hematocrit of 32.1, platelet count of 250.
Differential was not remarkable. LVH is elevated at 599, AST is
most recently 22. A urinalysis on 12/07/19 was negative for
protein. No reportive cast was made. A CEA was notable for a level
of 2.4 on 1/05/20. An echocardiogram obtained on 12/22/19
demonstrated normal LV size with mild concentric LVH and preserved
LV function. The right ventricle was mildly dilated and
hypertrophied with mild reduction in RV function. There was trace
MR with moderate TR. A peak systolic artery pressure of 64 plus
right atrial pressure was noted. 

In summary Dr. Rodriquez is a 77-year-old gentleman with a clear cut
pulmonary hypertension. The etiology of this is not clear at the
moment. Differential diagnosis could include chronic thromboembolic
disease, occult underlying pulmonary disease (doubt), obstructive
sleep apnea, and collagen vascular disease. In addition some
patients develop a marked pulmonary artery hypertension in the
setting of stiff left ventricle even with preserved left
ventricular function although this I think would be a diagnosis of
exclusion. The degree of his edema is quite striking and I agree
with increasing his diuretic regimen. I'm embarking on a course of
evaluation to exclude the most likely causes. In specific he will
be having a CT with IV contrast to rule out chronic thromboembolic
disease this afternoon. This has already been arranged by Dr.
Faust. In addition I'm sending serology including an ANA, an
antidouble stranded DNA and an anti SCL70. I've also asked Dr. Rodriquez
Page 4
Freeman Faust, M.D. 
RE: Jacob Rodriquez, M.D. 
January 18, 2120


to undergo polysonography to exclude obstructive sleep apnea. He
will be following up with our pulmonary function lab to have formal
pulmonary function testing performed in addition to having an
arterial blood gas drawn. If this evaluation should be unrevealing,
he may require more invasive diagnostics. I've already consulted
formally with Dr. Eddie Roy, the physician with most
experience in pulmonary hypertension at this hospital and he would
be able to assist us in the further evaluation of Dr. Rodriquez if our
workup is nondiagnostic.  

Dr. Faust, thank you again for referring Dr. Rodriquez for evaluation.
I'll plan on seeing him in approximately three to four weeks after
his diagnostic tests have been performed. Please do not hesitate to
call me with any further questions or concerns. 

Sincerely, 




Jose Church, M.D.

/ray

DD: 01/18/20
DT: 01/19/:0
DV: 01/18/20





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2120-09-08

                     MARY EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

RODRIQUEZ,JACOB   863-35-65-5                       VISIT DATE: 09/08/20

I saw and examined the patient personally.  I also reviewed and 

confirm the resident's detailed note.  Please refer to it.  

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Foot ulcer.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 78-year-old gentleman 

who is a diabetic developed left foot ulcer six weeks ago after he 

had shaving of some calluses by a podiatrist.  The wound has not 

healed and then got infected.  He was started on Keflex, then when 

the initial cultures came back showing resistance to Keflex so he 

was switched to Cipro, however, his final cultures showed MRSA.  He 

comes in with increasing redness and pain.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, diabetes, peripheral vascular 

disease, mitral regurgitation, anemia, sleep apnea and pulmonary 

hypertension.   

MEDICATIONS:  Documented on the chart.

ALLERGIES:  Documented on the chart.  

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  He is a Electrician.  He drinks 

alcohol occasionally, he does not smoke.  Family history of kidney 

stones.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  He is afebrile, vital signs 

are stable.  GENERAL:  The patient was awake, alert in no distress. 

He does not look toxic.  HEART:  He had a small heart murmur.  

LUNGS:  Clear to auscultation.  ABDOMEN:  Soft and nontender.  

EXTREMITIES:  He had multiple ulcers on his left foot, stage two or 

three, an ulcer on his heel as well as the distal third and fourth 

toes.  There was some mild surrounding cellulitis.  He had 3+ pedal 

edema.  The casts were symmetric and nontender.  There is no 

adenopathy.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The patient had a white count of about 16, 

mildly elevated but no bandemia.  His BUN and creatinine were 50 

and 1.8.  Blood cultures were sent. 

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  He was given a dose of Vancomycin.  

Surgery was consulted.  The primary came and saw the patient as 

well and he was admitted to the hospital.   

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Diabetic foot ulceration with cellulitis, rule 

out osteomyelitis.  

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Condition is 

stable.  

___________________________________                    TT554/9917 

CHRISTOPHER QUIGLEY, M.D.       CQ03                           D:09/09/20 

                                                       T:09/09/20 

Dictated by:  CHRISTOPHER QUIGLEY, M.D.       CQ03 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2120-12-15

Chief Complaint	

This is a visit for this patient  with a chief complaint 

1.diabetes management, difficulty getting in control.Also to monitor for potential complications of treatment and complications of the disease.

 

2. followup of ulcers on feet



3. edema



4. hypertension



5. pulmonary hypertension



Problems	    

Venous insufficiency	      

Edema	      

Mitral regurgitation	      

Anemia	      

Hypertension	      

Bundle branch block	      

Pulmonary hypertension	      

Diabetes mellitus	      

Sleep apnea	      

Lower extremity ulcer	      



History of Present Illness	

Diabetes= on oral agents- just glyburide one 2.5 mg qd

Trying to keep diet - reviewed

weight:stable

Keeps track of sugars-

Does not Bring in book to review - but says that sugars are running about 200 past two weeks

No hypoglycemic episodes

no polyuria,polydipsia,no fevers, no weight loss



 

2. followup of ulcers on feet- ws to have started on antibiotics wednesday, but the prescription was not delivered. Three/of four ulcers have healed. Seeing nurse daily for dressing changes. Has heel pad to remove pressure



3. edema

   taking zaroxylyn and lasix

   better controlled when on both

4. hypertension

  on  lisinopril, lasix. not on atenolol ? why



5. pulmonary hypertension

  not using his CPAP - did not like it this summer --found it hot. Discussed - advised to try again.



Past Medical History	

Past Medical History - 

pulm hypertension

sleep apnea

diabetes

mitral regurg

anemia, felt secondary to HCTZ

RBBB

+PPD  in college







Allergies	  

METFORMIN	 Diarrhea

EDECRIN (ETHACRYNATE SODIUM)	 GI upset

HCTZ (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)	 Hemolytic anemia



Preventive Health History	

says he is up to date. 

has not had colonoscopy- we are waiting for ulcers to heal, etc.



Habits	

smoking-no

drink alcohol-social only

drug use no illicit drugs

seat belts yes





Review of Systems	

Constitutional: no weight loss, fevers, fatigue,aches

Skin:Persistent rash on back, responsive to steroid cream;No change moles

HEENT: saw eye doctor - has hemorrhage - to get laser treatment

Respir: no cough,sputum; no wheezing

Cor: no chest pain, SOB, PND.  +edema

GI: no heartburn, nausea,vomiting,diarrhea ,constip

GU: no dysuria,frequency, urgency, hematuria

Endo: no sweating, heat intolerance

Heme: no bruising, bleeding







Vital Signs	    

Blood Pressure:	 164/86   

Weight:	 185   Pounds



Physical Exam	

WdWN male 



164/86

185 pounds

82



eczema  on back with some round 



 1+ palpable femoral pulses bilaterally, nonpalp popliteal arteries.

  Neuropathic ulcers on heel, left foot : ulcer on heel still open,with some drainage. clean margins

edema 1+



Neck: supple no nodes; thyroid not enlarged, no nodules. no bruits

CHEST: 

 some crackles at bases, R>L; no wheezes, rhonchi

COR: 

  reg rhythm, murm, soft,systolic blowing m;,No thrill, gallop, rub

ABD: 

  soft, BS nl. no masses No liver/spleen enlarg; no tendrnes











Impression	

Diabetes. 

  on glyburide

 + evidence of visual changes(hemorrhage)- followed by ophthal

 No evid of hypoglycemic episodes by hx.



 Not adequately controlled on current regimen. 



 

2. followup of ulcers on feet- three healed, one still open

3. edema

   pretty good control

4. hypertension

  still not adequately controlled

5. pulmonary hypertension

  



Plan	

Total face-to-face visit time: 45 minutes

Time spent counselling: 38 min

   Diagnosis explained

   reviewed potential complications of diabetes

   reviewed diet

   reviewed meds - increase glyburide

  

   

  

Ophthalmology



return in one month

 

2. followup of ulcers on feet



3. edema



4. hypertension



5. pulmonary hypertension







Return: 







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2121-03-28

Chief Complaint	

This is a visit for this patient  with a chief complaint 

1.diabetes managementAlso to monitor for potential complications of treatment and complications of the disease.

 

2. followup of ulcers on feet



3. edema



4. hypertension



5. pulmonary hypertension



Problems	    

Venous insufficiency	      

Edema	      

Mitral regurgitation	      

Anemia	      

Hypertension	      

Bundle branch block	      

Pulmonary hypertension	      

Diabetes mellitus	      

Sleep apnea	      

Lower extremity ulcer	      



History of Present Illness	

Diabetes= on oral agents- just glyburide 5mg tab bid

Trying to keep diet - reviewed

Says sugars in range - tho again no diary.Tells me that sugars usually in acceptable range, tho once was 55. 

No other hypoglycemic episodes



no polyuria,polydipsia,no fevers, no weight loss

We talked again about bringing in his log- 

I suspect he is very out of range but dont know, and his report of sugars of 55 make me concerned about increasing meds.



Still having problems with ulcers - seeing Dr Ulbrich regularly

seeing nurse daily for dressing changes. Has heel pad to remove pressure. Has had shoes checked. Is to see Dr Ulbrich 's nurse today for debridement. Is off antibiotics now; was on ? a few weeks ago?? 



3. edema- good control recently

   taking zaroxylyn and lasix

   better controlled when on both

4. hypertension

  on  lisinopril, lasix. not on atenolol - he stopped it because he did not like it, made him feel sleepy. Need to consider increasing bp meds- will await Creatinine tpday

5. pulmonary hypertension

  not using his CPAP - did not like it  Discussed - advised to try again.we reviewed the whole issue of pulm hypertension/ leg swelling etc



Past Medical History	

Past Medical History - 

pulm hypertension

sleep apnea

diabetes

mitral regurg

anemia, felt secondary to HCTZ

RBBB

+PPD  in college







Allergies	  

METFORMIN	 Diarrhea

EDECRIN (ETHACRYNATE SODIUM)	 GI upset

HCTZ (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE)	 Hemolytic anemia



Preventive Health History	

says he is up to date. 

has not had colonoscopy- we are waiting for ulcers to heal, etc.



Habits	

smoking-no

drink alcohol-social only

drug use no illicit drugs

seat belts yes





Review of Systems	

Constitutional: no weight loss, fevers, ++fatigue, NOaches 

Skin: rash better (shingles)

HEENT:Got  laser treatment- stable

Respir: no cough,sputum; no wheezing

Cor: no chest pain, SOB, PND.  +edema,. better than before

GI: no heartburn, nausea,vomiting,constip.

GU: no dysuria,frequency, urgency, hematuria

Endo: no sweating, heat intolerance

Heme: no bruising, bleeding







Vital Signs	  

Blood Pressure:	 140/80   Left Arm

Weight 182 today



Physical Exam	

WdWN male 

eczema  on back



 1+ palpable femoral pulses bilaterally, nonpalp popliteal arteries.

  Feet: dressings not changed as he is sseeing Dr Ulbrich shortly after this apt today

1+  femoral pulses bilaterallyNothing palp below

Neck: supple no nodes; thyroid not enlarged, no nodules. no bruits

CHEST: 

 some crackles at bases, R>L; no wheezes, rhonchi

Extrem: 1+ edema 





Impression	

Diabetes. 

  on glyburide

 + evidence of visual changes(hemorrhage)- followed by ophthal

?  hypoglycemic episodes by hx.



 ?? adequately controlled on current regimen. Last A1C very high. If still high, I think he needs much more help getting in control. Since he sees nurse daily, will have to ask for her to check sugars, adjust meds after. 



 

2.  ulcers 

3. edema

  

4. hypertension not adequately controlled

  

5. pulmonary hypertension

6. Renal insuff- need to better control his sugars and bp

7 anemia  

8. Really overall not doing well. 



Plan	



1. Diabetes: will check A1C and sugar. Will contact VNA to begin sugars by VNA so we can try and control better. 

   

   reviewed meds - 

 reviewed vascular complications

 reviewed checking sugars and bringing in book

  

2. followup of ulcers on feet

 to see Dr Ulbrich. 



3. edema

 continue current combination of lasix and zaroxy. Check K, creat

4. hypertension

 check renal function - ? restart atenolol or add increase lisinopril

5. pulmonary hypertension

encourage cpap

6. anemia- check if elig for epo Could start at 40000u/week



Return: one month

Call pt when i have results



Note: reviewed old heme values. Tends to run high WBC, low lymphs, high ESR. ??? why. May need heme consult. 





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>