<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2095-03-16

Trinity Regional Medical Center

8699 Mill Street              MARSH, CARL

Albertville, RI  87193                    39955317

(906) 517-8625                     03/16/2095





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Marsh is a 73-year-old male who comes for first visit to TRMC to initiate longitudinal care and follow up of multiple medical problems.



PROBLEMS:

1.  Chronic renal failure.  He has been on dialysis for the past four years.  He is currently dialyzed two times per week.  He apparently had been three times per week in the past.

2.  Hyperlipidemia.  Fasting lipid analysis one year ago showed total cholesterol 225, triglycerides 265, LDL 161, and HDL 40.  He has not been treated.

3.  Hyperparathyroidism.  PTH level one year ago was 143.  He is on calcium replacement.

4.  IgG monoclonal gammopathy.  This was noted on immunoelectrophoresis.  It was at very low levels.



MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin 81 mg q.d., Nephrocaps one q.d., and PhosLo 2001 mg t.i.d. by his report.



REVIEW OF SYMPTOMS:  He states he was told he was hypertensive at last dialysis. No significant weight change, febrile signs or symptoms, headache, blurred vision, tinnitus, chest pain, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, abdominal pain, nightsweats, diarrhea, skin rash, bruising, joint pain, or focal weakness.  



ALLERGIES:  No known allergies.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient appears well.  Blood pressure on multiple measurements range from 150-160/78-82, weight 144 pounds, and heart rate 72 and regular.  Chest: Clear to percussion and auscultation.  Cardiovascular exam:  No extra sounds or murmurs.  Abdominal exam:  No masses, tenderness, or organomegaly.  Extremities: No edema.  Skin: No rash.  Musculoskeletal exam: Grossly intact.



ASSESSMENT/PLAN:

1.  Chronic renal failure.  The patient will continue on dialysis.  I have requested screening blood tests.

2.  Hyperlipidemia.  This needs to be treated.  I have asked him to return for reestablishment of baseline.

3.  Hyperparathyroidism.  Secondary to chronic renal failure.  He is on calcium replacement.

4.  Low-grade IgG monoclonal gammopathy. Will recheck values and follow.

5.  Hypertension.  A degrees systolic hypertension warrants therapy.  He is due for dialysis tomorrow, however.  I gave him a prescription for atenolol 25 mg p.o. q.d.

6.  Adult health maintenance.  I gave him a prescription for aspirin, which he should be taking and asked him to return in two weeks for a full annual review.

  I instructed him to show renal staff the prescriptions tomorrow at dialysis.





______________________________

Xavier T Mccoy, M.D.











eScription document:4-4113812 EMS







DD: 03/16/95

DT: 03/16/95

DV: 03/16/95



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-09-19



 





KEKELA INPATIENT DIALYSIS ADMIT NOTE





NAME: Marsh, Carl

MRN: 99579205



Primary Care MD: Xavier T. Mccoy



Outpatient Nephrologist: Keith Tierney

Outpatient Dialysis Unit:  Sanford Memorial Hospital, S and T

Estimated dry weight: 61 kg

Dialysis access: left AVF



Reason for admission:    body jerking    since last night



HPI: 



74 year old Turkmenistan male with a past medical history of ESRD presumably secondary to HTN presents to the KEKELA ED with complaints of    body jerking    since last night.  The patient was in his otherwise good state of health when he went to his normal dialysis session yesterday.  The session was uneventful, and he finished dialysis around 7:30 pm.  Around 9 pm, he started noting un-controlable jerky movements of his jaw, arms, and legs.  He was unable to stand by himself, and had difficulty with any motor activity.  It was so bad that he was unable to feed himself, and needed help from his wife to do so.  The jerking continued throughout the night without getting better, and his daughter called his PCP's office today, at which time he was instructed to proceed to the KEKELA ED.  He has had a similar episode like this before in January of 2092, when he developed the exact same jerking movements after a long three day weekend when he went without dialysis (see note in LMR by neurology consultant).  It was deemed at that time that his myoclonus was due to    electrolyte disarray,    and he was admitted to EDUCARE-FARGO and received dialysis the same day with complete resolution of symptoms.  He has been symptom-free since that time.



He reports no other new events.  He denies any new medications.



Past Medical History: 



1.)	ESRD secondary to hypertension

n	on HD since November 2090

n	current access is left radiocephalic fistula placed in April of 2091

n	currently followed by Dr. Tierney at the Sanford Memorial Hospital

2.)	HTN

3.)	IgG monoclonal gammopathy

4.)	Hyperlipidemia



Allergies: NKDA



Medications: 



   Vitamin D   

Atenolol 25 mg po qd

ASA (he stopped on his own)

Nephrocaps 1 tab po qd

Phos-Lo 2001 mg po tid



Social History:   The patient immigrated from Tonga to Uganda in 2061. He lives with his wife in Mount Airy.  He lives with his wife in Mount Airy. He has five adult children.



Review of Systems:



Constitutional:  (-) fevers, chills, night sweats.

Pulmonary: (-) shortness of breath.

Cardiovascular: (-) chest pain, palpitations.

Gastrointestinal: (-) N/V, diarrhea, constipation

Skin: denies easy bruising

Rheumatologic: No arthritis or gout

Neurologic: (+) jerking movements



PHYSICAL EXAM

Temp: 98.2

BP: 102/61

HR: 63

RR:20

Sats: 96% on RA



Gen: pleasant older gentleman, lying in gurney with obvious myoclonus affecting his speech

HEENT: sclerae non-icteric, mucous membranes moist, normal sized tongue

Neck: supple, JVP 8, 2+ carotids

Lungs: slightly diminished breath sound on the left, otherwise unremarkable

Cor: S1, S2, regular with PVC's, soft systolic murmur at base

Abd: soft, NTND, no HSM, no bruits

Ext: no edema in LE b/l, 1+ pulses distally

Skin: + fat pads in supraclavicular region

Access: left AVF with good thrill

Neuro: CN 3-12 intact

            myoclonic jerking evident in jaw, arms, and legs, worse with intentional movements

 	strength normal throughout

	sensation preserved to light touch

	reflexes 1+ in upper extremities, difficult in LE due to myoclonic jerking

	cerebellar exam normal



LABS:



GLUCOSE                          73                        (54-118)       mg/dL

UREA N                           41               *        (9-25)         mg/dL

CREATININE                       9.2              *        (0.7-1.3)      mg/dL

SODIUM                           141                       (136-142)      mmol/L

POTASSIUM                        5.5              *        (3.5-5.0)      mmol/L

CHLORIDE                         91               *        (98-108)       mmol/L

TOTAL CO2                        37               *        (23-32)        mmol/L

ANION GAP                        13                        (3-15)         mmol/L

ALT/GPT                          19                        (7-52)         U/L

AST/GOT                          24                        (9-30)         U/L

ALK PHOS                         59                        (36-118)       U/L

AMYLASE                          176              *        (20-70)        U/L

TOT BILI                         0.4                       (0.2-1.2)      mg/dL

LIPASE                           50                        (3-60)         U/L

     

TOT PROT                         8.5              *        (6.0-8.0)      g/dL

ALBUMIN                          4.6                       (3.7-5.4)      g/dL

GLOBULIN                         3.9                       (2.0-4.0)      g/dL

CALCIUM                          9.7                       (8.8-10.5)     mg/dL

PHOSPHATE                        6.1              *#       (2.4-5.0)      mg/dL

MAGNESIUM                        2.4                       (1.8-2.5)      mg/dL



WBC                              7.64                      (4-10)         K/uL

RBC                              4.68                      (4.5-6.4)      M/uL

HGB                              14.5                      (13.5-18.0)    g/dL

HCT                              41.8                      (40-54)        %

MCV                              89.3                      (80-95)        um3

MCH                              30.9                      (27-32)        uug

MCHC                             34.6                      (32-36)        g/dL

RDW                              14.8             *        (10-14.5)

PLT                              232                       (150-450)      K/uL

 LYMP %                          25.7                      (18-41)

 MONO %                          9.2              *        (2.5-8.5)

 NEUT %                          61.0                      (48-76)

 EOS %                           3.9                       (0-5)

 BASO %                          0.3                       (0-1.5)



PT                               14.1                      (11.8-14.6)    sec

PTT                              27.5                      (23.8-36.6)    sec

PT(INR)                          1.1                       (0.9-1.1)



ASSESSMENT:



74 year old male who presents with:



1.)	Myoclonus   unclear etiology without obvious precipitants; the last time this happened, it was in the setting of not getting dialyzed after three days.  While he did get dialysis yesterday per his normal schedule, it is odd that his potassium today is 5.5, suggesting perhaps either dietary indiscretion (which he denies) or, perhaps, inadequate dialysis.  In addition, he says that his dialysis center has been taking him off    early    a few times in the past week, though he notes that he got a full run yesterday (3    hours)

2.)	chronic HD

3.)	h/o MGUS   shoulder fat pads



PLAN:



1.)	Admit to Renal Medicine service, Dr. Tierney attending

2.)	Will plan on dialysis tomorrow for two reasons: (1) high potassium, (2) see if this helps with myoclonus

3.)	Will contact dialysis center tomorrow to see if any problems with his runs, and what his most recent URR or Kt/V was

4.)	continue Phos-Lo 2001 tid with meals

5.)	Kayexalate 30 po tonight for elevated potassium



Discussed with Dr. Tierney







______________________



Uriah T. Quin, M.D.

Renal Fellow

#80467

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-12-13







Trinity Regional Medical Center

1190 Mill Street              MARSH, CARL

Albertville, RI  87193                    39955317

(906) 517-8625                     12/13/2096





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Marsh is a 75-year-old male who comes for comprehensive exam and follow up medical problems.

1.  Chronic renal failure.  He is on chronic dialysis twice a week.

2.  Hyperlipidemia.  Fasting lipid analysis 18 months ago showed total cholesterol 221, triglycerides 192, LDL 136, and HDL 47.

3.  Cataracts.  He is about to undergo cataract removal.  Comes as well today for clearance.



MEDICATIONS:  Nephrocaps 1 p.o. daily, Phoslo 670 mg tablets 3 p.o. t.i.d., and senna two tablets b.i.d. p.r.n.



ALLERGIES:  No known allergies to any medications.



HABITS:  He smokes one pack per week.  Denies alcohol or drug use.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Unchanged.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  He lives with wife and daughter.  He is retired.



REVIEW OF SYMPTOMS:  No significant weight change, febrile signs or symptoms, headache, blurred vision, tinnitus, chest pain, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, abdominal pain, nightsweats, diarrhea, dysuria, polyuria, skin rash, bruising, joint pain, or focal weakness.  



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Blood pressure 125/82, weight 138 pounds, and temperature 97.3.  BMI 19.8.  Skin exam:  No rash.  Head and neck exam:  Patient has bilateral arcus senilis.  He is edentulous.  Chest:  Clear to percussion and auscultation.  Cardiovascular exam:  No extra sounds or murmurs.  Pedal pulses are trace posterior tibial bilaterally.  Abdominal exam:  No masses, tenderness, or organomegaly.  Stool guaiac negative.  GU exam:  Both testes descended.  Testes were soft.  Prostate 2+ enlarged without masses or tenderness.  Lymph exam:  No axillary or cervical lymphadenopathy.  Musculoskeletal exam:  Grossly intact.  Neuro exam:  Grossly intact.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:

1.  Chronic renal failure.  Appears to be stable on routine dialysis.  Will check screening blood work.

2.  Hyperlipidemia.  His LDL goal is less than 130.  He is slightly above that.  Encouraged careful attention to nutrition.

3.  Cataract.  EKG and other preop testing were requested.

4.  Adult health maintenance.  Tetanus and Pneumovax given last year.  He reports influenza vaccine was given elsewhere.  A colonoscopy has not been done according to our records.  Colonoscopy requested today.  Home guaiac cards given as well.





______________________________

Xavier T Mccoy, M.D., M.Sc.











eScription document:6-2359741 EMSSten Tel







DD: 12/14/96

DT: 12/15/96

DV: 12/13/96



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-02-04






Trinity Regional Medical Center
1949 Mill Street              MARSH, CARL
Albertville, RI  87193                    39955317
(906) 517-8625                     02/04/2098




HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 76-year-old man male who comes in for follow up of chronic kidney disease and other medical problems.


PROBLEMS:
1.  Chronic renal disease.  He has dialysis twice per week.  He tells me he is on the transplant list.  The transplant team would like a positive CVS treated with levofloxacin
2.  Hyperlipidemia.  Fasting lipid analysis 2 weeks ago showed total cholesterol 255, triglycerides 203, HDL 39, and LDL 175.  He had been taking Crestor but says the bottle emptied and he did not know to refill it.
3.  Secondary hyperparathyroidism.  Recent PTH 829, calcium 10.1, and phosphorus 6.7.
4.  Superficial back pain.  He had an abscess drained overlying the right scapula several months ago.  Since then, he has had some mild pain.


MEDICATIONS:  He did not bring any tonight.  As listed:
1.  Aspirin 325 mg daily.
2.  Nephrocaps 1 daily.
3.  Phoslo 2001 mg t.i.d.


REVIEW OF SYMPTOMS:  No significant weight change, febrile signs or symptoms, headache, blurred vision, tinnitus, chest pain, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, abdominal pain, nightsweats, diarrhea, dysuria, polyuria, bruising, joint pain, or focal weakness.  


PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Chest:  Clear to percussion and auscultation.  Skin exam:   There are two small cavities overlying the right scapula  filled with dirt and slight surrounding erythema..  Abdominal exam:  No masses, tenderness or organomegaly.  Extremities:  No edema.


ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:
1.  Chronic kidney disease.  On dialysis.
2.  Hyperlipidemia.  I prescribed Zocor.
3.  Secondary hyperparathyroidism.  I am concerned about bone status.  Bone mineral density exam requested.
4.  Skin changes after abscess drainage.  Area was cleaned and covered.
 The patient has history of elevated total protein and amylase.  Will need follow up.




______________________________
Xavier T Mccoy, M.D., M.Sc.










eScription document:6-6685590 MEeScription






DD: 02/04/98
DT: 02/04/98
DV: 02/04/98



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>