<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2085-08-21


MIMA 5Z
36 Santa Fe Road, Suite Z                          WILKERSON, EDWARD
Louisa, MS 59817                                      37199514
(238) 757-3898                                           08/21/85


CHIEF COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 61 year old gentleman
here for his first visit to me as his PCP, referred by Dr.
Xavier.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS/PAST MEDICAL HISTORY BY PROBLEMS:
 The patient has no acute complaints today.  His medical
history includes:
1.  Hypertension.  He is currently on hydrochlorothiazide 25
mg q.d. and aspirin q.d.
2.  Hypercholesterolemia.  The patient is on 30 mg q.h.s. of
simvastatin.  His last lipid panel in April of this year
showed total cholesterol of 196, triglycerides 169, HDL 52,
and LDL of 110.  He has no LFTs on file.
3.  Psychiatry.  According to the patient, he carried a
diagnosis of major depression with paranoid features.  He is
being followed by Dr. Uhler, psychiatrist at Marshfield Clinic as well as Betty Villasenor, a therapist at Marshfield Clinic.  He is currently on Depakote, Tegretol, Risperdal,
and Paxil although he does not know the doses of his
medications.  He still feels depressed but his paranoid
symptoms have subsided.  He has no manic or hypermanic
episodes.

MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin 325 mg q.d., Paxil, Risperdal,
Tegretol, Depakote doses unknown, simvastatin 30 mg q.h.s.,
HCTZ 20 mg q.d.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  No tobacco, alcohol, or recreational drugs.
 He quit drinking alcohol 16 years ago.  He has not been
sexually active for 16 years and is currently not
interested.  He lives by himself in  Denver Drive, walks
about 20 minutes per day, and is from Louisa originally.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Mother and father died of MIs in their 70s.
 There is no history of sudden cardiac death.  No cancer,
liver, kidney, or thyroid disease in the family.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Blood pressure 132/84, heart rate 84,
and weight 202 pounds.  The remainder of the exam is
deferred.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:
1.  Hypertension.  The patient is well controlled on his
current regimen.  I will therefore not change anything
today.
2.  Hypercholesterolemia.  The patient is at his goal LDL
level.  I will continue to follow his lipid panel yearly.  I
will also check LFTs today, given that he had a statin.
3.  Psychiatry.  The patient will follow up with his
psychiatrist and therapist.  He will let me know his actual
medication and medication doses at his earliest convenience.
 Also, I will recheck an LFT as stated above, given that he
is on possibly hepatotoxic psychoactive medications.
4.  Healthcare maintenance.  I have emphasized to the
patient the benefits of weight reduction as well as
increasing his exercise.  He is not interested in any
exercise as in walking and I have therefore counseled him to
walk longer and faster.  He had a negative flexible
sigmoidoscopy in November 2083 and I will give him stool
cards today.  His last tetanus was 10 years ago and he is
not interested in the booster today.  His immunizations are
otherwise up to date according to him and he will need the
remainder of the history and a full physical exam at the
next visit in 3 months' time.


______________________________
Wyatt Yeo, M.D.


eScription document:0-726841 CFFocus

DD: 08/21/85
DT: 08/22/85
DV: 08/21/85



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================





August 21st



Dr Yeo  Mr Wilkerson



61 year old man  Hx hypertension.Hx elev cholesterol, on zocor.  Recently underwent a stress test for chest pain, with completely negative dopamine MIBI. PMH also + depression and paranoia , on rx. BP 132/84, p 84. 

\Health maintenance: will be given stool cards, is up to date with others . Declines tetanus. 



Dr. Yeo and I jointly interviewed and examined this  61year old patient who presents with  for f/u hypercholesterolemia, hypertension, recent stress test. See resident's note for details. PMH/FH/SH significant for depression/paranoia. ROS remarkable for + depression at this time . 



On exam, we found bp 132/80   pulse 80. Rest of exam deferred. See Resident's note for further detail. 



Impression and Plan reviewed and I agree with the resident's assessment of  and diagnosis of dperession, hypertension . We agree on the plan to review test results with patient, stool cards given, tetanus offered and declined.



______________________________                              



Connie Angelina Wills, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-03-11

Telephone call from pt

Complaining of brief episodes of feeling faint, sweaty on the back of his neck yesterday and today. Sxs resolve when he sits down and rests a few minutes. No associated sxs headaches, ataxia, vertigo, nausea, palps, CP, SOB, URI sxs, fever, trauma. Checked fingerstick when sxs developed today, 125. Drank orange juice, but sxs persisted, resolved after approx 1hr.

Problems

Elevated cholesterol 

PSYCH DISORDER: ANXIETY,PARANOIA, DEPRESSION 

PERSONALITY DISORDER 

H/O hematuria 

H/O breast mass 

Hypertension 

Borderline diabetes mellitus 

Overweight 

Erectile dysfunction 



Medications

Risperdal (RISPERIDONE) 3 MG PO QD

Tegretol (CARBAMAZEPINE) 400 MG PO QD

Paxil (PAROXETINE) 40MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Depakote (DIVALPROEX Sodium) 500MG, 2 Tablet(s) PO QD

Thorazine (CHLORPROMAZINE Hcl) 25MG, 1/2 Tablet(s) PO QD

ASA 81 MG PO QD

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

LISINOPRIL 10MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Folate (FOLIC Acid) 1MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

METFORMIN 500MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 



He declines appt today for eval. Urged to come to ED today for eval if sxs worsen. Otherwise, agrees to urgent care appt tomorrow at 2:50pm.





_____________________________________________

Patricia Y Whittaker,N.P.,M.S.









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-03-03

                                                       Patient Name: WILKERSON,EDWARD [ MRN: 37199514MEDIQUIK ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 3/3/2088





MIMA PCP VISIT



Health problems discussed:

1. DM type 2. Fingerstick in the office today 130. At home, these have been mostly in the 84 -130s, but rarely up to the 180-190s. Last HbA1c was 5.8.

--given outlier hyperglycemia and no hypoglycemia, increase metformin to 1000 bid from 1000 qAM/500 qPM

--recheck A1c today

--increase lisinopril to 20 daily given BP 142/66 today



2. Lipids. Last dLDL 108. Denies any muscle cramps or weakness.

--increase atorvastatin to 40 daily, check transaminases



3. Weight. Has lost 11 pounds intentionally since September by doing more walking, eating fewer potatoes, red meat, rice.  BMI now 26.  Patient congratulated, encouraged to continue with his current diet and increase exercise as tolerated. Cautioned on caffeine given h/o SVT.



4. SVT. To see Dr. Pate from cardiology in 2 days to f/u his SVT. No known further episodes since starting verapamil.



5. Health maintenance.

--due for colonoscopy: referred, given Rx for Golytely



PE:

Blood Pressure:   142/66   [Left Arm, Sitting]

Pulse:   74   [Regular, Brachial]

Weight:   191   [Pounds]

NAD, does not appear to be responding to internal stimuli

JVP 7

CTA bilat

RRR no mrg, no heave

Abd soft, nt/nd, nabs, no mass

No foot lesions

Trace bilat ankle pitting

2+ DP and PTs bilat



______________________________                              



Floyd Bobby Ventura, M.D.



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



Pt discussed with Dr. Ventura; I agree with his evaluation and plan.





______________________________                              



Nancy Elizabeth Roman, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-01-17

EDVISIT^37199514^WILKERSON, EDWARD^01/17/93^HODGES, CHAD

Please see the written documentation undertaken by Dr. Caldwell,

the resident who saw the patient primarily.  I have seen and

examined the patient personally, reviewed the written

documentation and agree with the assessment and plan.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Mr. Wilkerson is a 68-year-old

gentleman without significant past medical history, who is

actually being seen here by his primary care physician who

happens to be a resident rotating ____ normally sees him in MIMAIMA

Clinic.  According to Dr. Caldwell, his PCP, he generally does

not have very much past medical history, but when he gets

infected, he gets confused.  He presents today with confusion. 

His visiting nurse today noticed that he has been having weakness

and fatigue over the last few days, but today, he was confused as

he has been when he has been ill in the past.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Dementia, SVT, hypertension, and diabetes

type 2.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is a former smoker.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Otherwise, negative.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise negative except as previously

dictated.

MEDICATIONS:  Lisinopril, hydrochlorothiazide, omeprazole,

Risperdal, Tegretol, verapamil, and Tylenol #3.

ALLERGIES:  He has no known drug allergies.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is a healthy, well-appearing Caucasian

gentleman who nevertheless is disoriented to time.  He knows

place and name.  His heart rate is 101, respiratory rate is 20,

blood pressure is 121/92, and oxygen saturation is 96% on room

air, and his temperature is 101.5.  He had left lower lobe

crackles in his lung exam.  The remainder of his physical exam

was otherwise normal.  Mucus membranes were moist.  Abdomen was

soft.  Extremities had no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.

LABORATORY DATA:  The patient had a normal chest x-ray, negative

urinalysis.  White blood cell count was 7.12.  He had a

creatinine of 1.24, up from his baseline and a lactate of 3.8. 

His chest x-ray showed no acute process.

IMPRESSION:  My impression is that the patient has severe sepsis

by virtue of evidence of change in his mental status and his

creatinine, he was given a liter of normal saline in the

Emergency Department as a bolus.  Given that pneumonia and

urinary tract infection were highest on the list, we decided to

treat him with Rocephin and azithromycin.  He will be admitted to

the Medical Service.

______________________________

HODGES, CHAD M.D.

D: 01/17/93

T: 01/17/93

Dictated By: HODGES, CHAD

eScription document:0-50096032 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2093-04-11

MEDIQUIK Neurology Consultation 

Edward Wilkerson
MRN: 37199514
Please refer to Student Doctor Nicky Li for HPI, ROS and past medical history. 




Briefly, 68 yr old male w a h/o HTN, HL, DMII, peripheral neuropathy, schizoaffective disorder, Borderline Personality Disorder s/p SVT ablation on 4/10 who post-operatively has been confused with gait disturbance. Neurology was consulted for an evaluation of gait disturbance and encephalopathy. On exam patient is normotensive and afebrile with cognition remarkable for inattention, disorientation, perseveration and preservation of speech and visual spatial processing. His physical exam is further remarkable for asterixis and bilateral upper extremity tremulousness. His cranial nerves are intact. His has four limb give way weakness without focality. Reflexes are 3+ and symmetric in the upper extremities and 2+ and symmetric in the lower extremities. Toes are down. Finger to nose is preserved. He is unable to stand without assistance. Differential includes toxic metabolic disturbance (i.e. hyper ammonia in the setting of depakote use vs. drugs of abuse, vs. alcohol withdrawal vs. additional superimposed toxic metabolic disturbance)




Recommendations:

-please check Liver function panel

-check ammonia

-Check B12, folate, RPR, TSH

-please start multivitamin and thiamine 100mg daily
-please check carbamazepine and valproic acid levels; please verify carbamazepine dosing as prior records suggest 400mg QD and patient is on BID dosing

-serum and urine toxicology screen

-obtain collateral history regarding possible alcohol abuse and monitor for alcohol withdrawal

-would hold amitriptyline given anticholinergic properties

-if above workup negative and unrevealing would consider NCHCT but defer imaging at this time

Please page 73703 with questions




Charles Wallace MDp73703




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>