<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2065-04-28

                     MEDIQUIK EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
RUTLEDGE,XAVIER W.   539-54-14-3               VISIT DATE: 04/28/65
This patient was seen with Dr. Russell, medicine resident.  The 
chief complaint, history of presenting illness, past medical 
history, medications, allergies, social history, family history and 
review of systems are as noted by Dr. Russell on the record, and 
were reviewed with her and with the patient. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chills, temperature to 104 degrees. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this is a 56 year old 
man status post renal transplant, who was recently admitted to a 
hospital for rising creatinine.  Tests showed that he had 
cyclosporine toxicity of his graft and cyclosporine was reduced. 
He was discharged home yesterday.  This was confirmed by biopsy. 
He was fine overnight, but then had some chills this morning, and 
presented to the Emergency Department with a temperature of 104 
degrees. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Is as noted by Dr. Russell on the record 
and basically does not identify a source of infection.  The chest 
is clear to auscultation.  The abdomen is soft with the exception 
of some tenderness over his graft site.  The wound site was 
apparently inspected by the admitting team and was not found to 
show any evidence of infection. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Laboratory studies are still pending. 
Cultures were obtained of both blood and urine. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Fevers, status post renal transplant. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Disposition - 
admission.  Condition satisfactory.  The primary physician, Dr. 
Oviedo, was notified. 
___________________________________                    LX512/443 
KYLE CONLEY, M.D.    KC70                                D:04/28/65 
                                                       T:04/28/65 
Dictated by:  KYLE CONLEY, M.D.    KC70 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2065-12-11

                     MEDIQUIK EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
RUTLEDGE,XAVIER W.   539-54-14-3               VISIT DATE: 12/11/65
I saw this patient December 11, 2065 with the resident, Dr. 
William Arndt and the coordinator from Adventist Home. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This 56-year-old man came in with redness 
and pain in his left leg. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  History of present illness 
includes renal failure, renal transplant, insulin dependent 
diabetes mellitus and peripheral vascular disease.  He recently had 
a deep venous thrombosis of the left leg extending from the calf 
into the common femoral vein which is being treated now with 
Coumadin, but today he noticed the redness, swelling and pain in 
the leg.  Please see the resident's hand written record for 
explicit details of the patient's visit and findings. 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Please see the resident's hand written record 
for explicit details of the patient's visit and findings. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Please see the resident's hand written 
record for explicit details of the patient's visit and findings. 
MEDICATIONS:  Please see the resident's hand written record for 
explicit details of the patient's visit and findings. 
ALLERGIES:  Please see the resident's hand written record for 
explicit details of the patient's visit and findings. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Please see the resident's hand 
written record for explicit details of the patient's visit and 
findings. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On physical examination, about one half the 
area of the distal leg more anteriorly is warm, red, discolored and 
tender.  Homan's sign is negative. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was sent for Doppler 
ultrasound of the leg which showed improved flow through the common 
femoral vein, but persistent thrombosis in the superficial femoral 
of the gastrocnemius and popliteal veins.  He was begun on 
intravenous Nebcin for a presumed cellulitis.  The plan is several 
days of hospitalization with elevation and intravenous antibiotics. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Cellulitis of leg. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 
admitted to the hospital in fair condition. 
___________________________________                    BZ259/4420 
YUTAKA PRITCHARD, M.D.       YP66                          D:12/11/65 
                                                       T:12/11/65 
Dictated by:  YUTAKA PRITCHARD, M.D.       YP66 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2068-12-01

                     MEDIQUIK EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

RUTLEDGE,XAVIER W.   539-54-14-3

I was the patient's doctor during this emergency department stay.

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Infection in the left foot. 

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 59-year-old man 

with multiple medical problems including insulin-requiring diabetes 

who has a chronic, nonhealing ulcer on the plantar surface of his 

left foot.  He now complains of two days of increasing pain and 

redness and systemic malaise.  He denies chest pain, abdominal 

pain, streaking redness up to the thigh, nausea, vomiting, 

diarrhea, and dysuria.  

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative except as given above. 

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypercholesterolemia, gout, hypertension, 

insulin-requiring diabetes mellitus, chronic renal insufficiency, 

nephrotic syndrome, status post kidney transplant in 2059, on 

cyclosporine, thrombocytopenia, CMV, and hypomagnesemia 

intermittently.  Kidney transplant as noted above.

MEDICATIONS:  Levaquin, cyclosporine, magnesium, Lipitor, Coumadin, 

prednisone, Allopurinol, lisinopril, metoprolol, Lasix, and others 

as noted on the nurses' notes.  

ALLERGIES:  Codeine which caused a rash. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Social history noncontributory. 

Family history noncontributory.  

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Awake, alert, spontaneous and 

appropriate, in no distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Normal.  HEENT:  There 

was no evidence of head trauma, conjunctivae clear.  NECK:  Supple 

with no lymphadenopathy and no jugulovenous distention.  CHEST:  

Notable for babasilar rales with normal respiratory excursion.  

HEART:  Regular with no murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, 

nontender, no masses, no organomegaly.  SKIN/EXTREMITIES:  Other 

than the left foot and ankle, the skin and extremities were normal 

with no clubbing, cyanosis, lesions or rashes, although there was 

bilateral 1+ pitting edema in the lower extremities.  The left foot 

had an approximately 1 cm ulcer on the plantar surface and the 

entire left foot and ankle were quite erythematous with increased 

edema relative to the remainder of the lower extremities.  He also 

had tenderness on palpation of the ankle though there was no 

tenderness on passive motion of the toes.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Pending at this time.  The patient is being 

seen by the Surgery Department.  

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Infected diabetic foot ulcer.  

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient will 

be admitted to the Surgery Department for surgical management 

and inpatient medical management.  Condition fair.  

___________________________________                    OO280/953 

QUINTON OSWALD, M.D.   QO05                              D:12/01/68 

                                                       T:12/01/68 

Dictated by:  QUINTON OSWALD, M.D.   QO05 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-10-24

EDVISIT^53954143^Rutledge, Xavier^10/24/70^OCASIO, WANDA

This patient was seen by myself and Dr. Pappas on 10/24/2070.  I

confirm that I interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the

resident's documentation and discussed plan of care with the

patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 61-year-old gentleman with

a history of cadaveric renal transplant 11 years ago with a

history of DVT, on Coumadin, diabetes, chronic right lower

extremity edema, who comes in with dysuria and chills.  He had no

urinary output since last night.  He says his fevers started this

morning above 101.  He went to his PCP who sent him here.  He

denies any nausea or vomiting.  He has mild lower suprapubic

abdominal pain and some mild flank pain.  He has had some urinary

frequency.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, diabetes, gout,

hypercholesterolemia, end-stage renal disease, status post

transplant, anemia, BPH, and DVT.

MEDICATIONS:  Please refer to the EDUCARE-FARGO list in the chart.

ALLERGIES:  He has allergies to codeine.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  He is not a smoker, drinker, or drug user.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  As noted in the HPI, otherwise negative.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is an ill-appearing gentleman with

rigors.  Vital signs are as noted.  Head, eyes, ears, nose, and

throat are unremarkable.  Neck is supple.  He does have dry

mucous membranes.  Chest is clear to auscultation.  Heart is

slightly tachycardic.  Abdomen has some suprapubic fullness and

tenderness but otherwise is benign.  His rectal exam is

heme-positive.  There is no prostate tenderness.  His skin is

warm and flushed.  He has got toe amputations.  Extremities are

otherwise unremarkable.  Neuro exam is nonfocal.

LABORATORY DATA:  He has got a white count of 14, hematocrit of

35, and platelet count 139,000.  SMA-7 shows bicarbonate of 15

with an anion gap of 15, and a creatinine of 4.7 which is up from

his baseline.  LFTs are otherwise unremarkable.  A chest x-ray

was unremarkable.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  He did get a Foley catheter with

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

obstruction.  He was given levofloxacin and vancomycin.  He was

also given Tylenol.  He got some IV fluids.  He had an INR of 2.6

which was about baseline.  The plan was to admit him to the

hospital.  Transplant was subsequently called.

DIAGNOSIS:  Pyelonephritis.

______________________________

OCASIO, WANDA M.D.

D: 10/26/70

T: 10/26/70

Dictated By: OCASIO, WANDA

eScription document:5-6955464 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-06-12

Internal Medicine Admit Note   06/12/72

Patient Name: Xavier Rutledge (KEKELA 53954143)
Renal TPx Details:  Cadaveric RTX 2060 w/ CAN and baseline Cr 2.5
Renal Dx:  ESRD of unclear cause
Current Immsp:  CsA and Prednisone

Reason for Admit: Fever, diarrhea and probable UTI

Background:  63M with known CRRTx since 2060 with known CKD and baseline Cr 2.5 with urethral stricture and in-dwelling Foley catheter who presented to ED with h/o multiple episodes of diarrhea last night, cloudy urine and severe weakness.   He was on Ampicillin for a recent UTI.  He denies any fevers this past weekend, however he was febrile today at 102 F. He has chronic lower extremity edema for which he is on  high dose lasix with minimal response. In ED patient was hypoglycemic with FSBS 46.  He was givin 1amp D50 and a liter of NS IV.

Medical Hx:
1. ESRD s/p CRRTx 2060
 - Prior to TPx was on HD via RUE AVF, presumed ESRD d/t HTN
 - CRRTx 2060 requiring re-implantation of the ureter two times
 - Renal Bx (2065): cyclosporine toxicity, nephrolithiasis, TIF
 - Baseline Cr 2.4 - 2.8, Renal Bx 2065: 
2. Urethral stricture requiring repeated catherisation and c/b UTI's, foley in place.  Plan for suprapubic catheter placement by Dr. Acevedo.
 - Multiple UTI's w/ h/o Candida (Apr 2072), Klebsiella (September 2071), Proteus
3. Type 2 DM 
 - Diagnosed following TPx and steroids
 - On insulin
4. CMV retinitis post-transplant
5. Aortic stenosis
 - Echo 2071: AVA 1.3 cm and peak gradient 28 mmHg
6. Recurrent LE DVT's - on Coumadin
7. HTN
8. Torn right rotator cuff
9. Gout
10. BPH
11. Hypercholesterolemia
12. s/p left 5th toe amputation
13. h/o  C. dif colitis
14. s/p ccy and appy
15. G6PD deficiency

Medications:
Neoral 100mg bid po
Prednisone 5/10mg qd po
Lopressor 50mg bid po
Lasix 80 mg bid po
Iron Sulfate 325mg bid po
Calcium Carbonate 500 mg tid po
Flomax 0.8mg qhs po
Proscar 5 mg qd po
Coumadin 1 mg qd po
Procrit 10,000 U q week (Wed)
NPH 22 units qam and 10 U qpm, Insulin sliding scale qAC+HS
Immodium q4-6hrs prn loose stools
Ampicillin 500mg qid

Allergies: Codeine -> Nausea, Potassium -> Nausea and Rash, Quinine

Social History: Lives with wife, retired.  Denies tobacoo (quit 30 yrs ago), ETOH9(quit 30 yrs ago), and ilicit drug use

Family History: unremarkable

On examination: 
General:  Lying on bed in no distress
Vitals:  T99.8 F;  BP 97/44 mmHg;  HR 77/min;  R 20
HEENT:  (+) orbital edema b/l,   (+) facial flushing
CVS:  S1 and S2, no S3/Rub, clinical ESM loudes over aortic areaResp:  slight expiratory wheeze RLLB, no rhonchi or rales.
Abd:  Soft, non tender, no masses, NABS.  Left sided palpable graft with no tenderness.  Cloudy urine in Foley
Legs:  3+ edema bilaterally
RUE:  AVF with thrill and bruit
Neuro: A &O x 3

Results          
Date/Time         PT             PT-INR         PTT            
06/12/2072        28.3 (*#)      2.7 (*)        46.6 (*#)      

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2  
06/12/2072        138            3.6            110 (*)        20          
Date/Time         BUN            CRE            EGFR           GLU   06/12/2072        89 (*)         3.1 (*)        22 [11]        48          
Date/Time         ANION          
06/12/2072        8              

Date/Time         CA             PHOS           MG             TBILI
06/12/2072        8.5 (*)        4.1            1.7 (*)        0.7         
Date/Time         TP             ALB            GLOB           LDH  
06/12/2072        5.3 (*)        2.7 (*)        2.6            284         
Date/Time         AMY            LIPS            
06/12/2072        25             4 [21]         

Date/Time         bPO2           bPCO2          bPH          UBASEX  06/12/2072 [22]   39 (*)         38 (#)         7.32 (*#)      -6        
Date/Time         O2 Sat         K-PL           CO2-PL         HGBBG 06/12/2072 [23]   74.2 (*)       3.5            20 (*)         10.3                                                                      
Date/Time         HCT-BG         
06/12/2072 [24]   30 (*)         

Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP         TBILI 
06/12/2072        96 (*#)        157 (*#)       178 (*#)       0.7         
Date/Time         LDH            
06/12/2072        284 (*)        

Date/Time         UK             
06/12/2072        13             

Date/Time         UTIME          
06/12/2072        RANDOM         

Date/Time         UTIME          U/UNA          U/UCL        U/UOSM  06/12/2072        RANDOM         70             77             PEND           
Date/Time         MHGB           COHGB          
06/12/2072 [30]   0.3            0.5            

Date/Time         UA-COLOR       UA-GLUC        UA-BILI      UA-KET  06/12/2072        YELLOW [31]    NEG            NEG            NEG            
Date/Time         UA-SPGR        UA-BLD         UA-PH        UA-PROT 06/12/2072        1.014          3+             5.0            2+             
Date/Time         UA-UROBI       UA-NIT         UA-WBC       MIC-SED  		 
06/12/2072        NEG            NEG            3+             NEG            
Date/Time         OCAST          HCAST          UAS-RBC      UAS-WBC 06/12/2072        NEG            0              233 (*)        316         
Date/Time         UAS-BACT       UAS-SQHI       UAS-CRYS       
06/12/2072        TR             3+             NEG            

Date/Time         UA-EPIS        
06/12/2072        NEG            

Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT   06/12/2072        13.61 (*)      3.86 (*)       10.7 (*)       32.3  06/12/2072        13.65 (*#)     3.76 (*)       10.4 (*)       32.2  
Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT   06/12/2072        83.7           27.8           33.2           157   06/12/2072        85.7           27.5           32.1           151            
Date/Time         RDW            
06/12/2072        17.5 (*)       
06/12/2072        17.3 (*)       

Date/Time         %POLY-A        %LYMPH-A       %MONO-A       %EOS-A 06/12/2072        88.8 (*)       4.4 (*)        6.0            0.5            
Date/Time         %BASO-A        %POLY-M        %BAND-M    %LYMPH-M 06/12/2072        0.3            89 (*)         2              1 (*) 06/12/2072                       92 (*)         1              1 (*)          
Date/Time         %ATYPS         %MONO-M        %EOS-M      %BASO-M  06/12/2072        0              8              0              0     06/12/2072        0              6              0              0              
Date/Time         ANEUT-A        ALYMP-A        AMONO-A       AEOS-A 06/12/2072        12.09 (*)      .6 (*)         0.82 (*)       0.06           
Date/Time         ABASO-A        
06/12/2072        0.04           

Date/Time         ANISO          POIK           POLYCH         HYPO  06/12/2072        +              1+             1+             +     06/12/2072                       1+                                           
Date/Time         MACRO          MICRO          OVALS        TEARDR  06/12/2072        1+             +              1+                   06/12/2072                                      1+             1+             
Date/Time         PLT-EST        
06/12/2072        NL             
06/12/2072        NL             

Date/Time         ESR            
06/12/2072        PEND           
06/12/2072        20 (*)[32]   


Radiology:
06/12/2072 12:16 KEKELA Radiology                 Report Status:  Final
Type:  Chest PA & Lateral
HISTORY: Fever.
      
Chest: Frontal and lateral views of the chest are compared to prior exam dated 5/31/2072 and show mild enlargement of the cardiac silhouette and an atherosclerotic aorta. There are small bilateral posterior pleural effusions. Adjacent parenchymal opacity may reflect atelectasis or early pneumonia in theappropriate clinical setting. Mild diffuse elevation of        the interstitium appears chronic. Right upper lobe granuloma.
      
     IMPRESSION: Mild cardiomegaly with small bilateral posterior
     pleural effusions. Adjacent parenchymal opacity could reflect
     subsegmental atelectasis or early pneumonia in the appropriate
     clinical setting. These findings were communicated by me to Dr.
     Ximena Webber at 2:25 p.m
         
A/P:  63M with known CRRTx since 2060 with known CKD and baseline Cr 2.5 with urethral stricture and in-dwelling Foley. Pt. now with fevers, UTI, and diarrhea.  He will be admitted to George Rutledge, M.D. on the Internal Medicine.

1. Renal- CRRTx with creatinine elevated 3.1 (2.5), ? pyelonephritis 
 - Urine cultures sent in the ED. 
 - Would hold further iv fluids.  
 - Continue current Lasix dose
 - Strict I/O
 - Check Urine Protein/Creat Ratio
2. Urologic- urethral stricture and in-dwelling foley cath with fever and high urinary WBC. 
 - Given iv Levofloxacin/Ceftaz in the ED. 
 - Need to change Foley cathether.
 - Dr Acevedo to review for suprapubic catheter placement.
3. Immunosuppresion
 - Continue CsA and Prednisone
 - Check CsA level in the am.
4. Pulm-
5. Endo- hypoglycemic in ED, will monitor closely with q AC + HS accuchecks.
6. GI- diarrhea 
 - Will send stool for C-diff
 - Will check CMV viral load
7. Fluid Status- volume overloaded 
 - Adequate on oral lasix



_____________________________________________
Arlene T. Whitaker,PA-C
Internal Medicine
beeper #11830


Patient seen and examined with renal fellow. I agree with the review of patient problems, history, medication, physical examination, assessment and plan as detailed in the fellow note above. Followup clinic visit arranged with patient. 
Case was discussed with patient, renal transplant nurse, and pharmacist.

George T. Rutledge, M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>