<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2078-07-30



Reason for Visit

Follow-up



Chief Complaint

L post-auricular pain



History of Present Illness

Developed mild pain in L ear and postauricular area the last two weeks.  No trauma, no hearing loss, no vertigo, no URI symptoms



Problems

      Hypertension

Tolerating Zestril without problems. BP still elevated on Zestril 20mg.

      Obesity

She was started on Xenical by Internal Medicine.  She is taking it only Qd instead of AC, since it is giving her too much loose stool.  She feels increase flatulence, bloating sensation on Xenical.

      Depression

Stable on Prozac.  No adverse side effects.  No SI or HI.

      Knee pain

from medial meniscal tear.  No edema, erythema. Celebrex effective initially but now not.  She is taking on top of Celebrex also Motrin.  She is going for return visit with Dr. Vogel to discuss surgery.

      Anemia

Fe studies, vitamin B12, folate levels all normal. Asymptomatic without CP, SOB, or lightheadedness.  No abnormal vaginal bleeding.



Medications

      Zestril (LISINOPRIL)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Prozac (FLUOXETINE Hcl)    20MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO QD

      Xenical (ORLISTAT)    120MG,  1 Capsule(s)  PO TID

      IBUPROFEN   800MG,  1 Tablet(s)  PO TID

      Vaseretic 10-25 (ENALAPRIL 10mg + Hctz 25mg)    .5 TABLET PO QD



Allergies

      NKDA



Past Medical History

Reviewed electronic data

Reviewed old records

See problem list



Preventive Health History

See Health Maint.



Review of Systems

CONSTITUTIONAL: Appetite good, nutrition adequate

PAIN: see above

BREASTS: Inconsistent self-exam

RESP.: No cough

CVS: No PND, exertional chest pain, claudication. 

GI: No dyspepsia, constipation 

GU: No dysuria, diminished stream, incontinence



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   160/70 

      PULSE   72 

      WEIGHT   196 lb



Physical Exam

      Chest

clear to auscultation

      Cor/Cardiac

RRR, unchanged 2/6 SEM at RUSB

      Musc Skel

mild tenderness at medial joint line of L knee

      HEENT

L TM clear with good light reflex; L ear canal without worrisome lesion; L auricle and post-auricular area without palpable tenderness or signs of infection, no postauricular lymphadenopathy



Assessment and Plan

Summary: 50yoF with obesity, knee pain, hypertension



1)  hypertension: tolering Zestril. K and Cr are fine. Will increase Zestril to 40mg QD.  Patient also given a prescription for Hctz 12.5mg QD but told not to start it yet until his next BP check and start only if BP > 140/85.



2)  L knee pain: Celebrex not effective anymore. Patient told to stop and continue Ibuprofen 800mg TID with meals.  Patient will see Dr. Vogel and discuss surgery.  No benefit from PT.



3)  obesity:  taking only Xenical once a day. No significant weight change yet, but recently just started on Xenical.  Will follow.



4)  anemia: iron, vitamin B12, folate levels all normal.  Not still menstruating.  Rechecking Hct with reticulocyte count.



5)  cardiac murmur: TTE in 8/78



6)  L ear pain: etiology unclear.  Will follow expectantly.  



7)  h/o GERD and Barrett's esophagitis: EGD in 8/78



8)  hyperlipidemia: will recheck lipid panel at next visit and decide on statin therapy



Health Maintenance

- Breast exam/mammogram: 3/78 mammogram benign

- Pap smear: patient deferred to next visit

- Colonoscopy: will discuss at next visit



RTC: 1-2 months to f/u EGD and TTE results and recheck BP.  Patient will likely need to start Hctz.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-11-23

IVORY, LORI

2097545

11/22/78

PCP:Dr. Helen Updike



EDUCARE-PULLMAN TEAM A INTERN

ADMISSION NOTE



CC/ID: 51 yo F with no known h/o CHF or CAD, but with multiple cardiac risk factors, p/w dyspnea



HPI: Pt has had difficulty with bp ctrl due to poor med compliance (SBP 160-190 in clinic). Had been on Atenolol and Zestril but pt self-D/C'd Zestril several wks ago because she thought the Zestril made her feel nauseated. Since then, has had gradually developing DOE   from baseline of walking over 4-5 flights of stairs without difficulty to dyspnea on only a flight of stairs. She underwent L knee arthroscopy for medial meniscal tear on 11/19/78 without immediate complications. At 3 am that night, though, woke up with severe dyspnea, with some relief upon sitting up. Associated with some wheezing; tried some of husband's nebs   only slight relief. Later over the day, dyspnea worsened to the point that only few steps would make short of breath. Some association with non-radiating substernal chest tightness in evening; no N/V, lightheadness, diaphoresis, or pleuritic CP, F/S/C, or cough. Next day, dyspnea persisted so pt came into ED.



In ED, found to have BP of 230's/120's, satting 70's on RA. CTA PE-protocol showing no PE or DVT but with pulm edema and bibasilar atelectasis vs. PNA (unlikely). Given Lasix 40 mg IV x 1    2.7 L diuresis; started on nitropaste, Captopril, Labetalol    BP down to 140's. Also given ASA and Lopressor x 1 and started on Heparin IV. Given Levoflox x 1 for ? PNA on CXR. Had to be on BiPAP for several hrs   transitioned to 3L NC, satting mid-90's. Transferred to floor for further mgmt.



Has had recent 8/78 ECHO   EF 67% with mild MR, TR, and AI; nl LV size and function without WMA.





ROS:

-Has had mild R subscapular dull pain on night before admission; not associated with her chest tightness or dyspnea; resolved on own on day of admission.

-Pt thinks L leg may be more swollen than her R



PMH

1.	Hypertension

2.	Obesity: followed by Internal Medicine

3.	PUD: H.Pylori positive

4.	s/p L knee meniscal repair

5.	Depression 

6.	Anemia

7.	Hypercholesterolemia



MEDS (AT HOME)

Atenolol 25 mg po qd

Zestril 40 mg po qd (has not been taking)

Prozac 20 mg po qd

Ibuprofen 800 mg po tid PRN pain

Percocet PRN pain post-surgery (has not been taking) 



Allergies

NKDA



Social History 

Quit smoking 10 yrs ago (2 ppd x 4-5 yrs_

5-6 beers/night on wkends; last drink last Sunday; no h/o withdrawal or seizures

Railway Transport Operations Supervisor at BI; lives with husband



     

Family History

-No known FH of CAD

-DM in father



PHYS EXAM

GEN: Comfortable, converses appropriately, A+O x 3 

VS: T 98  HR 75  BP 152/92 (R arm, manual BP)  148/82 (L arm, manual BP)  RR 22  96% on 2L

HEENT: NC/AT; PERRL, EOMI. 

NECK: JVP 10 cm; no tracheal deviation. No carotid bruits.

CHEST: Crackles halfway up.

COR: No sternal heaves. Normal S1 and S2 with no loud P2. RRR, no M/R/G  

ABD: Soft, NT, ND, BS+

Ext: 1+ pedal edema. No asymmetric leg edema or palpable cords. Warm, DP 2+ bilaterally and radial pulses 2+ bilaterally and symmetric

Neuro: Moving all ext's without impairment and in symmetric fashion. No decrease in fine-touch in all ext's.



DATA



Sodium (Stat Lab)        138                         (135-145)        mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)     3.4                         (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)      104                         (100-108)        mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)           27.1                        (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)           15                          (8-25)           mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)    0.7                         (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)       171                H        (70-110)         mg/dl



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   5.2                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index     4.2                H        (0.0-3.5)        %

Troponin-T               0.08                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase          123                         (40-150)         U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   3.7                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

CPK Isoenzymes Index                                 (0.0-3.5)        %

     CPK and/or CKMB too low to calculate Relative Index.

Troponin-T               0.03                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase          110                         (40-150)         U/L



Creatine Kinase Isoenz   3.5                         (0.0-6.9)        ng/ml

Troponin-T               0.01                        (0.00-0.09)      ng/ml

Transaminase-SGOT        33                 H        (9-32)           U/L

Creatine Kinase          97                          (40-150)         U/L



WBC                      6.9                         (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                      33.6               L        (36.0-46.0)      %

PLT                      294                         (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                      85                          (80-100)         fl

MCH                      29.4                        (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                     34.4                        (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                      13.3                        (11.5-14.5)      %

Superstat PT             12.7                        (11.1-13.1)      sec

Superstat APTT           21.1               L        (22.1-35.1)      sec

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST     RECEIVED

Diff Method              Auto

Poly                     58                          (40-70)          %

Lymphs                   35                          (22-44)          %

Monos                    5                           (4-11)           %

EOS                      2                           (0-8)            %

Basos                    0                           (0-3)            %



Macrocytes               None

Microcytes               None

D-Dimer (ELISA)          1061               H        (<500)           ng/ml



-EKG (ED): NSR, ? STE in V1-2

-EKG (floor) 9 am: NSR with ? STE in V1-2

-EKG (floor) night: NSR with resolved STE in V1, still present in V2



CXR: pulm edema 



A/P

51 yo F with no known CAD or CHF, p/w acute CHF in setting of severe HTN, c/b troponin leak



1.CARDS:  Suspect that pt had flash pulm edema from HTN due to poor med compliance as well as from  fluid re-mobilization post-surgery. Acute ischemic event possible given some EKG changes as well as mildly elevated troponin, but these findings could be also explained as demand ischemia event.



-Serial EKG's

-Cardiac monitor, telemetry

-Troponin elevation likely due to demand ischemia; subsequent level was lower, indicating resolving. Doubt ACS at this time but will continue to follow enz's

-ASA, Lopressor

-BP ctrl with ACE-I & B-blocker, aiming for SBP goal of 140's-160's for overnight  (BP had been as high as 230's)

-Lipitor; Check fasting lipids & glucose, homocysteine

-Lasix as needed, aiming for TBB goal of neg 1-2 L; Strict I/O's, qd wt's

-ECHO and Adenosine-MIBI (when more stable)

 

2. Leg Edema: Doubt DVT, but given recent surgery and lack of mobility, will check LENI's

-Fragmin for DVT prophylaxis

-F/U LENI's



3. Miscellaneous:

  	Nexium

  	MVI, Folate, Thiamine

  	PT consult

  	Nutrition consult



4. Anemia

-Guaiac all stools; Bid Hct's for now

-Check iron studies, hemolysis labs, peripheral smear, retic count





___________

Xiomar Ortega #40179





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-02-03

Educare-Pullman Team D Intern Admit Note





Patient's name:  IVORY, LORI O	 

MRN:   2097545	 

Date of Admission: 02/03/79   	 

PCP: Helen Updike 		



Chief Complaint: CP, SOB    

 

History Obtained From: Pt, chart



History of Present Illness: 51 yo w w/ PMHx sig for HTN and diastolic dysfunction and recent admission with CHF in the context of HTN who presented w/ CC of SOB and CP that she said radiated down both of her arms. The pain and SOB started on the eve before admission while pt was at rest. Upon arrival of EMS pt was hypertensive to 220 by report.Given ASA, Nitros and brought to the EDUCARE-FARGO ED.   Daughter describes pt to be wheezing several days PTA. Pt c/o of nausea in the ED.    

  Pt denies F/C/V/ diaphoresis/ palpitations/ PND/ orthopnea/ diarrhea/ BRBPR/ melena/ dysuria/ hematuria/ myalgias/ arthralgias. No recent travel or sick contacts. 

Diminished exersize tolerance 2/2 knee pain. Of note, pt has been known to be poorly compliant with her medical as well as dietary regimen. Pt did say that she stopped taking her lasix close to a month ago.

 

ED Course: VS: T=98.7; BP=160/78; HR= 87 ; RR=20; SaO2=91 % on RA  

Lopressor 5 mg IV, Lopressor 25 mg PO, Nitropaste 1 inch, ASA 325, KCL 40 mEq x 2, MgSO4 2 gm x 1, Atenolol 25 mg, Lisinopril 40 mg, Zantac, Zofran 4 mg IV

UO 1850 cc.   



Floor Course: NAD, Related the history above



Review of System: 

See HPI 



Past Medical History: 

Diastolic Dysfunction: RVSP 43, EF 67 %, no valvular or SVMA; negative Adenosine MIBI in Nov 2078 

Hypertension 

Obesity 

Peptic ulcer disease

Status post left knee meniscal repair

Depression

Anemia

Hypercholesterolemia.

     

Medications: 

Atenolol 25 mg po qd

Zestril 40 mg po qd,

Prozac 20 mg po qd

Ibuprofen 800 mg po tid prn pain.

    

Allergies: NKDA

 

Family History: 

No known family history of CAD; + diabetes in her father.

 

Social history:  The patient works as an Railway Transport Operations Supervisor and lives with her husband.

Tobacco:   The patient quit smoking 10 years ago, but had an 8-10

pack year history prior to quitting.

Alcohol:  The patient drinks and with no history of alcohol withdrawal or seizures.  5-6 beers per night on weekends with her last drink many days ago

Drugs: previous use of cocaine and pot in HS 

Other: denies



Physical Exam:

VS: BP=122/60  HR=73  RR=18  SaO2=99 % on 2 L   Tmax= 98.2     

General: in NAD 

HEENT: NCAT, PERRL, EOMI, moist mucous membranes

Neck: supple, JVP flat

Chest: CTA b/l

Cor: Reg rhythm, nl rate, nl S1, S2, no S3, S4, murmurs or rubs

Abdomen: soft, non-distended, non-tendered; BS present; 

Ext: 2+ DP/PT pulses bilaterally; no pedal edema or cyanosis.

Neuro: A&O x 3; cranial nerves II-XII intact; motor and sensory functions grossly normal; non-focal exam.



Labs:

Chemistry

  Lytes/Renal/Glucose

    Sodium                 135   135-145 mmol/L     02/02/79 23:57

    Potassium              2.9L  3.4-4.8 mmol/L     02/02/79 23:57      

    Chloride               103   100-108 mmol/L     02/02/79 23:57       

    Carbon Dioxide        28.9   23.0-31.9 mmol/L   02/02/79 23:57     

    BUN                     19   8-25 mg/dl         02/02/79 23:57        

    Creatinine             0.8   0.6-1.5 mg/dl      02/02/79 23:57      

    Glucose                146H  70-110 mg/dl       02/02/79 23:57      

  General Chemistries

    Calcium                8.8   8.5-10.5 mg/dl     02/03/79 00:34

    Phosphorus             3.5   2.6-4.5 mg/dl      02/03/79 00:34

    Magnesium              1.3L  1.4-2.0 meq/L      02/03/79 00:34      

    Bilirubin(Total)       0.4   0-1.0 mg/dl        02/03/79 00:34

    Bilirubin(Direct       0.2   0-0.4 mg/dl        02/03/79 00:34

    Total Protein          7.1   6.0-8.3 g/dl       02/03/79 00:34

    Albumin                3.7   3.3-5.0 g/dl       02/03/79 00:34

    Globulin               3.4   2.6-4.1 g/dl       02/03/79 00:34

  

  Liver Function Tests

    ALT (SGPT)              17   7-30 U/L           02/03/79 00:34       

    AST (SGOT)              17   9-32 U/L           02/03/79 00:34       

    Alk Phos               104H  30-100 U/L         02/03/79 00:34      

    Bilirubin(Total)       0.4   0-1.0 mg/dl        02/03/79 00:34

    Bilirubin(Direct       0.2   0-0.4 mg/dl        02/03/79 00:34

  Cardiac Tests

 

    CK-MB(quant)      NEGATIVE   NEG                02/03/79 08:25 

    Troponin-I        NEGATIVE   NEG                02/03/79 08:25

    Hematology

  Complete Blood Count

    WBC                    6.4   4.5-11.0 th/cmm    02/02/79 23:08      

    RBC                   3.94L  4.00-5.20 mil/cm   02/02/79 23:08     

    Hgb                   11.8L  12.0-16.0 gm/dl    02/02/79 23:08     

    HCT                   33.1L  36.0-46.0 %        02/02/79 23:08    

    MCV                     84   80-100 fl          02/02/79 23:08

    MCH                   29.9   26.0-34.0 pg/rbc   02/02/79 23:08

    MCHC                  35.7   31.0-37.0 g/dl     02/02/79 23:08

    PLT                    242   150-350 th/cumm    02/02/79 23:08

    RDW                   12.9   11.5-14.5 %        02/02/79 23:08

  Blood Differential %

    Differential Req  RECEIVED                      02/02/79 23:05

    Diff Method           Auto                      02/02/79 23:08

    Neutrophils             68   40-70 %            02/02/79 23:08

    Lymphs                  25   22-44 %            02/02/79 23:08

    Monos                    4   4-11 %             02/02/79 23:08

    Eos                      3   0-8 %              02/02/79 23:08

    Basos                    0   0-3 %              02/02/79 23:08

  Blood Diff - Absolute

    Neutrophil #          4.28   1.8-7.7 th/cmm     02/02/79 23:08

    Lymph#                1.61   1.0-4.8 th/cmm     02/02/79 23:08

    Mono#                 0.27   0.2-0.4 th/cmm     02/02/79 23:08

    Eos#                  0.21   0.1-0.3 th/cmm     02/02/79 23:08

    Baso#                 0.02   0.0-0.3 th/cmm     02/02/79 23:08

    Anisocytosis          None   NORMAL             02/02/79 23:08

    Hypochromia           None   NORMAL             02/02/79 23:08

    Macrocytes            None                      02/02/79 23:08

    Microcytes            None                      02/02/79 23:08

  Coagulation

  Routine Coagulation

    PT                    12.2   11.1-13.1 sec      02/02/79 23:14     

    PT-INR                 1.0                      02/02/79 23:14

    PTT                   22.6   22.1-35.1 sec      02/02/79 23:19   





Microbiology:

NA



Radiology:

CXRAY:

Interstitial pulmonary edema, improved from the previous

examination.



EKG: Resolution of the previously Nov-2078 present ST Elevations in V1-V2; LVH

	

Assessment/Plan:

 51 yo F with hx of diastolc dysfunction and recent admission with flash pul edema in the setting of elevated BP, p/w similar symptoms, i.e. acute CHF in setting of severe HTN, no troponin leak, no new ischemic EKG changes



1.CARDS

-Serial EKG's

-Cardiac monitor, telemetry

- Serial Markers

-ASA, Lopressor

-BP ctrl with ACE-I & B-blocker, aiming for SBP goal of 140's-160's for overnight  (BP had been as high as 220's)

-Lipitor; Check fasting lipids   

-Lasix as needed; Strict I/O's, qd wt's

-No need for ECHO or Adenosine-MIBI on this admission given no new EKG changes 

 

2. HTN:

- seems to be well controlled at this time

- if becomes difficult to control will titrate BB up and consider affing another agent 

- may need to be worked up for 2/2 cause of HTN, such as RAS



3. Hx of med noncompliance:  

- will need repetitive reinforcement re importance of adherence to medical regimen

- will discuss potential benefit from being plugged into the CHF clinic

- consider nutrition consult

 

4. Anemia

-Guaiac all stools; 

- Resend iron studies, peripheral smear, retic count, folic acid, B12

- Consider transfusing idf HCT < 30



5. FEN: Low Sodium, Low Cholesterol, Low Fat Diet; Replete lytes as needed



6. Prophylaxis: 

Nexium 

 









-------------------------------

Tammy Yon, M.D. x 60562









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-05-01


Educare-Pullman B Admission Note

PATIENT:    Ivory, Lori
MR: 2097545
ADMIT DATE:    April 30, 2081
CODE STATUS:  Full
ATTENDING:   Aviles/Meyers
PCP:   Kathryn Oakley/Gricelda Ovalle

CC:   chest pain

HPI:
53 y/o female with PMHx significant for CHF/diastolic dysfunction, HTN who presents with 2 day history of chest pain.  Pain started yesterday AM while she was getting into her car and lasted a few minutes.  She had another episode later that day while trying to climb a step ladder in her kitchen and another episode in the ER today.  Each episode went away after few minute (during 3rd episode she got some NTG with relief of pain).  The pain feels like a pressure. She did have some diaphoresis with each episode and on the last episode also developed some nausea.  Inspiration makes the pain worse as well as sitting upright.  Denies palpitations.  Does have SOB with pain.  No recent illness. Did have URI few weeks ago.  Her activity is limited by arthritis in her knee, but she denies any CP with activity.

ER: Got ASA, Metoprolol 5mg IV x3, PE protocol CT neg.

Problems
Peptic ulcer disease : positive h pylori
Hypertension 
Menopause 
Obesity 
Depression 
Knee pain 
Palpitations 
Heart murmur 
Hyperlipidemia 
Anemia 
Congestive heart failure, diastolic dysfunction, EF 67% in 78
Bright red blood per rectum 

Medications
Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 TAB PO QD 
Enteric COATED ASA   81 MG PO QD 
Percocet  1 TAB PO Q4H PRN pain 
Ibuprofen 600 MG PO Q6H PRN pain 
Zestril  40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD x 30 days
Prozac  20 MG PO QD     stopped taking this due to insurance issues
Atenolol 50 MG PO QD 
Lasix  40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Allergies
NKA 

SOCIAL HISTORY
The patient used to work as Railway Transport Operations Supervisor with Blyth Inc.  Currently lives by herself.  She quit smoking about ten years ago, eight to ten pack year smoking history prior to quitting.  She drinks but has no history of alcohol withdrawal or seizures, says she drinks about five or six beers per.  There is a previous use of cocaine in high school but no drug use currently.

FAMILY HISTORY:   
Aunt- MI,  Positive for diabetes mellitus in her father.

ROS:  
	General: no recent weight loss/gain, no fatigue, no fevers, chills, no change in appetite
-	Respiratory: no cough, no SOB,  no hemoptysis, no wheezing
-	Cardiac: no chest pain/pressure, no palpitations
-	Gastrointestinal: no nausea, no vomiting, no diarrhea, no constipation, no bleeding
-	Neurologic: no seizures, headache, no weakness, no numbness/tingling
-	Musculoskeletal: B Knee pain
-	Urologic: No hematuria, no dysuria 
-	Hematologic: No bruising, no bleeding

PHYSICAL EXAM
VITALS:  159/93, 98.9, 78, 20, 98%
Gen: awake, alert, NAD
HEENT: PERRL, EOMI
Neck: 1cm cervical LN on left, no thryomegally, no LAD, no bruits
Oropharynx: clear, no lesions
CV: RRR no murmers
Pulm: CTA Bilaterally
Abd: + b.s, ND, no masses, does have some tenderness over RUQ area
Ext: 1 + dp pulses, no cyanosis, clubbing, or edema
Neuro: moving all four extremities, 
MS: B knees tender on palpation

   Chemistry  
Sodium (Stat Lab)                137                       (135-145)      mmol/L
Potassium (Stat Lab)             3.7                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L
Chloride (Stat Lab)              102                       (100-108)      mmol/L
CO2 (Stat Lab)                   28.6                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L
BUN (Stat Lab)                   12                        (8-25)         mg/dl
Creatinine (Stat Lab)            0.7                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl
Glucose (Stat Lab)               164              H        (70-110)       mg/dl

Calcium                          9.2                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       3.5                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        1.3              L        (1.4-2.0)      meq/L
Total Protein                    7.8                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl
Albumin                          4.1                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl
Globulin                         3.7                       (2.6-4.1)      g/dl
Direct Bilirubin                 0.1                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl
Total Bilirubin                  0.5                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl
Alkaline Phosphatase             129              H        (30-100)       U/L
Transaminase-SGPT                32               H        (7-30)         U/L
Amylase                          24                        (3-100)        units/L
Lipase                           1.7                       (1.3-6.0)      U/dl
Transaminase-SGOT                34               H        (9-32)         U/L

D-Dimer (ELISA)                  818              H        (<500)         ng/ml

Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)
Troponin-I                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

   Hematology:  
WBC                              5.2                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              34.8             L        (36.0-46.0)    %
HGB                              12.7                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl
RBC                              4.20                      (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm
PLT                              213                       (150-350)      th/cumm
MCV                              83                        (80-100)       fl
MCH                              30.2                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc
MCHC                             36.5                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl
RDW                              13.0                      (11.5-14.5)    %
Poly                             44                        (40-70)        %
Bands                            26               H        (0-10)         %
Lymphs                           20               L        (22-44)        %
Monos                            10                        (4-11)         %
EOS                              0                         (0-8)          %
Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %
Absolute Neuts                   2.29                      (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm
Absolute Bands                   1.35                                     th/cmm
Absolute Lymphs                  1.04                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm
Absolute Monos                   0.52             H        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm
Absolute EOS                     0.00             L        (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm
Absolute Basos                   0.00                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm
Aniso                            None                      (None)
Hypo                             None                      (None)
Macrocytes                       None                      (None)
Microcytes                       None                      (None)

  U/A
UA-Specific Gravity              1.015                     (1.001-1.035)
UA-pH                            5.0                       (5.0-9.0)
UA-WBC Screen                    NEGATIVE                  (NEG)
UA-Nitrite                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)
UA-Albumin                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)
UA-Glucose                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)
UA-Ketones                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)
UA-Occult Blood                  2+                        (NEG)
UA-SED-RBC                       3-5                       (0-2)          /hpf
UA-SED-WBC                       0-2                       (0-2)          /hpf
UA-SED-Bacteria                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)          /hpf
Hyaline Cast                     0-2                       (0-5)          /lpf
Squamous Cells                   NEGATIVE                  (NEG)          /hpf

   Radiology:  
CXR: neg

   Adenosine Stress Test 11/78 
The ECG response to pharmacological stress was  nondiagnostic for
 ischemia. The myocardial scans are within normal limits and do not
 demonstrate evidence of myocardial ischemia or infarction.

   Echo 11/78:
MITRAL VALVE
There is systolic anterior
motion (SAM) of the chordal apparatus which is a normal variant.  mild MR.
mild AI. EF is 67 %. mild TI. RVSP is 43 mmHg.

   EKG: 
sinus at 81 bpm, no ST changes, biphasic Ts in V1/V2?, qs in III, AV2

ASSESSMENT & PLAN
53 y/o female with CHF/diastolic dysfunction, HTN who presents with 2 day history of chest pain concerning for ACS.

Chest pain-concerning for ACS given symptoms. Does have HTN, HL, past smoking hx.
R/o MI with CE
Cont on telemetry
Cont metoprolol and titrate as BP/HR permits
Stress test given history
On ASA, BB, lipitor
PE CT poor study but negative
EtOH use-interested in quitting
Cont folate, thiamine, vitamins
Watch for signs of withdrawal
Ativan PRN, switch to standing if needs to take it
Mild transaminitis
Likely from EtOH, or passive congestion
If pain worsens, consider RUQ US
F/u hepatitis serologies
Is on Lipitor 40mg QD will leave her on this for now given CP
Anemia
F/u iron studies
Stool guiac
Depression
Restarted prozac
Prophylaxis
Nexium
Fragmin
Code
Full

__________________________________
Quintina Golden, MD 88097




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-02-21

 Follow-up

Reports episode of N/V/D 3 weeks ago.  Has had persistant RLQ pain that migrates somewhat x 3 weeks.  No BRBPR or change in bowel habits.  No vaginal bleeding.  Appetite normal currently.  no fevers/chills.

Problems
Peptic ulcer disease  : positive h pylori 
On prilosec w/good effect

Hypertension   
Recently we dropped back on Atenolol to 50 and d/c'ed HCTZ.  BP a little elevated today at 140.  Will need to reconsider regimen
Lasix 40, Lisino 40, atenolol 50

Menopause   
stable, no vaginal bleeding

Obesity   
Has not tried any methods of weight loss recently.  He appetite has increased lately and she attributes it to not drinking as much ETOH.
Requests referral to weight center today. Faxed

Depression   + ETOH dependence
Still seeing therapy and psychpharm
Symptoms improved from when I saw her last but has had a lot of deaths and illness in her family/friends recently. Finds that she is thinking about death (in these loved ones) but denies SI.  She is taking Prozac 40 and Remeron 7.5

Knee pain   
L knee OA.  Not doing PT or wearing brace as per Dr. Tillman.  Missed appt on 2/08 2/10 going to a funeral.  Will reschedule.  Still suspect weight loss to be most important factor.

Hyperlipidemia   
HDL low
On lipitor
May need to consider niacin

Congestive heart failure   
Some SOB while walking, but no orthopnea or PND.
On Lasix BB ACEi

Shoulder pain
Did not follow-up with PT, but sxs improving.


Medications
ATENOLOL 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  
Enteric Coated Asa (BABY) (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated (CHILDRENS)) 81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  
Fluoxetine Hcl 40 MG (20MG TABLET take 2) PO QD x 30 days, Take 2 caps daily 
IBUPROFEN 600 MG (600MG TABLET take 1) PO Q6H PRN pain  
Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS  
MIRTAZAPINE 7.5MG --15 MG (15MG TABLET ) PO QHS x 30 days, Take 1/2--1 tab at bedtime for sleep 
Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 TAB PO QD  
Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 20 MG (20MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO QD  
Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 30 days 

Allergies
NKA   

Results
10/06/2081 ALT/SGPT 49,  AST/SGOT 37,  ALKP 138 (H),  TBILI 0.6,  CBILI 0.00,  IBILI 0.9

10/06/2081 CHOL 148,  TRIG 156 (H),  HDL 32 (L),  LDL 85,  CHOL/HDL 4.63

Physical Exam

BP 142/84 P 78 T 98.2 WT 206.5 Ht 50 ''
GEN: well appearing, well groomed woman who appears her stated age
CV: RRR , JVP 5-6cm
Lungs: CTA
Abd: +BS, TTP (no rebound or guarding) in RLQ.  No HSM or other masses
LE: no edema, no rashes


Assessment and Plan

Lori is a 54 yo woman with multiple medical problems, but most recently her depression has been the most significant.

1. Abd pain: ?GI (colitis, phelgmon, etc)  v. GYN in origin (ovarian). Check labs and CT scan.  Will call if sxs worsen at all.

2. Depression: 
con't to follow-up with psych providers
con't Prozac and remeron

3. HTN: con't current regimen but may need to again increase atenolol or add back HCTZ

4. Knee pain: referral to Dr. Tillman, encourage weight loss

5. Obesity: WT center referral


Health Maint
Malignancy
Colon: Colo in 2079 w/ benign polyp-  F/u 2089
Breast: Mammo 1/2082 - Birads 1
Cervix: failed pap at last CPE, to repeat in 1 month

Vasc:
HDL low, considering 2nd agent
ASA daily
ETT in 2081 WNL
HF: no signs of failure.




Pt. seen/examined with Dr. Oakley.  I agree with A/P as per her note above.

_____________________________________________
Michael Queen, M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>