<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2149-06-08

**The source of this note is the RCH Emergency Dept. Information System. All updates should originate in EDIS.**

Redbud Community Hospital

Emergency Department Record - Observation Unit



EDIS Note Status:  Signed



Patient: JACKS, YASSEEN             MRN: 8841350        DOB:  8/15/2066     Sex: M

Registration Date/Time: 6/08/2149 2:09:00 AM





ED OBS Note





Admission Note

Time Patient Seen

4:18

Chief Complaint

DELTA MS / HYPERTENSION

HPI

82 y.o M w hx HTN, hyperthyroidism, baseline mild dementia p/w change in mental status.  Per pt. son he was unable  to recognize  his wife and wanted to get out of the house, he was agitated but non combative, episode lasted for about 1 hr.  Denies any f/c, no HA, No CP/palpitations, no speech difficulty, no neuromotor deficit, no numbness/ tingling of extremities.

PFSHx/ROS

Past Medical History: See HPI--. Family History non-contributory. Social History: non smoker quit 10 y.o

Allergy

NKA



ROS

Constitutional

(-)Major weight gain. (-)Fatigue. (-)Fever. (-)Chills.

Head/Eyes

(-)Headache. (-)Vision changes.

ENT/Neck

No signficiant findings.

Chest/Respiratory

(-)Shortness of breath. (-)Wheezing. (-)Dyspnea on exertion. (-)Cough.

Cardiovascular

(-)Leg swelling.

GI/Abdominal

(-)Vomiting. (-)Diarrhea.

GU/Flank/CVA/Pelvic

No signficiant findings.

Musculoskeletal/Extr/Back

No signficiant findings.

Skin

No signficiant findings.

Neuro

(-)Paresthesias. (-)Weakness.

Psych

Dementia that began ~ 1 year ago.

Heme/Lymph/Imm

No signficiant findings.

Endo

Hyperthyroidism.



ROS and PFSHx as noted above and in the ED record for this encounter.

All other systems otherwise negative.



PE

Constitutional

Patient is awake. Patient is alert. Patient is oriented x3. Patient is not lethargic.

Head/Eyes

Normal cephalic atramatic. Pupils are equal and reactive to light. Extraocular muscles are intact. Sclera are anicteric.

ENT

Airway Intact. Mucus membranes are moist. Tongue is midline.

Neck

Neck is supple. Full range of motion is present. Neck is non tender.  Carotid bruits are absent.

Chest/Respiratory

The lungs are clear to auscultation bilaterally. Rales are not present.

Cardiovascular

Normal heart sounds are present. Heart is regular rate and rhythm. No murmur is present.

GI/Abdomen

Abdomen is nontender and nondistended. Abdomen is soft. Bowel sounds are present.

Genitourinary

Costovertebral angle tenderness is present.

Musculoskeletal

Patient has normal range of motion. Patient has normal muscle bulk and tone. There is no tremor. There is no muscle rigidity.

Skin

Skin is intact. There is no rash. There are no lesions.

Neurologic

No focal deficit. Patient is alert and oriented x 3. Cranial nerve testing is intact. Motor strength testing is intact.

Psychiatric

Patient is non delusional. Patient is not anxious.

Heme/Lymph/Immun/Endocrine

Patient does not have lymphadenopathy.



Testing Results

EKG

EKG-->SB 50's

X-ray Interpretation

Head CT: neg.

CXR neg

Medical Decision Making/Plan

82 y.o M w hx in HPI p/w mental status change and elevated  BP.  Plan:

Monitor BP

Tele monitoring

Monitor mental status.



This note has been electronically signed by YVONNE WELCH, NP 6/08/2149 6:58:35 AM







Clinical staff documenting in the ED note include:



Attending/Nurse Practitioners(s)



YVONNE WELCH, NP

Attending Note

Attending MD Notes

I have examined the patient and discussed with the Nurse Practitioner the patient's care and agree with the plan.  Pt had episode of delerious speaking (full sentences, non-focal otherwise and was able to take a walk to calm down, has had similar before) and this self-resolved.  In ED, charming and without sx.  However, noted BP elevated.  Exam normal.  Plan:  obs o/n, reduce BP, and have patient f/u Monday for recheck to ensure it is not getting up again.



This note has been electronically signed by Xavier Uber, MD 6/08/2149 10:11:32 AM







Clinical staff documenting in the ED note include:



Attending/Nurse Practitioners(s)



Xavier Uber, MD



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2150-02-09


Educare-Fargo B Intern Admission Note


Patient: JACKS, Yasseen
MR #: 8841350
Admit Date: 2/09/50
Location: West 208
Attending: Dodge
PCP: Dr. Giovanni Gabriel (KEKELA / Keystone Heights)
Source: Patient, chart, ED pass-off
Code status: Full (presumed)
Contact: Son: Ursula 543-846-9534


CC: hypotension/unresponsiveness, cough


HPI: Mr. Jacks is an Indonesian 83M w/ HTN, dementia, OA and severe central canal stenosis (recent RCH admission 1/23 - 2/03/50 for associated LUE weakness), significant smoking history, RUL nodule (since &#8217;42), and h/o bronchiectasis, who presents from his nursing home w/ reported episode of hypotension and unresponsiveness on 2/08 around lunchtime.  Per notes, the pt was found to be unresponsive briefly after lunch, BP was checked and found to be in the 80&#8217;s systolic, EMS was activated and an IV was placed.  He quickly became responsive without intervention, and BP came up to the 80s/90s.  Per notes, no reported CP, abdominal pain, HA, LH, focal neurological symptoms, SOB, palpitations.  Of note, the pt was recently hospitalized at RCH 1/23 &#8211; 2/03/50 during which time he had labile BP&#8217;s including HTN as well as question of orthostasis, and was discharged on Hydralazine, HCTZ, Lisinopril, and Labetalol, after having taken only Atenolol and Terazosin on admission.  At rehab on 2/05 (3days PTA), his meds were changed to Atenolol, Terazosin, HCTZ, and Lisinopril.


In the ED, the pt&#8217;s vitals were T 96.4, HR 63, BP 98/53, RR 20, 95% on RA.  Labs sig for Na 129 (up to 131 after NS), Cr 1.58 (baseline 1.0 to 1.1 but recently 1.4 to 1.6), WBC 9.2 up to 15.6 (83% PMN) during time in the ED, Hct from 38.3 to 32.6 (MCV 85) in ED after fluids (guaiac negative), Head CT negative, CXR w/ slightly more prominent bibasilar L &gt; R opacities.  He also c/o cough while in the ED, w/ no other symptoms, w/ report of some rhonchorous breath sounds.  Two sets of blood cultures were drawn, he was given IVF (NS) at 120cc/hr, and he started on Vancomycin and Cefepime for presumed PNA.


On the floor, the pt complains of cough, mildly productive, but no fevers/chills, SOB, DOE, CP, hemoptysis, or any other sx, but is somewhat of a poor historian.  Of note, pt had recent chest CT (I+) on 1/27/50 to evaluate known RUL nodule, which showed likely aspiration PNA w/ multifocal dependent consolidation.  Pt initially was given 2days of Levofloxacin, but per Discharge Summary pt was not clinically behaving as if he had PNA, so Abx were stopped.


PMH / PSH:
-HTN (recent med adjustments as above)
-Osteoarthritis w/ severe central canal stenosis, recent admission 1/50 w/ LUE weakness/ataxia, followed by NSG/Neuro, currently working w/ PT, in neck collar currently
-RUL nodule first seen 2142, recent CT I+ on 1/27/50 showed 
-Left Thyroid nodule (1.7cm) noted on CT, unclear h/o any workup
-BPH
-Bronchiectasis in lingula, h/o remote ?thoracotomy as child
-Chronic cough
-Chronic mild thrombocytopenia




Meds at Home: 
  1. Acetaminophen (Tylenol  )  325-650 MG PO Q4H prn
  2. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin )  81 MG PO QD
  3. Atenolol  50 MG PO QD
  4. Cyanocobalamin (Vitamin B12)   1000 MCG PO QD
  5. Docusate Sodium (Colace )  100 MG PO BID
  6. Hydrochlorothiazide  25 MG PO QD
  7. Ipratropium Nebulizer (Atrovent Nebulizer )  0.5 MG NEB Q2H prn
  8. Lisinopril  40 MG PO QD
  9. Memantine (Namenda)   10 MG PO BID
10. Methimazole  5 MG PO QD
11. Miconazole Nitrate 2% Powder  1 APPLICATION TOP TID prn
12. Multivitamins  1 TAB PO QD
13. Omeprazole (Prilosec )  20 MG PO BID
14. Polyethylene Glycol  (Miralax )  17 GM PO QD prn
15. Simvastatin  80 MG PO QD
16. Terazosin Hcl  10 MG PO QHS
17. Trazodone  25 MG PO QHS prn anxiety,insomnia,agitation
      
All: NKDA


SH: Currently living at Lew Healthcare Clinic; normally lives w/ wife in apartment. Retired Plasterer .  Significant smoking history but none currently.  No EtOH or illicits.


FH:  NC


ROS:  As in HPI; poor historian.  Additionally:
Denies fevers/chills, diaphoresis
Denies HA, vision changes, weakness
Denies CP, chest pressure, palpitations, orthopnea, PND, LH
Denies SOB, wheeze, DOE
Denies n/v/d, constipation, melena, hematochezia
Denies dysuria, frequency, hematuria
Denies recent travel  


Exam: 
T  98.6
HR  70
BP 140/67
RR 18
O2 95% RA
Gen:  NAD, alert, conversant, pleasant, wearing neck collar
HEENT: NC/AT, PERRL, nonicteric. EOMI.  MM dry, w/o exudates.
Neck:  Supple, NT, full ROM, 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no LAD. JVP 7cm.
Pulm:  Decreased BS bilaterally, faint bibasilar crackles, no wheezes
Cor:  RRR, normal S1 S2, no m/r/g appreciated
Abd:  Soft, non-distended, non-tender, BS+, no HSM, guaiac neg in ED
Extr:  No LE edema, 2+ DP's bilaterally
Neuro: AOx~2 (&#8220;March 2150&#8221;, knew we were in &#8220;hospital&#8221;), CN II through XII intact, motor and sensory nonfocal (LUE strength WNL), DTR's 2+ and symmetric, no meningismus or photophobia


Labs/Rads:  


08-Feb-2150 15:38
Plasma Sodium                    129              L        (135-145)      mmol/L
Plasma Potassium                 3.7                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L
Plasma Chloride                  86               L        (100-108)      mmol/L
Plasma Carbon Dioxide            35.9             H        (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L
Calcium                          8.8                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       3.7                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        2.1              H        (1.4-2.0)      meq/L
Plasma Urea Nitrogen             51               H        (8-25)         mg/dl
Plasma Creatinine                1.58             H        (0.60-1.50)   mg/dl
eGFR                             45                                       mL/min/1.73m2     
Plasma Glucose                   125              H        (70-110)       mg/dl


Cardiac enzymes negative x 1


WBC                              9.2                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              38.3             L        (41.0-53.0)    %
HGB                              13.7                      (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl
RBC                              4.42             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm
PLT                              184                       (150-400)      th/cumm
MCV                              87                        (80-100)       fl
MCH                              30.9                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc
MCHC                             35.7                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl
RDW                              12.5                      (11.5-14.5)    %
DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED
Diff Method                      Auto
Poly                             78               H        (40-70)        %
Lymphs                           19               L        (22-44)        %
Monos                            2                L        (4-11)         %
EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %
Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %
Absolute Neuts                   7.20                      (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm
Absolute Lymphs                  1.73                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm
Absolute Monos                   0.19             L        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm
Absolute EOS                     0.07             L        (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm
Absolute Basos                   0.02                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm
Aniso                            None                      (None)
Hypo                             None                      (None)
Macrocytes                       None                      (None)
Microcytes                       None                      (None)


Blood cultures negative x 2


CXR 2/08:
     IMPRESSION:
     Slightly more prominent opacities at the left base


CT Brain 2/08:
     IMPRESSION:
     No acute infarct, acute parenchymal abnormality, extra-axial fluid
     collection, midline shift, mass effect, or hemorrhage is seen.
     
     Nonspecific white matter foci, likely representing chronic small
     vessel ischemic changes, and mild generalized volume loss.
     
     Unchanged anterior nasal septal defect, anterior subluxation of
     the left TMJ, and marked degenerative changes of the C1/C2
     articulation.




Chest CT I+ 1/27/50:
     IMPRESSION:
     Multifocal dependent consolidation, suggesting aspiration
     pneumonia.
     
     New small left pleural effusion.
     
     Enlarged prevascular lymph node and increase in size of
     prevascular lymph nodes.
     
     Central left peribronchial thickening, most likely represent
     secretions and/or reactive lymphoid tissues.  Follow-up chest CT
     in six weeks for resolution.
     
     New trace pericardial effusion.
     
     Thyroid nodule.




EKG:  NSR at 75bpm, Q&#8217;s in III and AVF, left axis
___________________________________________________________________________


Impression/Plan:


83M w/ HTN, dementia, OA and central canal stenosis, smoking history, stable RUL nodule, h/o bronchiectasis, recent imaging suggestive of aspiration PNA, and recent BP med changes, who presents w/ hypotension and brief unresponsiveness at rehab per note.  Here w/ WBC elevation, cough mildly productive, no fevers/chills/myalgias or concern for influenza, but concern for PNA, especially aspiration PNA given prior CT findings, CXR w/ increased L opacity.  Will need to exonerate urine and blood as well; no meningismus on exam.  In terms of the hypotensive episode, likely in setting of mild hypovolemia plus several new BP meds from recent discharge, plus further titration at rehab in preceding few days.  Mildly dry on exam, w/ likely hypovolemic hypoNa but will follow. Hct drop since arrival, will re-check, possibly dilutional, guaiac negative.


** Infection / PNA
--obtain sputum sample
--Vanco and Cefepime given cough and WBC elev, presumed HAP (possibly aspiration)
--obtain U/A since none obtained in ED
--f/u blood ctx x 2


** Hypotension on arrival
--infectious workup / treatment as above
--will only give Labetalol and Hydralazine for now (holding ACEi, HCTZ given mild renal failure above prior baseline), add back Terazosin as necessary
--gentle IVF overnight, re-check a.m. lytes (likely mild hypovolemic hyponatremia) and orthostatics after volume challenge


** Anemia
--guaiac negative in ED, will guaiac all stools, type and cross
--f/u rpt Hct, consider iron studies, retic, etc.


** Renal failure
--at same Cr as last week&#8217;s admission, but up from his baseline; BUN/Cr ratio appears c/w pre-renal picture, will check urine lytes, assess response to IVF


** FEN
--Regular no salt added diet w/ Aspiration precautions; gentle IVF as above
--S+S consult


** Ppx / Other
--heparin sc, PPI, bowel regimen
--Full code for now, re-assess w/ son tomorrow








_______________________________
Howard G. Xiong, MD
PGY-1
Pager #17730



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2150-06-01



KEYSTONE HEIGHTS HEALTH CENTER
REDBUD COMMUNITY HOSPITAL

Major Problems


Hypertension
BP on arrival by LPN 158/110 (lls) - though accuracy of measurement questioned by LPN. BP 140/90 by me x 2 10 and 15 min later during visit - lls. Cont labetalol 200 mg 2 tid and lisinopril 20 mg daily as well as furosemide 20 mg daily. No ha's, chest pain, dyspnea, PND or thopnia. No change in ble edema (1+/pitting). No acute distress, vital signs as noted, no jvd. Course breath sounds (L) base though no signs of consilidation. Nl pmi, rrr, nl s1 and s2. 2/6 sem at base w/o radiation. No rubs, gallops, clicks. Abd: soft, nt (+) bs no masses or hsm. 1+ pitting ble edema to distal tibiae bilaterally.      Imp: bordeline BP though technically at goal (less than 140/90) if not optimal (less than 120/80). Follow w/o any changes for now.

Osteoarthritis
C/o 2 wks of ble pain/lbp. Symptoms improved when bending forward. No spinal tenderness or si tenderness. Ble strength 5/5, dtrs 2+/=. (-) slr bilaterally. Toes downgoing. Nl gait.      Imp: symptoms and exam most c/w lumbar spinal stenosis from known djd (also has known cervical djd/spinal stenosis). We reviewed relatively benign nature of this dx however not much to offer other than pt and, if symptoms sever enough, surgey. Prefers to follow conservatively - advised using his walker and can refer to podiatry for "reverse orthodics" to try to help aleviate symptoms.

Acute renal failure, HISTORY OF


Spinal stenosis
4/13/50 neck ct at RCH showed stable 10 mm thickening posterior to the odontoid process resulting in severe canal stenosis w/ spinal cord compression however pt asymptomatic/stable. Has been seen by neurosurgery w/ advise to cont following conservatively and use cervical collar when ambulating due to risk of injury if he should fall. Reviewed findings and poc w/ pt. Accompanied by wife and son, ursula. All are in agreeement here.

Edema
No real change in 1+ ble edema on furosemide 20 mg daily. Checking bmp today and will increase furosemide to 40 mg daily/f/u in 1 mo.

Other Problems


Health maintenance
Has 12/10/50 cpe appt w/ me. Advised to come fasting to this appt.

Changes to Medications this visitfurosemide 40 mg   1 daily (QTY:30 Refills:5) 

Physical Exam
Blood pressure 140/90  Left sitting large cuff. 
Pulse 80  
Weight 198  

Pt education given on
	
  Medication use and/or side effects; med list review; diagnostic impression; test interpretation; treatment plan; reasons to call provider; provider coverage information; health maintenance issues; written med list/instructions given. 

Giovanni Gabriel, MD
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2152-06-26



 
Team 4 admission note


Admission Date/Time: June 26, 2152 at 7:30PM
Patient Name: Yasseen Jacks
MRN#: 8841350
Attending: Uriel Mays MD
Code status: DNR/DNI per discussion with son
Historian: medical record, patient's son Ursula Jacks


Chief Complaint: agitation


HPI: 
Mr. Jacks is an Indonesian-speaking 85M with a history of dementia, lung nodule, CHF who presents with progressively worsening agitation at home.  As patient is currently very somnolent this history is based on phone interview with Ursula Jacks who is the HCP and is very involved with his father's care.  The patient was diagnosed with dementia by his PCP about 3 years ago and has been relatively stable living at home (on 2nd floor) in Keystone Heights with his wife who has been his primary caretaker; their two sons are very involved as well.  Over the last 6 months they have noticed increasing confusion, agitation, and labile emotions.  They noted he has been confused about location, time (recalls distant past but not recent past), and has occasionally not been able to identify his wife.  He has become emotionally labile and sometimes agitated.  His son notes that he recently had to physically force him to sit down and take his medications.  His wife has had to stay up at night to watch the patient to make sure he did not wander.  They are particularly worried about his ability to take the flight of stairs to their home since it takes him about 15 min to get up and appears unsteady. About 1 wk ago, while his wife was out of their home, he wandered out and locked himself out; when she returned he angrily accused her of locking him out.  Their mother has had increasing difficulty caring for him and has called the 2 sons for help daily for the past week.  They called his PCP about these accelerating changes and he was started on lorazepam 0.5-1mg Q4h prn which brought mild improvement.  Out of concern for his father's and mother's safety they brought him to the ED for evaluation and placement which their PCP has already begun to discuss with them.


They have not noticed fever/chills, nausea/vomiting, diarrhea/constipation (on aggressive regimen), complaints of pain, vision changes.  They have noticed recent urinary incontinence in the last few days.  


In the ED:  VS were T: 98.2    P: 71    BP: 169/84    RR: 18    SaO2: 93% RA.  Exam was notable only for rales bilaterally and mild-moderate agitation. CXR was normal. CBC was at baseline.  UA pending. CT brain could not be performed due to agitation.  They spoke to his PCP who felt this was all due to progression of his dementia.  He was given ativan 2mg IV (total) and haldol 5mg IV (total).  Also got labetalol PO 200mg PO x 1.  




Past Medical History: 


Diabetes mellitus (adult onset): diet-controlled. 

Hyperlipidemia

Thyroid nodule: stable for years, on methimazole

Anemia

Benign essential hypertension

Congestive heart failure

Dementia

Lung Nodule: increase in size of lung nodule when CT repeated in Feb (suspicious for BAC) Son Ursula spoke to Dr. Daniel (per son's report) and they discussed observing and not being aggressive with surgery etc as even though it could be cancer, an invasive operation, considering his multiple other problems, could be much worse for him than simple observation. They have an appt with Dr. Daniel in September.








Fall in 2150 with DISH




Medications: reviewed with patient's son over phone
  1. Acetaminophen (Tylenol )  325-650 MG PO Q4H prn  2. Aspirin Enteric Coated (Enteric Coated Aspirin)  81 MG PO QD  3. Cyanocobalamin  1000 MCG PO QD  4. Docusate Sodium  100 MG PO BID  5. Furosemide  60 MG PO QD  6. Kcl Slow Release Tab (K-Dur)  10 MEQ PO QD  7. Labetalol Hcl  200 MG PO BID  8. Lisinopril  40 MG PO QD  9. Lorazepam  0.5-1 mg PO Q4H 10. Memantine  10 MG PO BID 11. Methimazole  5 MG PO QD 12. Multivitamins  1 TAB PO QD 13. Omeprazole  20 MG PO QD 14. Polyethylene Glycol   17 GM PO QD prn Constipation   15. Sennosides (Senna Tablets)  2 TAB PO BID 16. Simvastatin  80 MG PO QD

Allergies: 
AMOXICILLIN/CLAV.ACID 875/125 - reaction: diarrhea







Family History: 
Father had dementia in early 70s.  
Mother had breast cancer. 



Social History: 
Lives with wife in KH.  Sons are very involved.  can get around -but sits at home and does not do muchit is getting harder and harder for him to be at home - his wife is having a harder time caring for him.







Prior smoker - remote 20y ago. 
No etoh. 




Review of Systems: Otherwise negative x 10 systems. 


Physical Examination
Vital Signs: T 96.5F, HR 70, BP 177/84, RR 16, O2sat 93% on RA
General Appearance: elderly somnolent, but arousable and intermittently gives his name. 

HEENT: NC/AT, PERRLA, OP clear with slightly dry mucous membranes but with mouth open. 
Skin: 
No rashes, no petechia. Large scar  on back which son states is from unknown childhood surgery
Neck: Supple, unable to assess JVD
Lymphatics: No palpable cervical LAN
Chest: CTAB
Heart: RRR, normal S1/S2 tones, no M/G/R
Abdomen: 
soft, nontender, nondistended, normal bowel sounds. 
Extremities: warm, no c/c/e
Neuro: somnolent, arousable, moving all extremities.  


Diagnostic Studies: 
06/26/2152 NA 142,  K 3.3 (L),  CL 101,  CO2 32.4 (H),  BUN 14,  CRE 1.16,  EGFR &gt;60 [1],  GLU 118 (H)06/26/2152 ANION 9
06/26/2152 PHOS 2.2 (L),  MG 1.6,  TBILI 0.4,  DBILI 0.1,  TP 6.9,  ALB 4.0,  GLOB 2.906/26/2152 AMY 66,  LIPS 26
06/26/2152 ALT/SGPT 17,  AST/SGOT 19,  ALKP 99,  TBILI 0.4,  DBILI 0.106/26/2152 NT-BNP 688 [1]06/23/2152 LDLDIR PEND
06/23/2152 B12 1036,  FOLATE &gt;20.0 (H)
06/23/2152 TSH 2.78 [1]06/23/2152 HGBA1C PEND,  MEAN-GLU PEND
06/26/2152 WBC 7.6,  RBC 4.04 (L),  HGB 11.7 (L),  HCT 35.1 (L),  MCV 87,  MCH 29.0,  MCHC 33.3,  PLT 130 (L)06/26/2152 RDW 14.006/26/2152 METHOD Auto,  %NEUT 57,  %LYMPH 36,  %MONO 4,  %EOS 2,  %BASO 106/26/2152 PT 12.9,  PT-INR 1.1
06/26/2152 UA-COLOR Yellow,  UA-APP Clear,  UA-GLUC Negative,  UA-BILI Negative,  UA-KET Negative,  UR-SPGR 1.010 [1],  UA-BLD Negative,  UA-PH 6.506/26/2152 UA-PROT Negative,  UA-UROBI Negative,  UA-NIT Negative,  UA-WBC Negative
06/23/2152 IGG 867,  IGA 306,  IGM 174,  SPEP PEND


Radiology
06/26/2152 16:40 RCH RadiologyStudy Name CTBrW/OCAccession # 56286274Status Scheduled


06/26/2152 15:22 RCH RadiologyStudy Name Chest 2 ViewsAccession # 85765721Status Final


Exam Number:  85765721                        Report Status:  FinalType:  Chest 2 Views     IMPRESSION:      No evidence of pneumonia or pulmonary edema.
 
EKG: rate 70,. sinus with PAC, normal axis, left axis, QTC 488. 




Impression/Plan: 
In summary, Mr. Jacks is an 85yo Indonesian-speaking male with a history of dementia, lung nodule, CHF who presents with progressively worsening agitation at home.  His family are unable to continue caring for him. 


# Dementia / Agitation: differential include progression of his dementia as well as NPH (given mental status change, ? gait abnormality, and new urinary incontinence).  Currently, sedated from haldol and ativan given in the ED. B12, folate are wnl.  Metabolic panel shows some mild abnormalities but unlikely to be cause of mental status changes and there is no evidence of an infectious process (UA and CXR negative, no leukocytosis) currently. 
- CT brain pending 
- haldol 2mg PO BID prn (hold for sedation) 
- consider geriatric-psychiatry consult
- PT consult when more awake
- continue memantine
- holding lorazepam for now



# HTN: replacing labetalol with metoprolol 50mg TID and will titrate.  Continue lisinopril.  May need to give IV medications while sedated if BP continues to rise. Continue ASA. 
# CHF: continue lasix. 
# Hyperlipidemia; continue simvastatin
# Constipation: contiue home regimen: docusate, senna, miralax prn
# GERD: continue omeprazole
# B12 dificiency: continue B12, level is wnl. 

# Lung nodule: Noted to be increasing on f/u CXR.  PCP and family have elected to not pursue further surgical workup. 
# THyroid nodule: continue methimazole, TSH is wnl. 
# Pain: continue tylenol prn

# FEN: low salt, low cholesterol diet. continue MVI, Kcl
# Prophylaxis: GI: continue omeprazole; DVT: fragmin; Bowel: home regimen
# Disposition: pending placement
# Code Status: DNR/DNI per discussion with son


&gt; 70 min spent on pt mgmnt incl H/P, orders, notes with &gt; 50% time talking to patient, RN, and his son (Ursula Jacks) about plan and options.




________________________________
Uriel Mays MD (pgr 23190)
Team 4, Internal Medicine





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="not met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>