<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2083-10-06




VIGIL, ANTHONY
40984972
10/06/2083


ATTENDING PHYSICIANS:
Joshua Root, M.D.
Bloomfield Care Center, Suite 8466
990 Westwood Dr
Bangkok, NJ  53591

Amir Naranjo, M.D.
Boys Town National
2 Kelly Street
Bangkok, NJ  53591

Joshua Hanna, M.D.
Ashley County Medical Center
61 Meadowview Circle
Oneonta, NJ  19723

IDENTIFICATION:  This 65-year-old man with a 5-year history of cardiomyopathy is is admitted with worsening heart failure and recent presyncope for further evaluation.  He was diagnosed with progressive shortness of breath in 2078.  He was treated with diuretics and other medications at that time.  He did quite well until December of last year when he had a cardiac arrest and underwent ICD placement.  He has had worsening symptoms over the last year with increasing shortness of breath on flat ground and a very severe shortness of breath with stairs.  He has had some episodic nature to this.  Two days prior to admission, he had relatively rapid onset of shortness of breath while trying to play pool.  This recurred several times associated with diaphoresis.  He had no palpitations at that time.  He has no chest discomfort.

His past medical history is significant for history of shower emboli and TIA in 2081.  He has diabetes.  He had spinal stenosis surgery in 2078.

His current medical regimen is Bumex 3, recently decreased from 12 due to worsening renal function.  He is on spironolactone described as 6.25 daily, digoxin 0.125, Toprol-XL 12.5.  He has been on carvedilol, which was changed due to dizziness.  He is on lisinopril 1.25 mg and has had great difficulty tolerating any higher dose due to dizziness.  He is on metolazone 2.5 weekly.  He takes Coumadin 7.5 mg most days.  He is on insulin and Lantus.  He has no known drug allergies.

His family history is essentially unremarkable.  Mother unknown, father had onset of angina in his 80s.  The patient lives with his wife and son and is a retired Fire Chief.  He had an 80-pack-year smoking history but quit four years ago.  He has one glass of alcohol every 1-2 weeks.

Review of systems is negative for any problems with fevers, chills, change in his bowel or bladder habits.  He has no problems with swallowing.  He has no problems with hearing or vision.  Review of systems is otherwise negative.

On physical examination, blood pressure is 84/66 in the left arm and 86/62 in the right arm.  His chest is completely clear to auscultation and percussion.  Temperature is 35.9.  His heart rate is 100 and a regular rhythm.  His cardiac exam reveals left ventricular heave, which is visible.  He has a palpable and audible third heart sound.  The right ventricular impulse is present also.  He has a systolic murmur, which is heard everywhere, not otherwise easy to characterize.  It does not change with respiration.  The second component of the second sound is slightly increased in radiation consistent with a PA systolic pressure in the range of 50-60.  His legs are cool.  Venous pattern is very prominent.  His pulses are intact peripherally.  He has no abdominal bruits.  His jugular venous pressure is 14 cm.  He has no cervical adenopathy or thyromegaly.  His liver percusses at approximately 5 cm below the costal margin.  He has some increased resonance around the umbilicus.  Laterally, there is suggestion of some fluid in the distention.  There is no peripheral edema.  His joints are without obvious deformities, although he describes arthritis in his shoulder, neck, and back.  He has no skin rashes or sores, several very small ecchymoses.  His standing blood pressure is unchanged.  He has atrially triggered ventricular pacing at 98.

ASSESSMENT:
1.  Etiology of left ventricular dysfunction is undetermined.  We do not know information of recent catheterization or echocardiography.  The degree of his mitral disease is not clear.  He clearly did not have coronary artery disease on one studied initially.  However, the episodicity is significant.
2.  Current hemodynamic status shows marked volume overload and low cardiac output, and is cold and wet pattern.  His history of recent diuretic use suggests that he may have had relatively rapid onset of fluid after his last diuretic change.  However, the episode while playing pool also raises the possibility of a ventricular tachyarrhythmia undetected.  It is also possible that this is related to angina.
3.  Other related risks.  He is on Coumadin due to his embolic shower before.  It is possible that he has had other emboli, possibly even to coronary arteries leading to recent decline in function.

There are no obvious contraindications to transplant.  At this time, we are not planning to evaluate him but to treat the urgency of his heart failure decompensation.  Our plan is to hold his beta-blockers and ACE inhibitors for now, and to begin him on an IV diuretic infusion.  We will proceed with echocardiogram and catheterization if necessary to determine whether there are other conditions exacerbating his current decompensated state.


______________________________
Patricia Cameron Izzo, MD
Cardiac Services





eScription document:2-7203595 SFFocus



DD: 10/07/83
DT: 10/07/83
DV: 10/06/83



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-12-30

Lantus and Novolog Insulin Guidelines	



1.	Check blood sugars before meals and at bedtime.  In addition, some meals you may want to check your blood sugar (blood glucose or BG) 1 hour after taking your Novolog.  If it is over 150 you may need to take more Novolog with meals or decrease your carbohydrate intake.  You do not have to do this at every meal and you can alternate meals and/or days.  For example: Sat check before and after breakfast; Friday - lunch; Thursday - supper,etc.

2.	Be careful of the amount of carbohydrates (breads, pasta, cereal, fruit, etc) you eat at each meal and between meals.  Try to average about 60 gms. per meal and 15 gms.  for snacks.

3.	The goal for your blood sugars when you get up in the morning and before meals  is 80-110, 1 hour after taking Novolog (at the start of the meal) it is less than 140, and at bedtime 100 to 140.

4.	Your insulin may need adjusting several times before those goals can be met. When exercising you may need more carbs or less Novolog with meals.  



Long-acting insulin:  Lantus (insulin glargine)

           Take _14_ units at bedtime.  

           Do not mix with any other insulin.  Lantus starts to work in about 1 hr and lasts about 

                24 hours.  It has no peak.

           If your fasting blood sugar for two or more mornings is more than 120, increase your

                Lantus by 2 units at the next dose.  If it is more than 140 for two mornings then     

                increase by 4 units at the next dose.  

            If your fasting blood sugar is less than 70 then decrease your next dose of Lantus 

                 by 2 to 4 units.



Short-acting insulin:  Novolog  

Take 16 units of novolog with breakfast, 6 units with lunch, and 10 units with supper 

   (called  "standing dose") within 15 minutes of starting eat your meals. Do not take 

   standing dose if not eating.

Novolog starts to work in 15 minutes and lasts about 2 hours. It peaks in about 1 hour.  

You need to eat enough carbs to cover this insulin or you will have a low blood sugar.  

If blood sugar is < 80 take    your standing dose or sliding scale.  If < 60 do not take standing 

     dose.

Take  Novolog sliding scale (below) in addition to standing dose Novolog at mealtime 

If Blood sugar is   125 - 150 take  2 units more

                             150 - 200 take 3 units more 

                                         201 - 250 take 4 units more  	

                                         251 - 300 take 6 units more  

 			     301 - 350 take 8  units more 

	 >351 take 10 units more and call MD if blood sugar has not 

          decreased or has increased after 2 hours.



Bedtime High Blood Sugar:  If your blood sugar at bedtime is greater than 200 take Novolog by the sliding scale below in addition to Lantus. Do not mix the two insulins.  Do not take standing dose insulin at bedtime. Have your blood sugar checked 1 to 2 hours after taking novolog at bedtime to make sure you haven't gone too low.  If you are below 80 then have a snack and juice to hold you over until morning.

                                  If bedtime blood sugar is 201 - 250 take 2 units

                                                                          251 - 300 take 3 units

                                                                          301 - 350 take 4 units







Please follow up with your endocrinologist or primary care practitioner in 1-2 weeks.  Bring this paper and your blood sugar results from the time you were discharged.  For urgent problems or questions about your blood sugar or insulin call 387-8267 and ask for the page operator.  Have beeper #68537 paged (the diabetes specialist on-call will call you back if you leave a message). You may also try my pager anytime (30568) but I am not always available.



Olive Tripp, ACNP, CDE                                                        

Dixmont State Hospital                                                                                                   

Diabetes Management Service 

                                                        



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-06-12




VIGIL, ANTHONY
40984972
06/12/2084


Joshua A. Root, M.D.
Nutfield Surgicenter
980 Westwood Dr, Suite 8466
Bangkok, NJ  53591

Dear Dr. Root:

We had the pleasure of seeing this patient today in followup of his transplant of 03/25/2084.  He is doing quite well.  There are no exertional complaints of dyspnea or chest discomfort.  He is taking his medications without problems and denies fever, cough, rash or diarrhea.

He tells me his blood pressures at home are as high as 140-160 in the morning systolic dropping to the 130 systolic in the evenings.

His current medications are unchanged and include Neoral 125 mg b.i.d., prednisone 15 mg daily, CellCept 1 g b.i.d., aspirin 325 mg daily, Bactrim double strength one tablet every other day, calcium and vitamin D one tablet b.i.d., diltiazem CD 240 mg q.a.m. and 120 q.p.m., Lantus Insulin 20 units at bedtime, magnesium gluconate 500 mg b.i.d., multivitamin daily, Neurontin 100 mg t.i.d., NovoLog insulin p.r.n., nystatin elixir 5 mL q.i.d., omeprazole 40 mg daily, Valcyte 450 mg daily, vitamin C 500 mg b.i.d., and vitamin E 400 mg b.i.d.

On exam, he looks great.  His blood pressure is 166/98 initially, 148/82 on repeat.  His heart rate is 110.  He weighs 163 pounds.  His head and neck examination is unremarkable.  His venous pressures are less than 7 cm of water.  The lungs are clear.  The cardiac exam reveals a tachycardic rhythm with no rub, murmur or gallop.  The abdomen is unremarkable.  His numerous surgical wounds are well healed.  His extremities are warm without edema.

Electrocardiography is notable for sinus tachycardia at 108 beats per minute, some nonspecific ST changes.  He underwent right heart catheterization and biopsy today.  His right atrial pressure was 5.  His wedge pressure was 17.  His PA pressures were 40/20 with a mean of 30.  The biopsy results are pending at the time of this dictation.

In summary, the patient is doing well now six weeks after cardiac transplantation.  We will be making changes to his immunosuppressive regimen as dictated by the results of his blood work and biopsy.  It is very gratifying to see how well he is doing.  We will be sure to update you on a regular basis.

Sincerely,


______________________________
Glenn V Baxter, M.D.





eScription document:2-6397786 SFFocus

CC: Amir Naranjo M.D.
Boys Town National Research Hospital
3 Kelly Street
Bangkok, NJ 53591


DD: 06/12/84
DT: 06/12/84
DV: 06/12/84



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-03-09







VIGIL, ANTHONY
40984972
03/09/2087




Amir Naranjo, M.D.
Saint Josephs Hospital Of Atlanta
4 Kelly Street
Bangkok, NJ  53591


Dear Dr. Naranjo:


We saw Anthony Vigil in the Internal Medicine at the Dixmont State Hospital on 03/09/2087.  He underwent orthotopic heart transplant at the Dixmont State Hospital on 03/30/2084 and returns now for his annual evaluation.  In the interval since last seen, he has done reasonably well.  His last annual evaluation at Lorain Community Hospital revealed an ejection fraction of 55% by echocardiography and no coronary disease, although left anterior descending was tortuous.  Filling pressures were normal, then with a wedge of 15 and a right atrial pressure of 9 while the pulmonary artery pressure was 30/19 with a mean of 25.  The patient does have a herniated disk at L4 and stenosis at L5.  He has lower extremity cramps, which potentially due to his spine disease have been markedly exacerbated by Pravachol.  The Pravachol was therefore stopped, restarted, and stopped again.  He continues to take insulin and his last hemoglobin A1c was 6.6.  He has had two recent episodes of mild hypoglycemia.  He has had no dermatologic evaluation.  He denies angina, congestive heart failure, or arrhythmias.


Physical Examination:  Reveals a weight of 183 pounds, blood pressure of 121/71, pulse of 100.  Jugular venous pressure is 8 cm of water.  Carotid upstrokes are brisk without bruits.  There are diminished breath sounds in the left lung.  Point of maximum impulse is not displaced.  First heart sound is normal, second crisp and clear.  He has an S4 at the left sternal border.  The abdomen is without hepatosplenomegaly.  There is no peripheral edema.  Peripheral pulses are diminished.


The electrocardiogram reveals a right bundle-branch block pattern with an intrinsic rate of 98 beats per minute.  There are nonspecific T-wave changes particularly in the early precordium.


Current Medications:  Calcium with D 1250 mg twice per day, Cardura 4 mg, CellCept 1000 mg twice per day, diltiazem CD 240 mg twice per day, Ecotrin 81 mg per day, Lantus insulin 26 units at night, magnesium oxide 400 mg twice per day, vitamin, cyclosporine 100 mg twice per day, Neurontin 100 mg twice per day, NovoLog insulin as needed, prednisone 5 mg per day, vitamins C 500 mg twice per day, and vitamin E 400 units twice per day.


Impression:  The patient will undergo his annual evaluation over the next 24 hours.  This will include blood work, chest x-ray, echocardiogram, metabolic exercise stress test, cardiac catheterization, coronary angiography, and endomyocardial biopsy.  We will see him after completion of these studies and review the results with him.  We will transmit the results to you as well at that time.


Sincerely,




______________________________
Michael P Rasmussen, MD










eScription document:0-4411667 IFFocus


CC: Joshua Root M.D.
Bloomfield Care Center
724 Westwood Dr
Bangkok, NJ, 53591
Fax: 
Email: 




CC: James Ingles M.D.
Lorain Community Hospital
88 Cote Avenue
Phnom Penh, NJ, 71738
Fax: 
Email: 






DD: 03/09/87
DT: 03/09/87
DV: 03/09/87



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>