<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2094-01-29





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

ROSELAND COMMUNITY HOSPITAL



Major Problems

Diabetes mellitus

Blood sugars have been good at home.  Hemoglobin A1c's have been good.  We are rechecking that again.

Hypertension

Blood pressure is okay today, 140/68.  We will need to follow this closely.  Her potassium has been up a little bit.  We will need to change around her medications to see if the Norvasc that we put her on increased her potassium.

Health maintenance

She continues to decline sigmoidoscopy and mammogram.  The patient's cyst at the left leg has been removed and is well healed at this time.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 140/68  

Weight   166 pounds

Neck   Thyroid exam is unremarkable

Nodes   No lymphadenopathy

Chest   Lungs are clear with no wheezes, rales, or rhonchi

Cor   No murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  Carotids with normal upstroke without bruits

Extrem   Clear



Disposition

Return is to see me later in the spring.  Diabetes care is up-to-date.  She has her eyes checked and feet followed closely.  We will later discuss with her any further followup about the diabetes with Nutrition.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by   Ruba  Neil   on  Mar 8, 2094     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-08-11





INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES

ROSELAND COMMUNITY HOSPITAL



Major Problems

Health maintenance

Up-to-date.  Pneumococcal vaccine given in 2093.  Declines a sigmoidoscopy or colonoscopy.

Diabetes mellitus

Blood sugars have been very good.  Here today, it is 156.  She met with Camp who discussed extensively about her diabetes.  She found it very helpful.  Diet issues reinforced.

Sebaceous cyst

Resolved.

Hypertension

Blood pressure much improved, 130/60 after increasing her medications.  This is a great improvement.  When Camp checked, her blood pressure was also considerably better at that visit, 132/70.  Having her watch her salt and also her sugar in her diet.



Active Medications



glyburide 5mg po 2 tabs bid

metformin hydrochloride 500 mg po bid

lisinopril 20 mg po qd

atenolol 100mg po qd

Ecotrin 325 mg po qd

hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg po qd

Norvasc 5mg po qd



Physical examination

Blood pressure 130/60  

Weight   171 pounds

Chest   Lungs are clear

Cor   Unremarkable

Extrem   Clear



Disposition

Return is to see me in the fall.



Note transcribed by outside service   Transcription errors may be present.



Signed electronically by Ruba M  Neil  on Aug 14, 2094     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-08-21



Neil, Ruba

Internal Medicine Associates, Suite M

Shady Rest Care Center, 4th Floor , Room 483

Arroyo Grande, KS, 19741-6273

		RE: ALAINA  ROJAS

08/21/2097

Admission Note

87 yo woman with bilat leg swelling for several weeks; now with 1 week of redness L> R.  



Problems:

Diabetes mellitus- HgB A1c7.6

Hypertension- adequate control

Hyperlipidemia

Chronic renal failure

Iron deficiency anemia





Allergies:

No known drug allergy



Medications:

vitamin d 1000 units po daily

glipizide 10 mg po bid take 30min before meals

Prandin 2 mg before each meal 2 week supply til mail order arrives

ferrous sulfate 325mg po bid

lisinopril 40 mg po daily

Norvasc 10mg po daily

metoprolol 25mg po take 3 tabs twice a day

lovastatin 10mg po qpm take with food

furosemide 20 mg po daily

Ecotrin 325 mg po daily



Family history:

She was born in Arroyo Grande.  She had five children; four of them are alive, all living in the area.  Husband died in 2080. Mother had Parkinson's disease.  Sister had breast cancer at the age of 72.



Social history:

Continues to get out to the American Senior Center, except on one day.  In the spring, she continues to get out, goes to bingo and continues to be very active.  She gets out everyday.  She is very active.  Daughters are very involved with her.  We have gone over in detail on this visit managing all of her issues.  Continues to go to the club at Dekalb three times a week.  



Review of systems:

No change in bowel habits, although she is a little bit constipated.  Urine, no hematuria or urinary tract symptoms. Cardiac: No chest pain, shortness of breath, PND, or orthopnea.  Pulmonary, no wheezes or asthma symptoms. HEENT: No ear or throat symptoms.  Allergies: No new issues with that.  Neurologic: No new issues.  Psychiatric: Very anxious about all of the medications she has to take it as she was someone, who never needed pills.  We tried to reassure her and spent the majority of this 45-minute visit on that coordinating her care.



Physical Exam:

Blood pressure: 130/82

Pulse: 57

Weight: 167 pounds

Office blood glucose fingerstick: 221 at noon

Skin: Warm and dry.  No rashes

Neck: Carotids, normal upstroke without bruits

Nodes: Lymph nodes, no lymphadenopathy

Breasts: No masses, discharge, or tenderness

Chest: Lungs are entirely clear with no wheezes, rales, or rhonchi

Cor: No murmurs, rubs, or gallops, regular rate

Abdomen: Nontender without masses

Extrem: violaceous L shin without obvious streaking; swollen without tenderness.  R shin present but not as severe



Labs: pending



Assessment and plan:

Admit for antibiotics IV



Ruba Neil, MD pager #34596



Signed electronically by  Ruba Neil, MD

Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-10-31



INTERNAL MEDICINE ASSOCIATES
ROSELAND COMMUNITY HOSPITAL

Reason for visit
	
  f/u high blood sugar

Major Problems


Diabetes mellitus
PT here with no complaints except sugar still high. She was seen 2 days ago , for ?UTI and UC was neg. SHe has been taking bactrim . She is up at night urinating  freq , denies fever, GI sx, cough, rash , joint pain. She is taking her meds. Daughter in with her.

Active Medications

Bactrim DS 160mg/800mg po bid x 7 days
Ecotrin 325 mg po daily
ferrous sulfate 325mg po bid
free text medications  qid one touch ultra lancets
furosemide 20mg po daily
glipizide 10mg po bid take 30min before a meal
lisinopril 40 mg po daily
lovastatin 10mg po qpm take with food
metoprolol 25mg,  3 tabs po bid
Norvasc 10mg po daily
Prandin 2 mg before each meal
vitamin d 1000 units po daily

Physical Exam
Blood pressure 147/78  
Pulse 54  
Weight 159 today,  154 pounds
Office blood glucose fingerstick 448  at noon after breakfast
Office O2 saturation 100%  
General appearance   Well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.
Skin   Warm and dry.  No rashes
HEENT   ? jaundice to eyes
Nodes    no  cervical lymphadenopathy
Chest   Lungs are clear
Cor   Unremarkable
Abdomen   Nontender without masses
Musc skel   no CVA tenderness

Assessment and plan
	
  A elevated sugar ? infection? source
P discuss with Dr. Armstrong to ER for complete work up. ER notifiec and pt escorted to ER&gt;

Victoria Keene, NP

Signed electronically by  Victoria Keene, NP
Document Status: Final



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-12-04

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.










Internal Medicine
Medical Student Admission Note


PATIENT: Rojas, Alaina
MRN: 7269058
ADMIT DATE: 12/04/2097
PCP: Dr. Ruba Neil, Dr. William Aquino (onc)
CONTACT: Claire Ortega (daughter, 660-750-9168)
CODE STATUS: Full
SOURCE: Previous notes


CHIEF COMPLAINT: Mechanical Fall


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:
(Patient was taken to surgery immediately upon arriving to floor)
Per PCP: Ms. Rojas is a 87-year-old woman with a PMH of metastatic pancreatic cancer recently diagnosed s/p 1 dose of gemcitabine (on 11/14), DM, HTN, and CRI who presents s/p mechanical fall at home resulting in a right hip fracture. Patient was in USOH until the day of admission when she got up out of a chair to reach for her glasses, and then went to sit back down and missed the chair and fell to the ground. Per the PCP, the patient had no presyncopal symptoms and did not lose consciousness.


ED COURSE:
T 97.8 P 56   BP: 156/59  RR: 20  97% RA
Foreshortened RLExt
Needs basal insulin 


PMH/PSH:
(1)     Pancreatic cancer
a.        10/30/2097, patient presented to PCP with dark urine and progressively increasing FBSGs (h/o DM). She was admitted for evaluation of hyperglycemia and was noted to be jaundiced with elevated LFTs. RUQ U/S showed CBD dilatation with hypoechoic mass near head of pancreas measuring 4.1x5x5.5cm
b.       11/03/2097, ERCP showed 3cm distal bile duct stricture that was stented. LFTs trended down s/p biliary stenting. Biopsy obtained under EUS guidance showed pancreatic adenocarcinoma. CT scan revealed pulmonary nodules, likely metastatic disease
c.        11/14/2097, treated with 1st dose of 25% dose gemcitabine (given CKD), course s/p chemotx c/b fatigue, rash, worsening renal function and anemia. This resolved with fluids, blood tx, and discontinuation of most of her BP medications. She was scheduled for her second dose of gemcitabine on 12/05
(2)     Diabetes mellitus
a.        Last HgbA1c = 7.2 (10/08/2097)
b.       Was maintained on Glucophage, but this was discontinued 2/2 worsening renal function
c.        Recently placed on insulin with BS&#8217;s to be kept around 200 given CA dx

HTN (TTE on 11/11 showed EF=69%, no LVH)
Chronic renal failure &#8211; baseline creatinine 1.8-2.2
h/o BCC
h/o TIA


MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:
Vitamin d 1000 units po daily
Novolin R innolet 2-6 units sc bid prn per sliding scale
Novolin N innolet 22 units sc qam
ferrous sulfate 325mg po daily
metoprolol 25mg po bid 2 tabs
furosemide 10mg po daily
Ecotrin 325 mg po daily
Home physical therapy for strengthening and ROM generally.  Additionally L shoulder ROM and strengthening for frozen shoulder.


ALLERGIES:
NKDA


SOCIAL HISTORY:
Continues to get out to the American Senior Center, except on one day. Living independently with supportive family. Three daughters and 2 sons are very involved with her.


FAMILY HISTORY:
She was born in Arroyo Grande.  She had five children; four of them are alive, all living in the area.  Husband died in 2080. Mother had Parkinson's disease.  Sister had breast cancer at the age of 72.


PHYSICAL EXAM: (Exam was deferred because patient was taken immediately to OR)
VITALS (on arrival to floor):
                TEMP: 100.3
                HR: 62
                BP: 171/59
                RR: 18
                O2SAT: 98% on RA 




LABORATORY DATA:


Chemistries
              12/04/97      12/01/97  
              00:08         20:12     


NA            130(L)        138                                                 
K             4.3           4.8                                                 
CL            98(L)         104                                                 
CO2           19.1(L)       22.8(L)                                             
BUN           60(H)         58(H)                                               
CRE           2.1(H)        2.2(H)                                              
GLU           381(H)        362(H)                                              


General Chemistries
Calcium                          8.6                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       3.3                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L


Liver Function Tests
Total Protein                    7.1                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl
Albumin                          3.6                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl
Globulin                         3.5                       (2.6-4.1)      g/dl
Total Bilirubin                  0.8                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl
Alkaline Phosphatase             84                        (30-100)       U/L
Transaminase-SGPT                15                        (7-30)         U/L
Transaminase-SGOT                19                        (9-32)         U/L


CBC:
WBC                              10.8                      (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              27.3             L        (36.0-46.0)    %
HGB                              9.5              L        (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl
RBC                              3.07             L        (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm
PLT                              351              H        (150-350)      th/cumm
MCV                              89                        (80-100)       fl
MCH                              31.0                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc
MCHC                             34.8                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl
RDW                              16.0             H        (11.5-14.5)    %
DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED
Diff Method                      Auto
Poly                             82               H        (40-70)        %
Lymphs                           10               L        (22-44)        %
Monos                            6                         (4-11)         %
EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %
Basos                            1                         (0-3)          %
Absolute Neuts                   8.92             H        (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm
Absolute Lymphs                  1.00                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm
Absolute Monos                   0.63             H        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm
Absolute EOS                     0.14                      (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm
Absolute Basos                   0.07                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm
Aniso                            1+               H        (None)
Hypo                             None                      (None)
Macrocytes                       None                      (None)
Microcytes                       None                      (None)


Coagulation Studies
Superstat PT                     12.9                      (10.3-13.2)    sec
Superstat PT-INR                 1.1
Superstat APTT                   20.6             L        (22.1-34.0)    sec


STUDIES:
Plain Films:
     FINDINGS:
     Right hip: There is a transverse transcervical fracture through
     the sphenoid.  There is lateral superior displacement of the
     distal segment.  There is no evidence of dislocation.
     
     Pelvis: There is diffuse osteopenia involving the pelvis.  Again
     noted is a transcervical fracture to the right femur.  There is
     superior lateral displacement of the distal fracture segment.  The
     sacrum is not well seen secondary to overlying bowel gas.  Minimal
     degenerative changes of the lumbar spine are noted.
     
     Shoulder: There is no evidence of left shoulder dislocation or
     acute fracture.  The visualized lung fields and ribs are intact.
     There is minimal degenerative change involving the left a.c.
     joint.
     
     Chest: Comparison to 10/31/97.  Multiple pulmonary nodules are
     noted.  There is no evidence of focal consolidation or pulmonary
     edema.  No large pleural effusion or appreciable pneumothorax is
     identified.  The cardiomediastinal silhouette is stable.
     Degenerative changes of the thoracic spine are noted.
     
     IMPRESSION:
     Right transcervical femoral fracture.  No evidence of dislocation.
     
     No evidence of shoulder dislocation.
     
     Multiple pulmonary nodules consistent with metastatic disease.
     
     FINDINGS:
     Previously noted minimally displaced right hip fracture.
     Osteoarthrosis of the knee. Soft tissues swelling along the medial
     aspect of the knee is noted.  There are vascular calcifications.
     Generalized osteopenia.
     
     IMPRESSION:
     Right hip fracture as previously described.  Osteoarthrosis of the
     knee. 
       
EKG: Sinus bradycardia.


ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN:


87yo F with h/o metastatic pancreatic CA s/p 1 dose of gemcitabine and biliary stenting, CKD, DM, and HTN who p/w right hip fracture s/p mechanical fall at home. The plan of care by issue is as follows:


(1)     Right hip fracture: Patient will require post-operative anti-coagulation. Patient is undergoing high-risk procedure and is also at increased risk for VTE given cancer dx. According to guidelines from ACCP:


#UFH 5000 Units SC TID [or LMWH &gt;3400 Units SC QD (her CrCl &lt;30, therefore renally dosed = LMWH 30mg SC QD)] to be started either in PACU or on the floor.
#Compression stockings
#Pneumo-boots
#Plan to continue VTE prophylaxis for 4-6 weeks post-op
#Encourage ambulation as soon as tolerated (per ortho, pt might be ambulatory as soon as tomorrow)


(2)     DM
Patient recently started on insulin at home. Will continue half dose of home insulin with IVF with glucose.
#RISS, until tolerating POs, then restart normal insulin.


(3)     Dispo
Plan to D/C when clinically stable post-op. Per PCP, patient would like to return directly home after surgery without rehab (home rehab). Family notes that patient currently lives at daughter&#8217;s home where there are many steps which would make home rehab difficult.


#Consider rehab placement, follow-up attending recs, discuss with family in AM












_______________________________________
Brandon Hale
EFS III, Internal Medicine
Pager #28913


ADDENDUM:
Case and plan discussed and incorporated into this excellent EFSIII Note.




_______________________________
Fred Allen, M.D.
Medicine PGY1
Pager #80817



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>