<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2132-09-28




                                                                                                      962-85-18

                                                                                                      Jain, Oliver


September 28, 2132  Endocrine/Diabetes



Present Illness:  

Asked to see this 66 year old man who was transferred to LEPROSARIUM for care of an ischemic R foot. He has had a series of illness over the spring, beginning with a hospitalization for pneumonia in June. He later developed what was thought to be a splenic subcapsular hematoma (on Coumadin for chronic atrial fibrillation) and then subsequently developed LUQ pain and was found to have a splenic abscess that was drained. In the course of this illness, he also developed an ischemic R foot and was found (at what stage?) to have a popliteal aneurysm. 



At the time of his admission, he was found to have diabetes. He has been treated with Lantus insulin, most recently 15 Units at bedtime, on which regimen he has had consistent overnight drops, often to hypoglycemic levels. He reports that he weighed about 200 pounds before this illness but has lost about 50 pounds. 



Retinopathy:   He has had an eye exam in the recent past but I do not know any details.

Nephropathy:  BUN/Cr 8/0.77

Neuropathy:    Do not get a history of peripheral neuropathy

Cardiac:           Aware of having atrial fibrillation for about 4 years. Not aware of any history of coronary artery disease.

Vascular:         ? claudication preceding this spring&#8217;s illness.



Past Medical History:  

Surgery:                       R elbow surgery

                                    Umbilical hernia repair

Medical:                      Hypertension   

                                    Hyperlipidemia

                                    Chronic atrial fibrillation

Allergies:                     No known drug allergies.

Smoking History:        None.

Alcohol History:         Occasional 6-pack for a football game



Family History:  

Father:             Also developed, or was found to have, diabetes in the context of another illness within the last decade and now takes insulin in his 80&#8217;s.



Social History: 

Lives with his wife.



Review of Systems: above

Review of systems is otherwise negative.




Physical Exam:   

Pleasant man in no distress, flat p angio.

BP:   120-140/60-80                            P:   60&#8217;s-70&#8217;s, irregularly irregular       

Wt:   about 150 by history                  Ht: about 5&#8217;9.5&#8221;

HEENT:          Anicteric. Full EOM's. 

Fundi:              Not examined

Carotids:         Normal pulses, without bruits

Chest:              Clear to auscultation anteriorly

Heart:              Normal S1; physiologic S2.  No gallops.  No murmurs

Abdomen:       No hepatosplenomegaly. No masses. Mild LUQ tenderness. Upper abdominal scar is well healed.

Extremities:     R forefoot appears gangrenous. L foot is not ischemic but no pedal pulses are palpable.            



Impressions and Plan:   


66 year old man with gangrenous R foot and evidence for PVD on L as well.

Diabetes, type 2, of uncertain duration.

A1c is being checked.

D/C Lantus.

Start NPH 10 Units qAM.

After he is through with surgical procedure, it is unlikely that he will need insulin.



Thanks.



                                                                        Oren S. Ip, M.D., Ph.D.








****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2132-11-10


November 10, 2132 




Osiel M. Colon, M.D.
McCaw Family Medicine
84 Grace Drive, Suite 046
Delano, TX 28221


RE:                  Oliver Jain
LEPROSARIUM:              962-85-18


Dear Dr. Colon:


I am writing to inform you that I am seeing Mr. Oliver Jain in followup.  Mr. Jain was admitted to my service in transfer for right lower extremity ischemia and gangrene following atheroembolization from a popliteal aneurysm, as you know.  He was admitted in early September and stayed until early October.  During his hospital stay here his wounds were addressed.  He underwent angiograms to evaluate his arterial anatomy and he underwent reconstruction of the right wherein covered stent graft was used to cover disease in his proximal femoral artery and then he underwent an above knee to below knee popliteal artery bypass using PTFE with ligation of the aneurysm.  He also subsequently underwent angioplasty of his posterior tibial artery.  Given his atheroembolic phenomenon he had very limited vasculature remaining in the foot and I was concerned that the forefoot gangrene would progress and he would wind up losing the right foot.  In the interim since his discharge he appears to be doing quite well.  The gangrene of the right foot has remained stable with clearcut demarcation of the right first, second and third toes.  He also has some heel ulceration that I am hoping to nurse through.  He denies any rest pain or pain in the foot.  He has no evidence of fevers, chills, rigors or shakes in the interim.  He has since been discharged to home and has been walking with a walking shoe.  His left lower extremity aneurysm is yet to be treated and he has not developed any symptoms with regards to the left lower extremity.  He has been taking his Coumadin regularly and has had therapeutic INRs as he reports.  


On exam today he is doing quite well.  He is in good spirits and appears much better than in the hospital.  His head and neck exams were unremarkable.  His lungs were clear.  Heart was regular.  His proximal groin and leg incisions have healed up nicely, however there is some dry eschar on the midportion of the wound.  With regards to the toes he has clearcut demarcation and heel ulceration.  There is no evidence of cellulitis, induration or infection of the right lower extremity.  He continues to have a stable looking foot on the left.  Given his extensive peripheral vascular disease I performed PVRs in the office today, which revealed that he has pulsatile PVRs at the right calf and ankle.  He also has slight pulsatile PVRs at the right transmetatarsal level.  This bodes well with regards to his revascularization as well as his potential to either heal or remain stable with regards to the necrosis on the right foot.  His left calf, ankle and transmetatarsal PVRs were similar.  


In summary, this is an unfortunate gentleman who developed atheroembolic phenomena resulting in digital ischemia as well as heel ischemia with the potential for limb loss in the near future of the right lower extremity.  He does have an untreated aneurysm on the left with potential for atheroembolization of the left lower extremity.  Given this concern, I will proceed next with a left lower extremity revascularization to exclude the popliteal aneurysm so that he does not develop limb-threatening gangrene of the left.  With regards to the right I will try to initiate some hyperbaric oxygen therapy and will probably re-evaluate his distal circulation with an angiogram at the time of his next admission or some time thereafter.  I am hoping to facilitate healing of the heel wound with the final outcome of a transmetatarsal amputation of the right lower extremity but will see how it goes.  My thanks again for this referral.  I apologize for not sending you correspondence earlier.  With this correspondence I will send you his operative diagram as well as his most recent discharge summary.


Sincerely,




Quincy T. Uselton, M.D.


Enclosure:  Operative Note, Operative Drawing, Discharge Summary 


QU/xayasane                     36-33387396.doc



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2132-11-25

Vascular Surgery Admission Note



Patient Name:  Jain, Oliver

MRN:  9628518 

Date and Time: 11/25/32 2:40PM

Attending: Dr. Uselton

Fellow: Dr. Uselton

Junior Resident: Dr. Gonzales



cc: L popliteal aneursym



HPI: Mr. Jain is a 66 year old male with a h/o DM, HTN, HL, Chronic Afib, PVD and bilateral popliteal aneurysm s/p atheroembolic event to RLE w/ resultant RLE ischemia and dry gangrene of heel, toes and forefoot.  During his prior admission in September, he underwent diagnostic angio which showed occluded R SFA, thrombosed R popliteal aneurysm and occluded R posterior tibial artery.  On 10/01, he underwent a R SFA to BK popliteal bpg w/ saphenous vein graft; revised intraoperatively w/ AK pop to BK pop BPG using 8mm PTFE and angioplasty to the R PTA.  He has been doing well since discharge in October. His dry gangrene is stable and well demarcated.  He uses a special shoe at home for walking on RLE to offset weight on his toes and heel. 



He denies recent h/o fevers/chills, N/V, abdominal pain, or neurological sx.




PMH: 

B popliteal aneursyms

DM

PVD

HTN

HL

Chronic Atrial fibrillation

PSH: 

10/01/32-R fem-BK pop w/ saphenous vein graft and 8mm PTFE

9/28/32- Diagnostic angiogram

8/2132-exploratory lap and drainage of splenic abscess

L inguinal hernia repair

R elbow surgery





Meds: 

  1. Aspirin Enteric Coated  325 MG PO QD

  2. Calcium Carbonate 1250 Mg (500 Mg Elem Ca 1 TAB PO BID 



3. Clopidogrel (Plavix )  75 MG PO QD-last dose 11/19

  4. Digoxin  0.25 MG PO QD

  5. Diltiazem  90 MG PO QID

  6. Docusate Sodium (Colace)  100 MG PO BID

  7. Hydromorphone Hcl (Dilaudid )  2-4 MG PO Q3H prn Pain  

  8. Insulin Nph Human  15 units SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST

  9. Insulin Nph Human  4 UNITS SC QHS


10. Insulin Regular Inj  5 UNIT SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST


11. Insulin Regular Inj  8 UNIT SC QPM BEFORE SUPPER


12. Lansoprazole  30 MG PO QD


13. Metoprolol Succinate Extended Release (Toprol Xl )  100 MG PO QD


14. Pravastatin  20 MG PO QD


15. Sennosides (Senna Tablets)  2 TAB PO QHS


16. Warfarin Sodium (Coumadin )  5 MG PO QPM-last dose 11/22


ALL:  oxacillin&#224;rash

Family Hx: non-contributory


Social: Lives in Hebbronville, MA with wife.

Smoking: denies

ETOH-denies





ROS: as above, otherwise: denies CP, SOB, diarrhea, blood per rectum, bleeding or clotting disorders, urinary problems.





PE: 

VS: T 
98  HR  64  BP 111/56   RR 18 97%  RA

Well appearing male, NAD

Carotid 2+ no bruits

Irregularly irregular no m/r/g 

Lungs CTAB

Abd: soft, non tender, non distended +BS. Well healed-LUQ transverse incision.

Extremities: Skin is dry bilateral feet. 

RLE: Dry gangrene of entire 1st toe 2nd and 3rd toes, tips of 4th and 5th toes and forefoot.

R heel w/ 5cm x 3cm eschar on posteriolateral surface.



Pulses: R BK-pop BPG pulse is dopplerable



     Rad    Fem   Pop   DP          PT

R     2+    2+    --    Non-dop     dop

L     2+    2+    2+    2+          2+





PVR: pulsatile at bilateral ankles



ECG: atrial fibrillation



Imaging:



CXR-pending


A/P:  66M w/ a h/o HTN, HL, PVD and Bilateral popliteal aneursyms who presents for admission prior to L femoral to BK popliteal BPG tomorrow to exclude the L pop aneurysm.  

-Admit to Vascular Surgery

-Admission Labs

-CXR/ECG

-NPO after midnight

-IVF/ &#189; dose NPH while NPO



Case discussed with Dr. Nicholas Uselton, Vascular Fellow







________________________________

Brandi Xayasane PA-C 75197

Vascular Surgery 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2133-08-25



 



















Vascular Surgery Admission Note



Patient Name:  Jain, Oliver

MRN:  9628518 

Date and Time: 8/25/33 2:40PM

Attending: Dr. Uselton

Fellow: Dr. Joshi

Resident: Dr. Ray-Gallegos

Night Float: Dr. Xayachack

PA: Brandi Xayasane, PA-C



cc: RLE graft stenosis



HPI: Mr. Jain is a 67 year old male with a h/o DM, HTN, HL, Chronic Afib, PVD and bilateral popliteal aneurysm s/p R popliteal thrombosis w/ resultant RLE ischemia and dry gangrene of heel, toes and forefoot.  He has since undergone a R SFA to BK popliteal bpg w/ saphenous vein graft and 8mm PTFE w/ angioplasty to the R PTA.  In March of this year he underwent a distal bpg from the R posterior tibial artery to the plantar artery and then a R TMA later that month. His R TMA has healed well since then. He is also s/p L fem-pop bpg to repair his L popliteal aneurysm.  



He saw Dr. Uselton in follow up last week at which time graft surveillance duplex showed normal functioning graft on the left, however on the right he appears to have a high-grade stenosis at the distal aspect of the femoral popliteal graft.  The more distal graft on the right, which is the vein graft to the plantar artery in the foot remains patent.  



He denies recent h/o fevers/chills, N/V, abdominal pain, or neurological sx. He c/o some RLE edema for the past 3 weeks. His PCP put him on a water pill but it had no effect.



He continues on coumadin for graft patentcy. His last dose was Saturday.




PMH: 

B popliteal aneursyms

DM

PVD

HTN

HL

Chronic Atrial fibrillation







PSH: 

3/15/33 open R TMA with completion R TMA on 3/21/33

3/10/33 R PT to plantar artery bpg w/ non-reversed RUE cephalic vein

1/2133: angiogram and PTA of R SFA, R distal pop bpg anastamosis and R PTA

11/25/2132 L SFA-BK pop L SFA endarterectomy and jump graft to L PTA w/ 6-mm PTFE.

10/01/32-R fem-BK pop w/ saphenous vein graft and 8mm PTFE

9/28/32- Diagnostic angiogram

8/2132-exploratory lap and drainage of splenic abscess

L inguinal hernia repair

R elbow surgery





Meds: 


  1. Clopidogrel  75 MG PO QD  2. Digoxin  0.25 MG PO QD  3. Diltiazem  90 MG PO QID  4. Docusate Sodium (Colace)  100 MG PO BID prn Constipation    5. Insulin Nph Human  15 UNITS SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST  6. Insulin Nph Human  4 UNITS SC QHS  7. Insulin Regular Inj  5 UNIT SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST  8. Insulin Regular Inj  8 UNIT SC QPM BEFORE SUPPER  9. Lansoprazole (Prevacid)  30 MG PO QD 10. Metoprolol Succinate Extended Release  100 MG PO QD 11. Pravastatin  40 MG PO QPM 12. Warfarin Sodium  5 MG PO QPM dose last taken 08/22/2133
 
ALL:  oxacillin&#224;rash





Family Hx: non-contributory





Social: Lives in Hebbronville, MA with wife.

Smoking: denies

ETOH-denies





ROS: as above, otherwise: denies CP, SOB, diarrhea, blood per rectum, bleeding or clotting disorders, urinary problems.





PE: 

VS: T 98.1   HR  61  BP L 166/103  R 160/74  RR 
97%  RA

Well appearing male, NAD

Carotid 2+ no bruits

Irregularly irregular no m/r/g 

Lungs CTAB

Abd: soft, non tender, non distended +BS. 

Extremities: Skin is dry on bilateral feet. 

RLE: well healed RLE TMA; 

2+ pitting pre-tibial edema



Pulses: R BK-pop BPG pulse is not dopplerable



     Rad    Fem   Pop   DP          PT

R     2+    2+    
--    dop    dop
L     2+    2+    
--    1+           1+




PVR: pulsatile Bilaterally 


ECG: pending



Labs: INR 1.2; cre 0.83


Imaging:



JAIN, OLIVER                        DOB:    05 Feb 2066

9628518                                 Age:    67     Sex: M

17 Aug 2133                             RefMD:  USELTON, QUINCY              



TEST TYPE: Bypass Graft Duplex



HISTORY


Diabetes: Yes



REASON FOR STUDY


Surveillance



Graft:-

Summary:   Left superficial femoral - popliteal (below knee) Bypass

Op. Date:  11/17/2132

Surgeon:   



Results:-

          Velocity  Ratio  Stenosis

          --------  -----  --------   

Inflow:    102.0

Proximal:  103.0      1.0  Normal

Mid-graft:  41.0      0.8  Normal

Distal:    133.0      6.0  Severe

Outflow:    57.0      0.4  Normal



ABI:      




SYMPTOMS



FINDINGS


The inflow (the left  mid superficial femoral artery)  is patent.  The 


proximal anastomosis is widely patent.  The proximal, mid- and distal graft is

  widely patent.  The distal anastomosis terminates in the popliteal artery 


(below the knee)  and demonstrates a significant increase in peak systolic 


velocity, correlating with 50-99% stenosis.  The distal native ( posterior 


tibial artery)  is patent.



IMPRESSION


1. Patent the left mid superficial femoral to popliteal artery (below the 


knee) BPG with &gt;50 % stenosis in the distal anastomosis


2. The mid- distal graft velocities of 41.0  - 22 cm/sec  suggest a 


compromised graft.





CXR-lungs clear, heart size upper limit of normal.





A/P:  67M w/ a h/o HTN, HL, DM, PVD and bilateral popliteal aneursyms s/p L fem-pop bpg; R popliteal thrombosis and subsequent R fem-pop bpg, R PT to plantar bpg and R TMA; presents with stenosis of the distal anastamosis of his femoral popliteal graft on the Right. He will undergo angiogram with possible angioplasty of graft stenosis.   






-Admit to Vascular Surgery-Dr. Uselton

-CXR/ECG

-NPO after midnight

-IVF/ &#189; dose NPH while NPO

-INR on admission 1.2; start heparin gtt and continue to hold coumadin

-RLE edema- check venous duplex to r/o DVT



Case discussed with Dr. Neal Joshi, Vascular Surgery Fellow and Dr. V Uselton, Vascular Surgery Attending







________________________________

Brandi Xayasane PA-C 75197

Vascular Surgery 




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>