<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2102-05-19





Pulmonary Consult Note


Name:    Dalila Haynes
MR#:     78361343
Date of admit:      5/18/02
Date of consult:   5/19/02 
 


Reason for consult: Sarcoidosis


History of Present Illness:  Mrs Haynes is a very pleasant 67 yo female pmh significant for a diagnosis of sarcoidosis from a nodule biopsies on her left eye back in October.  She subsequently underwent a mediastinoscopy in April of this year for bulky adenopathy which the pathology was also consistent with sarcoidosis.  She present for evaluation of abdominal pain that has been present for months but became unbearable prompting a visit to the emergency room.  Mrs. Haynes reports that over the past few months she has been experiencing weight loss, early satiety, night sweats and fatigue.  He abdominal pain is described as a sharp to achy pain that started in her right side, progressed to her epigastric and suprapubic are and then her left side.  Currently it is diffuse associated with nausea and vomiting.  She denies bowel problems has had some difficulty with urination and some frequency since admission but this is generally not a problem.  ROS is also pertinet for HA which are chronic and palpations both of which are hard to describe.
 
ROS: In detail otherwise unremarkable.


Past Medical History:  

HTN, Hyperlipidemia (h/o normal stress test in past), palpitations, GERD, thyroid nodules, lichen sclerosis, bilateral adrenal adenomas, diabetes mellitus type II, sarcoidosis


Past Surgical History:  
 s/p uterine fibroid resection 2096, s/p left facial biopsy 10/01




 

Medications (current):  
 

Ciprofloxacin 500 mg q 12 hr
Lovenox 40 mg SC day
Lisinopril 40 mg Po day
Simvastatin 40 mg QHS
Nifedipine 60 mg Po day
Omeprazole 40 mg Po day
NPH/Insulin Aspart
Mag Sulfate
CA Carbonate
Colace




Allergies:              sulfa causes GI intolerance




Family History:   Sister x 2 w/MI, Sister w/DM type II, Niece w/DM type II, Brother w/prostate CA, Brother w/possible leukemia, Mother w CVA. No Hx of sarcoid or TB in the family.




Social History:  The patient is a lifelong nonsmoker with a 20 year exposure to secondhand smoke.  The patient has no known asbestos exposure.  The patient is widowed with four children and is retired from her former job at Lowe's.  She was born in Georgia moved to Chelsea in the 50's and the only place she has visited was Augusta.  No TB exposures or risk factors.  States she had been tested for TB in the past years ago.  No beryllium exposure.




Physical Examination:
Vital Signs:    97.6  P 93  BP 110/60  RR 18  Sat 99%RA
General Appearance:NAD
HEENT:  PERRL, EOMI, visual fields grossly intact
Skin:  warm and dry
Neck: Supple
Lungs:  CTA bilaterally
Heart:  RRR s1s2 no m/r/g
Abdomen:  +BS, soft, diffuse tenderness no r/g
Musculoskeletal:  wnl
Extremities:  No c/c/e
Neuro:  A+O x 3 no gross motor or sensory deficits.


Diagnostic Testing:  
 
WBC 4.5 Hg 11 Hct 33 Plt 331  P 57  L 31  M 9.2  Na 138  K 4.1  Cl 103  Co2 27  BUN 11 Cr 0.73  Glu 243  Ca 9.0  Mg 1.2  ESR 20  D-Dimer 529
 
Ace Pending
 
Urine Cx 5/18 negative from 10am mixed flora 10K 3 colonies
 
PFTs 3/02- FVC 2.6 85%  FEV1 1.93  82% Ratio 74
 
TTE 2/02-The left ventricle is small and/or underfilled. There isborderline concentric left ventricular hypertrophy. Overall left ventricularfunction is normal. The estimated ejection fraction is 60%. There are noregional wall motion abnormalities.  Otherwise unremarkable.
 
CT abdomen Pelvis-  5/18/02   
 
IMPRESSION:           1. Urothelial thickening involving renal pelvises, ureters, and     bladder. Findings consistent with infection versus less likely     inflammation.     2. Bladder calculus.     3. Abdominal lymphadenopathy, increased since prior study, may be     consistent with progression of known sarcoid, versus malignancy.     4. Adrenal nodules, unchanged.
 
CT Chest 3/16
 
IMPRESSION:     1. Mediastinal, bilateral hilar, supraclavicular,     retroperitoneal, and gastrohepatic adenopathy likely represents     lymphoma rather than sarcoidosis given the patient age and     abdominal involvement.     2. Bilateral adrenal nodules.
 
Path: 04/10/2102 PATHOLOGIC DIAGNOSIS:A. SPECIMEN DESIGNATED "4R LYMPH NODES, BIOPSY" (including FSA):     Lymph node with non-necrotizing granulomata (see NOTE).B. SPECIMEN DESIGNATED "4R LYMPH NODES, BIOPSY":     Lymph node with non-necrotizing granulomata (see NOTE).


Impression:  Mrs. Haynes is a pleasant 67 yo female with biopsy demonstrating non-caesating granululoma in a left eye nodule and mediastinal lymph nodes.  Cx data was not obtained.  However, hx is not suggestive of past tuberculosis risk factors.  Clinical picture very suggestive of systemic sarcoidosis.  At this time she does not have an absolute indication for sarcoid treatment but she may benefit symptomatically from low dose steroids.  At this time she is reluctant to start steroids without discussing it with her family and Dr. Villalpando.


Recommendations:  
 
-Would consider Cardiac MRI given her hx of palpitations as cardiac sarcoid is an absolute indication for treatment.
-Would recommend checking PPD
-Would recommend starting prednisone 30mg po qday.  Will discuss this further with patient and family tomorrow.  There is no rush for treatment at this time and we could waite until Dr. Villalpando is available to speak with Mrs. Haynes.
-Would also recommend Bactrim prophylaxis while she is on greater than 15 mg Po prednisone.  1 DS M/W/F.
-Will follow.




Thank you for this interesting consult. Please call with questions.
 
Patient seen examine and case discussed with Dr. Layton.
 
__________________________________
Hayden Lawrence, MD
Pulmonary Fellow
Department of Pulmonary care
Beeper #51549




 



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2103-09-02


September 02, 2103


Odessia Kay, M.D.
Willow Pointe Assisted Living Center
600 Cherry Street
Aumsville, IA 63482


Re:  Dalila Haynes
       783-61-34-3


Dear Dr. Kay: 


I saw Dalila Haynes today in consultation concerning the possibility of neurosarcoidosis.  She comes with her daughter who assists with the history.  I will review her history for the record.


She is a 69-year-old right-handed woman who was hospitalized at the Promptcare in July 2103 for evaluation of mental and motor slowing, memory loss, and weight loss.  Her daughter notes that she had deteriorated over the course of a month or two.  Her movements slowed down, and she became unsteady on her feet, and her memory deteriorated.  This culminated in a fall in July prompting her hospitalization.  During that hospitalization a head CT on 7/25/03 was reported unremarkable.  (There is mild ventriculomegaly on it.)  An MRI of the brain on 7/28 showed a few dots of restricted diffusion in the left thalamus. There was no abnormal enhancement.  This was consistent with small vessel stroke.  EEG showed generalized slowing of the background in the theta and delta range with no epileptiform features.  An LP showed normal glucose (74), elevated protein (102), lymphocytic pleocytosis (18-20 WBC, 56-69% lymphocytes, 29-40% monocytes, and 2-4% neutrophils) and 0-1 RBC.  CSF ACE was normal.  Cultures were negative.  CSF VDRL was negative.  Because she has a history of sarcoidosis, it was thought that this likely represented neurosarcoidosis.  She was started on prednisone 40 mg daily.  Her daughter has noted some improvement in her movements and cognition since starting the prednisone, but she remains abnormal.  She has lowered the prednisone to 10 mg daily now.  Reviewing the laboratory studies today, I see that although an RPR was non-reactive, a TA-IgG was positive, and the confirming treponemal tests (FTA) was also positive at the state lab.  She and her daughter are aware of no prior history of syphilis.  Other studies during her hospitalization included low serum Na (133) and Mg (1.3), normal vitamin B12, folate, TSH, and ESR (20).  CSF HSV PCR was negative.  HbA1C was elevated at 8.6.  


She has a history of asthma going back many years.  According to her daughter, she had a skin lesion excised from near her left eye about two years ago.  Apparently, this showed noncaseated granuloma, and that is when the diagnosis of sarcoidosis was first made.  She then had a mediatinoscopy on 4/10/02.  Biopsy of mediastinal nodes showed granulomatous inflammation without caseating necrosis, supporting the diagnosis of sarcoidosis.  She has type II DM, HTN, hypercholesterolemia, GERD, and she has had a thyroid adenoma.  


Her current medications are prednisone 10 mg daily, aspirin 81 mg daily, troglitazone, metformin, glyburide, sisinoril, pravastatin, vitamin D, calcium CO3, Colace, and an inhaler for her asthma as needed.  She is allergic to sulfa agents and to fluticasone nasal spray.  There is no history of allergy to PCN.  


Her parents both died of some type of cancer.  There is no family history of sarcoidosis or of neurologic disease.


She is a widow.  She has four children.  She used to work for Lowe's.  She now lives with a daughter. 


She has had no recent fever or chills.  Her weight has been stable and her appetite good.  There is no history of exertional chest pain or palpitations.  There is no history of cough, dyspnea, nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea.  She has had no rash or joint symptoms.


Pulse 126, regular.  BP 126/66.  She is obese.  Ears, nose, and throat are clear.  There are no cranial bruits.  The neck is supple with full carotid pulses and no bruits.  There are wheezes bilaterally.  The heart is regular with no murmur.  The abdomen is benign.  The extremities are normal.


There is general psychomotor slowing.  She is oriented to time, expect that she gets the date off by two days as Aug 31.  She is oriented to place.  She is inattentive.  She is able to recite the months in order, but she gets lost trying to recite them in reverse.  She has trouble registering 4 words, and she recalls only 2 of 4 after three minutes.  There is no aphasia.  She cannot copy interlocking pentagons and her copy of a 3D cube shows poor spacial representation.  


The visual fields are full.  The pupils are 3 mm and normally reactive.  The fundi are poorly visualized.  .  The eye movements are full and conjugate with no nystagmus; pursuit movement are saccadic.  Facial sensation is intact.  Facial power is normal and symmetric.  Hearing is grossly intact.  Weber and Rinne tests are normal.  The palate elevates normal.  Gag is present.  The sternocleidomastoid and trapezius power are normal.  The tongue protrudes in the midline.  Muscle bulk, tone, and power are normal.  There is a low-amplitude, high-frequency tremor in action and rest.  Temperature and pinprick sensation are diminished in the lower extremities with a distally-predominant gradient.  Reflexes are normal (2/4) and symmetric in the upper extremities and at the knees and absent at the ankles.  Plantar responses are flexor.  Coordination is intact.  Romberg is negative.  Gait and station are normal.


Her treponemal test for syphilis came back positive from the hospitalization in July.  Since syphilis, too, could cause noncaseating granulomas, and she has clearly has syphilis at some point in the past which was probably untreated, this raises some doubt about the diagnosis of sarcoidosis.  I will review that issue with you and with Dr, Villalpando.  She had CSF pleocytosis in July.  With that and the positive treponemal test (FTA), she will need a full course of intravenous penicillin for presumed neurosyphilis.  I will discuss arrangements for possible outpatient management of hatt with a PICC line and outpatient VNA services.  Concerning her need for prednisone, I think that will depend on our interpretation of the diagnosis of sarcoidosis in light of this new diagnosis.  If the evidence of sarcoidosis is not strong with this alternative diagnosis, then we can plan to complete the course of penicillin and taper and discontinue the prednisone and then follow her clinical course, her CSF, and her syphilis serologies.


Finally, from the MRI of 7/28, shows a couple of tiny foci of restricted diffusion in the left thalamus.  These are most consistent with small vessel ischemic strokes.  She has multiple risk factors for common small vessel disease and stroke, but in the context of her inflammatory CSF and evidence of prior syphilis, we must also consider cerebrovascular syphilis as the likely cause of this.


I would recommend treatment now with a 14-day course of high-dose (20-24 million units a day) penicillin.  She is already on prednisone which might help to prevent any possible Jarisch-Herxheimer reaction.  I think that if she remains stable after the initiation of her PCN therapy, then we can plan to taper and then discontinue the prednisone, to follow her clinically and with repeated LP, and determine any need for future corticosteroid therapy on her course.  


Thank you for this consultation.




Sincerely,






Keondre Viera, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2104-01-30


NEUROLOGY RESIDENT CONSULT NOTE 





PATIENT NAME: Dalila Haynes
MRN: 78361343
DATE OF CONSULT: 1/30/04



 
Consulted by: ED for altered mental status and generalized weakness



HPI:   

69 yo F h/o systemic sarcoidosis (extensive adenopathy in the chest, abdomen, and adrenal glands, and has been on corticosteroids), CNS syphillis s/p treatment  who presents with several weeks increasing generalized weakness and several days of increasing confusion. Patient is unable to give a reliable history; history from daughter Inez Haynes, whom I called on the phone, and from LMR (primarily Dr. Keondre Viera's August neurology note). Her daughter reports that current decline is similar to her presentation in July 2103.


She was hospitalized at Promptcare in July 2103 for evaluation of mental and motor slowing, memory loss, and weight loss that had progressed over 1 to 2 months. Head CT on 7/25/03 with only mild ventriculomegaly. An MRI of the brain on 7/28 showed a few dots of restricted diffusion in the left thalamus. There was no abnormal enhancement. This was consistent with small vessel stroke. EEG showed generalized slowing of the background in the theta and delta range with no epileptiform features. She had normal vitamin B12, folate, TSH, and ESR (20). CSF HSV PCR was negative. HbA1C was elevated at 8.6. An LP showed normal glucose (74), elevated protein (102), lymphocytic pleocytosis (18-20 WBC, 56-69% lymphocytes, 29-40% monocytes, and 2-4% neutrophils) and 0-1 RBC. CSF ACE was normal. Cultures were negative. CSF VDRL was negative. She was initially treated with prednisone 40 mg daily tapered down to 10 mg daily. In follow up, it was noted that RPR was non-reactive, a TA-IgG was positive, and the confirming treponemal tests (FTA) was also positive at the state lab. This was thought to represent neurosyphillis and she was admitted and treated w/ 14 days of IV penicillin. Prednisone was subsequently tapered to off since her presentation was thought to be consistent w/ neurosyphillis and not neurosarcoidosis.



Per her daughter, patient had improved back to being independent of ADL's and walking with a cane witout assistance. Over the last few weeks, she has gotten progressively more weak with multiple falls. Has trouble standing now, seems unsteady on her feet, has been primarily in bed for the last few days, requiring assistance to get to the bathroom or she falls down. Over the last several days, she has become even more globally weak and confused. She has been talking about relatives who are not in the house, thinking that they are there; thinking that the closet is the bathroom. It was a slow progression over a few weeks and then accelerated over the last few days. Patient reports intermittent headaches.


On presentation to the ED, she was noted to be tachycardic in the 120's (baseline resting tachycardia documented for many months, being worked up by cards), normotensive, afebrile, oriented x 2, and moving all extremities. 


 
ROS: 
Reliability of ROS is questionable.
Neurologic: Except as above, there have been no changes in vision or hearing, neck pain, tinnitus, vertigo, numbness, speaking, language, swallowing, or gait.



General: negative for fevers, chills, rashes, change in weight, chest pain, palpitations, shortness of breath, cough, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, and change in bowel or bladder habits.



PMH:   
1. Hypertension. 
2. Diabetes.
3. Systemic sarcoidosis
4. CNS syphilis status post treatment.
5. Osteoarthritis.
6. Thyroid nodules.
7. Bilateral adrenal adenomas.
8. Osteopenia.
9. Glaucoma.
10. Small-vessel ischemic strokes.



MEDS:
Actos 15 mg daily
Aspirin 81 mg daily
calcium plus vitamin D
lisinopril 40 mg daily
Nexium 40 mg daily
Pravachol 40 mg daily
Symbicort inhaler.



ALLERGIES:  bactrim - GI intolerance; fluticasone - cough



SOCIAL HX:  Retired. Lives with daughter Beltran. Does ADLs at home at baseline. Non-smoker. No EtOH. No illicit or IVDU.



FAMILY HX:  unable to obtain


PHYSICAL EXAM:  (time of exam = 11:15 PM)
V:  T 98   HR 118    BP 163/74    RR 14    O2Sat  98%


Gen: NAD, comfortable
HEENT: sclera anicteric.  MMM, OP clear.    
Neck:  Supple
Cor: RRR
Chest: CTAB 
Abdomen: Soft, NT, ND.  NABS 
Ext: WWP, no edema
Skin: No lesions, no rash


Neuro:

MS:

Gen: Alert, a little slow to respond to questions but appropriate

Orientation: thinks it is early Feb 2104 instead of Jan 30; PMC

Attention: Names days of week backwards correctly.

Speech/Lang: Fluent w/o paraphasic errors; Follows simple commands without L/R confusion.
 Difficulty w/ complex commands. Repetition and naming intact. Can read very large print.
Memory: 3/3 at 1 minute; 0/3 at 5 mins but recalls all 3 w/ category prompts. Names the president correctly, but not the VP or any prior presidents. Unable to give details of any recent events in the news (wars, senate election, etc).
Calculations:  Intact for 5+3 and 5 quarters
Praxis: 
Able to pantomime brushing hair and teeth.




CN:



II: VFFC; PERRL 3 to 2 bilat. Unable to visualize retina b/c clenches eyes shut
III,IV,VI: EOMI w/o nystagmus or diplopia; no ptosis

V: Sensation intact to light touch 

VII: 
Face symmetric

VIII: grossly intact

IX,X: Voice normal, palate elevates symmetrically

XI: SCM and trapezii full

XII: Tongue midline



Motor:  Normal bulk and tone; no tremor. No pronator drift. Strength clearly symmetric. Perhaps globally mildly weak but could also be decreased effort.



     Del  Bi  Tri  FE  IP   Quad  Hamst    Tib Ant  EHL  Gastro

R    5    5    5   5    5    5      5       5        5     5

L    5    5    5   5    5    5      5       5        5     5




Reflex: Normal and symmetric (2+) in bilat biceps, triceps, brachioradialis, patella and ankles.
 Toes w/ prominent withdrawal.



Sens: LT and temperature intact. Vibration rapidly extinguishes.



Coord: Rapid alternating, FTN, and HTS intact.



Gait: deferred





LABS:

01/30/2104 NA 134 (*),  K 4.5 (#),  CL 97 (*),  CO2 21 (*),  BUN 14,  CRE 0.79,  GLU 148 (*)01/30/2104 CA 10.401/30/2104 WBC 4.38,  HCT 33.3 (*),  PLT 358



UA negative


IMAGING:
HEAD CT TODAY:
There is no midline shift, mass effect, evidence of acute territorial infarction, or hemorrhage. Ventricles and sulci are prominent consistent with stable involutional change. There is no hydrocephalus. Chronic periventricular white matter changes are again noted. There is no significant soft tissue swelling or calvarial fracture. Prominent calcifications of a falx cerebri are incidentally noted. Imaged portions of the paranasal sinuses and mastoid air cells are clear. There is bilateral exophthalmus.
      
CXR: today
Faint opacity seen in the retrocardiac region which  could represent early pneumonia. Clinical correlation and interval follow-up is recommended.


EKG: sinus tachy. no ST changes or Q waves. 



ASSESSMENT AND RECOMMENDATIONS: 

69 yo F h/o systemic sarcoidosis (extensive adenopathy in the chest, abdomen, and adrenal glands, and has been on corticosteroids), CNS syphillis s/p treatment  who presents with several weeks of increasing generalized weakness and several days of increasing confusion. Exam notable for poor memory and some confusion about recent events.  Labs are unremarkable except minor electrolyte abnormalities. Head CT unremarkable. Her prior presentation was thought to be most likely due to neurosyphillis as detailed above, though there was still the possibility of neurosarcoid. She has not had a repeat LP to assess for resolution of prior abnormalities, and now that she has a recurrence of symptoms, she should have repeat LP. She should also have an MRI as a thalamic or frontal stroke is another possible etiology. This could be a more global failure to thrive in the setting of deconditioning followed by poor PO's, but this should be a diagnosis of exclusion. CXR raises a question of retrocardiac opacity suggesting possible PNA, but with normal WBC, no URI sx's or cough, and no fever, I think it is unlikely that she has PNA and will follow clinically.


-check her gait
-check ESR



-LP for standard studies and save 5-10 cc for additional studies depending on cell count/TP
-MRI of the brain
-EEG
-further lab w/u pending LP results
-remove foley catheter
-PT consult




___________________________________ 
Bobby S. Galvan M.D., Ph.D.                               
Pager #18454
PromptCare Neurology Resident PGY-3



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2104-04-14








Willow Pointe Assisted Living Center

839 Cherry Street

Aumsville, IA  63482

(296) 003-4642



HAYNES, DALILA

78361343

04/14/2104



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Haynes is a 69-year-old woman who comes in followup of her recent hospitalization and rehabilitation.  She is here with her daughter.  She notes that she is mostly feeling tired lately.  She is able to walk with help and is even unable to walk upstairs with assistance.  She is here in a wheelchair and says she is kind of tired and lets her daughter gives most of the history even when asked simple questions.  She has been checking her blood sugars and she shows me the results.  In the morning, the sugars have been fairly low in the 57-100 range, around noontime high at 144 up to 398, and in the evening high again 176-245.  She is taking Lantus 38 units at 9:00 p.m. and she is on NovoLog coverage less than 25-0 units, 125-152 units, 151-204 units, 201-256 units, 251-308 units and greater than 310 units.  She would like to switch over her Lantus to the Pens since the pen is so much easier for her.  She complains of hemorrhoids, although she says they are actually getting better, she had previously had four now she has two.  There is no bleeding.  There is no pain, kind of itchy and uncomfortable.  She is in fact not having any problem with constipation at this time.  She is having bowel movements every day.  She is not having any chest pain, no trouble breathing, no fevers, sweats or chills.  No abdominal symptoms.  She notes her stomach is really fine and it just not causing any trouble at all.



MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin, lisinopril 40 daily, Lantus 38, NovoLog coverage, omeprazole 40 daily, metoprolol, potassium chloride, Lasix 40 daily, Pravachol 40 nightly, and Symbicort.



ALLERGIES:  Bactrim GI intolerance, fluticasone, cough and sucralfate unknown.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  She has never smoked, no alcohol, no street drugs.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.  Blood pressure 121/65, pulse 106, weight 169.8, and temperature 98.6.  A delightful woman, English speaking and sitting in a wheelchair.  Quite alert, did know the president, could not recall the vice-president or against whom the president ran in the last election.  She did know the day of the week and she knew where she was.  She also remembered to remind me about a prescription when both her daughter and I almost forgot.  She is an absolutely delightful woman, appears well and alert despite the fact that she lets her daughter provides most of the history and responses.  She appears comfortable, breathing easily, no use of accessory muscles of inspiration, speaking in full sentences, no cough, no spine or flank tenderness.  Heart sounds S1, S2, regular rate and rhythm, no murmur, rub or gallop.  Chest is clear to auscultation anteriorly and posteriorly with no rales, wheezes, or rhonchi.  She is clear to percussion.  Extremities:  Without edema, cyanosis or clubbing, no calf tenderness.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:

1.  Diabetes.  Her A1c today was 6.6, which represents excellent control despite a fairly high glucoses she was recording.  I therefore did not want to increase her regimen despite the high glucoses.  We will continue for now.  I did give her an appointment with the diabetes nurse for help in management of her diabetes.

2.  Hypertension.  Her blood pressure is fine.  We will continue current regimen.  We will check electrolytes.

3.  Tachycardia actually improved relative to her last visit.  She is asymptomatic in this regard except for some fatigue.

4.  Fatigue.  This is most likely due to stepping down from the prednisone 60-40.  This is what the patient and her daughter believe.  She was somewhat fatigued before, but they note that it is worse with this.  She does need to come off the prednisone and Dr. Villalpando who she just saw is going to try to come up with another plan for her. Check cbc.

5.  Acid associated symptoms well controlled with omeprazole.

6.  Right knee mild osteoarthritis, not a problem today.

7.  CNS syphilis status post treatment.

8.  Question of CNS sarcoid currently on 40 mg of prednisone and hopefully she will be able to come off of that and perhaps get started on something else.

9.  Cholesterol.  We will recheck her cholesterol today and will check an SGPT.

10.  Thyroid nodules.  Ultrasound in July 2103 showed stability.

11.  Adrenal adenoma.  Her CAT scan in May 2102 showed stability and some adenopathy consistent with sarcoid.

12.  Lichen simplex chronicus.  Dermatology diagnosis from 2101.  Not addressed today.  Hopefully, she will be stronger at her next visit and we can recheck.

13.  Osteopenia.  She will continue calcium and vitamin D.  I encouraged weightbearing exercise as tolerated.

14.  Glaucoma suspect, not addressed today.

15.  Small vessel ischemic disease.  MRI from July showed changes consistent with small vessel ischemic stroke.  She is currently on aspirin and stable.

16. Hemorrhoids - anusolHC given. Given no bleeding and no pian, this hopefully will fuffice. Recommended avoiding constipation, as she is doing, with lots of dietary fruits and vegetables.



HgA1C 6.6
CBC slightly elevated WBC likely due to prednisone
SGPT, lytes o.k.
CHOL LDL 1124 elevated but HDL also high, protective, cntu pravachol and rercheck
letter sent

______________________________

Odessia Q Kay, M.D.











eScription document:3-89996385 JSSten Tel







DD: 04/15/04

DT: 04/15/04

DV: 04/14/04



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>