<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2085-02-11

NEUROLOGY  ADMIT NOTE

Patient: Betty Gillis

MRN: 78865189

Time of admission: 7:00PM



CC:  drooling

HPI: 73 RHF with h/o HTN, HL, OA, prior cerebellar stroke, taking ASA 325mg QD, who p/w drooling and L hand clumsiness which began while the patient was typing a letter this morning. The patient reports that she woke up around noon after going to bed feeling just fine around midnight.  She then called a friend and realized that her speech was slurred.  She waited for her symptoms to improve, and when they did not resolve, she called a cab to take her to her CH medical office. While there, she noticed tremors of her hands b/l; she was given an additional ASA 325mg today.  She has never had similar symptoms in the past.  She denies headache, vision changes, dizziness, or difficulty walking with this episode today.  She feels otherwise well. She reports that she discovered her prior stroke when she noted she felt more dizzy and unsteady and obtained an MRI which showed an old cerebellar infarct.



PMH: HTN, HL, Prior stroke-- likely cerebellar, OA, bilateral TKR, OA, GERD, h/o GIB required PRBC transfusions, psoriasis



Meds:

ASA 325 PO QD

HCTZ 12.5 QD

Zocor 20 QD

Prilosec

Doxepin for psoriasis

NKDA 

SH: denies tobacco, ETOH, illicips 



FH: NC

ROS: . Negative for HA, change vision, n/v, vertigo, tiinitus, numbness, tingling, difficulty with speech, swallowing or gait

Exam:	 

GEN:.WDWN, NAD, sitting up in bed, pleasant 				

RESP: Lungs CTA b/l`                  			CV: 

ABD: soft NTND					EXT:no c/c/e, excoriated scaly patches along dorsum of hands b/l

NEURO: 

MS:awake, alert, interactive, follows all commands. memory 3/3 items at 3 minutes. repetition intact, naming intact, comprehension slow but will correct mistakes

CN: Pupils 5-->3 b/l, eomi without nystagmus, VFFTC, L UMN facial, hearing intact to finger rub b/l, tongue midline, dysarthric

Motor:  nl bulk and tone, L pronator drift

	Delt	Bi	Tri	Grip	IP	Q	H	Gas	EHL

R	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5	5

L	4+	5	4+	5	5	5	5	5	5	



Reflexes:  

	Bi	Tri	BR	Knee	Ankle 

R	1+	1+	1+	1	1+	

L	1+	1+	1+	1+	1+

Toes downgoing bilaterally

Sensation: intact to LT, symmetric 

Coordination:  dysmetria F-T-N L > R, symmetric RAM

Gait:  not tested

Data:

Labs: CMP wnl, CBC wnl, U/A- LE++, 

Head CT: pending

MRI/MRA brain: pending



A/P:  73F with h/o prior infarct, HTN, HL, who presents with new L facial droop and L arm weakness, suspicious for stroke. 

1. Admit to Neurology floor service for observation and w/u including: CT/CTA, MRI/MRA, stroke labs (ESR, TSH, CRP, lipoprotein a, homocysteine), TTE with bubble study, Holter monitor placement.

2. SBP 140-180 for now.

3. Given that stroke may have occurred while patient was taking ASA, will administer Aggrenox.

4. Cipro for UTI

5. Pt reports she is eating well, therefore no need for swallow evaluation. 



Plan discussed with Neurology Senior, Veleria Blackwell. 



Hollis B Hughes MD

B 93439





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-04-22

 


GILLIS, BETTY
78865189
04/22/2085


Ines Estep, M.D.
930 Scotia Way
Big Bear Lake, CO  98839

To Dr. Estep:

I saw Betty Gillis in cardiovascular clinic with Dr. Vicente Noel on 04/22/2085.  Betty Gillis is a very pleasant 73-year-old woman who was recently admitted to the Griffin Memorial Hospital in early February 2085 with a right MCA territory stroke characterized clinically by drooling and left hand weakness.  Fortunately, her symptoms have now resolved and she is back to her regular activities.  We understand that she has also had previous strokes.  In December 2082, she was suffering a dizzy spell and subsequently an MRI of her brain found a posterior circulation cerebellar infarct as well as a couple of basal ganglia lacunar infarct.  She recalls having only V2 clinical events.

She was worked up in the Griffin Memorial Hospital and had a Holter, which demonstrated normal sinus rhythm with minor ectopy only, an echocardiogram, which was reported as essentially normal with the exception of a positive saline contrast bubble study suggesting a patent foramen ovale, an MRI of her head which demonstrated the infarct and marked microvascular disease, as well as a CT angiogram of her head and neck arteries, which demonstrated mild atheroma for the most part with a left internal carotid artery stenosis that was less than 50%.  She is referred to us today for an opinion as to how to manage the possible patent foramen ovale.

This lady has never had cardiac problems otherwise.  There is no history of atrial fibrillation, coronary artery disease or congestive heart failure.  She does not get exertional chest discomfort (chest pain or shortness of breath) and has no history of syncope or presyncope.  She has no history of PND, orthopnea or edema.  She remains fairly active despite her ataxic gait.  She tells me that she is able to walk several blocks without difficulty and never has any exertional chest pains or shortness of breath.  Moreover, she does not have claudication.  Functional inquiry is otherwise unremarkable save for her usual difficulties with psoriasis and eczema.  She denies difficulties with heartburn or GI bleeding recently.

Past Medical History:
1.  Stroke.
A.  Subcortical basal ganglia stroke.
B.  Cerebellar stroke in December 2085 with subsequent ataxic gait.
C.  Right MCA stroke with left hand weakness in February 2085.
2.  Hypertension
3.  Dyslipidemia.
4.  Insulin insensitivity
5.  Ex-smoker (1-1-1/2 packs per day for approximately 40 years, quit approximately 12 years ago).
6.  Possible patent foramen ovale.
7.  Degenerative joint disease/osteoarthritis.
A.  Status bilateral total knee replacement in 2084.
B.  Gastroesophageal reflux disease/hiatus hernia.
C.  Status post GI bleeding (query secondary to esophagitis)
8.  Osteoporosis.
9.  Bladder incontinence.

There is no history of other cardiac problems.  There is no history of venous thromboembolic disease.  This lady has not had frank diabetes.

Allergies:  She has no known drug allergies.

Current Medical Therapy:
1.  Aggrenox 25/200 p.o. b.i.d.
2.  Prilosec 20 mg p.o. daily.
3.  Doxepin 25 mg daily.
4.  Simvastatin 40 mg p.o. daily.
5.  Atenolol 12.5 mg p.o. daily.
6.  Fosamax 70 mg every week.
7.  BLANK 1 tab daily.
8.  Darifenacin 7.5 mg daily.

Family History:  Betty Gillis is adopted and does not know very much about her biological parents.  She believes that her biological father suffered a stroke at some point, but cannot say for certain how old he was.

Social History:  This woman is single.  She is a retired Secretary.  She is an ex-smoker (more than 40 pack years), but does not drink significant amounts of alcohol.  She has no other history of substance abuse.

Review of Systems:  Functional inquiry is positive for difficulties with psoriasis that are chronic and ongoing.  She has no other new symptoms.  There is no recent GI bleeding.  She has difficulties with bladder incontinence as well.

On physical examination today, her heart rate is 86 beats per minute and regular and her blood pressure is 122/78 in the right arm and 124/80 in the left arm.  Respiratory rate is 20 and she is pink on room air.  Head and neck exam is unremarkable.  There are no carotid bruits.  She has some kyphoscoliosis of her spine.  Her chest examination reveals no dullness to percussion and vesicular breath sounds only.  Her jugular venous pressure is not elevated.  Central pulses are normal in volume and contour.  Her apex beat is within normal limits.  Heart sounds include a normal S1 and S2 with no murmurs.  Her abdomen is soft and nontender.  There are no obvious masses.  Her aorta does not obviously appear to be enlarged.  Her pulses are palpable in her groin, but hard to feel behind her knees and distally.  They are symmetrical.  Informally, ABI test was not done today because she has several weeping eczematous lesions on her legs, which reflects psoriasis that has been excoriated.  A brief neurologic exam reveals dysmetria worse on the left than the right.

Impression:  Betty Gillis has had at least four strokes and has documented evidence of atherosclerotic vascular disease and cerebromicrovascular disease on recent imaging.  We reviewed the echocardiogram today and we wished to confirm with the reading echocardiographer that it is indeed positive.  (It does not look particularly positive to our eyes).  Certainly, if she does not indeed have a patent foramen ovale, there is no issue as to what to do about it.  If she does have one; however, it seems more likely that her strokes reflect her atherosclerotic vascular disease secondary to her atherosclerotic risk factors and that the bulk of treatment should be directed at modulating those.

Her hypertension is controlled today.  Her dyslipidemia is not bad.  However, the LDL is 76 and perhaps there is some added benefit to increasing her simvastatin to 80 mg p.o. daily.  We also note that she has had elevated glucoses in the past, as high as 191, as well as an elevated hemoglobin A1c up to 6.5.  It is probably worth having her screen formally to see whether or not she has type 2 diabetes mellitus versus insulin insensitivity only.  She may benefit from an oral hypoglycemic.

We recommend.
1.  We will review the echocardiogram with the reading echocardiographer to ensure that it does indeed show a patent foramen ovale.
2.  We suggest that she increase her statin from simvastatin 40 mg p.o. daily to simvastatin 80 mg p.o. daily.  We will leave this to her primary care physician to organize.
3.  We suggest that she be screened formally for diabetes mellitus type 2.

We will see her again as necessary, but for the time being, we have no plans to perform an intervention on this lady.


______________________________
Bobby Elston Braun, MD





eScription document:8-3518405 IFFocus

CC: Michael John Boyle MD
687 SCOTIA WAY
BIG BEAR LAKE, CO 17347


DD: 04/22/85
DT: 04/23/85
DV: 04/22/85



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-08-31

EDVISIT^78865189^GILLIS, BETTY^08/31/85^GUEVARA, ELIZABETH

The patient was seen with Dr. Izaguirre.  Resident's note was

reviewed.  The patient was seen and examined by me.  Please see

the resident's note for details of the patient's past medical,

social, family history, review of systems, and physical exam.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  EKG changes.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 73-year-old woman with a

history of 2 ischemic strokes in the past, hypertension and high

cholesterol who presents with 1-2 weeks of feeling tired after

breakfast.  She went into Copley Hospital with this complaint today,

is a somewhat difficult historian but denies any chest pain,

shortness of breath, diaphoresis, nausea, vomiting, arm pain,

diarrhea, constipation, dyspnea on exertion, recent change in her

medications or any other complaints.  Today, she had the symptoms

and was seen at the outside office.  An EKG was performed there

for which she was sent here with a reading of a T-wave inversion

in V2 and V3.  There seems to be lead placement problem V1 and

V3.  Leads appeared ____, but there is a slight T-wave inversion

in what would be V1 and V2, which seems to be new from prior EKG.

 Placement of leads could not be confirmed at CH.  The patient

was sent in here and arrived chest pain free and otherwise

asymptomatic.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, high cholesterol, COPD,

arthritis, ischemic strokes x2, GI bleed in the past,

osteoporosis, and colon polyps.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Bilateral total knee replacements.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She is a past smoker, never used drugs.  Lives

alone.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Unclear as the patient is adopted.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative except for some ____.

MEDICATIONS:  The patient takes PPIs, Prilosec, calcium,

atenolol, Aggrenox, iron, doxepin, Detrol, and simvastatin.

ALLERGIES:  None.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile, normal and stable vital

signs.  Pulse 73 and blood pressure 129/80.  Awake, alert, in no

distress.  Her exam is essentially unremarkable including clear

and equal breath sounds, normal JVD and regular rate and rhythm. 

No murmurs on cardiac examination.  Abdomen is soft and

nontender.  Skin is warm, dry, and intact except for some

psoriatic lesions that are old.  She has no pedal edema and the

rest of her examination is essentially unremarkable.  EKG in the

Emergency Department shows sinus rhythm at 65 with an upgoing

T-waves in all the precordial leads.  Laboratory examination

reveals negative cardiac enzymes and is otherwise unremarkable. 

PTT 21 and INR 1.  Chest x-ray shows no acute changes.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  She was seen by the CH

cardiologist, Dr. Brock.  In the Emergency Department, given

the patient's vascular disease, the plan is to admit for 2 sets

of enzymes and a stress in the morning.  She is well appearing at

the time of admission.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  EKG changes.

______________________________

GUEVARA, ELIZABETH M.D.

D: 08/31/85

T: 08/31/85

Dictated By: GUEVARA, ELIZABETH

eScription document:9-9287507 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-08-01


















 
ED Neurology Consult Note

August 01, 2087

Time of Exam: 3:15 AM



PATIENT: Gillis, Betty

MRN: 8308652



CC: L arm numbness



HPI: 75 yo woman with a history of R MCA, R cerebellar strokes who presents with L arm numbness. Patient was sitting on her couch this morning between 9-10 AM when she began to have L arm numbness. She initially thought it was from leaning on her arm but it did not improve when she moved. She also noted that it was not in any particular nerve distribution. Aside from this deficit, she denies any H/A, LOC, dizziness, blurry vision, facial droop, weakness, or aphasia. Her symptoms persisted for about 12 hours and then spontaneously resolved. Of note, she has some residual left sided weakness from her prior R MCA stroke and some balance issues from her cerebellar stroke. 




MEDICAL HISTORY

R MCA stroke: 02/85

R cerebellar stroke: 12/85

Osteoarthritis s/p bilateral knee replacements

GERD, chronic GI bleed with anemia

HTN

HLD

Bladder incontinence



ALLERGIES:

NKDA



MEDICATIONS:

Atenolol

Aggrenox

Detrol

Doxepin

Simvastatin

Omeprazole

Colace

Calcium

Iron

Vitamins



FAMILY HISTORY

Unknown, adopted. 



SOCIAL HISTORY

Denies smoking, EtOH. Lives alone and performs her own ADLs. 



PHYSICAL EXAM

VITALS:  Temp:   98.2        HR:  72                  BP: 98/72              RR: 18                   O2 Sat: 98%, RA 

NEURO: 

MS:

Gen:                         Alert, Appropriately Interactive, Normal Affect.

Orientation:             Full (to name, place, date and year).

Attention:                                Names months backwards correctly.

Speech/Lang:            Fluent w/o (phonemic or semantic) paraphasic errors

CN:

I:                              Not tested.

II, III:                      VFFC. PERRL 4 mm &#224; 2 mm. 

III,IV,VI:                 EOMI with normal smooth pursuits and volitional saccades. No apparent preference of gaze, nystagmus (or diplopia), or ptosis.

V:                            Sensation intact to LT 

VII:                          Upper and lower face symmetric without weakness.

VIII:                        Hears finger rub equally and bilaterally.

IX,X:                       Voice normal (&#8220;ga, ta, la&#8221;). Palate elevates symmetrically.

XI:                           SCM and trapezii with full and symmetric strength.

XII:                          Tongue protrudes midline without atrophy or fasciculations.

Motor:     

Normal bulk and tone; No pronator drift. 









Delt


Bi


Tri


HG


WE


FAb


IP


Quad


Hamst


TibAnt


EHL


Gastroc






C5


C6


C7


C8


C8/T1


T1


L2


L3


L4-S1


L4


L5


S1



R


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5



L


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+


4+



Coord:

Heel to shin, finger nose finger intact. 

Reflex: 






  


Bi


Tri


Bra


Pat


Ank


Toes






C6


C7


C6


L4


S1






R


2


2


2


2


2


down



L


2


2


2


2


2


down

Sens:   

LT intact throughout. 

Gait:        

Normal gait. Romberg positive (sways and catches herself on bed) 



LABS:

Plasma Sodium                    141                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.4                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  105                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide           
29.1                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 7                         (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          9.4                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       3.7                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        2.0                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             23                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                0.97                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             60                                       mL/min/1.73m2

Plasma Glucose                   105                       (70-110)       mg/dl

Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

Troponin-I                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

WBC                              6.1                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              30.4             L        (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              10.5             L        (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              3.17             L        (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              287                       (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              96                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              33.0                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             34.5                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              15.7             H        (11.5-14.5)    %

Superstat PT                     12.2                      (10.8-13.4)    sec

Superstat PT-INR                 1.0

Superstat APTT                   25.1                      (21.0-33.0)    sec

Diff Method                      Auto

Poly                             73               H        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           17               L        (22-44)        %

Monos                            6                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              4                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %

Absolute Neuts                   4.43                      (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  1.04                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   0.38                      (0.2-1.2)      th/mm3

Absolute EOS                     0.22                      (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.03                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm

Aniso                            None                      (None)

Hypo                             None                      (None)

Macrocytes                       None                      (None)

Microcytes                       None                      (None)



RADIOLOGY/STUDIES:

     1.  Scattered punctate foci of DWI hyperintensity that are not

     well evaluated on ADC or exponential images, in the right MCA/PCA

     border zone distribution.  Given the pattern of signal

     abnormality, these most likely represent subacute infarcts, with

     possible subacute on chronic right posterior corona radiata

     infarct.

     

     2.  Evidence of prior right MCA territory infarct and chronic

     small vessel ischemic disease.

     

     3.  No hemodynamically significant stenosis of the extracranial or

     intracranial circulation.



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN

75 yo woman with a history of stroke, HTN who presents with L arm numbness. While her deficits appear to have resolved, arguing against stroke, she clearly has multiple punctate foci of DWI hyperintensity that would be consistent with acute stroke. These strokes are in the PCA region and at the watershed region of the MCA/PCA and so could represent both anterior and posterior circulation emboli. Given that her carotid arteries are relatively clear, her heart or arch may be possible sources of embolus.

- Has had stroke workup in the past that has been unrevealing

- Would benefit from a repeat echocardiogram to assess for any new vegetations or thrombi

- Would also benefit from repeat Holter to assess for paroxysmal atrial fibrillation

- Admit to Internal Medicine service

__________________________________

Victor Q. Qiu, MDNeurology ED Consult

Pager 64012



Patient discussed with senior resident Dr. Bates who agrees with the plan. 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2087-09-03

Kekela Internal Medicine Intern Admission Note 


Patient Name: Gillis, Betty

MRN: 8308652

Date of Admission: 9/03/87

Attending: Mercado

Admitting Intern: Dalton Edwards

Source of History: patient, online chart





CC: SOB



HPI: 75 yo woman with a history of R MCA, R cerebellar stroke, TIAs, Iliac vein thrombosis, PFO, and recent RP hematoma and rectus sheath hematoma (at GMH 8/13/87-8/26/87) currently off of anticoagulation because of her recent bleeds. 
Pt reports sudden onset of SOB this AM.  Not associated with any other symptoms.  A contractor who was at her home at the time called EMS who took pt to hospital.  En route she developed nausea and had 1 episode of NBNB emesis.  Otherwise, she denies CP, cough, fever, chills, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting (other than the episode in the ambulance), change in bowel/bladder habits.  No exacerbating or alleviating symptoms.  Of note, she has some residual left sided weakness from her prior R MCA stroke and some balance issues from her cerebellar stroke.



In the ED the patient was tachypnic with SATS in the low 80s and  placed on oxygen by nasal cannula with improved sats on 4L to the mid 90s.  Then was able to be weaned to room air with sats still in the mid 90s.  She also was tachycardic to the 90s with BPs to the 90/60 with one episode of BP to 78 systolic.  She responded well to fluid with 2L in the ED and improved BPs.  CT showed stable RP and rectus sheath hematomas, no evidence of DVT or iliac thrombosis, and no evidence of PE.  CXR was clear.  



Of note, following her hospitalization at PROMPTCARE in July 2087 for TIA where she was found to have a small PFO and iliac vein thrombosis, she was started on Coumadin.  However, the patient was recently admitted to GMH with rectus sheath and RP hematoma.  Per the patient, she received 8 U PRBC there.  She also received FFP and vitamin K to reverse her Coumadin.  During her hospitalization she was in the ICU for hypotension and tachycardia.  An IVC filter was placed initially but subsequently d/c&#8217;d on 8/26/87.  She was discharged off of anticoagulation.   





PMH/PSH: 

R MCA stroke: 02/85

R cerebellar stroke: 12/85

Osteoarthritis s/p bilateral knee replacements

GERD, chronic GI bleed with anemia

HTN

HLD

Bladder incontinence

?Iliac vein thrombosis

Rectus sheath hematoma/Retroperitoneal hematoma



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:

Omeprazole 40 MG PO Daily

Atenolol 12.5 MG PO Daily

Simvastatin 40 MG PO Every night

Ferrous Sulfate 324 MG PO Two times a day



ALLERGIES: 

NKDA



FHX: Unknown, adopted.

       

     

SOCIAL HISTORY

Lives on her own in Big Bear Lake.  Performs all ADLs. 

Denies EtOH, IVDU

Former smoker ~50 pk yrs, quit 20 yrs ago.  





REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:

As per HPI, otherwise negative in all details.  



PHYSICAL EXAM:

Vitals: T     99.6   HR 75  BP 94/58      RR     22     O2sat 
98% 2L NC 

General: well-developed, well-nourished female NAD

Skin: no rashes

HEENT: NC/AT, sclera anicteric, normal conjunctiva.  Dry mucous membranes, no oral/buccal lesions. 

Chest: clear to auscultation b/l, no wheezes or rhonchi

CV:  RRR. Normal S1, S2. no m/r/g.

Abd: soft, non-tender, non-distended. 8x8 cm mass like structure on right abdomen at rectus.  Non tender, non-erythematous.  

Ext: warm, well-perfused, no clubbing, cyanosis, edema. No palpable cords, neg Homan&#8217;s sign b/l.

Neuro: alert, oriented x 3. CN2-12 intact except for slight left facial droop and mild slurring of speech. 
M: 5/5 strength at UE and LE bilaterally except for very slight decrease in left 
S: intact to LT b/l. 



LABORATORY:

Notable labs: Chem nl, ca 9.2

Lactate 1.4

VBG 7.34/44/57

Cbc 5.4&gt;40.6&lt;347

INR 1.1, PTT 19.2

Amylase 246, Lipase 330

LFTs: ALT 14, AST 28, Alk P 61

Tbili 1.1, Dbili 0.2



ECG:

NSR @ 75 BPM, nl axis, nl intervals, no evidence hypertrophy or ischemia, unchanged from prior 7/31/87.  



RADIOLOGY/IMAGING:

As noted above



ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN

75 yo woman with a history of R MCA, R cerebellar stroke, TIAs, Iliac vein thrombosis, PFO, and recent RP hematoma and rectus sheath hematoma (at GMH 8/13/87-8/24/87) currently off of anticoagulation because of her recent bleeds.  Pt reports sudden onset of SOB at rest this AM.  



##SOB: Unclear etiology.  CT PE negative however given history of possible iliac vein thrombosis, highly concerning in setting of being off of anticoagulation in the setting of RP and Rectus sheath hematomas.  However, given her rapid recovery in the ED with nebs and oxygen and subsequent weaning to room air, there is lower concern for a PE.  History of iliac vein thrombosis is unclear and not fully imaged on CT today.  

-continue monitor SOB

-nebs prn

-consider reimaging with CT venogram to assess necessity of anticoagulation/IVC filter

-f/u GMH records



##Elevated amylase/lipase: only one episode nausea/vomiting en route with EMS.  Currently no nausea, benign exam, nl WBC.  

-CT with ?dilated pancreatic duct but no evidence of pancreatitis

-RUQ U/S for evaluation of stone disease

-consider possibly 2/2 hypotension and ischemic injury of pancreas during recent admission with acute blood loss.



## Cardiac: 

Continue home atenolol, simvistatin.  



Nutrition: NPO pending assessment of RUQ U/S

IV fluids: D5 &#189; NS +20 KCL at 125 cc/hr

PPX: GI: Omeprazole  DVT: holding anticoagulation in setting of RP hematoma   BOWEL: Colace prn

Code Status: FULL, discussed with patient

Disposition: pending w/u SOB and assessment of elevated amylase/lipase





_________________________________

Dalton Edwards, MD, PGY-1 Pager 67387






****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>