<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2088-12-21

POLK GENERAL HOSPITAL
Internal Medicine
42 Lisbon Lane                             Holden, Matias
Palacios, NE  73819                             97198841
                                              12-21-88
 
 
 
Patient is a 34-year-old man who comes in for follow up on his newly 
diagnosed type II diabetes.  He has been very compliant with his 
medication regimen which consists of metformin 850mg PO t.i.d. and NPH 
insulin subQ q.AM.  He has had 2 episodes of sweating, but he did not 
check his blood sugar at the time.  He has not had any frank 
palpitations or lightheadedness.  He did have 1 episode where he had the 
sensation of several extra heart beats.  This was not accompanied by 
other symptoms including no chest pain.  He has never had a fingerstick 
blood glucose below the mid 150's.  I am looking through his log and see 
that his AM prebreakfast glucoses have been between 178-306 and before 
dinner they have been between 157-296.  He has already met several times 
with Makenzie Kim for diabetes education and for tailoring of his 
therapy and has met with a nutritionist to review the concepts of a 
diabetic diet.  
 
On physical exam, he is in no distress, his weight is 231, his blood 
pressure is 132/78 in the right arm sitting.
 
IMPRESSION AND PLAN: He still has high sugars. I will increase his 
insulin regimen.  He is amenable to adding a second injection and so his 
new regimen will be NPH insulin 15 units before breakfast and 15 units 
before bedtime.  And he continues to take metformin 850mg PO t.i.d. and 
I have given him a prescription for this, #90, refills 3, as well as 
syringes and needles, #60, refills 3.  He is to follow up with me in 
several months and sooner if he has new problems or concerns.  I have 
advised him about increasing his level of activity and about maintaining 
his diet and I have also asked him to contact me if he should have any 
symptoms of hypoglycemia and to obtain his fingerstick glucose reading 
at that time as well.  
 
 
 
_________________________
Xaiden Roberson, M.D.                                                   
 
PZ:WX:4138                                                              
DD:12-21-88                                                             
DT:12-23-88                                                             
DV:12-21-88                                                             
 ******** Approved but not reviewed by Provider ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-12-25





POLK GENERAL HOSPITAL

Internal Medicine

86 Lisbon Lane                             Golden, Matias

Palacios, NE  73819                             97198841

                                              12-25-90 







The patient is a 36-year-old man who comes in with a problem list that 

includes diabetes, high cholesterol, microalbuminuria, and probable lichen simplex 

chronicus.



Since I last saw him, he has changed insurances and needs new refills on 

all his medications. He has been without it for a couple of days. He has 

had no polyuria or polydipsia, and generally feels well. He has no chest 

pain, shortness of breath - no abdominal discomfort. He has no problems 

with is feet or eyesight. He has not seen an eye doctor in the past 

year.



MEDICATIONS:

Lisinopril, metformin, simvastatin, Glyburide. He is not currently using 

the metronidazole pill any longer. 



Laboratory Data: Last cholesterol was an LDL of 101 in September, Hgb 

A1C of 6.1.



PHYSICAL EXAM:

Patient is well appearing. His blood pressure is 140/82 in the right arm 

sitting, but this is also off his lisinopril. His weight is 168 lbs. 

Examination of the feet reveals response to vibratory sensation and 

light touch. There are no lesions. There is an approximately 2cm 

nonscaling plaque over the dorsal lateral aspect of the right ankle, 

which is pruritic.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:

1. Diabetes mellitus. Wait until he is back on his medications before 

checking his laboratory tests, including the microalbumin. He will come 

back in a few months to have these done.

2. Hyperlipidemia. I will check his lipids on his return visit.

3. Lichen simplex chronicus. Topical lidex was prescribed b.i.d. to the 

effected area only.



I will see him in several months in follow up visit on his laboratory 

work.







_________________________

Xaiden Roberson, M.D.



kp:WX:6214; DD:12-25-90; DT:12-28-90; DV:12-25-90 



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================





______________________________                              



Xian, Marlene Xaniyah, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-08-12

                                                       Patient Name: HOLDEN,MATIAS [ MRN: 97198841PGH ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 08/12/94





Reason for Visit	

Return visit for this 39m with hx poorly controlled DM who comes for  further mgmt of DM, HCV.



History of Present Illness	

Decided to change his lantus to bid (30 u bid) and found great response--> bs now 90-120 range mostly, all under 200.  

troubled by his hcv infxn, has been ruminating on how he got it.  had 2 episodes needle sticks at a past job 2+ yrs ago, wonders if could have gotten then.  never used iv drugs, never had partner who used iv drugs.  reviewed methods of transmission, low risk of sexual transmission, etc.





Problems	  

DM	      

H/O NEPHROLITHIASIS	      

ANKLE FRACTURE	      

H/O DRUG ABUSE	      

TOBACCO	      

WORK # 310-7911 EXT 5	      

ROSACEA	      

Elevated lipids	      

Microalbuminuria	      

? migraine	      

FHX: M/F/Sis/Bro DM, F s/p LE amputation; Sis migraines; no CAD/CVA, no htn, no prostate/colon CA	      

New Phone 3/11/94: 124-607-0785, work 485-914-7948	      



Allergies	  

NKA	      



Medications	  

ECASA (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED)	   (81MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s)) PO QD

*   GLUCOSE TEST STRIPS	 TOPICAL   (   take  ) TOP DAILY USE

INSULIN SYRINGES	 FOR DAILY  (   take  ) TP bid and prn

*   LANCETS	 Topical   (   take  ) TOP daily use

LANTUS (INSULIN GLARGINE)	 30 UNITS  SC BID

LISINOPRIL	 10 MG  PO QD

METFORMIN	 850 MG  PO TID

PRAVASTATIN	   (40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s)) PO QHS

on 20 at time of visit



Social History	

Lives with GF and her children.  Is no longer involved with ex-wife, who is mother of his children.   From Portugal originally; lived in OR for 18 yrs, in palacios since 2080, plans to stay.  Recently visited father/family in Portugal.

Has dtr 9, son 11 in Portugal.  Works as aveterinary assisstant, oversees 19 clients, really likes it.  Feels he understands what they are going thru from his own prior experience.  Not happy with his ins plan d/t hi copays & poor rx coverage, but his employer only offers one plan.



No etoh, no drug use currently.  No hx ivdu.

Has Rx coverage, but copays have all been increasing.  



Vital Signs	  

Blood Pressure:	 105/68   Left Arm

Pulse:	 68   Regular

Weight:	 220   Pounds



Physical Exam	

Gen: well appearing, NAD, good spirits.  



Impression	

39m with poorly controlled DM, albuminuria who comes for further mgmt dm and with recently dx'd hcv.  Over 1/2 this 25 minute visit was spent discussing modes of transmission of hcv and counseling regarding likely etiology/plans for bs, as well as disc of DM mgmt.



Plan	

DM: a1c had come down from 11.8-->9.9, but up to 10.4 last check.  now bs much better on total lantus 60u daily, split bid.  cont current regimen, recheck a1c next visit.  gave # for pt to r/s f/u with optho, last visit spring 2093.  cont metformin.  had abnl findings w/photos taken on dil exam; was to have f/u 2/94 but didn't happen.   malb elevated 97 in 9/93; on acei.  taking asa qd.  had pneumovax 2090.  foot exam nl 12/93.



Albuminuria: cont acei.  last 97 9/93.  cr stable 1.2 12/93.  follow cr on metformin.



HCV: hiv was neg.  hbv immune.  hav immune.  he had a needle stick around june 2092 at work, wasn't tested at that time for hcv/hiv, but had f/u test (for hiv only apparently) w/dr. roberson, neg at that time.  discussed that hcv may well have been from needle stick.  ruq u/s was nl, hcv genotype 1a.  lfts have been consistently nl, last 6/94.  was to have liver bx w/dr. kruse in april, but never occurred.  i will contact dr. kruse to facilitate arrangement of bx.



Atypical nevus: dnka appt w/derm for eval in march.  will rerefer at future visit.  copays $35 for nonpcp visit - difficult for him.



Hyperlipidemia: has low hdl 33 in 6/94, reviewed today & rec'd exercise.  ldl 119 on pravastatin -- inc to 40 mg.  lfts nl 6/94.  recheck lipids/lfts on inc prava next visit.



HM: lipids as above.  had Td booster 2089.  re: tob cessation/cutting down - he remains precontemplative.  tried wellbutrin in past w/no effect.  gave him # for pharm to consider Rx assistance progs, as he has been interested in this, filled out some paperwork for cheaper meds in past.  also offered to switch back to nph for cost reasons today, but he declined.



rtc 2-3mos f/u dm, hcv,  check lipids/lfts, umalb







______________________________                              



Kari Marlene Pryor, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-04-24

EDVISIT^97198841^HOLDEN, MATIAS^04/24/95^XIE, LORI

The patient was seen primarily by the PA.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed evaluation,

plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 41-year-old male

with diabetes and high blood pressure who presents to the

Emergency Room complaining of some sore throat symptoms for 3

days also reporting some chest discomfort that has been on and

off since Friday.  Denies any association with cough or

movement.  I guess it is at rest and also with activity and

noticing also increasing shortness of breath with activity.  No

lower extremity swelling and no PND.  Has been having off and on

chest discomfort.  However, in the past four months, had negative

ETT at Smithers Albany Center per his report.  Denies any

headache, fevers or chills or recent travel.  Did have a negative

ETT by his report at an outside hospital four months ago.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for hypertension, diabetes

insulin requiring, and hypercholesterolemia.

ALLERGIES:  He has no known allergies.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Insulin, lisinopril, metformin, and

anticholesterol medications.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient is a current smoker, denies any

alcohol or IV drug use.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Hernia repair in the past.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Sore throat, cough, shortness of breath, and

chest discomfort.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Afebrile, normal vital signs. He is

otherwise an overweight male in no acute distress.  Sclerae

nonicteric.  Lungs are clear to auscultation.  Cardiac exam S1,

S2, regular rhythm with no gallops, rubs, or murmurs.  Abdomen is

very soft and nontender.  No JVD on exam.  Back on head and neck

exam, TMs are clear bilaterally.  Oropharynx is clear.  Neck is

supple.

LABORATORY DATA:  Currently, still pending.

EKG normal sinus rhythm with no ST-T segment changes or evidence

of ischemia or infarct.

IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  A 41-year-old male, diabetic, hypertensive,

presents with URI symptoms.  No evidence of exam or indication

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

chest discomfort at any time as he has had for a few months,

worsening recently.  Does not appear to be exertional related,

however, given his significant risk factors and no documented

stress studies in our system we will place in Observation for a

rule out an ETT in the morning.

______________________________

XIE, LORI M.D.

D: 04/25/95

T: 04/25/95

Dictated By: XIE, LORI

eScription document:2-6202967 BF





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-06-06

                                                       Patient Name: HOLDEN,MATIAS [ MRN: 97198841PGH ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 06/06/2096





Reason for Visit

   Return visit for this 41m with hx HCV, poorly controlled DM who comes after recent job loss, depression.



History of Present Illness

   doing about the same, fluoxetine hasn't helped much, perhaps a little. &nbsp;has been on it since our last visit. hasn't yet been able to fill ativan rx from dr oliveira bc of holiday w/e, but will p/u today. &nbsp;was glad to see dr oliveira, helpful.<BR>saw a lawyer who agrees that his work termination likely is a violation of his rights, and atty is planning to pursue the case.<BR>brings bs log, has kept perfect records for past 3 wks since dr kenny visit: &nbsp;FBS 8am 130-190, outliers of 101 and 340 which was after big amt rice the night before. &nbsp;HS bs 10pm 120-180 x one outlier 235 the first day. these are the best his bs has been in many months. &nbsp;understands target a1c values.<BR>apparently on 40mg pravachol, rather than 80 as i had thought. &nbsp;has been taking 40 mg for several mos, at least since feb.<BR>c/o occ pain in LUQ, feels like a muscle cramp, occurs when at rest, sitting watching tv--> will feel pain on getting up from chair, sore to the touch, goes away on own after 5-10min. &nbsp;has been happening off and on for 5mos. &nbsp;no HB. &nbsp;no relation to food. &nbsp;no other gi sxs.



Problems

      DM        

      H/O NEPHROLITHIASIS        

      ANKLE FRACTURE        

      H/O DRUG ABUSE        

      TOBACCO        

      WORK # 310-7911 EXT 5        

      ROSACEA        

      Elevated lipids        

      Microalbuminuria        

      ? migraine        

      New Phone 3/11/94: 124-607-0785, work 485-914-7948        

      HCV        

      ETT SAC 12/94 neg        



Allergies

      NKA        



Medications

      ECASA (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED)     (81MG TABLET EC take 1 Tablet(s)) PO QD

      FLUOXETINE HCL   20 MG (20MG CAPSULE take 1 ) PO QD

      *   GLUCOSE TEST STRIPS   TOPICAL   (   take  ) TOP DAILY USE

      HUMALOG INSULIN (INSULIN LISPRO)   30 UNITS (100 U/ML VIAL take  ML) SC before dinner

      INSULIN SYRINGES   FOR  (     take  ) TP bid and prn

      *   LANCETS   Topical   (   take  ) TOP daily use

      LISINOPRIL   20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1 ) PO QD

      LORAZEPAM   1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1 ) PO TID x 15 day(s)

      METFORMIN   1000 MG (1000MG TABLET take 1 ) PO BID

      NPH HUMULIN INSULIN   70 UNITS IN THE AM, 50 UNITS AT HS (100 U/ML VIAL take  ML) SC bid before breakfast and before HS

      PRAVASTATIN   80 MG (80MG TABLET take 1 ) PO QHS

      TRIAMCINOLONE ACETONIDE 0.1%     (0.1% CREAM  take 1 ) TOP BID



Social History

   Smoking: 5 cigs/d.  Trying to quit.  Did manage to stop for 1 year, started again due to pressure/anxiety.<BR>Alcohol: none.<BR>Just lost his job as a veterinary aide - pt feels this was due to his elevated BG, has called in sick a few times, sometimes very sleepy.<BR>Lives alone.<BR>



Review of Systems

   No chest pain. &nbsp;No sob. &nbsp;Occ diarrhea with metformin, manageable. &nbsp;No abd pain x as per hpi, no n/v, brbpr, melena. &nbsp;No constipation. Wt down 6lb. &nbsp;Poor sleep. &nbsp;Anhedonia, no SI/HI. &nbsp;Poor motivation, but trying to make himself take his insulin, etc. &nbsp;nO HYPOGLYCEMIC SXS.



Vital Signs

      Blood Pressure:   110/61   Left Arm

      Pulse:   61   Regular

      Weight:   220   Pounds



Physical Exam

   Gen: well appearing, NAD, good spirits. &nbsp;HEENT: &nbsp;PERRL. EOMI. OP benign w/mmm, no lesions. &nbsp;Neck: supple, full ROM, no LAN. &nbsp;JVP flat. &nbsp;Carotids 2+ b/l without bruits. &nbsp;Chest: &nbsp;Lungs CTAB, no wheezes or rales. &nbsp;CV: &nbsp;RRR, nl s1, s2, no m/r/g. &nbsp;Abd: &nbsp;NABS, soft, NT/ND, no HSM, no guarding. &nbsp;Ext: wwp, no edema, clubbing or cyanosis. &nbsp;DP 2+ b/l. &nbsp;Neuro: nonfocal exam. &nbsp;



Laboratory Data

   bs 283



Impression

   41m with poorly controlled DM, albuminuria, HCV, hyperlipidemia, depressive sxs who comes for further mgmt dm, depression after recent job loss.



Plan

   Depression: situational. &nbsp;no si/hi.<BR>-inc fluoxetine to 40 qd, new rx given<BR>-fill meds & f/u dr oliveira as planned<BR>-cont work with legal advocate and financial counselor here to help with loss of job/insurance; disability forms in process as well<BR>-support offered<BR><BR>DM: a1c had come down from 11.8-->9.9, but up to 11.1 1/96. &nbsp;no appreciable improvemt in bs with dietary changes and some symptomatic hyperglycemia, now better since change in regimen<BR>--saw dr. kenny for additional help/consultation, doing substantially better on nph 70/50 am/pm, humalog pre dinner<BR>--inc pm NPH to 55 units<BR>--cont metformin 1000 bid (had been taking tid by mistake; written instructions given to dec to bid)<BR>-- had f/u ophtho scheduled 4/96; will check to see if this occurred<BR>--malb elevated 200 11/94; on acei--> dec to 35 in 6/95 on inc dose acei 20 qd lisinopril, recheck today<BR>--taking asa qd. &nbsp;<BR>--had pneumovax 2090. &nbsp;<BR>--foot exam nl 12/93.<BR>--flu shot done at work 2095<BR>--bp at target on acei<BR><BR>?OSA: sxs suggestive<BR>-sleep study referral made, appt sched 5/96, unclear if this happened, will need to review<BR><BR>Albuminuria: improved on inc dose acei. &nbsp;200s 11/94--> 36 in 6/95 <BR>-na/k/cr nl 1/96<BR><BR>HCV: hiv was neg. &nbsp;hbv immune (hbv vax thru work). &nbsp;hav immune. &nbsp;he had a needle stick around june 2092 at work, wasn't tested at that time for hcv/hiv, but had f/u test (for hiv only apparently) w/dr. roberson, neg at that time. hcv may well have been from needle stick. &nbsp;ruq u/s was nl, hcv genotype 1a. &nbsp;lfts have been consistently virtually nl, last nl 1/96 <BR>-bx with fibrosis<BR>-have tried to help him get ifn at reduced cost; see letters to pt since 1/95; not discussed today given DM priority issue<BR>-ast/alt today<BR><BR>Atypical nevus: dnka appt w/derm for eval in 3/94. &nbsp;will rerefer at future visit. &nbsp;copays $35 for nonpcp visit - difficult for him. &nbsp;await clarification of insurance status (hopefully will obtain free care), and can then rerefer<BR><BR>Hyperlipidemia: low hdl 30, ldl 141 on pravachol 3/96; per LMR was on 40qd at that time, but he believes he was only taking 20qd at that time; confirms that he has now been on 40 qd for at least several mos, however<BR>-recheck today on 40 qd<BR>-lfts nl 1/96, recheck<BR><BR>ED: suspect in part related to DM, had good response to small dose viagra. &nbsp;mood issues may contribute as well. &nbsp;improved off celexa.<BR>-has prn rx for viagra, not using recently, not discussed today<BR><BR>HM: lipids as above. &nbsp;<BR>had Td booster 2089. &nbsp;<BR>re: tob cessation/cutting down - he has made sig progress, not discussed today. &nbsp;tried wellbutrin in past w/no effect. &nbsp;<BR>pneumovax utd. <BR>flu done qyr<BR><BR>rtc 3-6 wks depr, DM, ?saw ophtho/sleep study

______________________________                              



Kari Marlene Pryor, MD



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>