<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2082-02-28

c.c.  Preop PE for cataract extraction on 3/7



S:  ROS:  General:  no history of fatigue, weight change, loss of appetite, or weakness.



HEENT:  no history of head injury, glaucoma, tinnitus, vertigo, motion sickness, URI, hearing loss.



Cardiovascular: + hypertension - adequate control for patient on zestril, EKG - w/ Q wave in II, III, f and poor r wave progression w/ ? inferior infarct, no chnage form 2065

no hypercholesterolemia, murmur, rheumatic fever, syncope, palpitations, edema, dyspnea.



Respiratory:  no history of asthma, COPD, TB, sleep apnea, SOB.



GI:  + history of GERD - stopped zantac about 6 months ago and had occ. reflux, but know symptoms are more frequent w/ epigatsric burning, no hx of PUD, bleeding, change in bowel habits.



Hepatobiliary:  no history of jaudice, hepatits, colic.



GU:  no history of CRF, hematuria, obstruction, colic-stones, UTI.



Musculoskeletal:  + history of arthritis, has some joint pain and stiffnes, notices increase in pain in left shoulder w/ movement, no limitation of ROM.  Pt was using tylenol only for pain control, but that doesn't work with the shoulder pain.  Does ROM exercises, but not daily



Neuro:  no history of seizures, stroke, TIAs, migraine, radiculopathy.  Pt has + hx for diabetic neuropathy w/ parasthesias in extremities and now notes numbness in feet at noc interfering w/ sleep



Peripheral Vascular:  no history of claudication, DVT, varicosities, cramps, ulcers.



Endocrine:  + history of diabetes mellitus.  Pt currently on glucophage and glyburide.  Pt's glyburide was recently increased to 10mg  BID form 5 mg BID.  Pt has seen the nutritionsit recently as well and has f/u appt.  She denies eating sweets.  States she has toast and egg for brkfst, lunch and dinner eats chicken or fish w/ rice and plaintain and veggie, for snacks she has fruit: banana, grapefruit or apple; drinks are water or diet soda



Heme/Onc:  no history of bruising, bleeding, anemia, lymphadenopathy, chemotherapy or radiation therapy.



Psych:  no history of anxiety, panic attacks, depression, or psychosis.



Skin:  no history of rash, abnormal pigmentation, pruritis.

================ Problems ================

LIPOMA          

FOOT PAIN          

SHOULDER PAIN          

URINARY TRACT INFECTION          

HYPOPHOSPHATEMIA          

ABNORMAL LIVER FUNCTION TESTS  - last tests ast and alt wnl 10/2081                  

OBESITY          

THYROID NODULE - dx 2074 s/p bx, treated w/ synthroid for several years, nl TSH since         

DIABETES         

PRURITUS          

BURSITIS          

RHEUMATOID ARTHRITIS/OA          

SBO -  Hospitalized 11/2080 resolved with conservative rx. Followed by Dr. Person





================ Medications ================

*   LANCETS    

*   One touch test strips  As  QD

GLUCOPHAGE (METFORMIN) 1000MG 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

glyburide  10mg PO BID

ZESTRIL (LISINOPRIL) 10MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

NEURONTIN (GABAPENTIN) 400MG 1 Capsule(s) PO QHS(increased form 300mg on 2/28)

zanatc 150mg qhs, restarted on 2/28/82





================ Allergies ================

NKDA                    





================ HealthMaintenance ================

Breast Exam	12/06/2081	nl Done 

Cholesterol	11/08/2077	186  

Colonoscopy	12/06/2081	scheduled  

HBA1C	10/28/2081	13.01  AFFINITY RESULT HBA1C CHROMATOGRAPH SUGGESTS A HEMOGLOBINOPATHY - SUGGEST SENDING A FUTURE SAMPLE MARKED HBA1C BY "AFFINITY" METHOD. IF CLINICALLY APPROPRIATE, ALSO SUGGEST SENDING A SAMPLE FOR HEMOGLOBIN ELECTROPHORESIS. *** AFFINITY *** OTHER HEMOGLOBINOPATHY ***

Influenza Vaccine	09/27/2081	L arm  

Mammogram	01/10/2082	BilScrMammo  

Microalbumin	05/14/2081	3.0  PERFORMED AT VAN WERT COUNTY HOSPITAL (NOTE)Reference Range:  0.0-2.0  mg/dl

Ophthal Exam	12/06/2081	sceduled for 1/22/82 with Dr. Xavier Done elsewhere 

Pap Smear	11/25/2080	NL VAGINA AND CERVIX/NO D/C Done 

Pneumovax	12/24/2075	 Done 

Rectal Exam	06/12/2079	No rectal masses  

Smoking status	12/16/2080	 Never a smoker 

Stool Guaiac Test	06/12/2079	Negative  Guaiac cards given x 3

UA-Protein	05/20/2081	NEGATIVE  



O:  NAD wt 180 144/80; 144/80 - rt arm, 3 minute intervals between readings

HEENT - eyes - not examined, otherwise unremarkable

neck - no carotid bruit, thyroid small rightsided, 1cm , nodule noted, no bruit

pulses - 2+ throughout

lungs - clear, good aeration  rr 12 and regular

abd - obese, soft , nontender, no organomegaly, normoactive bowle sounds

heart - 80 rrr s1s2

shoulder - from bil, + pain around 140 degrees on left



A:  1.  Diabetes -hopefully better control w/ med and diet changes

P:  cont w/ current meds

check hga1c, FBS, diet changes reinforced, pt to f/u w/ nutritionist



2.  Neuropathy - recent increase in symptoms 

P: increase neurotin to 400mg qhs

f/u if no improvemtn



3.  Shoulder pain/ arthritis hx

P:  change tylenol to celebrex 100mg BID to start after surg

ROM exercises as shown qd

f/u if no control



4. HTN - okay control for patient

P: cont zestril, check bun, crt lytes



5. GERD - increased symptoms

P:  restart zantac 150mg qhs

cont on reflux diet restrictions



6. cataract surg - pt ready, will not start celebrex til after surg



P. Ponce MS, RN, CS

Adult Nurse Practitioner



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-04-29

BP elevated at last Diabetes Clinic visit. 140/80 on HCTZ and ACE. Lo dose B blocker suggested.



Also c/o pain, clicking and locking in L knee.



PE: WD/WN in NAD



Vital signs

BP 140/80 Left Arm, P 84 Regular, Wt 198 lb 



L knee - no increased warmth, +/- effussion



Plan: MRI of L knee

        Start Lopressor 25 mg qd 

        RTC 1 week to se English for BP check 





_____________________________________________

Nebraska G. Hunter, MD











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-02-28

       



Team 1  Admission Note

Admission Date:  February 4, 2085

Patient Name:  Vanessa Asher

MRN#:  0467550

Attending:  Hunter, Nebrasska, MD

Intern: Len Wayne-Gregory, MD

Historian: patient, records



Chief Complaint:

Nausea and vomiting



HPI: 



74 yo female with a past medical history of poorly controlled diabetes (Hem A1C 10.3 in 2/85), hypertension and  hyperlipidemia who presents with two days of left eye pain and a one day history of nausea and vomiting.  The patient's eye pain began on 2 days prior to admission and has progressed to a severe stabbing pain that precipitated a visit to the MARY ED. The patient notes that her vision is more cloudy that usual although she does not see well out of that eye at baseline.  No right eye symptoms.   The patient also developed nausea and abdominal tenderness this AM.  The pain was mild.  She describes the pain as centered in her epigastrium.  She does not report chest pain or pressure and reports no symptoms of radiation to her shoulder or jaw.  She notes that the nausea is not associated with exercise or relieved by rest.  The discomfort has been constant since it began this am.  She denies hematemasis, fevers, chills, diarrhea.  The patient denies ever having chest pain or shortness of breath with exertion. 



IN the ED the patient was found to have a markedly elevated Intraocular pressure of 54.  She was treated with steroid, alpha blocker, Beta blocker drops and carbonic anhydrase inhibitors (both PO and drops) to lower her pressure.  The patient was thought to have acute closed angle glaucoma caused by proliferative diabetic retinopathy. 



Past Medical History:  

Diabetes:  HemA1C 10.3 in Feb 2085.  She has been on insulin for 3 years and has been a diabetic for 7 years

Eye

-Cataract in OD

-Laser ablation of diabetic retinopathy in OS

-vitreous hemorrhage in OS

Hypertension 

Diabetes mellitus

History of Small Bowel Obstruction in 2080

Anemia:  found to have sickle cell trait.  Iron studies, B12, folate WNL. Hct stable

? history of pancreatitis



Meds:

Humalog 75/25 34u at bkfst

Humalog 75/25 18u at dinner

Glucophage 1000mg BID

Neurontin 300mg HS (sometimes skips)

Bayer ASA 81mg QD

HCTZ 25mg QD

Norvasc 10mg QD (started yesterday; prescribed by Dr. Zajac)

Metoprolol 50mg, 1/2 tablet BID

Lisinopril 40mg QD

Lipitor 10mg QD

Ranitidine 150mg QD



All:  NKDA



FH:  

F deceased age 63 from "kidney problems", M deceased age 47 from fall and chest infection,  3 brothers A&W,  one brother died in his 70's with prostate Ca, 2 sisters deceased, one post op, the other had sudden death age 60's



SH:  

Pt lives with one of her daughters.  She does not smoke or drink ETOH



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION

Vital Signs: 98  132/70  57  20  100% on RA

General Appearance:  well in NAD

HEENT:  NC/AT, PERRLA, OP clear with MMM

Skin:  No rashes, no petechia

Neck:  Supple, trachea midline, JVD flat, 

Lymphatics: No palpable LAN

Chest:  CTAB

Heart: RRR, normal S1/S2 tones, soft SEM at USB

Abdomen:  soft, minimal epigastric tenderness to deep palpation. No rebound or guarding.  No masses,  no hepatosplenomegally.  Positive bowel sounds.  

Extremities:  warm, no c/c/e

Neuro: A&Ox3, non focal exam



LABS 



NA        	136       	          	          	          	          

K         	3.9       	          	          	          	          

CL        	108       	          	          	          	          

CO2       	25.0      	          	          	          	          

BUN       	26(H)     	          	          	          	          

CRE       	1.5       	          	          	          	          

GLU       	399(H)    	          	          	          	          



 



CA        	9.5       	          	          	          	          

PHOS      	4.4       	          	          	          	          

MG        	1.7       	          	          	          	          

TBILI     	0.6       	          	          	          	          

DBILI     	0.2       	          	          	          	          

TP        	8.2       	          	          	          	          

ALB       	3.8       	          	          	          	          

GLOB      	4.4(H)    	          	          	          	          

AMY       	144(H)    	          	          	          	          

LIPS      	7.0(H)    	          	          	          	           



ALT/SGPT  	14        	          	          	          	          

AST/SGOT  	16        	          	          	          	          

ALKP      	80        	          	          	          	          

TBILI     	0.6       	          	          	          	          

DBILI     	0.2       	          	          	          	          

 



CK-MB     	Negative  	          	          	          	          

TROP-I    	Negative  	          	          	          	          

 



WBC       	8.5       	          	          	          	          

RBC       	3.58(L)   	          	          	          	          

HGB       	10.8(L)   	          	          	          	          

HCT       	31.9(L)   	          	          	          	          

MCV       	89        	          	          	          	          

MCH       	30.2      	          	          	          	          

MCHC      	33.9      	          	          	          	          

PLT       	200       	          	          	          	          

RDW       	14.6(H)   	          	          	          	          

DIFFR     	Received  	          	          	          	          

METHOD    	Auto      	          	          	          	          

%NEUT     	75(H)     	          	          	          	          

%LYMPH    	22        	          	          	          	          

%MONO     	2(L)      	          	          	          	          

%EOS      	1         	          	          	          	          

%BASO     	0         	          	          	          	          

ANEUT     	6.37      	          	          	          	          

ALYMP     	1.87      	          	          	          	          

AMONS     	0.19(L)   	          	          	          	          

AEOSN     	0.05(L)   	          	          	          	          

ABASOP    	0.03      	          	          	          	          

ANISO     	None      	          	          	          	          

HYPO      	None      	          	          	          	          

MACRO     	None      	          	          	          	          

MICRO     	None      	          	          	          	          

 



PT        	12.3(T)   	          	          	          	          

PT-INR    	1.0(T)    	          	          	          	          

PTT       	20.8(LT)  	          	          	          	          



DIAGNOSTIC STUDIES: 



CXR: 

	No CHF.  On the lateral view only there is some increased patchy

	opacity in the posterior clear space which could represent

	developing atelectasis or, in the proper clinical setting, could

	represent a subtle focus focus of pneumonia.  There is new

	blunting of the posterior costophrenic angles consistent with a

	small amount of pleural fluid.



Abdominal Ultrasound:

NEGATIVE STUDY.



Exercise Stress Test:

  No ST segment changes were observed during this test.

        Arrhythmias:

          None.

        Comments:

        Fair exercise capacity. At peak exercise, patient complained of

        indigestion feeling relieved by belching after several minutes.

        Negative for ischemia.



EKG: 

NSR.  New TWI in V2, q in III, normal axis and intervals, no ST changes

	          	          

ASSESSMENT/PLAN:



The patient is a 74 yo female with poorly diabetes mellitus, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia who presents with acute closed angle glaucoma and nausea and vomiting. 



1.	Glaucoma.



Likely secondary to proliferative diabetic retinopathy.  As recommended by the ophthalmologic consultant, I will give the following meds

	-Xalatan qHS

-Pred Forte QID

-Timolol BID

-Trusopt BID

-Acetazolamide BID

-Alphagan

IOP will be monitored closely.  If it does not trend down, the patient may need surgery in the AM.



2.	Nausea and Vomiting



The differential diagnosis is broad and includes symptoms related to glaucoma, atypical angina, symptoms from an SBO given her history, chemical pancreatitis and viral gastroenteritis.  Of these, I believe that symptoms from glaucoma or gastroenteritis is most likely.  

-	I ordered a KUB on the floor which showed normal bowel gas per unofficial rads read.  

-	I think angina is unlikely given her history.  However, I believe that she needs a stress test given her severe diabetes.  I will be unable to arrange one for tomorrow (weekend day), but I believe she needs one as an out patient study in the near future.  I will give ASA, B blocker and ACE.  I will not give heparin given that her TIMI score is only 1. 

-	Chemical pancreatitis is possible although her exam is so bengin. I will therefore give pt full liqs tonight and follow her for pancreatitis symptoms.



3.	Chronic Renal Failure



This is likely secondary to diabetic nephropathy. Pt is at baseline creatinine



4.	Anemia



Pt is at baseline creatinine.  She was found to have sickle cell trait.  Iron studies, B12, folate WNL. Hct stable



5.	Diabetes



Will continue NPH and Regular insulin and cover with SSI.



6.	Prophylaxis



On nexium.  Holding heparin prophylaxis because the patient is ambulatory.







_______________

Len Wayne-Gregory, MD

28918















****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-07-17

 

Team D Internal Medicine Admit Note



Pt:Asher,Vanessa

MR#:	0467550

Date of Admission:7/17/85 



Attending: Dr. Nebraska Hunter

PCP: Dr. Hunter



HPI : 75 year old woman with PMH DM, HTN who presents with four episodes of substernal chest pain on day of admit. Episodes occurred at rest , lasted 30 seconds to 1 minute and were associated with nausea but no vomiting. No SOB, no radiation. She describes the pain as sharp. 



ED Course: On arrival to the ED vitals were BP 176/83 P 63 RR 20 T 98. She received ASA 325mg but was not felt to have pulse room for beta blocker. Her EKG was read as unchanged from prior and she had a negative first set of cardiac markers.  





PMH:   

DM - on Lispro insulin

Anemia - baseline Hct 33

CRI - baseline Cr  1.5

HTN

RA



Meds: 

Hctz (HYDROCHLOROTHIAZIDE) 25MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Asa (CHILDRENS) (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID (CHILDRENS)) 81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Ranitidine HCL 150 MG PO QD , For sx of reflux. For future prescriptions, please note that pt prefers Brand name only

Zestril (LISINOPRIL) 40MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO qd 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Lopressor (METOPROLOL TARTRATE) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Humalog MIX 75/25 (INSULIN LISPRO MIX 75/25) 30 U SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST/15 units before dinner 

Humalog MIX 75/25 (INSULIN LISPRO MIX 75/25) 15 U SC QPM BEFORE SUPPER 





Allergies: NKDA



SH:  	

	Tob: denies

	EtOH:  occasional

	Illicits:   denies 

	



ROS: LE parathesias, numbness. Unintentional 15 lbs weight loss x 2 months, describes decreased appetite. Otherwise negative. 



Exam:  	

	VS:  173/86 T 98.5 P 60 RR 22 100% on RA

              GEN:Alert and oriented x 3, pleasant, coopertive 

HEENT: EOMI, MMM

Neck:  	No LAD, JVP difficult to assess

Lungs: CTAB

Cor:  	RRR, no m/r/g

Abd:   	soft , diffusely tender, BS + , no HSM

Extr:  	 Trace edema b/l. NO palpable cord, neg. Homan's b/l

              Neuro:  . moves all extremities, alert and oriented able to give complete history. 

             GI/GU : Guiac negative per Dr. Jeffrey in ED

              



Labs:



Chemistry Detail for ASHER, VANESSA J



   MARY  PLASMA         16-Jul-2085 21:51  Accession# 4349B13794



Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units



Plasma Sodium                    138                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.3                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  104                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             35               H        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.6              H        (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Plasma Glucose                   125              H        (70-110)       mg/dl

Calcium                          9.3                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       4.3                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        2.3              H        (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Total Protein                    7.8                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl

Albumin                          3.7                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl

Globulin                         4.1                       (2.6-4.1)      g/dl

Direct Bilirubin                 0.1                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl

Total Bilirubin                  0.2                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase             62                        (30-100)       U/L

Transaminase-SGPT                14                        (7-30)         U/L

Transaminase-SGOT                16                        (9-32)         U/L





Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

Troponin-I                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)



Hematology Detail for ASHER, VANESSA J



   MARY  BLOOD          16-Jul-2085 17:34  Accession# 6184O55309



Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units



WBC                              7.8                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              29.1             L        (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              9.8              L        (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              3.34             L        (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              181                       (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              87                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              29.4                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             33.8                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              14.5                      (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               12.4                      (11.3-13.3)    sec

APTT                             23.0                      (22.1-35.1)    sec



             	     

EKG: NSR @64, normal axis, normal intervals, low voltage, < 1mm ST elevation in v4 and v6, 

both present on prior EKG of 2/85. 

CXR: Grossly stable chest examination, with no evidence for CHF.



__________________________________________________________________________________



A/P:  75 year old woman with DM, HTN p/w atypical chest pain. Ddx includes ischemia, chest wall pain, PNA, PE. No clinical signs of infection, negative CXR. No tacycardia, hypoxia or  sig. DVT/PE risk factores. Plan to r/o ACS by markers obtain adenosine MIBI in am. 

1)	Chest pain

a.	Cycle enzymes

b.	Lopressor as pulse allows

c.	Adenosine MIBI in AM 

2)	DM

a.	Hold Humalog while NPO. RISS

b.	Some signs of DM complications, followed by PCP

3)	HTN 

        a .Home regimen of Hctz/lisonopril/lopressor. Cr at baseline, so not holding

            lisinopril

        b. Hold BB for adenosine MIBI in am

4)	Weight Loss

a.	Current with age appropriate cancer screening. PCP f/u.

        5)  Prophy - Fragmin 2500 U SC qd 



  

        



_______________________________

J. Joseph Moreno, MD 

Pager # 43219      



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>