<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2072-12-16


MRN: 56817864

CAROLYN HUNTINGTON BAILEY HEALTH CENTER
468 Kristina Street                                Xia, Jean
North East, AL 81699                       CHB9278143
(687) 396-2722                                12-15-72


CHIEF COMPLAINT: Ms. Xia is a 53 year old woman who comes in in 
follow up. She notes that she is still having occasional sweats at 
night. She is using the clonidine but she can't take it two times a day, 
it makes her too sleepy, so she takes it about 3:30 towards the end of 
her workday and then again before she goes to bed. She is having some 
right lower back pain and otherwise is feeling well.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Negative except as noted. She is also taking the 
Cozaar which she had been taking before. 

She was called back in today as a result of labs which were done 
recently which showed hemoglobin A1C of 8.7, an elevated urine 
microalbuminuria and hypertension which needed follow up.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: On exam today, she is well developed and well 
nourished in no acute distress. Blood pressure 158/116, pulse 80, weight 
166. Pupils are equal and equally reactive to light. Lids and 
conjunctiva normal. Retinal fields normal. Disks sharp. Mouth and 
pharynx without erythema or exudate. No adenopathy or tenderness in the 
submandibular, cervical, posterior cervical, supraclavicular areas. 
Heart sounds: S1, S2, with a II/VI systolic murmur heard best at the 
right sternal border. No rub or gallop. Her chest was clear to 
auscultation anteriorly and posteriorly with no rales, wheezes or 
rhonchi. She was clear to percussion. She has normal bowel sounds. Her 
abdomen was soft and nontender, no mass, organomegaly, and no guarding, 
no rebound. Her extremities are without edema, cyanosis or clubbing. She 
has no spine or flank tenderness. Her neck is supple, no bruits. Her 
skin is essentially quite dry and itchy. She has multiple dark, 
hyperpigmented, post-inflammatory scarring on her lower extremities. Her 
mouth and pharynx are without erythema or exudate. 

IMPRESSION/PLAN:
1. Hypertension. Her blood pressure is really not well controlled. I 
will add atenolol to her regimen 50mg PO q.d. She drinks one cup of 
coffee a day and rarely has alcohol although she notes that she will 
occasionally have one, a scotch, on Friday or Saturday. She does not do 
drugs. She will return in three week for follow up of her blood 
pressure and at that time for a physical exam for which she will be due. 

2. Diabetes. The patient had been told in the past that she had diabetes 
but she was told she did not need any sort of treatment for it. Her 
creatinine was 0.8 last month and I explained to her that with her 
elevated hemoglobin at 8.7 she needs treatment. We will start her on 
Glucophage 500mg PO b.i.d. I expect we will need to increase this and if 
she tolerates this she should increase it to 1000mg over the next week. 
I also explained to her that if she does not eat or she is unable to eat 
or if she is NPO she needs to stop taking this medication. I suggested 
she actually take it with food to insure that she only takes when she is 
eating. I gave her a referral to Ophthalmology and to Podiatry. She also 
requested a glucometer machine and this was ordered for her along with 

CAROLYN HUNTINGTON BAILEY HEALTH CENTER
592 Kristina Street                                Xia, Jean
North East, AL 81699                       CHB9278143
(687) 396-2722                                12-16-72
Page 2


lancets, alcohol wipes and test strips and again she will return in two 
weeks for follow up.


______________________________
Yolanda Osburn, M.D.

CP:FO:3549 ; DD:12-16-72 ; DT:12-16-72 ; DV:12-16-72 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-04-23



Carolyn Huntington Bailey Health Center

592 Kristina Street                                        XIA, JEAN

North East, AL 81699                            58269151

(375) 512-0897                                            04/23/76


SUBJECTIVE:  The patient comes in today for followup of various problems.  She has hypertension.  She reports she ran out of medication she received yesterday for refills but has not gotten them yet.  She brings in her medication bottles.  Apparently, for her blood pressure, she is taking Norvasc and Cozaar, for her diabetes she is taking Glucotrol and Glucophage.



Regarding her diabetes, she says her fasting sugar are somewhere around 90.  Her last hemoglobin A1c was in 11/2075 and was 6.4%.  Her hypertension, she has been out of medication for three or four day, but she generally reports is well controlled.  She does not know why she was on atenolol, but has been taking it.  She has no complaints.



She does complain of lower back pain.  She says she has had this for many many years.  She underwent physical therapy last year which was at Schroder Hospital.  She says she has no trauma.  She has pain across the lower back.  She rates it 8/10.  She has it everyday and radiates down to her right leg.  It has been worse recently.  She takes Aleve with minimal relief.  She says that she wants a speciality referral.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She has no chest pain or pressure, palpitations, pedal edema.  She has no shortness of breath, cough, or wheezing.  She has no urinary frequency or urgency.  She has no nausea or vomiting, no diarrhea, heartburn or abdominal pain.



Medications

Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 100 MG PO QD , NEEDS TO MAKE AN APPOINTMENT

Glucophage (METFORMIN) 1000 MG take bid bid PO BID 

Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 10 MG take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

Glucotrol XL (GLIPIZIDE XL) 5 MG take qd Tablet(s) PO QD 

Ultram (TRAMADOL) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO Q6H PRN pain 

Skelaxin (METAXALONE) 800 MG (800MG TABLET take 1) PO TID PRN muscle pain 





Problems

Diabetes 

HX kidney stones 

Perimenopausal sx 

Hypertension 





Allergies

Clonidine Hcl - Sleepiness, 

Codeine - Rash, 





Vital signs

BP 174/100, P 72, Wt 163 lb 





Gen: Well appearing in NAD

ENT-Sclera were white, conjuctiva clear. The oropharynx was pink without exudate.  The neck was supple with out adenopathy.  

LUNG- clear bilaterally, without rhonci, wheeze or rales, Normal excursion was noted.

Cor- heart rate was normal, rhythm was regular.  No murmurs, gallops or rubs were detected

ABD- soft, nontender, with bowel sounds present. No organomegaly was detected.

Extremities:  no clubbing cyanosis or edema. No swelling or erythema was noted on joint examOn examination, there is pain on palpation of the lower lumbar region including over the sacroiliac area.  She has positive straight leg raise on the right.

Skin- no abnormal lesions noted.



 

MMP

ASSESSMENT:

1.  Hypertension, poorly controlled at this time.  We will have her start the Norvasc and Cozaar, have her return in two weeks for followup of blood pressure.

2.  Diabetes.  I will check a hemoglobin A1c.  It is due, it has been six months.  I will have her continue Glucophage at this point.

3.  Lower back pain.  I will obtain x-ray of the lower back.  We will have her see Orthopedics for evaluation of her back pain.





______________________________

Charles Moran, M.D.

Dictated By: Charles Moran

eScription document:0-0545950 SFFocus

DD: 04/23/76

DT: 04/24/76

DV: 04/23/76



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-01-22



Carolyn Huntington Bailey Health Center

592 Kristina Street                                        XIA, JEAN

North East, AL 81699                            58269151

(375) 512-0897                                            01/22/77





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Xia is a 57-year-old woman who comes in for evaluation of treatment of diabetes and hypertension, reporting that for the last 3 days she has had trouble with her vision, her blood pressure has been high.  She has been having a lot of headaches.  She has had pain in her right thumb that goes to her right lateral side area.  She has been having hot flashes but no fevers, sweats or chills.  Her sugars have been okay in the 99-120 range, the highest was about 135-140.  She does not really understand why she is feeling so bad with these headaches and other problems.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Conducted in detail and was otherwise negative.



MEDICATIONS:  She has not taken any medications for the last two days.  She does have her diabetes medications but no blood pressure medication.  She usually takes Cozaar 100 daily, Glucophage 1000 b.i.d., Glucotrol XL 5 daily, Lipitor 20 daily, Norvasc 10 daily.  She has not been needing Nexium of late.



ALLERGIES:  Clonidine caused sleepiness and codeine rash.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  She does not smoke or use street drugs.  She does have a little bit of white wine when she has guests on occasion.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On exam, well developed, well nourished, no acute distress.  Blood pressure 152/120, pulse 76, temperature 97.2, weight 166.  Pleasant, articulate in English, she appears comfortable.  Pupils equal, equally reactive to light.  Retinal fields have sharp disks.  Mouth and pharynx without erythema or exudate, no adenopathy or tenderness in the submandibular, cervical, posterior cervical, supraclavicular areas.  Thyroid nontender, non-nodular.  Neck supple, no spine or flank tenderness.  No bruits, no stridor.  Heart sounds S1, S2, regular rate and rhythm, no murmur, rub or gallop.  Chest is clear to auscultation anteriorly and posteriorly with no rales, wheezes or rhonchi.  She is clear to percussion.  Normal bowel sounds.  Abdomen soft, nontender, no mass, organomegaly, no guarding, no rebound.  Extremities are without edema, cyanosis or clubbing, no calf tenderness.  Sensation is intact to microfilament testing bilaterally on her feet.  Pedal pulses are present.  Feet are warm.  There is no rash, maceration, or lesion on her feet.



LABORATORY DATA:  Hemoglobin A1c from October was 7.2.  LDL from last May was 164.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:

1.  Diabetes.  Her diabetes has been near goal.  We will recheck glucose, hemoglobin A1c, UA, and microalbuminuria and see how she is doing today.

2.  Elevated cholesterol.  Her cholesterol was nowhere near our target of 100.  She is on an increased Lipitor.  We will check cholesterol, see how she is doing at this point, and an OT, PT to make sure she is tolerating the medication.

3.  Hypertension.  All of her symptoms today are most likely due to her hypertension.  I explained at great length that the reason for all of her symptoms is the fact she stopped taking her medication.  She seemed surprised that it would have such an immediate and strong effect and I explained to her that it does.  She has to take her medication every day.  I told her she had to leave the Carolyn Huntington right now, go immediately to the drugstore to pick up the medication and she said she would do that.  I also asked her to return next week so we can recheck her blood pressure and make sure it is controlled.

4.  Health maintenance.  I will schedule her for a mammogram.

5.  Colonic adenoma from 11/2076.  She will need follow-up colonoscopy every three years per GI.



hga1c 6.9, ldl 86, letter to pt







______________________________

Yolanda Osburn, M.D.





Dictated By: Yolanda Osburn





eScription document:9-2062651 EMSSten Tel







DD: 01/23/77

DT: 01/24/77

DV: 01/22/77



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-06-22

                                                       Patient Name: XIA,JEAN  [ 58269151(PROMPTCARE) ] 

                                                         Date of Visit: 06/22/2078





Reason for Visit

pt was cleaning ear, now has pain mainly in left. worse over past three days.

 

reports now taking atenolol (50 mg which she just took half an hour ago) and losartan,  Reports stopped amilodipine and hctz.  she had leg cramps, but is not clear which of these caused that.  reports feels bp is high because she forgot to take med.





Review of Systems

Constitutional: No fever, chills, fatigue, nightsweats, insomnia, change in weight

ENT/Mouth: No rhinitis, epistaxis, sinus pain, change in hearing, tinnitus, discharge from ears,  oral lesions, problems chewing, dental pain, sore throat

Cardiovascular: no chest pain, pressure, palpitation, PND, orthopnea, dyspnea on exertion, pedal edema, nocturia, claudication, 

Respiratory: no cough, sputum, dyspnea, pleuritic pain, wheeze, loud snoring, hemoptysis





Allergies

      CLONIDINE    - Sleepiness, 

      Codeine    - Rash, 

      LISINOPRIL    - cough, 

      Ibuprofen    - cramps, 

      AMLODIPINE    - cramps, 



Problems

      Diabetes

      HX kidney stones

      Perimenopausal sx

      Hypertension

      Colonic adenoma 11/11/76



Medications

      Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN)   20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD , please cancel previous script for 10 mg of lipitor thanks you, dr osburn

      Glucotrol Xl (GLIPIZIDE Xl)   5 MG     take qd Tablet(s) PO QD 

      PIROXICAM   20 MG (20MG CAPSULE take 1) PO QD 

      Glucophage (METFORMIN)   1000 MG    take bid bid PO BID 

      Cozaar (LOSARTAN)   100 MG PO QD 

      ATENOLOL   100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      Cortisporin Otic Suspension   4 DROP AS QID 



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   210/118 

      PULSE   80 

      TEMPERATURE   97.3 F

      WEIGHT   160 lb



Physical Exam



Gen: Well appearing in NAD, WD, WN 

ENT-Sclera were white, fundi disc sharp, conjunctiva clear, tympanic membranes normal, ear canal AS somewhat red. The oropharynx was pink without exudate. The neck was supple with out adenopathy. 

LUNG- clear bilaterally, without rhonci, wheeze or rales, Normal excursion was noted. 

Cor- heart rate was normal, rhythm was regular. No murmurs, gallops or rubs were detected 

Extremities: no clubbing cyanosis or edema. 

Skin- no abnormal lesions noted.







Impression

Ear- benign exam but symptomatic - try cortisporun otic

 

HTN- very high, no sign of end organ injury at this moment- will increase atenolol to 100, and have her rtc for recheck.  It would be helpful to know whether cramps came from hctz or amilodipine.



______________________________

Charles Craig Max Zavaleta, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>