<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2092-05-06

Patient Name: WILHELM, GOLDY;  MRN: 9543443

Dictated at: 05/06/2092 by EDWARD XAYASANE, M.D. 



 

CHIEF COMPLAINT: Right leg pain and difficulty walking.   

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: Ms. Wilhelm is a 68-year-old right-handed female who has had a three-week history of having right leg pain and difficulty walking. She states that her pain started about three weeks ago when she was bending and picking up a pot. She states she had a pain in her back that radiated around her right side down her groin into her medial leg, not past the knee. She states that it went away at that time. The next day she felt worsened and had difficulty working and saw her physician.  An MRI was ordered. Since then, she feels about 60-75 percent better. She states that her pain is constant and describes it as a sharp pain. She does state she feels weak and her knee would buckle. She does not have any numbness or tingling. She states she uses a walker to get to her bathroom, however, otherwise stays in the recliner. Her symptoms are increased with lying down and standing and decreased with sitting.  

 

Therapeutically, she has not received any physical therapy or occupational therapy. She is currently taking Darvocet, however, less frequently, and Celebrex for arthritis. Diagnostically, she has had an MRI scan in April 2092 that showed multi-level spinal stenosis, most prominent at L3/L4, especially on the right side, secondary to facet arthropathy and ligamentum flavum infolding, as well as possibly a mild disk bulge. Her mammogram was done in 2091 which was okay. She has not had a bone mineral density at this time.  

 

MEDICATIONS: Currently, the medication she is on is Celebrex, Hyzaar for her blood pressure, and Darvocet for her pain.   

ALLERGIES: She states that taking Tylenol With Codeine gives her toes a burning sensation, and ibuprofen causes tinnitus.   

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY: She has got high blood pressure and shoulder arthritis.  

 

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY: She had a left breast biopsy which she states was not cancerous.  

 

SOCIAL/FUNCTIONAL HISTORY: She is functionally currently not working. She is taking sick time. She has not worked for the past three weeks. She is a Head Nurse and worked at The Library Corporation for the last 35 years. She states her job is medium as far as intensity of work. Functionally, her activities of daily living are limited, and she uses an assistive device.  

 

SOCIAL HISTORY: She is widowed and she has four healthy children, ages 51, 50, 48, and 46. She does not smoke or drink.   

FAMILY HISTORY: She has aunts with diabetes and brother that had an myocardial infarction at 59.  

 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: On review of systems, no fevers, chills, recent infections, bladder, thyroid problems, rash, shortness of breath, palpations, chest pain, nausea, abdominal pain, diarrhea, or bowel or bladder or sexual problems or urination difficulty.  She does have some joint pain and swelling in her shoulders and her feet occasionally. She does not have any numbness or tingling. She does have some trouble walking secondary to the pain. She does not feel fatigued and her appetite is okay and she does not feel anxious or stressed. She does have some mild trouble with sleeping, however, this has improved over the last few days.  

 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: On physical examination, well-developed, well-nourished, well-groomed, normal mood and affect, but slightly anxious with movement, female in no acute distress at this time. On musculoskeletal examination of lumbar spine, flexion was within normal limits. Extension she had her type of pain at about 10-20 degrees. Side-bending was unremarkable. On hip examination she had some decreased internal rotation on the right when compared to the left. Straight leg raise bilaterally was negative, however, supine, slight guarding on the right.  Femoral stretch was positive on the right but not on the left. On neurological examination, as far as motor examination, there is some slight decrease, half a grade, quadriceps and hip flexors; however, this was functional; otherwise unremarkable on the right or the left. Her reflexes were 2 plus in the achilles. Babinskis were downgoing, 1 plus at the patella on the right, and 2 plus on the left. Sensory examination slightly decreased at L3 on the right; however, normal throughout; otherwise, gait was antalgic on the right and she did not want to bear weight.  

 

IMPRESSION:  

1. Right L3 acute radiculopathy secondary to herniated disk and facet arthropathy.  

2. Functional limitations secondary to pain, causing her functional weakness.  

 

RECOMMENDATIONS:  

1. Transforaminal epidural steroid injection at L3 and L4 on the right.  

2. Physical therapy after her injection.  

3. Continue her medications of Darvocet and Celebrex.  4. Keep her out of work until she is able to receive the injection, as well as continue with her physical therapy to improve her strength, given her acute radiculopathy.   

The patient was seen and examined with Dr. Xayasane, who agrees with the plan above.  

 

 

_______________________________ 

Edward Xayasane, M.D.  

cc: David Utterback, M.D.  

DD:05/06/2092 

DT:05/09/2092 

TL:95468     :423 

 





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-06-03

 Time of visit: 6/03/2097, 1330 hours
Time of note: 1630 hours

Patient seen and examined with the team.  Note of Dr. Ellis reviewed, findings confirmed.  Available electronic notes reviewed, X-rays reviewed, labs reviewed.  

73 y. o. woman who has worked as a nurse at TLC for 40 years.  Nonsmoker.  History of hypertension treated with Hyzaar.  Current illness began 5-6 months ago with fatigue, dyspnea on exertion that has progressed to the point that she has to stop to catch her breath after walking up only 4-5 steps in a stairwell.  She finds it difficult to get started on her work because of fatigue.  She has had a cough that initially produced yellowish, "slimy" sputum, but more recently has been dry.  She notes occasional wheezing.  She also noted muscle and joint pain involving the shoulders and lower extremities over the past 5-6 months that she attributed to "arthritis".  No polyuria, but has noted nocturia X2 for the past 5-6 months. During the same period of time, has noted very dry mouth. No abdominal pain, but some difficulty with constipation for the past two weeks.

Appetite diminished and she lost about 30 pounds.  She noted a nodule on the extensor surface of the left elbow that her PCP "cut into" recently.  She has also noted a nodule on the dorsal surface of the right foot that seems to "get larger".  

She experienced substernal chest pain with radiation to the back that lasted several hours, prompting her to come to the ER.  No associated diaphoresis, nausea.  Pain somewhat better with sitting up.  

Of note, she has known of having a cardiac murmur for many years.  

Exam:  Pleasant black woman in no distress.  BP 158/79, Pulse 80, regular; O2 sat 98% on room air.  Afebrile.  Skin darkly pigmented nodule left elbow extensor surface, similar nodule right dorsal foot just proximal to 4th/5th toe.  No other rashes.  HEENT:  pale conjunctivae, anicteric.  No nasal findings, no facial skin findings (specifically, no lupus pernio).  Dry mucous membranes.  Neck: small, soft, mobile 0.5 cm node left anterior cervical chain.  Chest:  inspiratory crackles at both bases.  Cardiac: No JVD.  Regular rhythm.  III/VI (I do not feel a thrill) harsh nearly holosystolic murmur heard throughout the precordium, but especially prominent at the RUSB with radiation to the clavicles, neck.  Also heard at the apex and radiates to the left mid-back (?same murmur).  The murmur intensifies when she stands.  No gallops.  No rub.  Abdomen soft and nontender.  No spleen tip.  Liver edge not palpable.  
Lymph nodes:  fullness below the left axilla, although not confident of discrete nodes.  

Data:  There is considerable testing available to us from her recent visits to the Walk-In Clinic and to Dr. Utter.  

A CXR from 5/2097 shows bilateral hilar adenopathy, mediastinal adenopathy, and interstitial infiltrates.  

Creatinine 1.7

Date/Time         CA             ALB            
06/03/2097        12.3 (H)       3.4            
06/02/2097        12.8 (H)       3.5            
05/28/2097        11.8 (H)       3.5            

Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          
06/03/2097        41 (H)         41 (H)         67             0.7            

Date/Time         NT-BNP         CK             CK-MB          CKMBRI         
06/03/2097                       135            9.6 (H)                       
06/03/2097                       126            8.6 (H)        6.8 (H)        
E                      
06/02/2097        4285 (H)[1]                                                 
06/02/2097                                      NEGATIVE                      

Date/Time         TROP-I         TROP-T         
06/03/2097                       0.12 (H)       
06/03/2097                       0.12 (H)       
06/02/2097        NEGATIVE                      
06/02/2097        NEGATIVE                      

Date/Time         FE             TIBC           FER                         
05/28/2097        33             237            130                           
Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            
06/03/2097        6.4            3.98 (L)       10.2 (L)       30.4 (L)       

Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            
06/03/2097        76 (L)         25.5 (L)       33.5           198                  

Date/Time         DIFFR          METHOD         %NEUT          %LYMPH         
06/03/2097        RECEIVED       Auto           71 (H)         20 (L)         

Date/Time         %MONO          %EOS           %BASO          
06/03/2097        6              3              0              

Date/Time         RETIC          
06/03/2097        1.7            


Serum angiotensin converting enzyme 68 (7-46 U/L)
LDH 354

EKG:  ST elevations V1-3.

Problems:

1.  Dyspnea on exertion, progressive.
2.  Interstitial lung disease.
3.  Bilateral hilar adenopathy
4.  Weight loss
5.  Symptomatic hypercalcemia
		Nocturia
		Arthralgias
		Constipation
		Fatigue
6.  Prominent systolic murmur(s?). Changes with maneuvers suggest this may be secondary to hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy.  There was evidence to suggest this on an echo from 2085, but obviously, need more recent data.
7.  Minimally elevated troponins.  Uncertain significance.
8.  Anemia, mildly microcytic.
9.  Elevated LDH.
10.  Renal insufficiency, likely secondary to uncontrolled hypercalcemia.
11.  History of hypertension.

Discussion:

Sarcoidosis, until proven otherwise.  She is obviously older than typical presentation of sarcoidosis, but she had previous lymphadenopathy that may have been a first presentation of the illness with spontaneous remission.  The lung findings, systemic symptoms, hypercalcemia, anemia, abnormal serum ACE level are all suggestive of this diagnosis.  

Her hypercalcemia is symptomatic and should be treated with volume repletion.  She should not receive diuretics at present.  Long term treatment will be dependent on the underlying diagnosis and its treatment.  I think she will need corticosteroids for her sarcoidosis and I expect this will improve the hypercalcemia, but we need definitive diagnosis first.  

The cardiac murmur is impressive, but likely unrelated to the pulmonary disease.  We need echocardiogram to better define valvular function.  The minimally elevated troponins are not felt to be of clinical significance at this point.  Appreciate Cardiology input on this finding.  

Suggest:

1.  Stop HCTZ,avoid diuretics until fully volume repleted.
2.  IV normal saline.  May need rates in the 150-200 range to control her hypercalcemia acutely, but she has had this for some time, so can be conservative with fluids approach.
3.  Agree with check PTH, vitamin D levels.
4.  Follow lytes, creatinine, calcium, Hct.
5.  Agree with check echocardiogram.
6.  We should ask the Pulmonary Service to see her in consultation.  Bronchoscopy with biopsy may be the best way to obtain confirmatory tissue for diagnosis of sarcoidosis.





_____________________________________________
Edmond I. Utterback, M.D.
Pager #57863
Internal Medicine B Attending



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-06-29
Internal Medicine B Intern Admission Note

PATIENT: GOLDY WILHELM
MRN: 9543443
ADMIT DATE: June 29, 2097
ATTENDING: Dr. William Xian
PCP: Dr. Casey Frey (new)
CONTACT: Leo Wilhelm, son  705-690-8475
CODE: Full

Source: Patient, family, chart
ID/CC: no appetite, acute renal failure

HPI: 73 yo black woman with h/o HTN and recurrent non-malignant axillary lymphadenopathy, newly diagnosed with HOCM in the setting of fatigue, weight loss and hypercalcemia concerning for sarcoidosis during a work-up at her last admission to MEDIQUIK on 6/2-6/20/97. At that time, the patient noted that 3-4 mo PTA she had experienced worsening fatigue and dry mouth, as well as poor oral intake with associated 30 lb weight loss. 

In early May, she presented to the walk-in clinic with these complaints and a CXR showed increased interstitial markings and mediastinal lymphadenopathy subsequently confirmed by CT. A PET CT showed FDG avidity in multiple enlarged thoracic and axillary nodes. The patient was seen at the lymphoma center by Dr. Utter, and concern was raised for multiple processes including sarcoid, lupus-like syndromes, Castleman's, and indolent lymphoma. Labs drawn at different times in recent past were notable for a Ca of 11.8 with Alb of 3.5, a mild tranaminitis in the 40s, LDH of 354, ACE of 68, normal TSH, HCT of 30.2, ESR of 85, SPEP with diffuse gamma globulin increase, positive ANA at 1:2560 with nuclear pore staining (highly specific for biliary cirrhosis), elevated B2MG at 17.5, and elevated kappa and lambda free light chains at 66 and 83.5, respectively and negative HIV. The patient   s hypercalcemia was treated with IVF, lasix at times, and a dose of bisphosphonate, which led to a decrease in Ca to 10.1.

Axillary lymph node biopsy 6/08/97 revealed non-specific follicular hyperplasia, though to be consistent with a reactive process. Oncology was consulted, and a lymphoma work-up was pursued; flow cytometry revealed polyclonal CD19+ B cells, CD4+ and CD8+ T cells, with no evidence for a monoclonal B or unusual T cell population. Repeat CT examination of the chest revealed no change in the bilateral axillary, mediastinal, and hilar lymphadenopathy and offered no further clues to diagnostic possibilities.  The patient underwent pulmonary function testing, which showed a reduction in the FEV1, FVC, and FEV1/FVC ratio; total lung capacity and subdivisions were normal, resistance and specific conductance were normal, and single breath diffusion capacity was reduced. On 7/19/97, a bronchoscopy was attempted, but the patient was unable to tolerate the procedure, and it was not performed. Thoracic surgery was consulted and recommended that the patient be evaluated in the outpatient setting for biopsy under general anesthesia. Fungal antibodies were sent, and a trial of steroids was not attempted during hospitalization. 
 
Since discharge, the pt reports that she continues to feel very fatigued, and has not    felt like eating.    She reports significant acid reflux, saying    only water goes down    and a lack of appetite with very dry mouth. She notes continued weight loss of 15lbs since leaving the hospital, tolerating little more than 1-2 cans of Ensure/day per her family. She further denies N/V, diarrhea, fever/chills/dizziness or recent infection. Of note, she has been drinking little, but urinating 9-10 times a day, clear urine with large volumes. She has not had a bowel movement for several days. She has continued her medications as instructed at the time of discharge.

In addition, her family notes a dramatic change in her mood and activity level since prior to hospitalization. She used to be very active, working nearly every day and keeping up her household. She now spends most of her day in bed sleeping, relying on her children for help and awakening early in the AM unintentionally. She has felt too tired to pursue her usual nightly bingo game. She denies suicidal ideation, saying she has her four grandchildren to liver for.
   
ED COURSE: At the ED, the patient was afebrile, HR 59, BP 136/61, RR 16, O2 Sat 95%. She was given IVF and labs were drawn.


PMH/PSH:
   HOCM
   LAD
   HTN 
   Uterine prolapse
   Urge incontinence
   Rectocele
   Bladder prolapse

MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:
Multivitamins (Mvi) 1 TAB PO QD
Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin ) 325 MG PO QD
Atorvastatin (Lipitor ) 40 MG PO QD
Sennosides (Senna Tablets ) 2 TAB PO BID prn [constipation]
Docusate Sodium (Colace ) 100 MG PO TID prn [constipation]
Metoprolol Tartrate (Lopressor) 100 MG PO Q6H
Omeprazole (Prilosec ) 40 MG PO QD
Verapamil Hcl 60 MG PO Q8H
Nifedipine (Sustained Release) 30 MG PO QD

ALLERGIES: NKDA

SH: No EtOH, tob, drugs. Originally from Tajikistan. 4 children, 4 grandchildren, all in the area. Widowed for 42 years, has worked at MEDIQUIK for 40 years as a nurse.

FH: DM in children.

Exam:  	VS:   T=98.3      HR=73-84 reg     BP= 127-160/63-74     RR=18-20     SaO2= 96% RA 
General: thin black woman lying in bed 
HEENT: PERRL, prominent arcus senilus w/ ?band keratopathy, dry muc membranes, geographic tongue
Skin: atrophic, hypopigmented scars over knees bilaterally 
Neck: Soft and supple, no appreciable cervical LAD, flat JVP 
Chest: dry crackles diffusely at bases, otherwise clear 
Cardiac: regular, IV/VI harsh SEM at RSB, louder with valsalva 
Abd: soft, nontender 
Extr: without edema 
Neuro: A&O x3, CN II-XII intact, motor strength grossly intact throughout, patient able to stand and walk unassisted
                  DTRs within nlm range
	
DATA: 
          	06/30/97  	06/29/97  	06/20/97  
          	05:05     	03:51     	00:06     

NA        	136       	132(L)    	136       	          	          
K         	3.5       	3.5       	3.4       	          	          
CL        	104       	104       	99(L)     	          	          
CO2       	25.3      	25.2      	23.8      	          	          
BUN       	19        	30(H)     	17        	          	          
CRE       	1.8(H)    	2.2(H)    	1.6(H)    	          	          
GLU       	          	93        	113(H)    	          	          

TBILI     	0.5       	          	          	          	          
DBILI     	0.2       	          	          	          	          
TP        	8.0       	          	          	          	          
ALB       	3.4       	          	          	          	          
GLOB      	4.6(H)    	          	          	          	          
AMY       	90        	          	          	          	          
LIPS      	4.1       	          	          	          	          
	
ALT/SGPT  	55(H)     	          	          	          	          
AST/SGOT  	56(H)     	          	          	          	          
ALKP      	113(H)    	          	          	          	          
TBILI     	0.5       	          	          	          	          
DBILI     	0.2       	          	          	          	          

CK        	61        	          	          	          	          
CK-MB     	5.4       	          	          	          	          

WBC       	5.8       	6.7       	5.8       	          	          
RBC       	3.84(L)   	3.64(L)   	3.73(L)   	          	          
HGB       	10.4(L)   	9.7(L)    	10.0(L)   	          	          
HCT       	29.9(L)   	28.0(L)   	28.5(L)   	          	          
MCV       	78(L)     	77(L)     	76(L)     	          	          
MCH       	27.0      	26.7      	26.9      	          	          
MCHC      	34.8      	34.8      	35.2      	          	          
PLT       	235       	247       	247       	          	          
RDW       	16.5(H)   	16.4(H)   	16.0(H)   	          	          
DIFFR     	          	Received  	Received  	          	          
METHOD    	          	see detail	see detail	          	          
%NEUT     	          	63        	70        	          	          
%LYMPH    	          	24        	20(L)     	          	          
%MONO     	          	8         	6         	          	          
%EOS      	          	4         	3         	          	          
%BASO     	          	1         	1         	          	          
ANEUT     	          	4.30      	4.10      	          	          
ALYMP     	          	1.60      	1.16      	          	          
AMONS     	          	0.51(H)   	0.37      	          	          
AEOSN     	          	0.25      	0.15      	          	          
ABASOP    	          	0.04      	0.03      	          	          
ANISO     	          	1+(H)     	None      	          	          
HYPO      	          	None      	None      	          	          
MACRO     	          	None      	None      	          	          
MICRO     	          	2+(H)     	2+(H)     	          	          
P-COM     	          	see detail	see detail	          	          

PT        	12.4(T)   	          	          	          	          
PT-INR    	1.1(T)    	          	          	          	          

UA-COLOR  	Yellow    	Yellow    	          	          	          
UA-APP    	Clear     	Clear     	          	          	          
UA-GLUC   	Negative  	1+        	          	          	          
UA-BILI   	Negative  	Negative  	          	          	          
UA-KET    	Negative  	Negative  	          	          	          
UA-SPGR   	1.010     	1.010(T)  	          	          	          
UA-BLD    	1+        	1+        	          	          	          
UA-PH     	5.5       	6.0       	          	          	          
UA-PROT   	1+        	1+        	          	          	          
UA-UROBI  	Trace     	Negative  	          	          	          
UA-NIT    	Negative  	Negative  	          	          	          
UA-WBC    	Negative  	Negative  	          	          	          
HCAST     	0-2       	3-5       	          	          	          
UAS-RBC   	0-2       	0-2       	          	          	          
UAS-WBC   	3-5       	3-5       	          	          	          
UAS-BACT  	Negative  	Negative  	          	          	          
UAS-SQHI  	Negative  	Few       	          	          	          

ECG: NSR @ 82bpm, LVH unchanged from prior study


Impression: 
73F h/o newly dx HOCM, chronic systemic LAD, fatigue, and weight loss concerning for sarcoid vs. PBC vs. neoplasm, presenting with acute renal failure in setting of little PO intake and likely hypercalcemia. Hypercalcemia (as in vitamin D excess secondary to sarcoid) can cause polyuria via osmotic diuresis, with dehydration, anorexia, constipation, and PUD, fatigue and depression. This would thus represent a unifying diagnosis for this pt   s anorexia and acute renal failure, which is most likely prerenal.

Plan: 
ARF: - f/u Ca + Phos. Expect Ca to be high, Phos to be low. Cont IVF
   - Cre 2.2   1.8 (bl 1.2-15) s/p IVF 500cc x1, on D5    NS @ 100cc/hr, re-evaluate and re-bolus in AM
          - Maintain good UO, no Foley b/c recording stricts I   s + O   s, 700cc out of clear urine O/N
Fatigue/Weight Loss/LAD/lack of appetite: 
-prior labs somewhat concerning for PBC, esp with elev AlkP
-f/u anti-mitochondrial Ab, TSH, f/u pending labs from prior w/u
-consider re-attempting transbronchial biopsy, revisit w/ thoracics 
Anemia: -Hct stable, slightly microcytic. MVI




___________________________________________
Casey Frey, M.D.                 Pager 46311




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-12-15

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.

Internal Medicine B Admission Note


PATIENT: Goldy Wilhelm 
MRN:     9543443
ADMIT DATE:  12/15/97
ATTENDING: Gregory Thomson
PCP:   Casey Frey
CONTACT:  Gracen Logan (HCP, daughter) 625-248-3647; Flowers (son) 705-690-8475
Code status: Full 
Source: patient, son, records


CC:  N/V, poor PO intake
HPI: Ms. Wilhelm is a 74 year-old woman with a history of HOCM, HTN, DM, and sarcoidosis who underwent a Hartmann&#8217;s procedure with small bowel resection on 10/18 after which she was discharged to Harton Center on 11/07 and then re-admitted to MEDIQUIK on 11/17 with left-sided pleuritic chest pain and a saddle pulmonary embolus as well as large right lower extremity DVT.  She had an IVC filter placed and was started on anticoagulation and discharged again to Harton Center on 12/1 and now presents with nausea, vomiting, and several days of poor PO intake.  This is actually her fifth admission to MEDIQUIK this year &#8211; first in June when she was diagnosed with HOCM and then in July when she was started on empiric steroids for sarcoidosis.  She says her appetite has never returned to normal since her surgery (although her July admission note also documented malaise and poor appetite) and that she has had some mild nausea on a daily basis since her surgery.  The nausea and her fatigue became worse four or five days prior to admission and since then she has been vomiting many times a day.  The nausea is not related to meals and she has not noted any blood in the emesis.  She has had poor intake as a result of the nausea and has only had broth over the last few days.  She denies fevers, chills, headaches, cough, abdominal pain, or change in the character of her colostomy output.  


ED COURSE:  
On arrival to the ED, vitals were as follows: 98, 164/84, 84, 24, 98%/RA.  Her abdomen was non-tender and minimally distended.  CT of the abdomen was concerning for a distal small bowel obstruction although no focal transition point was identified.  She was seen by surgery and an NGT was placed.  She was given 2L of IVF and morphine 2mg IV x2.   


ROS
As above, otherwise reports baseline blurry vision (has been told of cataracts in the past). Denies SOB, cough, CP, chest pressure, orthopnea, palpitations.
Foley catheter in place but denies suprapubic tenderness.  


MEDICAL HISTORY
-          PE: saddle embolus 11/17, s/p IVC filter, on coumadin
-          lupus anticoagulant positive
-          HTN
-          HOCM: diagnosed 6/97
-          Sarcoidosis: empirically started on prednisone 7/97 in the setting of hypercalcemia
-          PBC: +AMA, not confirmed on biopsy
-          Urge incontinence, rectocele, bladder prolapse 
-          H/o PAF 
-          DM


SURGICAL HISTORY
-                 10/18/97: Perforated diverticulitis, s/p ex lap, hartmanns procedure, small bowel resection and mobilization of left colon 
-                 Multiple LN biopsies




FAMILY HISTORY 
Three children with DM.


SOCIAL HISTORY
Originally from .  Widowed 42 years, 4 children, 4 grandchildren.  Works in TLC as a nurse.  No tobacco/alcohol/drugs.  


ALLERGIES:  NKDA


MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION:
  1. Acetaminophen (Tylenol  )  650 MG PO Q4H prn  
  2. Albuterol Inhaler (Albuterol Mdi )  4 PUFF INH Q2H prn bronchospasm
  3. Albuterol Nebulizer  2.5 MG QID
  4. Aluminum/Magnesium Hydroxide +  Simethicone (Maalox Susp)  15-30 ML PO Q6H prn GI Upset/Heartburn
  5. Amiodarone  200 MG QD
  6. Ascorbic Acid  500 MG BID
  7. Bisacodyl (Dulcolax )  10 MG PO QD prn constipation
  8. Clopidogrel (Plavix )  75 MG QD
  9. Docusate Sodium (Colace )  100 MG BID
10. Ferrous Sulfate  325 MG QD
11. Furosemide (Lasix )  20 MG QOD
12. Insulin Regular Inj  Sliding scale SC 
                If BS &lt;= 200 give 0 Units 
                For BS from 201 to 250 give 4 Units 
                For BS from 251 to 300 give 6 Units 
                For BS from 301 to 350 give 8 Units 
                For BS from 351 to 400 give 10 Units 
13. Ipratropium Inhaler  4 PUFF INH Q2H prn bronchospasm
14. Magnesium Oxide   400 MG BID
15. Metoprolol Tartrate (Lopressor )  100 MG Q8H
16. Mirtazapine  7.5  MG QHS
17. Omeprazole  20 MG BID
18. Ondansetron Odt (Chemo N/V) (Zofran Odt (Chemo N/V))  4 MG PO Q8H prn nausea
19. Oxycodone  5-10 MG PO Q6H prn pain
20. Pentoxifylline (Trental)   400 MG TID
21. Prednisone  5 MG QD
22. Quetiapine (Seroquel)   25 MG PO BID prn agitation
23. Sennosides (Senna Tablets)  2 TAB PO QHS prn constipation
24. Simethicone  160 MG TID
25. Spironolactone (Aldactone )  25 MG QD
26. Verapamil Hcl  60 MG TID
27. Warfarin Sodium (Coumadin )  5 MG QPM


PHYSICAL EXAM
VITALS:  99.1, 95, 132/86, 97%/RA
GEN&#8217;L    pleasant African-American woman, tired but NAD, 
HEENT   dry mucous membranes, NGT in place, OP clear, +conjunctival pallor 
NECK     supple, no LAD, JVP&lt;5 cm, no carotid bruits 
HEART RRR, normal S1, S2, 3/6 SEM louder at base and increases in harshness with valsalva
LUNG     CTAB, no rhonchi, rales 
ABD       +BS, soft, non-tender, non-distended, midline incisional wound with dry, sterile dressing, colostomy bag in LLQ with brown stool
EXT        R LE with dry sterile dressing over shin, 2+ DP pulse, wwp; L LE with dry sterile dressing from foot to knee, toes warm, no edema 
NEURO: AO x 3; alert; CN II-XII grossly intact; Motor: 4/5 B UE/LE; sensation grossly intact to light touch


LABS:
&#183;Hematology:  
              12/15/97      12/14/97  


WBC           6.0           7.4                                                
HGB           7.6(L)        8.6(L)                                              
HCT           22.7(L)       25.6(L)                                             
MCV           87            87                                                  
PLT           372(H)        416(H)                                              
RDW           15.2(H)       15.3(H)                                             
%NEUT         68(H)         79(H)                                               
%LYMPH        24            16(L)                                               
%MONO         7             5                                                   
%EOS          1             0                                                   
%BASO         0             0                                                   


&#183;Chemistries:   
              12/15/97      12/14/97  


NA            134(L)        133(L)                                             
K             4.5           5.7(HT)                                             
CL            100           100                                                 
CO2           22.7(L)       22.5(L)                                             
BUN           31(H)         32(H)                                               
CRE           1.8(H)        2.1(H)                                              
GLU           82            139(H)                                              


ALB                         2.7(L)                                              
LACT          0.6                                                               


&#183;LFTs:  
ALT/SGPT      23                                                                
AST/SGOT      18                                                                
ALKP          123(H)                                                            
TBILI         0.5                                                               
DBILI         0.1                                                               


&#183;Coags:  
              12/15/97      12/14/97  


PT            38.7(H)       35.7(HT)                                            
PT-INR       4.3           3.9(T)                                              
PTT                         48.1(HT)                                            




RADIOLOGY/STUDIES:
CXR (12/14):     Lines/tubes:  Interval placement of left-sided PICC line the tip of the PICC line does not cross midline there is a nasogastric tube with the tip below the diaphragm
     Lungs:  There is a persistent opacity in the left mid hemithorax
     Pleura:  There is no pleural effusion or pneumothorax.
     Heart and mediastinum:  The heart and the mediastinum are normal.


CT Abd (12/14):     LOWER THORAX: There been interval resolution of the previously identified bilateral pleural effusions.  There is linear atelectasis of the lung bases.
     HEPATOBILIARY: No focal hepatic lesions.  No biliary ductal dilatation.  There are stable findings of porcelain gallbladder.
     SPLEEN: No splenomegaly.
     PANCREAS: No focal masses or ductal dilatation.
     ADRENALS: No adrenal nodules.
     KIDNEYS/URETERS: No hydronephrosis, stones, or solid mass lesions. Two left renal exophytic lesions are identified, stable in size compared with the prior examination and consistent with renal cysts.
     PELVIC ORGANS/BLADDER: There is a Foley catheter in place. There is a fibroid uterus.
     
     PERITONEUM / RETROPERITONEUM: No free air is seen.  There is trace free fluid.
     LYMPH NODES: No lymphadenopathy.
     VESSELS: There are scattered vascular calcifications. An IVC filter is in place.
     GI TRACT: There is diffuse dilation of the proximal and mid small bowel with multiple air fluid levels.  There are loops of nondilated distal small bowel and the colon is not dilated.  There has been a prior  a prior colostomy. There is diverticulosis.
     BONES AND SOFT TISSUES: Unremarkable.
     
     IMPRESSION: Findings concerning for distal small bowel obstruction though no discrete transition point is identified.  Alternately, this could reflect ileus.  Close clinical follow up advised.   




EKG: NSR at 94bpm, leftward axis, biatrial enlargement, normal PR interval, narrow QRS, LVH, TWIs in I, aVL


ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN
Ms. Wilhelm is a 74 year-old woman with a history of HOCM, hypertension, sarcoidosis, diabetes, who underwent a Hartmann&#8217;s procedure with small bowel resection on 10/18 and was re-admitted on 11/17 with a saddle PE and large RLE DVT for which she was managed with IVC filter and anticoagulation who now presents with several days of nausea and vomiting and concern for small bowel obstruction on CT.  



SBO: Her clinical presentation and CT findings are concerning for small bowel obstruction (although ileus remains a possibility.  Lactate was within normal limits so small bowel ischemia unlikely.  Also abdominal exam remains benign at this time.  

Appreciate surgery input
NGT to low wall suction
NPO except meds for bowel rest
Serial abdominal exams
Check colostomy output guaiac
Acute renal failure: Her creatinine was up from a baseline of 1.0 to 2.1 on admission.  With IVF hydration in the ED it has already started to come down to 1.8 so it was likely pre-renal in the setting of poor intake and vomiting.  

Continue IVF while NPO
Will trend Cr and pursue further ARF work-up if not down on AM labs
Anemia: Baseline hematocrit in low 30s, last 32.6 prior to discharge on 11/30.  She does not appear to have an active source of bleeding and her bilirubin is within normal limits so she is unlikely to be hemolyzing.  She likely either has iron-deficiency anemia (although she has been taking iron supplements) or anemia of chronic disease &#8211; or a combination thereof.  Her RDW is only mildly elevated which likely indicates inappropriately low hematopoiesis.  

Transfuse 1U PRBCs
Check colostomy guaiac
Check iron studies, reticulocyte count
Elevated INR/hypercoagulability: She is baseline hypercoagulable with lupus anticoagulant and has had the recent large DVT/PE s/p IVC filter placement.  She comes in with an elevated INR and is likely supratherapeutic on her coumadin.  She does not need to be reversed as she does not seem to be actively bleeding.

Hold Coumadin for now
Follow up INR, goal 2-3
HOCM/HTN: 

Continue lopressor, verapamil
Sarcoid:

Continue Prednisone at 5mg daily
PAF

Continue Amiodarone &#8211; follow-up with PCP regarding indication for Amio


F/E/N:  NPO
PPX: coumadin, PPI, bowel regimen


CODE:  Full



__________________________________
Antoinette S Delaney, MD, Pager #63784





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2098-08-03



Internal Medicine G Intern Admission Note

PATIENT:  Wilhelm, Goldy

MRN: 9543443

ADMIT DATE: 8/2/98

PCP:  Dr. Casey Frey



HPI: 74F with sarcoidosis, HTN, CHF, HOCM, PE s/p IVC filter now on coumadin, PVD s/p L BKA, and DM who presents from her rehab facility with failure to thrive and increasing lethargy for several weeks. Of note, pt had recent admission to MEDIQUIK (6/29-7/05) at which time she presented with similar complaints of fatigue/lethargy and routine CBC demonstrated an elevated WBC (15) and low Hct (23). She was ultimately found to have an Enterococcus bacteremia and intra-abdominal abscess that grew out E. coli. She underwent IR drainage of the abdominal collection and completed a course of Vanc/CTX. Outpatient f/u abd CT (7/18) showed near complete resolution of the intra-abdominal collection. Since that time, however, pt&#8217;s sons report increasing lethargy at her nursing facility. Patient has no complaints. Specifically, she denies fatigue, chest pain, shortness of breath, dizziness, motor weakness and fevers and chills. However, given concern on the part of her sons, pt was taken to the MEDIQUIK ED. 



In the MEDIQUIK ED, she was afebrile with HR 70, BP 150/74, RR 24, and Sa02 100% RA. 



PMH: 

Hypertension

History of Congestive heart failure, HOCM(EF =77%)

Pulmonary embolism (11/97) s/p IVC filter now on coumadin

Peripheral vascular disease 

s/p left BKA 4/29/98 due to ischemic gangrene of left foot.

Diabetes mellitus (HbA1C = 6.3mg/dL  - 1/98)

Sarcoidosis

Breast mass w/ axillary lymphadenopathy

Perforated small bowel diverticulitis s/p sigmoid resection w/Hartmann procedure with diverting colostomy by Dr. Joshi in 10/97 (removed  9" of jejunum)

Heterozygous hemoglobin S - on 6/20/2085 Hb electropheresis



Meds: 

  1. Artificial Tears  1 DROP OD QID

  2. Bisacodyl (Dulcolax)  5 MG PO QD prn constipation

  3. Calcium Carbonate/Vitd (250mg Ca++/125u Vitd)  2 TAB PO BID

  4. Citalopram (Celexa)  40 MG PO QD

  5. Clonidine  0.1 MG PO BID

  6. Docusate Sodium (Colace )  100 MG PO BID

  7. Hydralazine Hcl  100 MG PO QID

  8. Insulin Glargine (Lantus )  25 UNITS SC QAM

  9. Megestrol Acetate Suspension (Megace  )  400 MG PO QD


10. Melatonin  3 MG PO QHS


11. Metoclopramide Hcl (Reglan)  10 MG PO Q6H


12. Multivitamins (Mvi)  1 TAB PO QD


13. Niferex 150  150 MG PO BID


14. Omeprazole (Prilosec)  20 MG PO QD


15. Ondansetron Odt (Zofran Odt)  4 MG PO Q8H prn nausea/vomiting


16. Pentoxifylline  400 MG PO TID


17. Polyethylene Glycol  (Miralax)  17 GM PO QD


18. Prednisone  10 MG PO QD


19. Propoxyphene Nap/Acetaminophen 100/650 (Darvocet-N 100)  1 TAB PO Q4H prn 


20. Propranolol Hcl (Inderal )  60 MG PO QID


21. Verapamil Hcl  120 MG PO TID


22. Warfarin Sodium (Coumadin )  4 MG PO QPM



Allergies: 

Propranolol - SOB



Family history: 

Noncontributory



Social History: Pt lives at Ingham Hospital. She denies EtOH, tobacco, and illicit drugs.



ROS: As per HPI



PE: 

Vitals: 
T 97.2      HR 85     BP 192/80       RR 18       Sa02   98% RA

Gen: Quiet woman, whispering, appears somnolent but NAD

HEENT: PERRL, MMM, o/p clear

Neck: No bruits, JVP flat

Chest: CTAB

Card: RRR, nl s1/s2, II/VI crescendo/decrescendo murmur at USBs, harsh SEM at apex

Abd: + BS, NTND, no HSM, rectal exam is guaiac negative

Ext: L BKA, R pulses acquired via doppler

Neuro: A&amp;Ox3, CNs II-XII intact



Labs: 

140      106     46 

----------------------(145

5.7(H)  23      1.58

Baseline Cr 1.2



Ca 9.2      PO4 3.9     Mg 2



15.5&gt;25.1&lt;252       (Baseline Hct 30)



PT 40      PTT 30.8         INR 4.6



U/A: 0-2 RBCs, 20-50 WBCs, moderate squams



EKG: 84bpm, sinus, normal axis, ST elevations in V2-V3 (old)



Imaging: 

CXR (8/2/98): 1.  Increased interstitial markings may represent worsened mild pulmonary edema or interstitial infection.



Abd CT (7/18/98): Near complete resolution of previously seen left lower quadrant fluid collection. Stable small cystic lesions in pancreas which likely represent side branch IPMN.



Abd CT (6/30/98): New 4.8 x 4.0 cm thick walled fluid collection in the LLQ which contains a small amount of gas.  This would be amenable to percutaneous drainage. Small bilateral pleural effusions, decreased in size. Bilateral benign renal cysts. Gallbladder wall calcifications.



A/P: 74F with sarcoidosis, HTN, CHF, HOCM, PE s/p IVC filter now on coumadin, PVD s/p L BKA, and DM who presents from her rehab facility with failure to thrive and increasing lethargy for several weeks. 



1. Failure to thrive / lethargy: The etiology of this pt&#8217;s lethargy is unclear. It is notable, however, that her presentation on this admission is very similar to her presentation in July at which time she was found to be bacteremic with an additional intra-abdominal bacterial collection. At present, there is no clear source of infection, although her urinalysis is suspicious for a UTI. Elevated WBC in someone on chronic steroids is concerning for infection, but pt is hemodynamically stable and afebrile. In addition to bacteremia, UTI and re-accumulation of an intra-abdominal collection, other possible causes of her lethargy include toxic/metabolic causes (such as uremia), anemia, or depression. 

                - F/u blood,  urine, and respiratory cultures

                - Will hold off on empirically starting abx based on urinalysis (If we were to start abx, would 

                 recommend vanc/cefepime given micro history)

- Culture if spikes

                - Consider repeat abd imaging if pt continues to have a leukocytosis and doesn&#8217;t clinically 

                 improve



2. Anemia &#8211; Source of anemia has been unclear in the past. During last admission, pt was found to be guaiac positive on rectal exam but guaiac negative out of colostomy. GI at that time had deferred colonoscopy. It is possible that her anemia may be responsible for her failure to thrive. 

                - Type and screen

                - Will transfuse 1 unit of pRBCs and monitor for clinical improvement

                - Check post-transfusion Hct 



3. HTN &#8211; pt has long-standing refractory hypertension despite numerous anti-hypertensive agents

                - Per pharmacy recommendations, holding propranolol given h/o SOB

                - Continue clonidine, verapimil and hydral (titrate as needed)

4. Elevated INR &#8211; pt has a supratherapeutic INR. Given that pt is near discharge Hct from previous admission, do not feel that she is actively bleeding. As such, do not feel the need to actively reverse her. 

                - Monitor daily INRs

                - Hold warfarin overnight



5. Renal insufficiency &#8211; Cr 1.58 today (baseline 1.2). Likely secondary to prerenal 

                - Fluid resuscitation 

                - Recheck lytes in AM



6. Diabetes 

                - FSG QAC + HS

                - Lantus + RISS



7. FEN

                - Diabetic diet



8. PPx &#8211; Pboots, teds on R leg







Gerardo Valadez, M.D. 

Internal Medicine, PGY-1

Pager 47234




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>