<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2099-07-17

                     KEKELA EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
LEON,MAURICE   436-34-21-1                 VISIT DATE: 07/17/99
Patient seen on 7/17/99 by myself and the medical resident at 4:30 
p.m. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest wall pain. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  The patient is a 44 year old male 
complaining of chest wall pain, constant, times 24 hours.  The 
patient states the pain is worse with respirations and movement. 
The patient claims similar episode in past, and was told had a 
"pulled muscle". 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Patient denies trauma, denies nausea and 
vomiting, diaphoresis and shortness of breath. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Positive for hypertension and asthma. 
MEDICATIONS:  Procardia, Albuterol, Accolate. 
ALLERGIES:  None. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  A well developed, well nourished male lying 
on stretcher, communicative and in no apparent distress.  Temp 
98.3, heart rate 112, blood pressure 133/86, pulse ox 95% on room 
air.  HEENT - normocephalic, atraumatic.  Heart - regular rate and 
rhythm without murmurs, rubs or gallops.  Lungs clear without 
wheezing.  Abdomen soft, non-tender, positive bowel sounds. 
Extremities without clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  Chest wall - 
positive reproducible pain on palpation which improved when 
palpation stopped. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest wall pain, probable costochondritis. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Plan - discharge 
with nonsteroidal anti-inflammatories which patient has taken and 
tolerated in the past.  Discharged in stable condition. 
___________________________________                    HP506/6486 
WINIFRED MANNING, M.D.  WM26                               D:07/17/99 
                                                       T:07/17/99 
Dictated by:  WINIFRED MANNING, M.D.  WM26 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2099-02-01

                     KEKELA EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

LEON,MAURICE   436-34-21-1                 VISIT DATE: 02/01/99

Resident history reviewed, patient seen and examined by me. 

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 45-year-old 

black male who now presents for evaluation of chest pain.  The 

patient states he has had intermittent left-sided chest pain for 

the past several weeks.  He states he had a more prolonged episode 

of substernal chest pressure today while driving.  He states the 

pain radiated down his left arm and he did experience a mild amount 

of associated shortness of breath and diaphoresis.  He denies any 

nausea, vomiting, palpitations, light-headedness or syncope.  On 

arrival he states the pain is approximately 7/10 in intensity.  He 

denies any prior history of coronary artery disease, pulmonary 

embolus or deep venous thrombosis.  His cardiac risk factors 

include history of hypertension and hypercholesterolemia.  He also 

denies any chest wall trauma or any recent upper respiratory 

infection symptoms, cough, fever or chills.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative except per HPI.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Significant for hypertension, asthma and 

hypercholesterolemia.

MEDICATIONS:  Tenovate, albuterol MDI, Azmacort MDI, adalat.

ALLERGIES:  Bupropron which causes pruritus.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  He is adopted and does not know 

his family history.  The patient is a former smoker who quit 

approximately one year ago.  The patient is a former smoker with an 

approximately 15-pack-year history.  He states he quit one year 

ago.  He does admit to heavy drinking, approximately 3-4 drinks per 

day.  He has no prior history of illicit drug use and currently 

lives with his family.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  This is a well-developed, 

well-nourished, slightly anxious appearing male who appears in 

otherwise no acute distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature is 96.2, 

blood pressure 142/96, pulse 108, respiratory rate 20, oxygen 

saturation 96% on room air.  HEENT:  Mucous membranes are moist 

without lesions.  NECK:  Supple without jugular venous distention.  

LUNGS:  Clear to auscultation.  HEART:  Tachycardic, regular rate 

and rhythm without gallops, murmurs or rubs.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, 

nontender, nondistended.  EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis or 

edema.  No calf tenderness.  Negative Homan's sign.  NEURO:  Awake, 

alert, oriented x 3.  Nonfocal.

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  CBC, white count 6.2, hematocrit 45, 

platelets 210.  SMA-7 notable for a bicarb of 19.  D-dimer is 

pending.  CPK 134, cardiac troponin I 0.00, coagulation profile is 

normal.  Electrocardiogram shows normal sinus rhythm at a rate of 

93 with nonspecific T wave changes.  No significant change compared 

with prior tracing dated May 01, 2099.  Chest x-ray reveals no 

acute disease.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was treated with 

aspirin, nitroglycerin and morphine with relief of his pain and 

remained hemodynamically stable.

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  The patient's primary care 

physician, Dr. Greene was notified and agrees with the management 

plan.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Atypical chest pain.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted to emergency department observation under low risk for 

cardiac ischemia protocol and is currently awaiting evaluation with 

an exercise stress test as well as results of D-dimer to evaluate 

for the remote possibility of pulmonary embolism.  The patient is 

currently in stable condition. 

___________________________________                    CL893/2080 

MAX RHODES, M.D.       MR75                        D:02/01/99 

                                                       T:02/01/99 

Dictated by:  MAX RHODES, M.D.       MR75 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2099-09-27

EDVISIT^43634211^LEON, MAURICE^9/27/2099^HALEY, BEVERLY

ADDENDUM:

The patient had dizzy spells since 12/2099, which resolved after

resection of his cervical medullary tumor.  He had recurrence 3

times this morning of similar episodes.  He feels presyncopal and

has headache.  He denies any nausea, vomiting, fevers, chills or

upper respiratory symptoms.  He has had some epigastric pain. 

During all of these episodes, he never lost consciousness, but he

does a fall and slump.  He feels lightheaded prior to the

episode.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Remarkable for rheumatoid arthritis,

psoriasis, hypertension, cholesterol, and asthma.

Social history, family history, and review of systems are as per

the written note.  The patient was counseled regarding smoking

cessation.

MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin, Lipitor, nifedipine, and Neurontin.

ALLERGIES:  None.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is awake, alert, in no acute

distress.  Vital signs are remarkable for temperature of 97.3,

pulse 58, respiratory rate 16, blood pressure 134/79, and oxygen

saturation is 96% on room air.  For full physical exam findings,

please see the resident's written notes.  Specifically, HEENT

exam is atraumatic and normal to inspection.  There is minimal

right ptosis on my exam.  Neck is normal, supple, with posterior

well-healed cervical scar.  There is no lymphadenopathy on my

exam.  Respiratory, cardiac, abdominal, skin, and musculoskeletal

exam are within normal limits as documented.  Neurologically, the

patient is oriented with normal pleasant mood and affect.  Speech

is fluent.  Cranial nerves are remarkable only for intermittent

right-sided ptosis.  Extraocular movements are otherwise intact,

and the patient is moving all 4 extremities without any motor or

sensory deficit.

LABORATORY DATA:  CBC and electrolytes are remarkable for BUN and

creatinine ratio of 22-0.9 respectively.  CK and troponin are

flat.  INR is 1.  EKG demonstrates sinus rhythm without any

significant ST-T wave changes when compared to prior studies.

IMAGING STUDIES:  Head CT is unremarkable.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient with possible

presyncope without EKG changes, nor any evidence for new disease

on his head CT, will undergo consultation by Neurology and

Neurosurgery, and will be admitted to the ED Observation area for

likely MR imaging prior to admission.  The patient if not

admitted to either of the Neurosurgery or Neurology Services will

require admission to the Medicine Service for syncope workup.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

DISPOSITION:  Admitted to ED Observation Unit.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  Near syncope.

SECONDARY DIAGNOSIS:  Status post cervical medullary tumor

resection.

______________________________

HALEY, BEVERLY MD

D: 09/27/99

T: 09/27/99

Dictated By: HALEY, BEVERLY

eScription document:7-2933615 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2099-03-29


Neurology resident consult note
 


Patient Name:      Leon

MRN:                      43634211

Date:                      0021

Consult reason:  
?abnormal gait



HPI:  53RHM who going to bed Wednesday was in usoh, but Thursday 2:30AM awoke w/ terrible HA, so came to ED; got CT head and LP, both negative for blood. However, BP was reportedly as high as 190/106 (and wife says she&#8217;s measured it this high at home at least once in past 2 weeks), and blood glucose 400s. I see no LMR note about the visit, but am told that he was given some medication for his BP, given some insulin and a Rx for insulin, and instructed to see his PCP the next day, and discharged. Friday he did see his PCP, who told him not to take insulin but to take oral DM meds instead, and told him to return to the ED b/c he still had a terrible HA, so he came back to the EDUCARE-PULLMAN ED tonight. He was given caffeine, ibuprofen, Tylenol, and compazine, reported that his HA was gone. However, a staff physician in the ED on exam noted a wide based gait. An MRI was originally ordered, but canceled when it came to notice that he has an implanted device to prevent syncope that precludes MRI. Neurology is now consulted.to comment on his gait and other sx. 



Patient and his wife tell me that his gait is baseline, and has been as it is for years; they have noticed no change and have no complaints. 

He is very unpleasant and un-forthcoming about his history, slow to cooperate w/ exam; says he wants to go home, resents being in the ED still now that his HA is gone. 



VS in ED tonight: BP 172/95 max, but mostly 150-160s; temp 98, hr 89, 100% RA

Blood glucose not measured tonight. 



ROS: 

Negative for: changes in vision or hearing, neck pain, tinnitus, vertigo, weakness, numbness, difficulty with comprehension, speaking, language, swallowing, eating, balance or gait. 

General review of systems negative for:  fevers, chills, rashes, change in weight, energy level or appetite, chest pain, palpitations, shortness of breath, cough, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, and change in bowel or bladder habits (i.e incontinence). 



MEDS: metoprolol, omeprazole, simvastatin (he is unsure whether this is all)

ALL: nkda

PMH: 

-HTN; he denies prior dx of DM before yesterday night

-recurrent cardiogenic syncope, for which he has had &#8220;Reveal&#8221; device implanted, then explanted b/c of pain, then recurrent sycope and reimplantation of device, after which syncope stopped (see notes in LMR from Dr. Susan Root)



SH: denies t/e/d, works as &#8220;Pipefitter&#8221;

FH: HTN, DM



Neurologic Examination: 

MS: unpleasant, uncooperative w/ history, angry about being in the ED still

AOx3, appropriately interactive and conversational. Normal affect. 

Speech is fluent with intact comprehension and repetition, no paraphasic errors. 

Concentration and attention intact. 

CN: Visual fields full to confrontation; pupils equal and reactive 3&gt;2 direct and concensual; no ptosis; 

Extraocular movements full without nystagmus; facial sensation to LT normal. 

Hearing intact to finger rub bilaterally; face, tongue and palate are symmetric; SCM and traps 5/5.

Motor: Normal bulk and tone; no tremor, rigidity, or bradykinesia. No pronator drift. Finger tapping normal.


Delt


Bi


Tri


FE


IP


Quad


Hamst


TibAnt


EHL


Gastro






C5


C6


C7


C8/T1


L2


L3


L4-S1


L4


L5


S1



R


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5



L


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5


5





Sensory: Intact/symmetric LT/PP/T/JPS throughout.   

Reflexes: absent throughout. 


Cerebellar: Finger-nose-finger, rapid alternating movements, heel-knee-shin normal and symmetric b/l.

Gait: Slightly wide based. Normal arm swing, normal speed. Able to walk on toes and heels. Some difficulty w/ tandem walk. Negative Romberg. 



A/P:  53RHM w/ HTN urgency yesterday, newly diagnosed DM w/ FS in 300-400s yesterday, who yesterday presented w/ new HA and negative w/u for SAH, now back again for same HA, which has finally resolved in apparently in concert w/ some improvement in BP (current BP 150s) and w/ medications. Neurology was specifically consulted for his gait, which does appear a bit wide-based, but he and wife confirm that this is chronic, and I strongly doubt any relation to his current HA problems. Most obvious medical issues to focus on here are his poorly controlled HTN, which I suspect is the primary cause of his HA, and his uncontrolled DM, of which he obviously does not yet understand the import and does not seem likely to comply with insulin treatment without further education. 



In any case, I find no acute neurological issues. 



Recs: 

-BP management

-DM management. 



Thanks for this interesting consult. 

Case/plan discussed w/ KEKELA neurology attending by phone, Dr. Ivan Guy. 

Call w/ questions 86383. 



Keith Gilbert, MD, PhD, 

Neurology resident PGY3



Addendum: 

He did not mention this when I questioned him and wife about PMH, but digging through prior LMR notes I find this addition to his PMH: 

A note from Dr. Robert Irish, neurosurgery, from 3/2099 notes that he is s/p &#8220;cervical laminectomy and foramen magnum resection followed by removal of an intramedullary tumor near his foramen magnum.  He is doing much better today.  He states that his headaches are considerably better, and the left hemibody dysesthesias are much better tolerated since the initiation of Neurontin.&#8221;






****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>