<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2072-11-25

                     RGH EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

MULLINS,DOLORES U   728-41-92-0               VISIT DATE: 01/24/73

This patient was seen, interviewed and examined by myself as well 

as Dr. Hawkins whose note I reviewed and with which I agree.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 70-year-old female who 

presents with inability to control her left arm and left leg.  The 

patient had onset of her symptoms approximately two hours prior to 

arrival.  The patient denies any change in sensation but she 

definitely did notice weakness with decreased ability to control 

her left side extremities.  The patient states that her left arm 

control was regained after approximately one or two hours.  Her 

left leg control is better but still is not back to baseline.  

Review of systems, family history and social history as per the 

resident's note.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, 

hypertension.

MEDICATIONS:  Insulin, Diltiazem, labetalol.

ALLERGIES:  TETANUS.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  This is a well-developed, well-nourished 

female, in mild distress, appears concerned.  Temperature is 96.9 

degrees, pulse 65, respiratory rate of 18, blood pressure is 

163/104.  Repeat blood pressure is 174/80.  Oxygen saturation is 

97% on room air.  HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic.  Pupils are 

equally round and reactive to light and accommodation.  Extraocular 

motions are intact.  No nystagmus.  NECK:  Supple with full range 

of motion.  2+ carotids, no bruits.  CARDIAC:  Regular rate and 

rhythm.  EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis or edema.  Extremities 

are nontender to palpation throughout.  NEURO:  Alert, oriented x 

3.  Follows commands, appropriate.  Cranial nerves II-XII are 

intact.  There is 5/5 motor strength in individual motor group 

testing of the upper extremities and lower extremities bilaterally. 

The patient is unable to stand without assistance.  Comprehension 

is within normal limits.  Further details of the physical 

examination are as per the resident's note.

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Labs are significant for a glucose of 162, 

BUN of 20, creatinine 1.3, sodium 145, potassium 4.2, chloride 108, 

bicarb 26, calcium 9.4.  White count is 8.1, hematocrit 39.0, 

platelets 341.  A UA shows no blood, no leucocyte esterase, no 

ketones.  Head CT shows no acute intracranial abnormality and mild 

involutional changes.  EKG shows a sinus rhythm at 57 beats per 

minute with non-specific T wave changes.  This is compared to an 

EKG from 2068 and was found to be without significant change.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was seen and evaluated 

in the Emergency Department with labs and studies obtained as 

documented above.  The initial concerns were for a focal seizure 

versus a TIA.  The patient was hypertensive on her arrival and, 

therefore, received labetalol for improved blood pressure control 

and the Neurology Service was consulted early in the patient's 

care.  The patient does not have any evidence of focal motor group 

weakness at this time, nor sensation changes.  The patient will 

require admission to the Neurology Service for further workup of 

her seizure versus TIA.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  TIA.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 

admitted to the hospital in satisfactory condition.

___________________________________                    OH527/2519 

YULIANNA ELKINS, M.D.   YE96                            D:01/24/73 

                                                       T:01/24/73 

Dictated by:  YULIANNA ELKINS, M.D.   YE96 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2079-09-01

 

Rheumatology Consult Note

Name: Mullins, Dolores U
MRN: 72841920
DOB: 06/06/02
Location: 78Q-47-4
Consult date: 09/01/79
Referring Physician: Gay Langley
Source of history: patient interview, medical records
Code status: Full

Reason for Consult: bilateral LE pain up to knees
HPI:
77 yo F w/h/o type I DM and HTN.  At the beginning of this year, she began to have intermittent    burning    pain of her feet and sometimes her lower legs/feet.  This pain typically occurred on one leg more than the other, without an overall predominance of one side.  In the past month, she has had continuous, bilateral    burning    pain that began in both feet.  Several weeks ago, her pain worsened considerably such that she was having difficulty shopping.  Around this time, the pain spread up her legs to above her knees.  She also noted having difficulty putting on shoes and was told by a friend that her feet were swollen (she is unable to see her feet due to blindness).  Her pain continued to worsen until the night prior to admission, when she was in her bathroom and found herself in such pain that she was unable to get up to leave the bathroom.  A friend found her after 8 hours and EMS was called.  In the ED, she was found to have BP elevated to 190, Cr elevated to 2.8, FSG down to 51, and R-sided hydronephrosis.  Labetolol/diltiazem were given for HTN with good response, IV hydration was given with subsequent decline in Cr, and Foley was placed with resolution of hydronephrosis on subsequent MRI.   

She has never had    burning    pain of the kind that she presented with prior to this year.  Of note, she has had    years    of tingling without numbness in her lower extremities bilaterally extending to above her knees.  She also notes numbness of the tips of her R 2nd-4th digits.  ROS positive for subjective decline in urine output and constipation (1 BM/2days).  She denies fever/chills/sweats, recent weight loss, fatigue, hypoglycemic episodes, cough/rhinorrhea/sore throat, SOB, orthpnea, CP, palpitations, abdominal pain, diarrhea, dysuria, polyuria/polydipsia.  

PMH: 
1) DM     type 1, since 2060, c/b retinopathy, nephropathy
2) HTN
3) Hypercholesterolemia
4) L internal capsule CVA 11/72
5) L eye legally blind 2/2 open angle glaucoma
6) thyroid nodule 7/78        benign    per patient
7) CRI     per HHMR, Cr 1.4 (4/78, 1/79) and 1.84 on 6/29/79

PSH:
1) bilateral cataracts
2) L eye    glaucoma    surgery
3) L eye    pressure shunt   
4) TAH at age 25




Admission Meds:
1) Labetalol 200 mg bid
2) HCTZ 25 mg qd
3) Lovastatin 20 mg qd
4) Enalapril 20 mg qd
5) Diltiazem 120 mg bid
6) ASA 81 mg qd
7) Novolin 10 U qam
8) NPH 70 U qam, 40 U qpm

Inpatient Meds: 
1) Ferrous sulphate 325 po tid
2) Enoxaparin 30 sc qd
3) Simvastatin 40 po qhs
4) Diltiazem SR 120 po bid
5) Labetolol 200 mg bid
6) Novolog SS ac, RISS qhs
7) NPH 70 U qam, 30 U qpm
8) Regular Insulin 10 U qam
9) Colchicine 0.6 mg qd (2 doses given)
10) Lumigan ou 1 drop qd
11) Prednisolone 1% 1 drop au bid
12) Colace 100 mg po bid
13) ASA 81 mg po qd
14) Oxycodone 10 mg po q6h prn
Gabapentin 100 mg tid     5 doses given before being discontinued

Allergies: NKDA

SH: Never smoked, does not currently drink ETOH, no h/o substance abuse, lives on the 2nd floor of an apartment (15 steps) and has neighbors who check in on her.  She is widowed with closest family being a cousin in Alaska.  She has been able to meet her needs of daily living independently. 

FH: Mother with fatal MI at 65, no family h/o rheumatic disease or cancer.  

PE: 
Tm 99.5, Tc 97.3, HR 51 (46-72), BP 126/50 (120-154/50-70), RR 18 (16-18), O2 sat 96% (94-98) RA
Gen     NAD when immobile, but great pain with minimal movement or contact with lower extremities
HEENT     2 mm pupils, EOM intact, no scleral icterus, oropharnyx nl, no gouty tophi on pinna
Neck     Supple, no lymphadenopathy, no JVD
CV     RRR, nl S1 S2, 2/6 SEM best heard in RUSB
Chest     Late inspiratory crackles at bases bilaterally
Abd     +BS, soft, NT, ND, liver edge above chostochondral margin, no palpable splenomegaly, no masses
Back     R CVA and flank tenderness
MSK     Heberdin and Bouchard   s nodes of PIPs/DIPs bilaterally, varus deformity of R 2nd-4th DIPs, no joint tenderness or reduced ROM of upper extremities; visible knee effusions bilaterally without erythema or warmth; exquisite tenderness to minimal motion or palpation of knees, tibio-talars, tarsals, and MTPs; no effusions palpable or visible in tibio-talars, tarsals, and MTPs
Ext     WWP, 1+ pedal edema bilaterally
Pulses     2+ DP bilaterally
Skin     no rashes, dry skin covering LEs greatest on medial aspect
Neuro    no focal upper extremity motor deficits, 5/5 finger grip




Labs:
Na 139, K 4.2, Cl 106, CO2 23, BUN 61, Cr 1.79 (1.69 yesterday), Glu 141, Ca 8.9, P 3.8, Mg 2.1
TP 6.9, Alb 3.0, Glob 3.9
ALT 14, AST 12, ALKP 76, TBILI 0.4
FE 12, TIBC 205, B12 303, Folate 12.7
HGBA1C 6.1
Uric acid 11.5
ESR 101, CRP 141.6
WBC 12.51 (N76 L14 M8 E2), Hct 28.8, Plt 398
Beta-hydroxybutyrate 0.41
UA sg 1.018, pH 5.0, protein 2+, 6 WBCs/hpf, 2+ bacteria, 1+ squames, no urine crystals

Studies:
TTE  (8/31/79, no prior studies)     Mild concentric LVH, LVEF 77%, impaired relaxation c/w diastolic dysfunction, mild left atrial enlargement, nl right atrium and ventricle, mild aortic stenosis, mild mitral regurgitation, estimated PASP 48.6, nl aortic root, no pericardial effusions
LE Doppler (8/31/79)     No evidence of proximal DVTs or calf DVTs bilaterally
Abdominal MRI (8/31/79)     Tiny cortical right renal hemorrhagic cysts, small hiatal hernia, right extrarenal pelvis without hydronephrosis or obstructing mass lesion
Renal U/S (8/30/79)     Mild right hydronephrosis with prominent extrarenal pelvis and multiple renal cysts, nl left kidney
CXR (8/29/79)     No evidence of pulmonary edema, PNX, or pleural effusion; aorta tortuous and partially calcified; degenerative changes of thoracic spine and left shoulder, cardiac silhouette prominent but wnl

Microbiology:
Blood cultures x2     Negative at 2 days
Urine cultures x2     5000 colonies mixed, 500 colonies probable lactobacilli

A/P: 77 yo F w/h/o DM and HTN who presented with several weeks of worsening bilateral LE burning pain exacerbated by movement and pressure.  She was found to have exquisitely tender joints up to and including her knees with visible synovial effusions of her knees bilaterally.  Aspiration of one of her knees revealed needle-shaped negatively birefringent crystals, diagnostic of gout.  This is consistent with her elevated uric acid and her elevated markers of inflammation (ESR/CRP).  Given that she has a long history of symptoms of LE diabetic neuropathy and that she has some diffuse soft tissue tenderness, she may also have some pain from diabetic neuropathy that may declare itself after her gout is treated.  However, her current inability to walk can be clearly attributed to gout.  

Recs:
- Solumedrol 40 mg bid IV, prednisone 40 mg qd starting tomorrow with 12-day outpatient taper (40 mg x 3 days, 30 mg x 3 days, 20 mg x 3 days, 10 mg x 3 days)
- Colchicine po 0.6 mg qd for 2 weeks, then 0.6 mg qod for 2 weeks
- Continue to hold HCTZ     discuss with PCP need to restart as outpatient as it is a risk factor for hyperuricemia
- F/u with rheumatology in 4 weeks for initiation of allopurinol (please arrange appointment w/ Dr. Yau)



Procedure: R knee aspiration
Patient was informed of the risks of bleeding and infection and gave consent. The medial aspect of the right knee was sterilized using iodine swabs x3, sterile gloves used in a one-handed sterile lateral approach. 1.5cc of 1% lidocaine was injected to raise a wheal inferior to the R patella. A 18G needle was inserted into the knee and approximately 20cc of opaque, yellow fluid was withdrawn. A slide was prepared and examined under the microscope by myself, Dr. Yau, and Dr. Woodard.  Abundant intracellular and extracellular needle-shapped negatively birefringent crystals were observed.  Synovial fluid sample was also submitted for culture, Gram stain, cell count, and crystal analysis.



__________________________________
Isaac Ito, MS4 x79975


Addendum:
Patient seen, records reviewed, case reviewed with medical student. Agree with excellent note above. Patient seen with Dr. Woodard.




______________________
Unknown Yau, MD
Rheumatology fellow




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-06-04

EDVISIT^72841920^MULLINS, DOLORES^06/04/80^KROLL, OLIVIA

The patient was seen in conjunction with the PA.  This is a

shared visit.  I confirm I have interviewed and examined the

patient.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Rule out CVA.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, this is a 70-year-old

female with hypertension, hypercholesteremia, and diabetes who

was found by a neighbor at approximately 9:30 this morning,

nonverbal with right-sided facial droop.  The patient was seated

in the chair upon EMS arrival.  Per the neighbor who had returned

from vacation, went up to check on her and found her this way,

nonverbal, seated in a chair, but consciousness.  Per EMS, the

patient was responding to commands, able to stand, had symmetric

handgrips, unknown when she was last seen normal.  Per the

neighbor, the patient's baseline is alert and oriented. 

Fingerstick in the field was 179.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  As stated per HPI and written chart.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Unknown.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Unknown.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Limited secondary to the patient's medical

condition and severity.

MEDICATIONS:  Per medication list.

ALLERGIES:  Tetanus per old medical records.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Blood pressure 216/76, pulse is 68, and O2

saturation 99%.  HEENT:  Atraumatic with left pupil defect. 

Lungs:  Equal and bilateral.  Cardiovascular:  S1 and S2. 

Abdomen:  Soft and nontender.  Skin:  Intact, warm, and dry. 

Neurologic:  Right-sided facial droop, bilateral hand grip. 

Normal plantar flexion able to sit up, and following commands.

IMAGING STUDIED:  EKG normal sinus, no acute ST segment

elevation.

LABORATORY DATA:  Chemistries are remarkable for creatinine of

2.8, sodium and chloride pending.  Bicarbonate of 22.  CK 256

with a MB of 4, troponin negative.  No white count, hematocrit of

34, and platelets of 410,000.  INR 1.1.  UA showed 3+ protein, no

leukocyte esterase, nitrites.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Upon the patient's arrival in

Emergency Department, Stroke team was paged, underwent a stat

head CT, which showed no bleed, but a question of a hypodensity. 

The patient sent her for an urgent MRI/MRA and will be admitted

to the Neurology Service.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSIS:  CVA.

SECONDARY DIAGNOSES:  Diabetes and hypertension.

DISPOSITION:  Plan for admission to Neurology Service.

Please see written chart and nurse's note.  Old HHMR records

reviewed.

______________________________

KROLL, OLIVIA M.D.

D: 06/04/80

T: 06/04/80

Dictated By: KROLL, OLIVIA

eScription document:7-1892564 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-07-19

EDVISIT^72841920^MULLINS, DOLORES^07/19/80^TAVARES, IDRIS

I saw this patient with Dr. Xavier Palacios.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient. 

Please see the resident's note for further details.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Fast heart rate.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 78-year-old female

with history of a left MCA stroke, atrial fibrillation,

hypertension, diabetes, and renal insufficiency who was

transferred from Southwest Montana Radiology for atrial

fibrillation with rapid ventricular response.  The patient has

been in Southwest Montana for the last several weeks.  During her

rehabilitation stay, the patient was noted to have sinus

bradycardia and sinus pauses.  The patient's metoprolol was

stopped.  The patient was previously on metoprolol 6.25 mg every

6 hours.  The patient was noted to have atrial fibrillation with

rapid ventricular response on exam this morning.  The patient is

followed by Dr. Octavia Xue of Heritage Hospital Cardiology. 

Given the difficulty that Southwest Montana has had ____

the patient's atrial fibrillation, the patient was transferred

here to Riverton General Hospital for further management and

further placement.  The patient is asymptomatic.  The patient

denies any chest pain or shortness of breath.  The patient denies

any lightheadedness.  The patient has no other complaints.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient's vital signs revealed the

following:  Temperature is 96.4, heart rate of 79, respiratory

rate of 18, blood pressure is 112/63, and oxygen saturations at

100% on room air.  The patient's oxygen saturation was

interpreted as normal.  General:  No acute distress, pleasant,

and multiple family members at bedside.  HEENT:  The patient's

head was normocephalic.  Mucous membranes were dry.  Posterior

oropharynx was clear.  Neck:  Supple.  No carotid bruits.  No

JVD.  Respiratory:  Clear to auscultation bilaterally.  No focal

rhonchi, rales, or wheezes.  Cardiovascular:  Irregularly

irregular, tachycardic.  No gross murmurs, rubs, or gallops were

appreciated.  GI:  Abdomen:  Soft.  No rebound or guarding. 

Minimal suprapubic tenderness to palpation.  G-tube in place. 

Rectal exam:  Deferred.  GU exam:  Deferred.  Skin:  Warm and

dry.  No rash or lesions were noted.  Back:  No costovertebral

angle tenderness.  Extremities:  Warm and well perfused.  Lower

extremity pitting edema rising up to the knees.  No palpable

cords.  Neurologic:  The patient was alert and oriented.  The

patient moved all 4 extremities with fair strength.  The patient

did have a right facial droop.  I did not ambulate the patient.

INITIAL IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  The patient is a 78-year-old female

with history of atrial fibrillation, and recent left MCA stroke

who was transferred from Southwest Montana for management

of her atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response.  The

patient is hemodynamically stable at this time.  The patient is

asymptomatic.  The patient will need rate control and will need

to be admitted to Heritage Hospital Cardiology.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Upon arrival to the Emergency

Department, the patient had history and physical exam performed. 

The patient then had 12-lead EKG performed.  The patient's

12-lead EKG was notable for atrial fibrillation with rapid

ventricular response.  The patient did have some nonspecific ST-T

changes when compared to her prior EKG.  The patient's laboratory

studies so far has been largely unremarkable.  The patient's

first set of cardiac markers were negative.  The patient's

complete blood count was notable for an elevated white blood cell

count of 10.8.  The patient's hematocrit of 33.2.  The patient's

platelets were somewhat elevated at 560,000.  The patient's

portable chest x-ray has been ordered and results of the

patient's portable chest x-ray are still pending at this time. 

The case was then discussed with the Heritage Hospital

cardiologist on call.  The patient ____ will be admitted to

Heritage Hospital Cardiology and to a monitor bed.  I did try to

page Dr. Octavia Xue to let her know about the patient's

admission to Heritage Hospital Cardiology.  The patient and

patient's family were in agreement with the plan.  The patient

was started on metoprolol down her G-tube.  The patient had a

good response to the metoprolol.  The patient was given

metoprolol 6.25 mg.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSES:

1.  Atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response.

2.  History of a left MCA stroke.

DISPOSITION:  The patient was admitted to Heritage Hospital

Cardiology.

CONDITION AT TIME OF DISPOSITION:  Stable and satisfactory.

______________________________

TAVARES, IDRIS M.D.

D: 07/19/80

T: 07/19/80

Dictated By: TAVARES, IDRIS

eScription document:4-5337537 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>