<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2094-09-18

EDVISIT^11289501^FAY, BROOK^9/18/2094^XAYSANA, YUSEF

I confirm that I have interviewed and examined the patient,

reviewed the resident's documentation on the patient's chart, and

discussed the evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the

patient and the resident, Dr. Vanburen.  Please see his note for

full details.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  A 67-year-old female who presents to

triage complaining of substernal chest pain, diaphoretic.  Triage

note states that she is complaining of substernal chest pain

radiating to the neck with this and diaphoresis.  She is cool and

pale.  Her triage vital signs showed pulse of 148, up to 180s. 

She was tachypneic.  Her blood pressure was unobtainable and her

sats were 90% on room air.  She is hypoxic.  She was afebrile,

temperature 96.  She was immediately brought back to room.  At

that time, she complained of palpitations, diaphoresis, and chest

pain since 10 p.m.  She has had no history of an MI.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  She does have history of hypertension,

diabetes, and hypercholesterolemia.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She denies any tobacco or IV drugs or any other

drugs.  She lives with her family who is at her bedside.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  She has had bilateral tubal ligation.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Currently, chest pain, palpitations,

diaphoresis, and shortness of breath.  Otherwise, all systems are

negative.

MEDICATIONS:  She is on metformin and Lipitor.

ALLERGIES:  She has no known drug allergies.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is awake, alert, in moderate distress.

 She is tachycardic to 180 in the monitor.  Her blood pressure is

not able to be obtained at this time.  Her saturations are 100%

on room air, normal interpretation.  She is alert, awake and

oriented, follows commands.  Her head is atraumatic.  Her pharynx

is normal.  Her neck is supple and nontender.  She is in no

respiratory distress with normal breath sounds.  Her heart is

tachycardic with a narrow complex tachycardia on monitor.  Her

abdomen is soft and nontender.  Her skin is intact but

diaphoretic.  Extremities are without pedal edema.  She is

oriented x3 with no cranial nerve and no motor or sensory

deficits.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  She was placed on a monitor, EKG

and received oxygen as well with this.  She was explained that

she was going to receive adenosine 6 mg and this did break her

off from her SVT.  I was present during this time.  She had an

EKG that then transformed to normal sinus rhythm at 91 with an

incomplete right bundle-branch block with no previous to compare.

 She received aspirin, Lopressor, and nitroglycerin and remained

hemodynamically stable throughout her ED stay.  For her

tachycardia and chest pain, we ruled out AFib, complex

tachycardia, pulmonary embolism, and acute coronary syndrome. 

She was admitted for telemetry as well as a cardiac rule out. 

Her white count was 12 and her hematocrit was 42.  BUN 29 and

creatinine 1.2.  The d-dimer was negative.  Troponin was

negative.  Her chest x-ray was negative.

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

1.  SVT.

2.  Chest pain, rule out acute coronary syndrome.

3.  Abnormal EKG.

CRITICAL CARE TIME:  20 minutes.

______________________________

XAYSANA, YUSEF M.D.

D: 09/20/94

T: 09/21/94

Dictated By: XAYSANA, YUSEF

eScription document:8-5805926 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2095-09-04

ADULT PHYSICAL EXAM VISIT
DATE:
9/04/95

New pt to me; previously cared for by Dr. Winston, Dr. Dye.

pt nearly 20 min late for 30 min appt

CONCERNS:
1. Need refill on cholesterol med



PMH/PROBLEM LIST:
CHRONIC JOINT PAIN 
GERDS
INTERTRIGO 
Htn
dyslipidemia
dm
avnrt 2094 
obesity
rbbb
oa
mild rhabdo thought to be due to crestor
neg dipyridamole myocardial PET scan 8/94 (no flow limiting CAD, nl LV fxn)


MEDICATIONS:
albuterol inh 
oyst-cal 500 w/ vit D -- 1 tab bid
tramadol 50 mg tabs  -- 1 tab q 6 hrs
metformin 500 mg po bid 
avandia 8 mg po qd 
lisnopril 10 mg po qd
hctz 25 mg po qd 
asa 81 mg po qd 
atenolol 50 mg po qd
omeprazole 20 mg po qd 
loratadine 10 mg po qd 
1 touch lancets
1 touch blood glucose strips 
2 touch monitor
fosamax 70 mg tabs , 1 tab q wk
doxepin 25 mg po qd 
amitriptyline 10 mgpo qd 
cholesterol med - hasn't taken in 1.5 months 

ALLERGIES:
crestor --rhabdo

SOCIAL HISTORY and HABITS:
Tobacco: no
Alcohol: no
Recreational Drugs: none
Sexual History: yes, doesn't use condoms
Diet:  pt says is varied. 
Exercise: walks a little
Seat Belts: yes


REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:

cough --
reports 2 weeks of cough; associated w/ tickling senstation in throat
no nasal discharge, no fever

 
leg pain -- 
years in duration
told she had arthritis


PHYSICAL EXAM
VS: 206 1/2 lb  59.75 inches 98.5  126/92  72
GENERAL: Well-appearing, in no apparent distress.
SKIN: No suspicious lesions.
HEENT: Head normocephalic, atraumatic.  Sclerae and conjunctiva unremarkable.  EOMI.    No nasal discharge.  Mucous membranes moist with no erythema, lesions, or exudate.
NECK:  no lymphadenopathy, no thyroidmegaly.  
PULM: No accessory muscle use.  Clear to auscultation without wheezes, rhonchi, or rales.  
CV: RRR, normal S1,S2, no murmur/rug/or gallop.
BREASTS: symmetric.  No nipple or skin abnormalities, no mass lesions, no axillary nodes.
ABDOMEN: Soft, non-tender, non-distended with no HSM.
GYN: Derferred as had pelvic, PAP earlier this year.
NEURO: Alert, oriented.

ASSESSMENT and PLAN:
This is a a 68 yr old f with the following issues:

#1 Routine Health Maintenance:
--PAP; pt reports had nl PAP this year w/ Dr. Dye
--mammography -- per pt had this year w/ Dr. Dye and was nl
--colorectal -- had at GH this year and was wnl per pt
--osteoporosis screening -- pt reports she had this done this year by other PCP -- is already on fosamax
--asa if risk for cad -- already on

Imms: pneumcoccal -- pt reports 3 years ago but isn't entirely sure, Td -- doesn't recall

Asked pt to get records.  

#2 HTN
126/92; 92 not at goal.  Pt doesn't want me to recheck her bp today. No changes in med today, will check at next visit.
--check lytes given meds

#3 DM
Report that she check sugars at home.  107 this nl.  69-107 in general.  
--check Hgb A1c
--check U microalbumin

#4 Dyslipidemia
Will check fasting lipids today to determine starting point and to guide which med to use.  Of note, had h/o mild rhabdo in 2094 in setting of crestor use -- this was noted during CCH hospitalization.  Gemfibrozil was recommended (unclear if pt ever took), although it was suggested that pt could do trial of pravachol.

#5 Obesity
Discussed risks of obestiy.
Has appt already with nutritionist at GH later this month.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2096-09-17

 Medicine Admission Note


Patient Name:  Fay, Brook
MRN: 11289501
Date: 9/16/96
Admitting Staff: Tellez
Location:  59H

Reason for Admission:  Dysphagia

HPI: Ms. Fay is a 69 year-old woman with diabetes who presented from home with an approximately 2 month history of progressive dysphagia, solid and liquid. About that time she was prescribed Amoxicillin and Metronidazole, presumably for H. pylori eradication (not confirmed); she reports an adverse reaction to amoxicillin with rash and facial swelling. The meds were discontinued and she started a course of oral methylprednisolone. She stopped this several weeks ago because it made her jittery. Approximately the same time she began to notice that food and pills would feel stuck in the throat; on further questioning, she also may have noted the presence of white spots in the mouth around this time as well. No fevers, chills, night sweats, nausea, vomiting, chest pain, palpitations, headache, lightheadedness, vertigo, rash or new joint pain; no recent travel. She does note that her blood sugars at home have been consistently elevated to the 200-300 range.

In the ED, Ms. Fay was afebrile and hemodynamically stable. She was evaluated by the GI department. A screening HIV test was negative. She was found to have mild hyponatremia and mild hyperkalemia, as well as a question of subtle ECG changes. The above findings prompted admission for further workup.

ROS: Pertinent positives and negatives above.

PMH/PSH:   
Diabetes mellitus
Hypertension
Hyperlipidemia
Obesity
GERD
Osteoarthritis and low back pain
H/o AVNRT (2094)

ALLERGIES: Reported rash and facial swelling with Amoxicillin

MEDICATIONS: 
Atenolol 50mg daily
Diclofenac 75 mg Q8 prn
Metformin 500mg PO BID
Pantoprazole 40 mg daily
Loratadine
Albuterol MDI
Meclizine 25mg PRN
Aledronate 70mg weekly

FAMILY HISTORY: Noncontributory

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Lives alone; family heavily involved in her care and assist with secondary ADLs. No alcohol, tobacco or drug use. Born in Peru, last visit about one year ago.

PHYSICAL EXAM:	
Gen: Alert, NAD
VS:  Afebrile   82   100/54   18   100% RA
HEENT:  Conjunctivae clear, anicteric, NP clear, OP with mild thrush, upper dentures; no sinus tenderness
Neck:  Supple, no adenopathy; no palpable thyromegaly
Heart: RRR, s1s2 without murmur
Lungs: CTA bilaterally without wheeze/rales
ABD: Soft, nontender, nondistended, nabs, no mass
EXT:  Warm, no edema
Skin: No rash or petechiae
Neuro: A&Ox3, no focal deficits
       
LABORATORY:
15.6 > 42.3 < 487   (77 poly, 17 lymph)
130 / 5.3 / 99 / 21 / 38 / 1.1 < 375   eGFR 48
ALT/AST normal
CK/MG/Troponin normal x 2 sets
UA: 3+ glucose, otherwise negative

MICROBIOLOGY: Urine culture pending

RADIOLOGY: None

ECG: NSR, incomplete RBBB; T wave flattening/inversion in V2-V3 that was not noted on 2094 ECG

IMPRESSION and PLAN: 66 year-old woman with solid/liquid dysphagia, oral candidiasis, and poorly controlled diabetes mellitus. The presence of thrush raises suspicion for esophageal candidiasis, though she does not report odynophagia. Mechanical obstruction should be ruled out. The presence of mild hyponatremia and hyperkalemia is likely attributable to the fact that she abruptly discontinued exogenous corticosteroids after a several week course; she is hemodynamically stable. Finally, there is little here to suggest acute coronary syndrome, though she falls into a subgroup of patients more likely to present with minimal symptoms. ECG warrants following. Diabetes is poorly controlled and may require initiation of insulin therapy; though sugars here may have been confounded by the dose of steroids given in ED.

CV: CR monitor overnight; cycle ECG and cardiac biomarkers; aspirin, continue beta blocker
Pulm: No issues; albuterol prn
GI: Upper endoscopy tentatively planned for the morning; NPO after midnight; continue home ppi
Endocrine: Sliding scale insulin, metformin; consider diabetes education, and discuss with PCP whether initiation of insulin is warranted. Check HbA1c, TFTs
FEN: Monitor lytes; lowfat ADA diet
Infectious Disease: Following EGD, fluconazole for candidiasis; leukocytosis is unexplained, but not focal evidence of infection
PPx: Enoxaparin may be started after EGD
Social work consult to assess support network and assist with discharge planning

Terry Iyer will assume care in the morning. Please page Dr. Iyer directly at 00450 with questions arising after 8:00am.


________________________________
Paul Gardner, MD
Pager 48272




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2097-07-30

                                                       Patient Name: FAY,BROOK  [ 11289501(CCH) ] F

                                                         Date of Visit: 07/30/2097





Reason for Visit

Mrs. Fay is a 70 year old spanish speaking female with multiple medical problems who presents today as a follow up for her diabetes, adrenal insufficiency



History of Present Illness

Insulin- was having erratic dosing and hypoglycemia- changed to lantus last week, but had problems- mainly from understanding it, changed back to other, may have 

 

adrenal- trying to lower prednisone. tolerating 3 mg, stopped completely on her own- feels better.

 

had eyes exam- told no dbr- about two weeks ago 





Review of Systems

Constitutional: No fever, chills, fatigue, nightsweats, insomnia, change in weight

Eyes: No double vision, blurred vision, red, dry, itchy or painful eyes. No discharge

ENT/Mouth: No rhinitis, epistaxis, sinus pain, change in hearing, tinnitus, discharge from ears, ear pain oral lesions, problems chewing, dental pain, sore throat

Cardiovascular: no chest pain, pressure, palpitation, PND, orthopnea, dyspnea on exertion, pedal edema, nocturia, claudication, 

Respiratory: no cough, sputum, dyspnea, pleuritic pain, wheeze, loud snoring, hemoptysis

Gastrointestinal: No dysphagia, odynophagia, heartburn, abdominal pain, change in the bowel habits, diarrhea, constipation, melena, hematochezia, incontinence, nausea, vomiting

Genitourinary: No incontinence, dysuria, frequency, hesitancy, discharge, 

Muskuloskeletal: No muscle aches, tremor, weakness, myalgia, joint pain or swelling

Skin/Breasts: no rashes, moles, itch,



Allergies

      Penicillins    - Rash, Itching



Problems

      elevated cholesterol

      degenerative joint disease

      gastroesophageal reflux disease

      Depression

      Diabetes mellitus

      hypertension

      Low back pain

      Seasonal allergies

      Adrenal insufficiency

      candidal esophagitis



Medications

      Amitriptyline Hcl   10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS  #60 Tablet(s)

      Asa (CHILDRENS) (ACETYLSALICYLIC Acid (CHILDRENS))   81 MG (81MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  #100 Tablet(s)

      ATENOLOL   50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  #30 Tablet(s)

      Betamethasone/clotrimazole 0.05%/1%   1 APPLICATION (CREAM(GM) ) TOP BID  #45 gram(s)

      CHOLECALCIFEROL   800 UNITS (400 UNIT TABLET take 2) PO Q24H  #180 Tablet(s)

      Diclofenac Sodium    50   PO BID  #60 Tablet(s)

      ERGOCALCIFEROL   50000 UNITS (50000 UNIT CAPSULE take 1) PO as directed , once per month  #1 Capsule(s)

      Fosamax (ALENDRONATE)   70 MG (70MG TABLET take 1) PO QWEEK  #4 Tablet(s)

      Lantus (INSULIN Glargine)   15 UNITS (100 U/ML VIAL  ML) SC QHS , dc previous insulin #10 ML(s)

      METFORMIN   1000 MG (1000MG TABLET take 1) PO BID x 30 days #60 Tablet(s)

      OMEPRAZOLE   40 MG (20MG CAPSULE DR take 2) PO QD  #60 Capsule(s)

      PREDNISONE   3 MG (1MG TABLET take 3) PO QD  #90 Tablet(s)

      SIMVASTATIN   40 MG (40MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS  #100 Tablet(s)

      TRAMADOL   50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO Q6H  #90 Tablet(s)

      Zeasorb (TALC Powder)   1 APPLICATION TOP TID , to affected area #70 gram(s)



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   154/71 

      PULSE   66 

      WEIGHT   175 lb



Physical Exam



Gen: Well appearing in NAD, WD, WN





Impression

DM- having problems with glucometer, but based on sisters measurements not too bad. ha1c has come down 0.7%.  Hopefully with better medical management will continue to drop.  Continues to have difficulty with medications. 

 

adrenal insufficiency- now off prednisone after gradual taper. 

 

lipids- back on statin, will check when due.

 

htn- high again today.  will plan to taper atenolol, as recent data show limits as treatment of hypertension, and add hctz/lisinopril, both are first line agents for htn. see back in two weeks.

 

back pain- pt appt next week



______________________________

Lonnie Leroy George Zuniga, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="not met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>