<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2069-10-07

                     ZOLLMAN EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
MASSEY,RAMONA   446-90-33-6                       VISIT DATE: 10/07/69
TIME OF DICTATION:  1 p.m. 
PRESENTING COMPLAINT and HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This 
patient is a 63-year-old female who presents to the Zollman Community Clinic Emergency Department from home after the patient 
was found down by her daughter inside her home for an unspecified 
amount of time.  The paramedics and police were called the scene. 
The police were able to force open the door of the home.  The 
patient was found unconscious on the floor, having a generalized 
tonic clonic seizure.  The patient was intubated and given 4 mg of 
Ativan prior to arrival in the Emergency Department with the 
paramedics.  On arrival in the Emergency Department, the patient 
was noted to be comatose, intubated, and clearly in acute distress. 
The patient has a history of diabetes mellitus.  She has had a 
seizure in the past, apparently secondary to hypoglycemia.  She 
also has a history of high blood pressure.  She is on diltiazem, 
lisinopril, and medications for hypercholesterolemia. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her temperature is 100.6 degrees F., her 
pulse 150, her respiratory rate 12, her blood pressure on arrival 
205/90, and her O2 saturation is 98%.  On physical examination, the 
HEENT examination reveals a normocephalic head with no evidence of 
trauma on examination.  The pupils are equal and round, weakly 
reactive to light.  The pupils are 2 mm.  The fundi cannot be 
visualized.  The neck is supple.  There are no step-offs noted. 
The chest is clear to auscultation bilaterally.  The heart has 
normal S1 and S2, no S3 or S4, and no murmur.  The abdomen is 
protuberant, but soft and non-tender, without guarding, rebound, 
masses, or organomegaly.  The extremities are grossly within normal 
limits.  Grossly, there is no posturing; there are no Babinskis; 
the reflexes are about 1+ bilaterally. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  The head CT is noted to be negative.  The 
EKG reveals ST elevations in III and possibly aVF.  The heart rate 
is approximately 130.  The chest x-ray shows proper tube placement. 
The troponin I is 2.2, and is in the process of being repeated. 
The glucose is 174, the BUN 57, the creatinine 5.8, the sodium 137, 
the potassium 5.3, the chloride 101, the CO2 18.  The CK is noted 
to be 920, and the CK-MB is 2.6%.  The toxicology screen is 
negative.  The troponin I again is 2.2.  The urine toxicology is 
also noted to be negative.  The white count is 14, the hemoglobin 
11, the hematocrit 36, and the platelet count 350.  The urinalysis 
shows 3+ blood.  There are only 1-3 WBCs in the urine. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:   The plan is to admit the patient 
to the Intensive Care Unit for further work-up and evaluation.  An 
LP will be done in the Emergency Department, and following the LP, 
the patient will be sent to the Medical Intensive Care Unit. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  The diagnostic impression in the Emergency 
Department is seizure and coma of undetermined etiology. 
DISPOSITION (including condition on discharge):  The patient will 
be admitted to the Medical Intensive Care Unit following her lumbar 
puncture. 
___________________________________                    HB768/1408 
H. SHAWN HOWELL, M.D.  SH37                            D:10/07/69 
                                                       T:10/07/69 
Dictated by:  H. SHAWN HOWELL, M.D.  SH37 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2075-07-03

EDVISIT^44690336^Massey, Ramona^07/03/75^KEELER, ELIOT

The patient was seen on 07/03/2075 with Dr. Ellington.  The patient

was interviewed and examined by me.  Resident's note was reviewed

and confirmed.  Plan of care was discussed.  Please see

resident's note for details.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Briefly, this is a 74-year-old woman

with history of insulin-dependent diabetes and end-stage renal

disease who presented to Emergency Department after an episode of

confusion associated with a blood sugar in the field to 67 (per

EMS) and responsive to orange juice with normal mental status

upon arrival in the ED.  On further history, it seems that the

patient took her usual dose of insulin this morning and ate

breakfast but missed lunch and dinner because of a flood in the

basement that had preoccupied her.  She has had prior episodes of

hypoglycemia associated with skipping meals.  Otherwise, she has

been feeling well.  No recent change in medications.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes, hypertension, asthma, CVA/TIA,

and end-stage renal disease (predialysis).

MEDICATIONS:  Insulin, diltiazem, Nephrocaps, methyldopa,

Flovent, and Pravachol.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Awake, alert, sitting up in bed, and

eating supper.  No acute distress.  Temperature 97.2, pulse is

81, respirations 16, blood pressure 170/82, and pulse oximetry

100% on room air.  Cardiovascular exam:  Regular rate and rhythm.

 Lungs are clear.  Abdomen is soft and nontender.  Skin is warm

and well perfused.  Neurologic:  Alert and oriented x3 and

nonfocal.

LABORATORY DATA:  EKG:  Without ischemia.  White count 9.4, blood

glucose 93, creatinine 8.5, sodium 140, and potassium 4.9.

CLINICAL IMPRESSION:  Hypoglycemia in setting of renal failure

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********

PLAN:  To lower NPH dose from 30 to 25 units.  PCP, Dr. Mcgee

was e-mailed.  The patient will follow up with him on Monday.

______________________________

KEELER, ELIOT M.D.

D: 07/04/75

T: 07/04/75

Dictated By: KEELER, ELIOT

eScription document:4-4697792 BFFocus





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2077-01-31



LEPROSARIUM INPATIENT DIALYSIS ADMIT NOTE



Outpatient Nephrologist:   Dr. Mcgee

Outpatient Dialysis Unit:   BH

Estimated dry weight:  68.5 kg

Dialysis access:  RUE AVF



Reason for admission: hypoglycemia



HPI: 

76F ESRD on HD.  Felt "woozy" last night and found by daughter to be confused.  Daughter called 911 and FS glucose 30.  Pt has had recurrent episodes of hypoglycemia - says b/c she "doesn't want to eat".  She says she has an endocrinologist, Dr. Hayes, but does not remember where the office is located.  She takes insulin once a day (30u NPH and 10u R).  ROS otherwise negative in detail.



Past Medical History: 

ESRD presumed 2/2 type 2 DM

 - on HD since 2075, TTS

Type 2 DM (Insulin-dependent) 

 - multiple episodes of hypoglycemia in the past

asthma - no intubations d/t asthma exacerbation, has previously been on steroids

stroke/TIA in past

seizure 2069, unclear etiology

multinodular goiter

HTN

hyperlipidemia



Past Surgical History: 

s/p TAH-BSO



Vascular access history:  

R brachiocephalic fistula 11/75 after 3 prior failed attempts at access

   - given high risk of further thrombosis, started on coumadin 11/75

   - negative hypercoaguable w/u as per LMR notes



Allergies: NKDA



Medications: 

insulin

methyldopa 250mg qd

lisinopril 10mg qd

diltiazem 300mg qd

pravastatin 10mg qhs

Nephrocaps

heparin 5000u bid

colace 100mg bid



Social History:   40 pack-years, 2-3 EtOH drink/week, lives alone.  



Family History: 



PHYSICAL EXAM

Weight: 72.8kg

Temp: 98.4

BP: 150/82

HR: 91

RR: 22

O2 sat 100%



Gen: Obese AA woman in NAD.

HEENT: sclerae non-icteric, O&P clear and moist

Neck: supple, no LAD, JVP elevated

Lungs: CTA b/l

Cor: regular, s1s2, no m/c/r/g

Abd: soft, NTND, no HSM, no abdominal bruits

Ext: no edema in LE b/l, 2+ pulses distally

Skin: warm, smooth, no rashes

Back: no CVAT

Vascular access: site clean and without inflammation, systolic and diastolic bruit present



LABS:

Date/Time         WBC            HGB            HCT            MCV            

01/31/2077       8.15           11.5 (#)       34.7 (*)       87.3           



Date/Time         PLT            

01/31/2077       231            



Date/Time         UA-GLUC        UA-KET         UA-SPGR        UA-BLD         

01/31/2077       TR             NEG            1.009          1+             



Date/Time         UA-PH          UA-PROT        UA-NIT         UA-WBC         

01/31/2077       8.0            2+             NEG            NEG            



Date/Time         UAS-BACT       

01/31/2077       TR             



Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            

01/31/2077       137            5.1 (*)        95 (*)         27             

01/31/2077       134 (*)        6.2 (*)        94 (*)         25             

01/31/2077       136            5.8 (*)        97 (*)         20 (*)         



Date/Time         BUN            CRE            EGFR           GLU            

01/31/2077       49 (*)         8.0 (*)        5              68             

01/31/2077       43 (*)         8.0 (*)        5              83             



Date/Time         ANION          

01/31/2077       15                  



Date/Time         CA             PHOS           MG             

01/31/2077       10.2                          1.9            

01/31/2077       10.6 (*)       5.8 (*)        2.0            



Date/Time         CK             CK-MB          TROP-I         

01/31/2077      insufficient blood



Date/Time         PT             PT-INR         PTT            

01/31/2077       15.8 (*)       1.3 (*)        28.6 (#)       



Blood cultures negative to date (01/31/77)



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:



76F ESRD presumed from Type 2 DM, now admitted for hypoglycemia.



1.  DM: Check HbA1c.  Endocrine to see, given recurrent hypoglycemia.  Nutrition to see.

2.  HD today, as per usual schedule.  Will check iron studies, PTH, 25OH Vit D, URR.

3.  Hyperkalemia: Recirculation studies with HD today.

4.  CAD risk: Check fasting lipids, start ECASA 81mg qd, wean diltiazem and methyldopa and increase lisinopril as tolerated by BP.  Would not start beta-blocker at present until hypoglycemic episodes resolved.

5.  INR: Aiming for INR 1.5-2 - adjust coumadin accordingly.

6.  PO4: Start Phoslo 667mg po tid with meals.

6.  Dispo: Needs social work, PT, OT to see, as does not appear to be safe at home.



Lois Ochs

Renal Fellow

48324



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-01-18


Date 01/18/2080 TIPTREE VASCULAR SURGERY CONSULT NOTE 
PATIENT: Massey, Ramona
MRN: 44690336
Attending: Andersen
HPI: 


The patient is a 79yF with ESRD on HD. She is being dialyzed via a right brachiocephalic fistula that was created in Nov 2075. The patient is a very poor historian and the subsequent information has been collected from the medical record. While the fistula is beng used successfully for dialysis, it has undergone aneurysmal dilatation and the patient has also developed non-healing areas over the fistula at points of access. There is note made in the chart that the patient has had difficulty with recurrent outflow stenosis and for this she seems to have undergone angioplasty at Brooks Hospital (no record in LMR) recently. The patient does not have any complaints. 
PMH: 
ESRD on HD; CKD; DM; HTN; HL
PSH: 
Right brachiocephalic AV fistula creation 11/75; right forearm loop AV graft creation 02/75; right antecubital AV fistula creation 03/74; right snuff box AV fistula creation 10/70
MEDS (In house): 
ASA 81mg po qday; Calcium acetate 667mg po qac; Captopril 62.5mg po tid; Colace 100mg po qday; Heparin 5000U sc tid; Metoprolol 50mg pot id; Pravastatin 40mg po qhs; amlodipine 5mg po qday; Donepezil 5mg po qday; Nephrocaps 1tab po qday; RISS
ALL: 
NKDA
FH: 
NC
SH: 
Lives with her daughter in Brewton, VA; goes to dialysis TThSa
PE: 98.7 65 120/62 18 95% RA
Elderly woman sitting up in chair with Posey jacket on; appears comfortable; focused physical exam reveals right upper arm with well-healed incisions over forearm, graft in forearm without thrill, brachiocephalic fistula with aneurysmal changes, more prominently toward antecubital fossa, skin with small non-healing ulcers, strongly palpable thrill; radial pulse 1+, hand warm
--


Labs 
Chem: 136/ 4.4/ 93/ 29/ 72/ 9.6/ 170
CBC: 7.3/ 35.3/ 208
Coags: 14.4/ 1.1/ 27.5
--


ASSESSMENT / PLAN:
79yF with ESRD on HD being dialysed via right brachiocephalic fistula that is aneurysmal. Per the record she may also have outflow stenosis.
- Will discuss further management (fistulogram vs intervention vs follow up in clinic) with Dr. Andersen
- We will follow with you
--
Discussed with Dr. Sean Ferreira, Vascular Surgery fellow, who agrees with assessment and plan. Will discuss with Dr. Andersen. 


________________
Gabrielle Valdez
PGY-2
77183



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-02-03

Brooks HospitalStaff Admission Note
Intern: Putnam
Att: Volpe



CC: 

question of unresponsive


HPI:80 yoF with ESRD on HD (T/R/Sa), severe dementia, and h/o falls, discharged 12 days ago from ZCC s/p fall and femur fracture. Patient was evauated by Ortho who wanted to pursue a trial of non-operative management with bracing

 as patient was a poor surgical candidate.  


The patient was seen one day PTA in the ED for hypotension at HD. Appearantly on the trasfer to BH the patient fainted in the ambulance. The patient denied all complaints and had a normal head CT and EKG and was discharged home.  


Patient was at YGH today and per nursing notes, the patient was not responsive verbally, wuith BP 136/58, BS 105, O2 100% on RA during this period.  However,  nursing reports some epidoses of apnea, clinically resolving after 15 minutes, during this episode, afterwhich the patient perked up on her own. Per LMR patient is only intermittenly verbal and severely demented at baseline.  Incontinent at baseline, no acute incontinence, no jerking or shaking.


Of note, patient is cared for by daughter and numerous ancillary serivces. The patient's family has refused SNF placement in the past. Patient makes only occasional urine at baseline.


Daughter reports patient has been eating fine at home, but is worried about these two episodes of "unresponsiveness". Patient is scheduled for fistulogram tomorrow and patient is supposed to be NPO after midnight for this procedure.


ED Course: Patient is being admitted for observation. Patient has baseline normal VS, follows commands, patient has not passed out or become apneic in ED. CT Head not repeated as done yesterday. ED physician states EKG shows no acute infarct.



ROS: Good appetite, no fevers, patient has been compliant with all medications per daughter. No coughs or colds, NO prlonged diarrhea.


PMH:

CRI -on HD (T,Th,Sa)LGIB 12/80 - at ZCC, no cause identified, Hct 27 on d/cfrequent fallsHTNDM2CVA (2068)dementiaR knee OA, chronic contracturelegal blindnessuncertain h/o seizures

MEDS:

1.  ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID   81 MG PO  DAILY  2.  AMLODIPINE   10 MG PO  DAILY  3.  CINACALCET   30 MG PO  DAILY  4.  DONEPEZIL HCL   5 MG PO  DAILY  5.  LABETALOL HCL   100 MG PO  BID  6.  LISINOPRIL   40 MG PO  DAILY  7.  NEPHRO-VIT RX   1 TAB PO  DAILY  8.  PRAVASTATIN   40 MG PO  BEDTIME  9.  SEVELAMER   800 MG PO  AC  


ALL:NKDA

SH:lives with daughter (Grace) who provides FT care; unable to perform ADL/IADLs.



FH:No family hx of dementia or seizures


PE: VS: T 98 P 82 139/56 100% RA
General: well appearing, NAD
HEENT: Eyes: PERRLA, EOMI
Nose: mucosa pink, no erythema or discharge
Neck: 6 cm JVD
Lungs: CTA b/l, no rales/rhonchi/wheezes
Heart: RRR, S1+S2, no m/r/g
Abdomen: soft, ND/NT, +BS, no hepatosplenomegaly
Extremities: 2+ radial/DP pulses, no clubbing/cyanosis/edema, right leg in brace


LABS:
Results02/03/2081 NA 138,  K 3.7,  CL 97 (L),  CO2 30 (H),  BUN 16,  CRE 3.68 (H),  EGFR 13 (L),  GLU 156 (H)01/28/2081 NA 129 (*),  K 5.0,  CL 92 (*),  CO2 26,  BUN 34 (*),  CRE 4.41 (*),  EGFR 10,  GLU 268 (*)01/28/2081 NA 132 (*),  K 5.6 (*#),  CL 94 (*),  CO2 26,  BUN 34 (*),  CRE 4.30 (*#),  EGFR 10,  GLU 200 (*)01/27/2081 NA 136,  K 4.2,  CL 98,  CO2 29,  BUN 21,  CRE 3.29 (*#),  EGFR 13,  GLU 231 (*)01/27/2081 K 4.102/03/2081 ANION 1001/28/2081 ANION 1101/28/2081 ANION 1201/27/2081 ANION 901/28/2081 GLU-POC 209 (*)01/28/2081 GLU-POC 235 (*)01/27/2081 GLU-POC 202 (*)01/27/2081 GLU-POC 309 (*)01/27/2081 GLU-POC 269 (*)02/03/2081 CA 7.0 (L),  TBILI 0.2,  TP 6.2,  ALB 2.6 (L)01/28/2081 CA 9.0,  PHOS 3.9,  ALB 2.6 (*)01/28/2081 CA 9.7,  MG 2.201/27/2081 25 OH-VITD 6.7 (*)01/27/2081 CA 10.102/03/2081 ALT/SGPT 9,  AST/SGOT 12,  ALKP 162 (H),  TBILI 0.202/03/2081 CK 21 (L),  CK-MB Test Not Performed,  TROP-T 0.232 (HH)02/03/2081 WBC 10.4,  RBC 3.36 (L),  HGB 8.6 (#L),  HCT 27.8 (#L),  MCV 83,  MCH 25.5 (L),  MCHC 30.9 (L),  PLT 265 (#)01/28/2081 WBC 9.63,  RBC 3.46 (*),  HGB 9.0 (*),  HCT 27.8 (*),  MCV 80.6,  MCH 26.1 (*),  MCHC 32.4,  PLT 17701/28/2081 WBC 10.91 (*),  RBC 3.71 (*),  HGB 9.6 (*),  HCT 30.5 (*),  MCV 82.2,  MCH 25.9 (*),  MCHC 31.5 (*),  PLT 174 (#)01/27/2081 WBC 10.39 (*),  RBC 3.60 (*),  HGB 9.4 (*),  HCT 29.1 (*),  MCV 81.1,  MCH 26.2 (*),  MCHC 32.3,  PLT 142 (*)02/03/2081 RDW 18.5 (H)01/28/2081 RDW 18.4 (*)01/28/2081 RDW 19.4 (*)01/27/2081 RDW 19.4 (*)02/03/2081 %NEUT 75.4 (H),  %MONO 8.6 (H),  %EOS 0.5,  %BASO 0.2,  %LYMPH-M 15.3 (L)01/28/2081 %BAND-M 0,  %POLY-M 68 (#),  %LYMPH-M 21,  %ATYPS 002/03/2081 %DIFCOM SMEAR REVIEWED01/28/2081 %MONO-M 10 (*#),  %EOS-M 1,  %BASO-M 002/03/2081 ANISO ++,  HYPO +++,  MICRO ++01/28/2081 ANISO 1+,  POIK 2+,  HYPO 1+,  MICRO 1+,  SPHERO 2+,  PLT-EST NL01/28/2081 PT 15.5 (*),  PT-INR 1.2 (*),  PTT 44.0 (*)01/28/2081 PT 15.3 (*),  PT-INR 1.2 (*),  PTT 44.8 (*)01/27/2081 PT 15.7 (*),  PT-INR 1.2 (*),  PTT 43.3 (*)


STUDIES:
EKG: NSR, 81 bpm, no acute injury pattern



2/02 CT Head: IMPRESSION:     1.  No acute intracranial abnormality.     2.  Moderate periventricular white matter changes     3.  Bilateral basal ganglia lacunes.


A/P: 80 year old female with severe dementia and ESRD presenting with two poorly characterized episodes of non-responsiveness, normal in between episodes, and with a new troponin elevation, about twice of baseline, with a reassuring EKG and CK.



#) AMS - Unclear etiology? Head CT neg. Ddx dehydration vs. infection vs. recurrent CVA/seizure/syncope vs ischemia vs. progression of dementia.-will check UA, CXR. CIS-will check orthostatics-cycle cardiac BM x 2 sets w/ EKG's-TTE, carotid u/s in am to w/u ?syncope. Cont home Asa/statin-telemetry -IVF as needed-consider EEG#) ESRD on HD - Will notify renal of admission-consider fistulogram order as inpatient-continue renal meds#) HTN - Cont AceI, CCB, BB#) DM - Diet-controlled. Will write for Humalog SS#) Dementia - Cont Alzheimers meds#) FEN - renal diet (NPO after MN), pureed diet with thin liquids, IVF, daily labs#) PPX - heparin sc

Code: DNR/DNI confirmed with family
HCP: Grace Qiu, child, 842-696-1812



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>