<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2070-08-18

                     KEKELA EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT
 
DIETZ,SUSIE   538-41-21-0                    VISIT DATE: 08/18/70
PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Palpitations, mouth full of blood. 
HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  A 52 year old female who 
presented complaining of palpitations and her mouth full of blood. 
The patient states that she was awakened this morning from her 
sleep with her mouth full of blood and what she thought was coffee 
grounds and stated that she had some palpitations and nausea, and 
came to the hospital to be seen.  She gives no history of ulcers. 
She states that she had some light pressure in her chest and some 
palpitations. 
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Upon presentation here, she has no complaints. 
No complaint of light-headedness or dizziness, no complaint of 
chest pain or shortness of breath here. 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  She has history of hypertension and 
diabetes, anxiety and panic attacks, hepatitis B as well. 
MEDICATIONS:  Alprazolam and Tolinase 
ALLERGIES:  She has no allergies. 
SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Unremarkable.  Has a drink 
every now and again. 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is afebrile with stable vital signs. 
Pulse 98, respirations 16, blood pressure 163/112 initially.  She 
is asymptomatic in the Emergency Department at this time.  On exam, 
her HEENT exam is normal.  No blood in her oropharynx.  No evidence 
of any oral trauma.  No evidence of head trauma.  Neck is supple, 
flexion and extension normal.  Pulmonary exam - clear breath sounds 
bilaterally.  Cardiac exam - regular rate and rhythm, a 2/6 murmur 
heard.  Abdomen is soft, non-tender with normal bowel sounds, no 
epigastric pain or tenderness, no hepatosplenomegaly, no masses, no 
rebound or guarding.  Guaiac negative with normal rectal tone. 
Pulses normal throughout.  Good full range of motion.  Neuro exam 
normal.  Has no palpitations, chest pain or hematemesis at this 
point. 
LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Initial EKG shows normal sinus tach at 108, 
but repeat was normal EKG with rate of 88.  No evidence of any 
acute changes on EKG.  PT/PTT normal.  Troponin and CK normal. 
Electrolytes, BUN, creatinine and blood sugar normal.  Hematocrit 
of 42 with normal white count.  Urinalysis - 1+ blood, 1+ glucose, 
no white cells, no red cells.  Urine pregnancy test negative and 
chest x-ray negative. 
THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  NG tube was placed with lavage, no 
evidence of blood. 
CLINICAL IMPRESSION:  A 52 year old female who complained of 
palpitations and a mouth full of blood with a negative workup, no 
evidence of a GI bleed, no evidence of any cardiac disease or acute 
cardiac problems, normal laboratory studies. 
FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Palpitations. 
DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Being discharged 
to home.  Condition on discharge is stable. 
___________________________________                    ZT090/110 
URIEL XING, M.D.       UX93                           D:08/18/70 
                                                       T:08/18/70 
Dictated by:  URIEL XING, M.D.       UX93 
 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-04-08

                     KEKELA EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

DIETZ,SUSIE   538-41-21-0                    VISIT DATE: 04/08/72

This patient was seen in conjunction with resident physician, 

Echols.  Please see resident's note for explicit details of the 

visit.  

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Chest pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This patient is a 47-year-old 

female who presents to the emergency department complaining of 

chest pain.  The patient has had multiple emergency department 

visits for nonspecific symptoms.  She has a diagnosis of panic 

attacks.  The patient states that over the last day or two, she has 

been having symptoms of left neck pain and arm pain, with exertion. 

The patient presents for evaluation. 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Negative for shortness of breath, weakness, 

numbness, headache, blurred vision, fevers, chills.  Other review 

of systems are negative.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes and hypertension.

MEDICATIONS:  Glucophage, Klonopin, diltiazem.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies. 

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory. 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  This is a well-appearing female in no 

distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 98.6, pulse 86, respiratory 

rate 18, blood pressure 140/60.  Oxygen saturation is 100% on room 

air.  HEENT:  Scalp is intact, with no evidence of trauma, 

lacerations, or abrasions.  Pupils are round, reactive to light and 

accommodation.  Tympanic membranes are clear bilaterally.  Pharynx 

is non-erythematous with a midline uvula.  NECK:  Trachea is 

midline without stridor.  Carotids are 2+ without bruits.  CHEST:  

Clear to auscultation and percussion.  CARDIOVASCULAR:  S1, S2, no 

murmurs, gallops, or rubs.  ABDOMEN:  Soft, non-tender, 

non-distended.  No organomegaly.  Positive bowel sounds.  No 

peritoneal signs.  EXTREMITIES:  Negative for clubbing, cyanosis, 

or edema.  SKIN:  Negative for rash, petechiae, or urticaria.  

NEUROLOGICAL:  Awake, alert and oriented x 3.  Cranial nerves 

II-XII are intact.  Symmetric strength, reflexes, and sensation.  

Normal gait.   

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  Initial cardiogram was unremarkable and no 

change from previous.  The patient had an exercise treadmill test 

in 2069 which was consistent with, but diagnostic of, ischemia. 

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient was given aspirin by 

mouth, O2 via nasal cannula.  Given the patient's previous exercise 

treadmill test, her history of hypertension and diabetes, and 

nonspecific symptoms, the patient will be admitted to the hospital 

for a rule out myocardial infarction and stress MIBI testing.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Chest pain, unclear etiology.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient was 

admitted in stable condition.

___________________________________                    CG993/95284 

RICHARD ZAHN, M.D.       RZ5                           D:04/08/72 

                                                       T:04/08/72 

Dictated by:  RICHARD ZAHN, M.D.       RZ5 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-10-17

CARDIOLOGY ADMISSION NOTE



Susie DIETZ									96O-776

KCH 538-41-21-0

Date of admission 10/17/74

Ref:  Scott Fink, MD, 1480 Campanello Street, DARTMOUTH 76846



This 57-yr-old female w/CP syndrome, CRFs of DM, HTN, no documented vascular disease, w/several prior evals for CP syndrome.  ETT 11/11/73:  7'8    on SBP, typical CP, nondiagnostic ECG changes interpreted as c/w but not diagnostic of ischemia.  In USH, able to walk 1 flight w/o symptoms until this AM when she had L neck pain radiating to head and down L arm lasting 2 min; also intermittent palpitations, diaphoresis, symptom complex present for some time.  On arrival in ER w/o chest symptoms, BP 174/110, P 100, no ST abnormalities.  Admitted for eval.



ROS:  Denies fevers, chills, N/V, diarrhea, presyncope, claudication.  All other pertinent systems neg.



PMH:  DM, HTN, panic attacks, hx of hep B, fatty liver disease, pos PPD.



Meds:  aspirin 81mg qd, metformin 850mg bid, nifedipine.  Contrast allergy in record (details unknown), intolerant of lisinopril.  



No family hx of premature CAD.  Does not smoke, rare alcohol.



PE:  BP 113/75, P 90, comfortable lying in bed, A&A.  No JVD, carotids normal upstrokes w/o bruits, chest CTA.  ND PMI, RRR, normal intensity S1, phys split S2, no M/R/G.  Abdomen soft NT.  Extremities no C/C/E, warm to touch.  Femorals, DPs and PTs 2+, no bruit.  Power normal in all 4.  



Labs:  crea 0.8, TPNI < assay, crit 40.

ECG:  SR, normal axis/intervals, no diagnostic Qs, no ST or T-wave abnormalities.



I&P:  Pt w/CP syndrome, CRFs including DM.  Low clinical probability of acute coronary syndrome.  Low risk status other than DM.  Plan serial cardiac TPNs and ECGs overnight.  If she remains w/o objective evidence of ischemia or high-risk features will proceed w/ETT MIBI tomorrow or as outpt.  Continue aspirin, start low-dose beta blockade, continue DM mgmt.  Fasting lipid profile.  Pt should be on an ARB if BP will tolerate.





________________

Paul B. Stokes, MD





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-10-07







Hospital De Doctor Pila

0744 Roseann Circle              DIETZ, SUSIE

San Manuel, WY  76846                    53841210

(082) 471-7456                     10/07/2076





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Dietz is a 59-year-old woman who comes for follow up of diabetes and other medical problems.



PROBLEMS:

1.  Diabetes mellitus.  Last A1c six months ago was 6.6.  Last eye exam also was six months ago.

2.  Hypertension.  No chest pain, shortness of breath, or pedal edema.

3.  Hypercholesterolemia.  A fasting lipid analysis done five months ago showed total cholesterol of 158, triglycerides of 55, HDL of 52, and an LDL of 95.



MEDICATIONS:  Aspirin 81 mg p.o. daily, calcium carbonate 600 mg b.i.d., Diovan 80 mg daily, Glucophage 850 mg b.i.d., lorazepam 1 mg q.i.d. p.r.n., Paxil 10 mg daily, and fluvastatin 20 mg daily, but she ran out some time ago.



REVIEW OF SYMPTOMS:  She has noted some pruritus between several toes on both feet. No significant weight change, febrile signs or symptoms, headache, blurred vision, tinnitus, chest pain, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, abdominal pain, nightsweats, diarrhea, dysuria, polyuria, skin rash, bruising, joint pain, or focal weakness.  





PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient is in no acute distress.  Blood pressure 124/80, weight 154 pounds, and temperature 98.6.  Skin exam: Notable for slight erythema and breakdown between several toes on the right and left feet.  No scaling elsewhere.  Pedal pulses 1+ bilaterally.  Sensation is intact on plantar aspect of both feet.  Chest: Clear to percussion and auscultation.  Extremities: No edema.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:

1.  Diabetes mellitus.  Good control.  Will recheck values today.

2.  Hypertension.  Good control.  Diovan renewed.

3.  Hypercholesterolemia.  I reviewed with the patient the need to take medication essentially for lifelong.  Better control of LDL than previous value also indicated.  I gave her a prescription for Crestor 10 mg p.o. daily.

4.  Tinea pedis.  I explained disorder to the patient and preventive care.  Also, gave prescription for clotrimazole cream.

5.  Adult health maintenance.  Mammogram requested.  Influenza vaccine given.





______________________________

Roger S Conrad, M.D.











eScription document:2-8665601 EMSSten Tel







DD: 10/07/76

DT: 10/08/76

DV: 10/07/76



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>