<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2066-02-07

                     KCM EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

RIVERS,KARSTEN   957-18-08-4                    VISIT DATE: 02/07/66

The patient was seen and examined by me.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 39-year-old man with a 

history of hypertension and diabetes, whose social history is 

unremarkable, who has a negative review of systems, and who has no 

history of any surgical procedures.  He presents with a burn on the 

right side of the neck.  He presents to the emergency department 

with a minor amount of redness on the right side of the neck and 

minor soft tissue swelling.  The trachea is midline.  The uvula is 

midline.  There is no airway compromise.  There are no airway 

complaints.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  No voice change.  The airway is patent and 

intact.  The lungs are clear, with no wheezes.  The examination 

shows a first-degree burn of the right side of the neck, with no 

blistering and no breakage of the skin.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The patient received a tetanus shot 

and was seen by the Burn Service.  He was dressed with Bacitracin 

and discharged home.  He was to follow up in 48 hours just for a 

recheck.  The Burn Service essentially signed off on him, with no 

need for follow-up, but given this was his neck and only 

first-degree, I asked him to return here for follow-up.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  First-degree burn of the right side of the neck.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  He is discharged 

with Bacitracin ointment and analgesics, and is to follow up in 48 

hours.  The patient's condition on discharge is stable.  

___________________________________                    RO904/06747 

XAVIER ODONNELL, M.D.       XO71                           D:02/07/66 

                                                       T:02/07/66 

Dictated by:  XAVIER ODONNELL, M.D.       XO71 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2071-04-11

            Burn Surgery Admission H&P 		Date/Time: 4/11/71, 9am
****************************************************
Name: Rivers, Karsten   
MRN# 95718084 
Resident: Gillis
Attending: Michael 
****************************************************
CC: burn to R foot
HPI: 
44yo diabetic M with peripheral neuropathy, fell asleep in front of space heater approximately 3 weeks ago and noted swelling/blisters at tips of R 1st-3rd toes upon waking.  His wounds have been managed until this time by his podiatrist and his mother (a former doctor) has been doing dressing changes at home- initially with silvadene but over the past several days with ?betadine as directed by his podiatrist.  The pt is a floor covering installer, and has been bearing weight on the R foot since his injury and admits that he has not been compliant wearing a heel boot.  He has not had fever/chills, nausea/emesis and in general feels well.  He has not had pain in the foot, but does have a significant neuropathy.  His podiatrist recommended that he be evaluated by plastic/burn surgery and he presents to burn clinic for further evaluation.
-- 
PMHx: 
NIDDM
HTN
dyslipidemia
PSHx: 
R shoulder
L hip
umbilical hernia
Meds: 
toprol xl 100 qd
glucophage 1000 bid
neurontin 400 bid
minoxidil 10 qd
lipitor 20 qd
lasix 20 qd
avalide 300/12.5 qd
ASA 81 qd
cipro 500 bid
All: Augmentin- rash
SHx: 
smoker
-- 
PE: 
General: AOx3, NAD 
Chest: CTA B 
Heart: RRR 
Abdomen: obese, NT/ND  
Extremities: wwp, +3rd degree burns with areas of grey eschar at tips of 1st-3rd toes on R extending to plantar surfaces; some areas of pink granulating tissue.  + surrounding erythema- does not extend beyond toes onto foot, most significant on 3rd toe.  +wound on lat surface of 4th toe (site of recent corn removal per pt)- clean with no erythema/drainage    
Pulses: dp/pt 2+ bilaterally
-- 
Labs: 
	pending
	EKG: pending 
-- 
Imaging: 
CXR: pending
-- 
Assessment: 
44yo M with 3rd degree burn to R 1st/2nd/3rd toes and superimposed cellulitis.  
--
Plan:
Admit to Michael/burn service
triple abx, leg elevation at all times, NWB RLE
dressing changes with silvadine/gauze bid
OR for debridement/possible grafting when celluliltis improves; f/u labs, UA, CXR, EKG
--
D/W Dr. Michael, who agrees with assessment and plan.
-- 
Julia Gillis MD
50741




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-10-26




RIVERS, KARSTEN
95718084
10/26/2073


To Whom It May Concern:

I had the pleasure of seeing Mr. Karsten Rivers in the Cardiovascular Clinic at the Kimball County Manor for initial evaluation and management.  As you may know, he is a 47-year-old gentleman with a history of poorly controlled hypertension, poorly controlled insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, former tobacco use, morbid obesity, no family history of early coronary disease and no known coronary disease.  He was presented to the Cardiovascular Clinic today for preoperative evaluation prior to an orthopedic surgery scheduled for later on this week by Dr. Phillip Isaac Crosby, at the Lamoni Nursing Rehabilitation Center.  This gentleman has a torn ligament in his right hip and is scheduled for laparoscopic repair at the Lamoni Nursing Rehabilitation.  Mr. Rivers, as mentioned, denies any history of known coronary artery disease.  He has had a prior stress test greater than 15 years ago, but none recently.  He denies any recent catheterization or echocardiogram.  He works currently as a floor coverer in Shelton and has done so for 20 years.  He is able to ambulate approximately two flights of steps, but at the top of the steps develops slight dyspnea on exertion, unclear whether or not this is related to a cardiac etiology or secondary to his morbid obesity with his weight over 400 pounds.  He denies any heart failure symptoms, orthopnea, PND, lower extremity edema or nocturia though he has been maintained on Lasix diuresis in the past though none currently.  Additionally, he has poorly controlled diabetes for which he is being followed in the Diabetes Clinic here at the KCM as well as poorly controlled hypertension for which he is on multiple agents.  He denies any history of exertional chest discomfort and as mentioned, he is still quite active despite his BLANK as an Interior Designs floor coverer.

Review of systems is otherwise unremarkable.

Past medical history is remarkable for hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, insulin dependent diabetes mellitus and morbid obesity.

Medications include Toprol-XL 125 mg p.o. daily, aspirin 81 mg p.o. daily, Lipitor 20 mg p.o. daily, Neurontin 400 mg p.o. daily, insulin, Aldactone 25 mg p.o. daily, Avapro 300 mg p.o. daily and minoxidil 10 mg p.o. daily.

He is allergic to penicillin for which he develops a rash.

His social history is remarkable for former tobacco use for many years, though he quit more than three years ago.  He has no extensive alcohol or illicit drug use history.  He lives locally with his wife and five children and as mentioned is a floor coverer in ID working at Provo.  He is followed by Dr. Gilmore at the Helena Hospital for primary care.

On examination, he is afebrile, heart rate is 98 and regular, blood pressure 148/78 and respiratory rate is 16 breaths per minute in no acute distress.  He is a well-appearing gentleman in stated age with morbid obesity.  His jugular venous pressure is difficult to estimate given his habitus.  He is clear to auscultation bilaterally.  He has a regular rate and rhythm with a normal S1, S2 and no murmur, rub or gallop.  His abdomen is obese, nontender with positive bowel sounds and no hepatomegalies appreciated.  His extremities are warm and well perfused with trace edema at the ankles.  He has good distal pulsations.  His carotids are 2+ bilaterally without bruit.

Laboratory values are not available today.

ECG reveals normal sinus rhythm with a heart rate of 99.  He has left anterior fascicular hemiblock with normal R wave progression through his precordium.  No evidence for LVH or prior infarction.  He does have low voltage in his limb leads, consistent with his morbid obesity.

Impression:  Mr. Rivers is a very pleasant 47-year-old gentleman with multiple cardiac risk factors, notably insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus as well as poorly controlled hypertension with no known coronary artery disease now presenting for cardiovascular clearance prior to elective hip repair scheduled for three days from now.  This gentleman has no known coronary disease and has a reasonable exercise capacity, which I estimate to be 3 to 5 METS.  Most recently, given his hip and orthopedic issues, he has been unable to ambulate even to three METS.  However, prior to his orthopedic injury several months ago, he was able to ambulate up two flights of steps with only minimal dyspnea upon reaching the top step and without any exertional chest discomfort.  However, given his multiple risk factors, notably his poorly controlled diabetes and poorly controlled hypertension as well as former tobacco use, he certainly is at very high risk for obstructive coronary disease.  As such, I recommended we obtain a Persantine PET stress test for tomorrow morning.  If this test is normal without any high risk features or without any evidence for obstructive coronary disease, it would be reasonable for him to proceed with surgery later on this week.  This test will also suffice for his upcoming gastric laparoscopic bypass surgery, which is scheduled for 01/2074.  With regards to his medication, his blood pressure still is not at goal below 130.  As such, I have increased his Toprol-XL from 125 mg to 200 mg p.o. daily.  This medication should be continued through all surgery.  Additionally, if this is not sufficient in bringing his blood pressure down below 130, I would recommend the addition of a diuretic to his regimen either Lasix 20 mg p.o. daily or hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg p.o. daily.  Additionally, it will be essential that his diabetes be taken better control of and he is now working closely with the diabetes center here at the KCM to do so.  His last A1c was approximately 13 and this is certainly way out of range for someone of his young age.  I am hopeful with continued medical therapy this gentleman can continue to improve his life and undergo orthopedic surgery as well as gastric bypass surgery with significant improvement to his quality of life and future cardiac risk.  With regards to his hypertension, he is on multiple agents including Toprol-XL, Aldactone, Avapro and minoxidil.  Given the multitude of agents, it would be reasonable to screen this gentleman for secondary causes of hypertension including hyperthyroidism as well as hyperaldosteronism, but notably he has currently started the Aldactone and this would be difficult to do while on the medication.  We could consider in the future, if his blood pressure is not well controlled either washing out the Aldactone and then followed by renin and aldosterone testing versus BLANK sampling in the future if deemed necessary.  Additionally, if he is found to have coronary artery disease, one other option despite his lack of claudication would be evaluation of renal artery stenosis.  As mentioned, I will obtain the stress imaging tomorrow morning and then we will be able to have a better assessment of whether or not it would be reasonable to proceed with surgery in the near future.  I will follow back with him in approximately several months' time for followup of his general cardiovascular care.

Please do not hesitate to contact me if there is anything I can do to contribute to his ongoing medical care in the interim.  He has been provided both my e-mail and pager number to contact me if there is anything I can do to assist in his care going forward.

Thank you.

Sincerely,


______________________________
Kenneth Sweet, MD





eScription document:9-9031123 IFFocus

CC: Gabriel Michael MD
67 COMANCHE STREET

SHELTON, NH, 23574
Fax: 
Email: gmichael@KCM.ORG


CC: Phillip Isaac Crosby M.D.
Lamoni Nursing Rehabilitation Center
725 Dan Chan
Shelton, NH, 64187
Fax: 
Email: 



DD: 10/26/73
DT: 10/27/73
DV: 10/26/73



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-06-09

Reason for Visit This is a  47 year old  male referred to the diabetes management service for uncontrolled diabetes by Dr. OldhamChief Complaint This patient is admitted to the hospital for gastric bypassHistory of Present Illness The patient has a  10  year history of Type 2 diabetes.  He was treated with  metformin and insulin. Unclear when metformin was discontinued. Currently the patient is treated with   detemir 60 bid and novolog 50 ac  as an outpatient . The control has been poor.  The patient tests his blood sugar  several  times a day with results ranging from 200-300.The current diet is not well controlled.  The patient has not been bothered by  hypoglycemia .  Diabetic complications include neuropathy with numbness in feet and nephropathy with macroalbuminuria.
He had gastric bypass last night. He received Lantus 30. He was on D5W over night with glucose values over 300.. He currently is on LR iv drip. He has abdominal pain and is not yet eating
 Allergies noPast Medical History Concurrent medical problems include:htn, osa, right hip replacement, renal cell caFamily History Family history is positive for diabetes       Social History The patient is employed as a floor covering installer      .Habits The patient is a smoker.The patient's alcohol intake may be excessive   .Review of Systems ROS: quite nauseated now and unable to give detailsMedications  lipitor 40
gabapentin 400 qd
toprol 200
lasix 120
metolazone 22.5 qod
insulin as above
 Laboratory Data Relevant lab data:HgA1c 13.7 ( 2/2074)K 3.4Creatinine 1.24Urine microalbumin screen positivePhysical Exam Vitals Bp 140/60 P  82 Wt.384Skin no acanthosis, Heent no asymmetry, no lid lagNeck no bruits heard no thyromegaly Chest clearCor S1, S2 normal, no murmursAbd obese,  post-opExtremities 1+ edema, no ulcers dorsalis pedis pulses intact , venous insufficiency changesNeuro  Vibratory sense decreased  Monofilament testing intactImpression My impression is that his diabetes is chronically poorly controlled. It is unclear if he is compliant with stated insulin doses. He is now post-op with hyperglycemia, having received 50% of his usual insulin dose last night.He clearly needs more insulinRecommendation My recommendations are:1.No need for D5W while glucose values remain over 2067.Increase glargine to 60  units q 12 hours(give tonight and in am)3.Give regular 30 units sc times one dose now4.Give new sliding scale:regular q 6 hours
   BG 150-200     5 units
   BG  201-250   10 units   BG  251-300   15 units   BG &gt; 301        20 units___________________Katie W Fitzgerald, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-02-17


Internal Medicine Admission Note


Patient Name: Rivers, Karsten
MRN (HH): 
32054233
Attending: Dr. Gilmore




CC    Ulcer on right outer foot x 2 days


HPI    
49 year old man with longstanding diabetes and neuropathy presented to HH ED for  right foot ulcer. Patient reports that 2 days ago, when he clean his feet, he noticed a piece of skin detached from his right outer foot. He removed the skin and cleaned the wound with alcohol swab and dressed with bind aid. He did not note any injury to his foot, did not find any foreign object in his shoes. He does recall that 5 days ago, his daughter broke a vase but he did not  step on it. The next day, he noticed right groin 
pain and felt a lump in the area. The right foot became warmer and more painful. He however denies any chills, fever, shaking or diaphoresis. He has been diagnosed with DM for more than 20 years, was on insulin and had constant high blood glucose (&gt;600) most of the time before the gastric bypass surgery. He has neuropathy for more than 10 years. He had laparoscopic Roux-en-Y on 06/08/2074. His weight lost from 435 lbs before the Sx to 275 lbs. He is no longer on insulin. Current hypoglycemic regimen includes metformin 850 mg daily. Last A1C was less than 7. He reports dry cough and he attributes to lisinopril. 


In ED, he was given morphine for pain and vancomycin iv for infection. Blood culture sent before given antibiotics.


PMH  

DM
Obesity s/p Roux-en-Y
Right renal cancer s/p partial nephrectomy
HTN
Diabetic neuropathy



Family History:    
Renal failure in father
      
Habits
Denies smoking, ex-smoker, quit 6 years ago
Social ETOH
Denies recreational drugs      
                  
Social History:  
Occupation    Floor Covering Installer  
Married, lives with spouse and children


 
Medications
Caltrate Plus D(600MG/400IU) (CALCIUM 600mg + Vitamin D(400IU)) 1 TAB PO BID
Labetalol Hcl 300 MG (300MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID x 90 days #180 Tablet(s)
Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 80 MG (80 MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #1 Month(s) Supply
Lisinopril 20 MG (20 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #Tablet(s)
Miconazole Nitrate 2% Powder 1 APPLICATION (2% POWDER ) TOP TID #1 month(s) SupplyOmeprazole 20 MG (20 MG CAPSULE DR Take 1) PO BID #60 Tablet(s) 
                        
Allergies                        

Penicillins - Rash


ROS
Negative except noted in HPI




Physical Examination

Vitals: BP 142/67, HR 87, R 18, T 99, O2 sat 99 rm air
Patient is in no apparent distress, good attention to hygiene and body habitus.  
Oriented to person, place and time. obese. Mood normal and appropriate to situation. 

Eyes: EOMI
HEENT:  NC/AT  
Neck:  Supple.No JVD. Thyroid is palpable with normal size and consistency. 
Respiratory:  Auscultation of lungs reveal clear lung fields. 
Cardiovascular:  Heart auscultation reveals normal S1 and S2 and no murmurs.
Abdomen: Abdomen soft, nontender, bowel sounds present, no palpable masses.  
Neurological Examination: No focal deficit.  DTR WNL
Extremity exam: +Right foot shallow ulcer with right foot erythema, warm and tender. Right groin enlarged and tender lymph node 



ResultsDate/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            02/17/2076        137            3.8            100            30 (H)         Date/Time         BUN            CRE            EGFR           GLU            02/17/2076        24 (H)         1.32 (H)       &gt; 60           177 (H)        Date/Time         ANION          02/17/2076        8              Date/Time         CA             TBILI          TP             ALB            02/17/2076        9.0            0.6            6.8            4.0            Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          02/17/2076        10             15             110            0.6            Date/Time         UACET          02/17/2076        NEGATIVE       Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            02/17/2076        13.6 (H)       4.30 (L)       11.9 (L)       35.2 (L)       Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            02/17/2076        82             27.7 (L)       33.9           237            Date/Time         RDW            02/17/2076        13.4           Date/Time         %NEUT          %MONO          %EOS           %BASO          02/17/2076        82.0 (H)       4.1            1.4            0.3            Date/Time         %LYMPH-M       02/17/2076        12.2 (L)       Date/Time         UA-COLOR       UA-APP         UA-GLUC        UA-BILI        02/17/2076        YELLOW         CLEAR          NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       Date/Time         UR-SPGR        UA-BLD         UA-PH          UA-PROT        02/17/2076        1.019          NEGATIVE       5.0            TRACE (H)      Date/Time         UA-UROBI       UA-NIT         UA-WBC         02/17/2076        1.0            NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       EKG: NSR at 77 BPM. No st elevation
CXR: No infiltrates
Right foot x-ray: No sigh suggest osteomyelitis
Assessment:  

49 year old male with longstanding DM and diabetic neuropathy presents with new onset right foot ulcer and right groin lymph node enlargement. WBC is elevated. He likely has diabetic foot ulcer and foot cellulitis. X-ray dose not suggest osteomyelitis.


Plan:   

#1) Diabetic foot ulcer and cellulitis: given his risk for polymicrobial infection, will cover with broad spectrum antibiotics  for aerobes and anaerobes plus MRSA.
-Vancomycin 1 gm iv daily
-Zosyn 4.5 gm iv q6H
-F/U blood culture
-Pain management
-IV NS 75 ml/hr


#2) DM, well controlled with metformin after gastric bypass. 
-Hold metformin
-NPH 5 u SC BID
-Low scale SS
-FS qAC


3#) HTN, on lisinopril and developed dry cough 
-d/c lisinopril, start Cozaar 50 mg daily
-Continue labetalol 300mg bid
-hold lasix


DVT prophylaxis


Code Full




Ollie Kern, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>