<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2059-08-07

                     PCC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

FERRARA,LAUREN   481-85-43-7                       VISIT DATE: 08/07/59

I have examined and treated the patient myself as well as reviewed 

and confirmed the resident's detailed documentation.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Briefly, this 68-year-old woman 

with a history of diabetes and a past history of ulcers on the 

right foot complains of increased pain on the right leg over the 

past three days.  It was worse yesterday.  It was slightly better 

today.  She has not really been able to get out of bed secondary to 

the pain, whereas she is usually very active.  She denies fever, 

chills, palpitations, and diarrhea.  She has not recently checked 

her blood sugar.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes mellitus, hypothyroidism, dementia, 

chronic ulcer of left great toe.  Past surgical history:  

Hysterectomy in the distant past.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 97.2, pulse 70, 

respirations 18.  Blood pressure was initially 241/90.  HEENT:  

Within normal limits.  NECK:  Within normal limits.  LUNGS:  Within 

normal limits.  HEART:  Normal except for a 3/6 systolic ejection 

murmur.  ABDOMEN:  Soft and nontender.  EXTREMITIES:  Normal pulses 

throughout except that most of the pulses are heard only by 

Doppler, and on the left posterior tibial and dorsalis pedis pulses 

there is no Doppler pulse available.  The lower extremities are 

both cool and somewhat modeled to the mid thigh.  Toes are somewhat 

dusky.  There is a 5 x 5-mm shallow ulcer on the medial aspect of 

the left great toe.  

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  The Orthopedic Service was 

consulted and did AVIs and PVRs which indicated an ischemic lower 

extremity with a question of aortoiliac disease versus thrombus.

CONSULTATIONS (including PCP):  Orthopedic Service.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Arterial insufficiency.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  The patient is 

being admitted to the Orthopedic Service, is not being heparinized 

at present; and a decision of angiography or MRA will be 

considered.  The patient was admitted to the hospital in stable 

condition.

___________________________________                    YC253/88823 

LOGAN COLEMAN, M.D.       LC2                         D:08/07/59 

                                                       T:08/08/59 

Dictated by:  LOGAN COLEMAN, M.D.       LC2 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2061-10-12





Joanne Elyssia Pagan, M.D.

LEPROSARIUM

509 Ferncroft Drive

Union City, CT 33636



Dear Dr. Pagan:



Your patient Lauren Ferrara came into the office today for a follow-up visit.  As you know, she has a long and complex history of peripheral vascular disease with bilateral lower extremity bypass grafts.  Her left lower extremity bypass graft had occluded once previously, but was successfully restored by Dr. Tejeda.  In 02/61, we had detected a high-grade stenosis in the distal aspect of this graft by surveillance, and she underwent revision with a local patch angioplasty.  A subsequent ultrasound study done in 04/61 showed a widely patent graft and she has remained entirely asymptomatic.  She is not particularly active.  She denies any rest pain in the feet or significant claudication symptoms.  Recently, however, her husband had noticed some cyanosis of her left toes.  She remains on low dose aspirin in addition to Lipitor and her other medications.  She is a nonsmoker.



On examination today, she appeared well and in good spirits.  Blood pressure was measured at 130/60 in the right arm.  Lower extremity pulses are 2+ at the femoral level bilaterally.  On the right, there is a strong, easily appreciated pulse over her popliteal to dorsalis pedis bypass graft, and the foot is warm and well perfused.  On the left, I could not appreciate a pulse over her bypass graft incisions.  The left foot is slightly cooler than the right, and there are some mild cyanotic changes on the first toe in particular.  There are no frank or impending ulcerations or areas of irreversible ischemia.  There is a strong Doppler signal obtained over the posterior tibial artery at the ankle with an occlusion pressure of approximately 100 mmHg.  This yields an ankle index of nearly 0.7 and maybe falsely elevated.  A follow-up ultrasound study was performed in the vascular laboratory today.  The right lower extremity bypass remains widely patent.  As suspected, the left lower extremity bypass has now demonstrated to be occluded.



Ms. Ferrara left lower extremity bypass graft has occluded sometime during the last several months and her collateralization is clearly more marginal.  At the present time, she does not have any clear-cut symptoms of critical limb ischemia, though the slight discoloration of her toes is a clear sign.  The previous history of this graft including a prior thrombosis requiring thrombectomy and multiple revisions would not board well for any attempted thrombolysis or repeated rescue of this particular conduit.  Conversely, she has already had all of her lower extremity veins used for bypass operations and any redo bypass would be technically complicated.  I will need to review her previous angiograms from earlier this year to determine the status of her runoff and what the alternatives might be.  At the present time, however, she appears to have marginal, though reasonable collateralization and is essentially asymptomatic.  I think it would be reasonable to increase her antithrombotic therapy and I added a daily dose of Plavix to supplement a baby aspirin.  I spent sometime discussing the signs of worsening ischemia including more diffuse cyanotic skin changes of the toes, rest pain, or ulceration.  At a minimum, I will see her back in two months for reexamination, but I strongly encouraged the patient and her husband to contact us soon if there are any symptoms that suggest worsening of her circulation.  If her collateralization can remain stable, it certainly would be preferable to avoid having to consider a complex redo bypass with very limited remaining vein in this patient.



Thank you again for allowing us to participate in her care.  Please do not hesitate to contact me if I can be of further assistance.



Sincerely,



______________________________

Ricardo Jacob Updyke, MD





CC: Robin U. Tejeda M.D.

98 Bulova Drive, Room 625

Bethlehem, CT  65189







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2062-11-19







FERRARA, LAUREN

48185437

11/19/2062





HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Ferrara returns for followup visit.  She is now approximately one month out from a redo left popliteal to peroneal artery bypass graft using a basilic vein from right arm.  Postoperatively, she did well, although she was very sensitive to pain medication in the hospital and it was difficult to get her moving.  She complains of persistent weakness and numbness in her right hand and some pain shooting into her right forearm.  According to the patient, this was present early during her hospitalization, but because of other issues, it was not paid very much attention.  She denies any significant pain in the leg.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On examination today, she appears generally well.  The right arm harvest site is healed well and the upper arm is soft without any evidence of hematoma, whatsoever.  The hand is warm and well perfused with intact distal pulses; however, she clearly has weakness of flexion of the first and second digits and some weakness of opposition.  She appears to have intact ulnar and radial function.  The lower extremity incision has also healed well and there is a strong Doppler signal over the peroneal artery at the ankle.  The foot is warm and well perfused and the previous ischemic lesion on the big toe is healing.  She had a followup graft scan today, which revealed her bypass graft to be patent with no evidence of significant narrowing.  The ankle index was measured at 0.88 on the left and 0.64 on the right.



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  Ms. Ferrara lower extremity circulation is stable and her bypass graft is functioning nicely.  Unfortunately, she appears to have had some neuropathic complication in her right arm that may have been related to her vein harvest surgery.  The exam suggests some possible partial comprise of median nerve function.  In any case, she is able to function reasonably well and a course of occupational therapy may improve things.  There is no evidence of compression from hematoma and no evidence of infection.  We will continue to follow her closely with a return visit scheduled in six weeks and a course of therapy was prescribed.







Ricardo Jacob Updyke, MD













****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-03-10








PCC: Respiratory

26 Monica Street

Buena Vista, CT  84376

272-413-0358



FERRARA, LAUREN

48185437

03/10/2067



MAJOR DIAGNOSIS:  Lung mass.



HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Lauren is a 75-year-old woman.  She has only a very remote history of smoking, smoking not at all after the age of 30.  In early March, she was undergoing a routine physical.  At that time, she reported she had some mild weight loss.  However, she had been trying to lose weight.  She had no respiratory symptoms of dyspnea or cough.  A chest x-ray was obtained, which revealed a 6 cm left lung mass.  The patient subsequently had a CT scan.  The CT scan revealed a 4 x 6 lung mass in the posterior subsegment of the right upper lobe.  There were some modestly enlarged hilar nodes, but all below 2 cm.  She has some tiny sub 5 mm nodules in both lungs.  The patient is referred by her primary care physician, Dr. Jordon for further evaluation.  The patient has no history of lung .  She has no history of asthma or allergies.  She has not had any history of TB or a positive PPD.  She may have had some mild asbestos exposure when she worked in a publishing company, which had asbestos containing pipes.  She has no history of malignancy.  She has no avocational exposures to dust or danders.



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Includes:

1.  Mild vascular dementia.

2.  Hypertension.

3.  Hyperlipidemia.

4.  Diabetes.

5.  Hypothyroidism.

6.  Peripheral vascular disease.

7.  Anemia.

8.  Renal artery stenosis with mild renal failure.

9.  Carotid artery stenosis.



MEDICATIONS:  Levoxyl 88 mcg a day, Plavix 75 mg a day, Aricept 10 mg a day, furosemide 20 mg a day, nifedipine 90 mg a day, Crestor 20 mg a day, metoprolol 25 mg a day, calcium, Zetia 10 mg a day, vitamin D, Nephrocaps 1 mg a day, fish oil, aspirin 81 mg a day.



ALLERGIES:  Penicillin and estrogens and red dye #5.



SOCIAL HISTORY:  She lives with her husband.  She does not drink.  She has a very remote smoking history in her teens and early 20s.



FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  Otherwise, negative.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is in no distress.  Her O2 saturation is 95%.  Her blood pressure is 130/70, her pulse is 53.  Head and neck exam:  She is normocephalic and atraumatic.  Her nares are without discharge.  Oropharynx with dentures.  She has no erythema or exudate.  Neck is supple without adenopathy, thyromegaly, or bruits.  Her thorax is kyphotic.  She has normal fremitus and percussion.  Her lungs are clear.  Cardiac exam:  No JVD, S1, S2 without S3, S4, or murmurs.  Abdomen is soft.  Extremities have no clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  She has residual of vascular surgery in her legs.  She has slightly diminished peripheral pulses.



LABORATORY DATA:  Spirometry is normal.



IMAGING STUDIES:  A chest CT is as noted.



IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  A 75-year-old with a large right lung mass.  This is likely to be malignant, although a nonmalignant process or inflammatory processes are remotely possible.  At this point, I am going to refer her for a PET CT scan.  Her small nodules in her lung fields bilaterally are all sub 5mm and may not be related to this malignancy.  She does have modestly enlarged hilar nodes.  I am going to refer her to Thoracic Surgery for consideration of a mediastinoscopy and potential resection.  She would likely require cardiac clearance before this would occur.  She can follow up with me after her surgery if this proves to be an inflammatory lung disorder.  Otherwise, she will follow up with Oncology.  If she was deemed not to be an appropriate surgical candidate, either because of metastatic disease or because of comorbidity, she could have this lesion biopsied via a transthoracic needle aspirate.





______________________________

Pamela Falk, M.D.











eScription document:5-33744827 EMSSten Tel



CC: Jaclyn Jordon M.D.

Mondovi Hospital

566 Ferncroft Drive

Union City, CT, 33636

Fax: 

Email: 







DD: 03/10/67

DT: 03/10/67

DV: 03/10/67



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>