<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2082-04-10







Records not available

Here for follow up on DM,  and HTN 

Doing well, no new problems. No polis

Pt did not bring BS chart. 

AM values:   78 ,    138 (after breakfast)

  Weight:  gained  lbs

Exercise: yes   no

Smoking:  no

Main problem is back and knee pains on and off, worse with bad weather, no swelling , Motrim helps

HTN: 168/78   at home, no cp, no sob

Recurrent utis : no dysuria , no sxs

MEDICATIONS





PREMARIN (CONJUGATED ESTROGENS) 2 GM     PV QHS SIG ONE APPLICATOR FULL AT HSX 1WK THEN TWICE PER WEEK

ATIVAN (LORAZEPAM)   0.5MG  1 Tablet(s) PNGT QD  

GLYBURIDE   5MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD 

COZAAR (LOSARTAN)   50MG  1 Tablet(s) PO QD  





PROBLEMS



Diabetes mellitus  

Hypertension  





ALLERGIES



Penicillins  Rash  

Codeine  GI upset  

Sulfa  Rash  

* lisinopril  cough  







PE:         

BP:     160/80                  HR:        78         

Chest:  clear

Heart: reg, nl S1, S2

Abd: soft, non tender        

Extr: no edema



A-P : 



DM:   A ( A1C), B (blood pressure)  and  C  (cholesterol) targets emphasized. 

Diet: No sweets, low fat  diet reinforced.

Nutritionist  Referral done. 

Podiatry  referral done 

Opthalmology referral done

Exercise encouraged. 

Check BS twice a day, write them down and bring log book all visits. Recheck A1c before next visit.

Meds: Cont oral agent, same dose.  

ASA 325 mg qd recommended., done.

Blood pressure:is high. Will double Cozaar dose to 50 bid.  Check chem 7 

LDL Cholesterol: on target. Cont same tx. Recheck cho  in      

Pneumonia vac today

Follow up in  3   months.

mammogram ordered

We did not deal with bone density, records are not available and I do not remember what we did about it. Will rediscuss issue next visit



HEALTH MAINTENANCE



Complete Physical Exam 05/19/2081   

Breast Exam 05/19/2081  Done 

Home glucose monitoring  04/10/2082   

Hypoglycemia Assessment/Counseling  04/10/2082   

M-alb/creat ratio 04/10/2082 ordered  

Microalbumin 04/10/2082   

Microalbumin 04/10/2082 ordered  

Nutrition Referral 04/10/2082 referral done  

Ophthal Exam 04/10/2082 referrala done Other 

Colonoscopy 04/10/2082 offered , she will think about it  

Stool Guaiac 04/10/2082 stool cards givne Other 

Pneumovax 04/10/2082  Done 

Podiatry exam 04/10/2082 referral done  

Influenza Vaccine 10/24/2081   

Cholesterol 08/02/2081 212  DESIRABLE: less then 200

Mammogram 02/08/2081 BilScrMammo  

Pap Smear 12/29/2079 See report in Results  

Smoking status 01/26/2082  Never a smoker 

UA-Protein 01/24/2082 Negative  

HBA1C 08/03/2081 7.20  

Domestic Violence Screening 01/26/2082 neg  









____________________________

Tatyana A. Morris, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-10-31

Team B Internal Medicine Intern Admission Note

Louise Urquhart

MR# 2072665

Date of Admission: 10/30/82

PCP: Dr. Tatyana Butler (Solemar Hospital)





ID/CC:	75 yo F with HTN, DM2, RCC s/p right radical nephrectomy 2079 presents with hypertensive urgency



HPI:   	Has h/o HTN, saw her PCP in September, BP 168/78, supposed to be on cozaar 50 mg BID, added HCTZ 25 mg QD.  However, patient has only been taking cozaar 50 mg QD.  Needed renewal of her prescription, was sent to medical walk in clinic prior to filling it, found BP to be 230/110.  Had HA 2 nights ago lasting couple hours, posterior neck across top of head.  While in waiting room also had HA, 4/10 from back of neck across top of head.  No other sx - no CP, SOB, visual changes, abdominal pain, unilateral weakness, numbness, hematuria.  Was stressed out over argument with granddaughter yesterday.  In ED afebrile T 96.5, BP 235/92, HR 91, RR 18.  No evidence papilledema, no focal neurologic signs.  EKG with new TWI V1-V4, head CT and CXR unremarkable.  Given hydralazine 10 mg IV x 2, ativan 1 mg IV x1, and lopressor 25 mg PO x1, BP improved to 160's/80's.



ROS:   No F/C/NS.  No change in weight/appetite. No CP/Palpitations/Orthopnea/PND/LE edema/Claudication. No SOB/cough/hemoptysis/wheezing/sore throat/rash.  No N/V/D/hematochezia/melena. No delta MS/LOC. No slurring of speech, unilateral weakness. No dysuria.  + Right heel pain since jumping to grab her dog 2 weeks ago.  Otherwise negative in detail.



PMH:

HTN

DM2 - x 5 yrs, no retinopathy, nephropathy, neuropathy, HBA1C 7.2 7/26

RCC s/p right radical nephrectomy 2079, 4 cm, grade II/IV, confined in capsule

S/p colonoscopic polypectomy tubular adenoma 2079

Diverticulosis

Osteoporosis



Medications:

Cozaar 50 mg PO BID (only taking 50 QD)

HCTZ 25 mg PO QD (added 9/82, not taking)

Glyburide 5 mg PO QD

Premarin  PO QHS (not taking)

Fosamax 70 mg PO QWK (not taking)

Ativan 0.5 mg PO QD PRN

Tums

MVI



Allergies:  	PCN, sulfa    rash, ACE-I    cough, codeine    GI upset



SH:  	Patient lives in Marianna with husband of 54 yrs.  Used to work at Filenesas a salesperson.  Son handicapped after hit by drunk driver 9 yrs ago, this remains a significant stressor for her.

	Tob:		Very rare, quit 30 yrs ago

	EtOH:  		Used to drink occasional glass wine, none recently

	Illicits: 	Negative



FH:	No MI, cancer.  Brother with    poor circulation   .



Exam:  	VS:	T= 98.2	HR= 68	BP= 152/81	RR= 18

General:  NAD, well appearing

HEENT: NC/AT,  PERRL, anicteric. EOMI.  Fundi poorly visualized.  OP w/ MMM, no erythema or injection.

Skin:	No rashes

Neck:  	Supple, full ROM, no JVD , 2+ carotids w/o bruits, no thyromegaly or nodules, no nodes

Chest: 	CTA&P bilaterally

CVS:  	RRR nl S1 S2, no m/r/g

Abd:  	nl BS, soft, non-tender, no HSM, no abdominal bruits

Extr:  	no c/c/e 2+ DP's bilaterally

Neuro: AAOX3, MS nl, CN II through XII intact, Motor 5/5 UE and LE, Sensory intact to LT, vibration sense distally. F to N nl, RAM nl.  



DATA:

Chemistry:	

SH  BLOOD          30-Oct-2082 19:57



Plasma Sodium           133       L              135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium        5.4       H              3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride         98        L              100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide   26.6                     24.0-30.0      mmol/L

Calcium                 10.4                     8.5-10.5       mg/dl

Phosphorus              2.4       L              2.6-4.5        mg/dl

Magnesium               1.6                      1.4-2.0        meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen    18                       8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine       1.1                      0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose          230       H              70-110         mg/dl

Total Protein           8.2       H              6.0-8.0        g/dl

Albumin                 4.0                      3.1-4.3        g/dl

Globulin                4.2       H              2.6-4.1        g/dl

Direct Bilirubin        0.2                      0-0.4          mg/dl

Total Bilirubin         0.4                      0-1.0          mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase    94                       30-100         U/L

Transaminase-SGPT       27                       7-30           U/L

Transaminase-SGOT       53        H              9-25           U/L

Creatine Kinase         108                      40-150         U/L



SH  BLOOD          30-Oct-2082 23:10



Creatine Kinase Isoenzy 1.9                      0.0-6.9        ng/ml

Troponin-T              <0.01                    0.00-0.09      ng/ml

Creatine Kinase         203       H              40-150         U/L



Heme:	

SH  BLOOD          30-Oct-2082 19:52



WBC                     14.2      H              4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                     42.0                     36.0-46.0      %

HGB                     14.2                     12.0-16.0      gm/dl

RBC                     4.78                     4.00-5.20      mil/cmm

PLT                     220                      150-350        th/cumm

MCV                     88                       80-100         fl

MCH                     29.7                     26.0-34.0      pg/rbc

MCHC                    33.8                     31.0-37.0      g/dl

RDW                     12.8                     11.5-14.5      %

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST    RECEIVED

Diff Method             Auto

Poly                    71        H              40-70          %

Lymphs                  23                       22-44          %

Monos                   3         L              4-11           %

EOS                     2                        0-8            %

Basos                   1                        0-3            %

Absolute Neuts          10.27     H              1.8-7.7        th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs         3.20                     1.0-4.8        th/cmm

Absolute Monos          0.46      H              0.2-0.4        th/cmm

Absolute EOS            0.22                     0.1-0.3        th/cmm

Absolute Basos          0.07                     0.0-0.3        th/cmm



Urinalysis:

Pending

Microbiology:

None

CXR:	

Official read pending, no infiltrates, CHF

Head CT:

FINDINGS:

	Dystrophic calcification in the basal ganglia bilaterally.  Head

	CT otherwise negative.  No intracranial hemorrhage, mass, mass

	effect, or edema.  No gross evidence of acute infarction, although

	MRI with diffusion weighted imaging would be more sensitive.

	Intracranial arterial calcification.  Bilateral lens implants.

	

IMPRESSION:

	Essentially normal head CT.



EKG:	

NSR 90 BPM, nl intervals, nl axis, deepening of old TWI aVL, new TWI V1-V4, isolated q in III

___________________________________________



Impression: 75 yo F with HTN, DM2, RCC s/p right radical nephrectomy 2079 presents with hypertensive urgency.  Not taking all of prescribed meds.  Could have left sided renal artery stenosis exacerbating HTN in setting of unilateral kidney, K is elevated, although Cr normal on cozaar.  Needs tight BP control esp in setting of DM to prevent nephrosclerosis.





Plan: 

HTN - BP now better controlled, cont to cycle q1 hr for now.  Will repeat EKG, ROMI with serial cardiac enzymes.  ASA, monitor.  Cont cozaar 50 mg qd (may need to d/c or decrease dose if K remains elevated) and start lopressor 25 TID and titrate up as needed for BP control.  Will not attempt to lower BP beyond 150-160's for now to prevent drop in cerebral perfusion pressure.  Cont ativan 0.5-1 mg PO BID PRN.  Consider MRI/MRA to assess for RAS given such severe BP elevation.  Strict I/O's.

F/E/N - Kayexalate 30g x 1, recheck K in AM, consider lasix.

DM - Cont glyburide, check QID FS with insulin SS.  Diabetic diet

Proph - Nexium, SC heparin





_________________________________

Xander H. Leonard, MD

Pager #77615





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-07-09

Pt here for new PCP and f/u on multiple issues.



Medications

Premarin (CONJUGATED Estrogens) 2 GM PV QHS : SIG ONE APPLICATOR FULL AT HSX 1WK THEN TWICE PER WEEK

Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 50MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO bid

ATENOLOL 50MG, 0.5 Tablet(s) PO QD

Ativan (LORAZEPAM) 0.5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PNGT QD

GLYBURIDE 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 



Allergies

Codeine - GI upset

Sulfa - Rash

* lisinopril - cough

Penicillins - Rash

* hctz - cramps 



Problems

Diabetes mellitus - cheated last weekend at a party, but mostly sugars 60-150s.  Last low-sugar rxn was a month ago, and her glyb. was decreased.  She may have "polys".  She still has not called her eye doctor for an appt. b/c too busy.  Urine microalbumin nl.  HBA1C 6.6%



Hypertension - did not increase atenolol as advised by Dr Buckley.  Her home BPs are 150/70, but her pulse is often in the 50s, which is why she is taking only 1/2 of atenolol.



Renal cancer : incidentally discovered, s/p nephrectomy



Hyperparathyroidism : ? 2/2 Vit D deficiency. Thyroid nodules.  Being evaluated by Dr Lawson, SH Endocrine.  However, the last time she went to Endo. she was told she did not have an appt. She has not rec'd another in the mail.  She never had the thyroid bx.  Last Ca nl. but phos low.



Dyspepsia/ H Pylori : unable to tolerate bismuth, TCN, metronidazole or clarithromycin and metronidazole.  She has occ. dyspepsia, for which she takes prn ranitidine, none lately.  Of note, recent guaiacs positive.  She had a colonoscopy 2079, which showed a polyp and diverticulosis.  Three year f/u rec.  Pt has been afraid to reschedule b/c was not sufficiently anesthetised the last time and had a lot of pain.



Plantar Fasciitis - resolved.



RHM - UTD.



SH - married.  Husband has some medical problems, but is able to drive her on all her errands, as she does not dirve. No cigs, EtOH, sexual activity.  She has 4 children and 9 grandchildren.  Her son was hit by a car some years ago, and sustained head trauma, now in assisted living.  She is very stressed all the time worrying about him.  She became tearful telling me about this.  Enjoys gardening and attending her quilting group.



ROS - + for hearing loss, diff. w/ memory related to stress and anxiety about son, as above in specific items, occ. constip.  Neg. otherwise.



PLAN:

Rev'd medical and SH. 

Re-refer to Dr Lawson, emailed Dr Lawson.

Disc. pt's intent about cancer surveillance.  She states that she would want to be treated if she had ca, and therefore agrees to upper and lower endo. if I request she receive adequate analgesia.

F/U 2 mo.  BP not done today b/c she became upset.  Prob. will need a third BP med, but not incr. bb.







_____________________________________________

Patricia Lund, M.D.











****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-03-05

77 yo F one hour late for appt.  She is planning parathyroid surgery.  She is supposed to be taking ca and vit. D supplements.  She took the vit. D for a few days, but that is all.  She has fatigue and leg cramps attrib. to hyperparathyroidism.



Medications

Premarin (CONJUGATED Estrogens) 2 GM PV QHS : SIG ONE APPLICATOR FULL AT HSX 1WK THEN TWICE PER WEEK

Ativan (LORAZEPAM) 0.5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PNGT QD

Hydralazine Hcl 25MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO BID

GLYBURIDE 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ATENOLOL 50MG, 0.5 Tablet(s) PO QD

Aspirin (CHILDRENS) (ACETYLSALICYLIC Aci... 81MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Stopped cozaar b/o noncoverage, stopped nifedipine b/c did not agree w/ her.



Allergies

Codeine - GI upset

Sulfa - Rash

* lisinopril - cough

Penicillins - Rash

* hctz - cramps 



Problems

Diabetes mellitus - does not do home glucometry b/c thinks she knows what her sugar is w/o testing it.  Recent HBA1C<7%, LDL 124.

Hypertension - no CP, SOB, HA, edema, dizziness.

Renal cancer : incidentally discovered, s/p nephrectomy

Dyspepsia/ H Pylori : unable to tolerate bismuth, TCN, metronidazole or clarithromycin and metronidazole. No sx at this time.

Thyroid nodules : biopsy benign

Plantar Fasciitis 

Osteoporosis : bone density 9/11/2082

Colonic polyps : tubular adenoma. g+ stool 5/83. Refusing f/u colo.

Diverticulosis 

H/O Vitamin D deficiency 



SH - mostly worried about husband's health problems.



PE - appears well

BP 170/100

HR 66

Lungs clear

Cor reg w/o MRG

No edema



IMP

HyperPTH - for surgery, but we need to control her BP first.  She needs to take the supplements rec. by Dr Lawson.

HTN not controlled, not adherent to rx, various barriers.

DM pr. controlled, though does not check glycemia.  Needs LDL<100

Anxiety

Hx colon polyps, f/u is recommended.

Hx renal ca, rec. f/u.

H. pylori, not treated, no current sx.



PLAN:

Given rec. for Caltrate 600+D to take bid.

Rx Benicar, ARB covered by free care.

Lipitor rx.

She agrees to resume furosemide, if can skip it on days she goes out, rx to RHC.

F/U 1-2 mo, BP, breast check, order abd/pelvic CT surveillance s/p renal ca, f/u labs.

She declines colo, despite stated risk of colon ca w/ polyps, but might consider it later.

She is advised to stop the asa 10 days prior to any surgery.







_____________________________________________

Patricia Lund, M.D.



cc:Dr Lawson





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>