<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2120-10-23

Patient Name: FLAHERTY, XAVIER;  MRN: 1935081
Dictated on: 10/23/2120 by ROSITA KO, M.D. 

 
The patient is a 72-year-old male, paraplegic, referred for evaluation of recurrent bladder infections.  The patient has persistent presence of bacteria in his urine and there is a concern that he might have a persistent source of infection.  The patient denies fevers, chills, sweats, decrease in energy, loss of appetite, pain in the lower abdomen or penile discharge.  He reports there is some soreness around the meatus, which he attributes to self-catheterizing he is required to do 3 times a day.  He is well educated in terms of cleaning around the side and the appropriate way to do self-catheterization.   
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Diabetes, hypertension, paraplegia secondary to unclear disk problems in 2107, right hip ulcer with trochanteric osteomyelitis in December 2118, treated with Unasyn x6 weeks and debridement and surgical flap, sacral decubiti in 2119 treated with Unasyn x6 weeks, local debridement healing by secondary intention.  No history of kidney stones.   
SOCIAL:  Ex-tobacco use 2-3 packs per day, quit 25 years. Alcohol prior heavy use, quit 25 years.  Lives alone.  Prior work included Heavy-Duty Equipment Mechanic, Ironworker, as well as Electric Appliance Servicer.  
 
ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.  
 
MEDICATIONS:  Blood pressure medication, name unknown. Metformin.  Note, patient had been on Bactrim prophylaxis over the spring.   
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Blood pressure 150/100, heart rate 100, temperature 97.9.  In general, vigorous, well-appearing man in wheelchair.  Awake and alert.  HEENT, sclerae anicteric.  Conjunctivae noninjected.  Neck supple.  No significant lymphadenopathy.  Chest, clear to auscultation bilaterally.  Cardiac, regular rate and rhythm.  No murmurs.  Abdomen benign.  Extremities, warm and well perfused.  No edema.  
 
IMPRESSION:  Presence of bacteria in static urine within the bladder is not necessarily diagnostic as infection given patient's lack of symptoms and likely reflects colonization.   
PLAN:  Would not treat patient with antibiotics unless he develops signs or symptoms of infection such as fevers, chills, sweats, elevated white blood cell count, pain in the suprapubic area or decreased energy.  
 
_________________________ 
Rosita Ko, M.D.  
 
DD:10/23/2120 
DT:10/24/2120 
AO:29724     :0269
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2121-05-19





Internal Medicine

HOLY CROSS HOSPITAL



History of present illness   The patient is a 72 year old male, with a past medical history of paraplegia (due to spinal ischemia), DMII, HTN, and recurrent UTI's, who came in for a follow up visit. The patient says that he has been feeling well. He continues to exercise frequently. No chest pain, abdominal pain, SOB, or fevers.



Allergies

No known drug allergy   



Change in therapies and Renewals

Zestril 30mg PO QD QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 11/22/2118

iron supplement 325mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:1 year Start: 6/15/2119

aspirin 81 mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:1 yr Start: 6/15/2119

Xanax 0.25mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 6/15/2119

free text medications regranex  45 gram QTY:1 Refills:1 yr Start: 6/19/2119

Glucophage 850 mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 7/18/2120 take with meals

Lipitor 20mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 4/07/2121

Neurontin 300 mg po tid QTY:270 Refills:3 Start: 4/07/2121

multivitamins 1 tab po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 5/19/2121

atenolol 25mg po qd Start: 5/19/2121



Past medical history   Paraplegia- On 10/06 the patient had a lumbar laminectomy for sciatica. His sciatical pain improved until 5/07 when he developed proximal leg weakness. By 7/07 the patient was bound to a wheelchair. Orginally an extensive workup suggested that the patient had an extramedullary tumor from T8-T12. However all biopsies were inconclusive. The patient subsequently received a T10 laminectomy on 9/09 that revealed Spinal Vascular Malformation but no tumor. The patient received serial MRI's until 12/14 that were able to demonstrate no "recurrent" tumors. 



			

DMII-first diagnosed in 2113 



			

HTN 



			

Recurrent UTI's 

PSA of 6.6 



			



			

Flap 3 Closure Surgery-patient says that he received this surgery to correct damage to his skin caused by his multiple back surgeries 

2690's received surgery for shrapnel removal 



			

Sacral decubitus ulcers



Family history   Father - was an alcoholic who died in an accident

Mom- died at the age of 76 with peripheral vascular disease 

Brother- died in 50's of CAD, was an alcoholic



Social history   The patient lives alone. He never married and has no children. He is a retired Heavy-Duty Equipment Mechanic (15yrs) and Concrete Finisher (25yrs). He is a veteran. 

The patient quit smoking 20 years ago but had smoked 1.5ppd*20yrs (30 pack year). Very rarely drinks.



Physical examination

Pulse 92  

Blood pressure 150/80  

Respiratory rate 16  

General appearance   NAD

Heent   PERRLA, EOMI, no oral erythema or lesions

Chest   b/l clear to ascultation

Cor   S1/S2+, RRR, no murmurs

Abdomen   Nt/nd/ +bs

Extrem   no edema



Assessment and plan   The patient is a 72 year old male, with a past medical history of paraplegia (due to spinal ischemia), DMII, HTN, and recurrent UTI's, who came in for a follow up visit. 



			

1. Diabetes 

-HemA1C 10/20->7.5. Will recheck

-cont metformin to 850mg bid - Ordered repeat chem 7 (creatinine) and LFTs

-patient sees an opthamologist yearly 

-referred patient again to podiatrist 

-NEXT visit patient will bring cath supplies and WILL check for microalbuniuria -

-increased lipitor to 20 (patient's Chol 179 and LDL 111) -> goal LDL 70 

-patient refused nutrition consult 

-patient is taking ASA 

-patient is on a MVI



			

2. HTN 

-started atenolol 25 qd

-current regiment is atenolol 25qd and Zestril to 30mg qd 



3. ?CAD

-EKG 4/21 showed evidence of old ("silent") inferior MI

-ordered TTE

-WILL consider ETT

-will check homocysteine level



			

3. Paraplegia 

-on neurontin for neuropathic pain control 



			

4.Recurent UTI -appreciate ID consult will give prophylaxis for recurrent UTI's. Also, will not treat patient unless he has systemic symptoms of fevers or there is a great increase in the amount of burning he has on urination 



			

5. Elevated PSA 

-appreciate urology consult -they felt that in light of stability of PSA and patient's desire not be biopsied that no intervention should occur at this time. -urology wants to see the patient annually (next visit 12/21) 



			

6. Anxiety 

-well controlled, will continue the Zanax



7. Health Maintenance 

-patient has received pneumovac 

-last colonoscopy was on 12/18 

-NEEDS flu vaccine in spring



			

Return to clinic in 1 month



Addendum

			

I was present during key portions of the evaluation of the patient and agree with John Ross's findings and plan as written.Diabetes followup good.  Appropriately managed.

Rebecca Downs



Signed electronically by John  Ross MD on May 25, 2121     Rebecca  Downs MD on May 29, 2121     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2122-09-14





Internal Medicine

HOLY CROSS HOSPITAL



History of present illness

			

  Mr. Flaherty is a 74 year old male with a PMH paraplegia (secondary to spinal ischemia), DM, HTN, sacral decibutus ulcer, and recurrent UTI's who came in for a follow up visit. The patient says that he feels well. He says that his fingersticks have averaged about "124" and have ranged 80-150. He's says that he's improved his diet. He says that his BP has been checked several times by visiting nurses and each time was SBP of 120. He says that his abcess under his left axilla has healed well and is no longer bothering him. He says that his sacral decibutus ulcer has resolved. 



On review of systems, no chest pain, SOB, abdominal pain, nausea/vomiting, fevers, dysuria, or lightheadnesses.



Allergies

No known drug allergy   



Change in therapies and Renewals



Zestril 20mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 11/22/2118

iron supplement 325mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:1 year Start: 6/15/2119

aspirin 81 mg po qd QTY:30 Refills:1 yr Start: 6/15/2119

Xanax 0.25mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 6/15/2119

Glucophage 1000 mg po bid QTY:180 Refills:3 Start: 7/18/2120 take with meals

Lipitor 20mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 4/07/2121

Neurontin 300 mg po tid QTY:270 Refills:3 Start: 4/07/2121

multivitamins 1 tab po qd QTY:90 Refills:3 Start: 5/19/2121

atenolol 25mg po qd QTY:90 Refills:6 Start: 5/19/2121



Past medical history

			

  1. Paraplegia- On 10/06 the patient had a lumbar laminectomy for sciatica. His sciatical pain improved until 5/07 when he developed proximal leg weakness. By 7/07 the patient was bound to a wheelchair. Orginally an extensive workup suggested that the patient had an extramedullary tumor from T8-T12. However all biopsies were inconclusive. The patient subsequently received a T10 laminectomy on 9/09 that revealed Spinal Vascular Malformation but no tumor. The patient received serial MRI's until 12/14 that were able to demonstrate no "recurrent" tumors.

2. DMII-first diagnosed in 2113

3. HTN

4. Recurrent UTI's

5. PSA of 6.6

6. Flap 3 Closure Surgery-patient says that he received this surgery to correct damage to his skin caused by his multiple back surgeries

2070's received surgery for shrapnel removal

7. Sacral decubitus ulcers



Family history

			

  Father - was an alcoholic who died in an accident

Mom- died at the age of 76 with peripheral vascular disease 

Brother- died in 50's of CAD, was an alcoholic



Social history

			

  The patient lives alone. He never married and has no children. He is a retired Heavy-Duty Equipment Mechanic (15yrs) and Concrete Finisher (25yrs). He is a veteran. 

The patient quit smoking 20 years ago but had smoked 1.5ppd*20yrs (30 pack year). Very rarely drinks.



Physical examination

Blood pressure 135/70  

Pulse 82  

Respiratory rate 12  

General appearance   NAD, pleasant. In a wheelchair

Skin   Abcess under left axilla has healed well. No erythema or exudate.

Heent   PERRLA, EOMI, no oral erythema or lesions

Chest   b/l clear to ascultation

Cor   S1/S2+, RRR, no murmurs

Abdomen   Nt/nd/ +bs

Rectal exam   refused

Genitalia   refused

Extrem   no edema

Neuro   CNII-XII intact, 5/5 strength in upper 2 extermities, no numbness or tingling, 0/5 strength b/l lower extremities



Assessment and plan

			

  The patient is a 74 year old male, with a past medical history of paraplegia (due to spinal ischemia), DMII, HTN, and recurrent UTI's, who came in for a follow up visit. 



			

1. Diabetes 

-spoke with the patient about his diabetes control. He understands that his hemoglobin A1C is 8.4. However, he doesnt want to start insulin (inconvenient) and actos (the expense). Our plan is to check another hemoglobin A1C since his diet has improved. Will consider starting low dose glypizide if hem A1C still grossly elevated

-current regiment is metformin 1000mg bid -HemA1C 2/22 was 8.5 

-patient sees an opthamologist yearly 

-patient saw a podiatrist in 1/22 

-patient on lipitor 20 -> 9/21 lipid panel Cholesterol 147, LDL 67, HDL 42 

-patient is taking ASA 

-patient is on a MVI 



			

2. HTN 

-spoke with the patient about the fact that his SBP is 130-135. He said that he would like to hold off on advancing treatment for now

-for now will continue Zestril 20mg qd and atenolol 25mg po qd

-current regiment is atenolol 25qd and Zestril 10mg qd   



			

3. Sacral decibutus ulcer 

-patient says that the wound has healed  



4. Paraplegia 

-on neurontin for neuropathic pain control 

-WILL CONSIDER increase the dosage



			

5.Recurent UTI 

-Will not give prophylaxis for recurrent UTI's. Also, will not treat patient unless he has systemic symptoms of fevers or there is a great increase in the amount of burning he has on urination 



			

6. Elevated PSA 

-urology felt that in light of stability of PSA and patient's desire not be biopsied that no intervention should occur at this time. 

-urology wants to see the patient annually. Spoke with the patient again about this today. He doesnt want to see urology again and doesnt want a rectal exam.



			

7. Anxiety 

-well controlled, will continue the Zanax 



			

8. Health Maintenance 

-patient has received pneumovac 

-last colonoscopy was on 12/18 

-gave the patient a flu vaccine (9/22) (Lot BDIKB454QH and expiration 7/3/23)



			

Return to clinic in 2 months (spoke to patient about him coming more frequently but he says that it is very difficult to come in so he'll do the best he can)



Addendum

			



			

I was present during key portions of the evaluation of the patient and agree with John Ross's findings and plan as written.  Pt. is thin, has gotten maximum benefit from metformin so options include sulfonyurea or insulin.

Francis Lawrence



Signed electronically by Ross, John on Sep 21, 2122     Lawrence, Francis X on Sep 22, 2122     



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2126-09-04




















Manamana 5 Admission Note



PATIENT:  Flaherty, Xavier

MRN: 1935081

ADMIT DATE: 9/04/26

PCP:  Michael Ring MD

ATTENDING PHYSICIAN: Manamana 5 WARD

Source: patient, chart (please note that patient is a poor historian)



CHIEF COMPLAINT- 

s/p 2 falls at home

fever in the emergency ward



HISTORY OF THE PRESENT ILLNESS

Mr. Flaherty is a 78 yo gentleman with a PMH notable for diabetes mellitus, HTN, paraplegia 2/2 spinal vascular malformations now wheelchair bound with a suprapubic catheter, and multiple ulcers who presents after 2 falls at home, found by EMS to be living in squalor and found to have a Tmax of 104 degrees F in the emergency ward.



Patient states that he was in his usual state of health, which includes wheeling himself around his apartment and preparing simple meals such as oatmeal, until the week prior to admission.  Mr Flaherty noted that he felt &#8220;lousy&#8221; throughout the week.  He is unable to characterize this feeling, stating simply, &#8220;something wasn&#8217;t right.&#8221;  Patient states he &#8220;may have felt nauseous&#8221; and &#8220;I might have had a fever.&#8221;  However, patient denies vomiting, sick contacts, abdominal pain, change in appetite, recent antibiotic use, SOB, DOE, chest pain/pressure/tightness, suprapubic pain, change in stool caliber/color/frequency, sore throat, change in his chronic cough, sputum production, drainage around his SPC site, hematemesis, pain at his ulcer sites, and increased pus/output from ulcer sites.  



Of note, patient states, &#8220;If it wasn&#8217;t for the fireman, I wouldn&#8217;t be here.  




Of note, patient states, &#8220;My house is fine.&#8221;  He denies feeling unsafe at home, denies difficulty with bills, denies rodent/vermin/cockroach infestation, denies leaving his stove on.



EMS-&gt;ED course:

Upon EMS arrival, they found his apartment in disarray and placed a section 12 order.

VS: BP: 140/90, HR 117, RR20, T97.1, 95% RA, after blood cultures were drawn, the patient was started on unasyn, given a 500 cc bolus, and sent to the floor.





REVIEW OF SYSTEMS

General 
no weight loss, gain; no chills, night sweats

HEENT 
+rhinorrhea

Pulmonary no wheezing, no hemoptysis

Cardiac no palpitations

Endocrine no polydipsia, polyuria, or polyphagia

Extremity &#8211; no lower extremity edema

Neurology &#8211; no headache, no photophobia, no changes in strength or sensation



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY/PSH

1. Paraplegia- 2/2 spinal ischemia from surgical complication

2. DMII - first diagnosed in 2113, last A1C 8.4 (8/1/26) 

3. HTN 

4. Recurrent UTI's (requires catheterization to urinate)

5. PSA of 6.6 

6. 2070's received surgery for shrapnel removal 

7. 
Sacral decubitus ulcers



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION

- iron supplement 325mg po bid - from 325mg po daily - Rx (Qty:180 Rf:3)- aspirin 81 mg po daily- atenolol 50mg po daily (called to pharm)- Colace 100mg 1 po daily take one tab tid- Glucophage 1000 mg po bid take with meals- Lantus SoloStar Pen 10 units sc at bedtime- Lipitor 20mg po daily- multivitamins 1 tab po daily- Neurontin 600 mg po tid- Xanax 0.25mg po bid prn- Zestril 40mg po daily



ALLERGIES/ADVERSE REACTIONS 

nkda



FAMILY HISTORY

Father - was an alcoholic who died in an accident 

Mom- died at the age of 76 with peripheral vascular disease 

Brother- died in 50's of CAD, was an alcoholic



SOCIAL HISTORY

General &#8211; Pt lives alone in a 2 bdr apt.  Needs help with shopping, which he gets from his good friend. 



ADLs: Dress with assistance, eats independently, ambulate with wheel chair, toilet independently, and hygiene is questionable (especially at home).   IADLs: shop with friend, housekeep with friend, accounting independently, food prep independently, and transportation with help from friend



He never married and has no children. He is a retired Heavy-Duty Equipment Mechanic (15yrs) and Concrete Finisher (25yrs). He is a veteran. 



Tobacco &#8211; The patient quit smoking 23 years ago &#8211; distant 30 pack year smoking history

Alcohol &#8211; rarely drinks

Illicit drugs &#8211; none



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION 

VITALS:  T98       HR94     BP134/63            RR12     SaO299 RA

General &#8211; obese older gentleman, resting comfortably in bed, mildy malodorous, appropriately conversant, speaking full sentences

HEENT- no evidence of head trauma, no pharyngeal erythema/exudates

Neck &#8211; supple with no lymphadenopathy 

Pulmonary &#8211; equal air entry b/l, crackles 1/3 the way up b/l, decreased BS LLB 

Cardiac &#8211; distant HS, S1+S2 nml, RRR, no MRG

Abdomen &#8211; soft and obese, SPC in place w/o drainage/fluctuance, +BS, no TTP

Back &#8211; lumbar scar noted, no CVAT

Extremity &#8211; b/l LE atrophic, no edema, L large area of blanching, confluent erythema from mid-thigh to lateral lower L leg, +warmth, L hip ulcer 5 cm diam with induration

Rectal &#8211; decreased tone, hard stool in vault, 9 o&#8217;clock .5 cm area of increased density (?folliculitis), no fluctuance or pain



LABORATORIES


NA            132(L)                                                            

K             3.5                                                     
         

CL            94(L)                                                             

CO2           26.8                                                              

BUN           14                                                                

CRE           0.78                                                              

EGFR          &gt;60(T)                                                            

GLU           244(H)                                                            

ANION         11                                                                



CA            9.5                                                               



CK-MB         Negative                                                          

TROP-I        Negative                                                          



WBC           19.7(H)                                                           

RBC           4.61                                                              

HGB           13.8                                                              

HCT           40.7(L)                                                           

MCV           88                                                                

MCH           29.9                                                              

MCHC          33.9                                                              

PLT           319                                                               

RDW           13.5                                                              



UA-COLOR      Yellow                                                            

UA-APP        Clear                                                             

UA-GLUC       2+(T)                                                             

UA-BILI       Negative                                                          

UA-KET        3+                                                                

UR-SPGR       1.020(T)                                                          

UA-BLD        2+                                                                

UA-PH         6.0                                                               

UA-PROT       2+                                                                

UA-UROBI      Negative                                                          

UA-NIT        Negative                                                          

UA-WBC        Negative                                                          



UAS-RBC       None                                                              

UAS-WBC       20-50                                                             

UAS-BACT      Moderate                                                          

UAS-AMOR      PRESENT                                   
                                                



RADIOLOGICAL STUDIES


CT brain w/o contrast: No evidence of acute intracranial hemorrhage, mass-effect, midline shift or acute territorial infarction. Chronic healed naso-orbito-ethmoid fracture.

CXR - Progression of predominantly bibasilar nodular and interstitial opacities, possibly be due to chronic aspiration. Recommend CT.



EKG

Nsr 94 bpm, LAD, no Q waves, no ST-T changes

            

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN

78 yo M with DM, HTN, ulcers, indwelling SPC who presents with one week of feeling &#8220;lousy&#8221; and a maximum temperature of 104 degrees F.  Exam was remarkable for LLE erythema consistent with cellulitis.  Labs were notable for a high WBC with a neutrophilic predominance and a clean urinalysis.  Given his history of fever, exam, and lab studies, infection is the most likely cause of Mr. Flaherty&#8217;s current presentation.  



ISSUE #1: Fever and leukocytosis


Most likely secondary to cellulitis vs wound infection

Blood cultures, urine cultures, wound cultures, and respiratory cultures

Panculture if SPIKES

f/u microbiology c and s

start broad spectrum antibiotics: Vancomycin 1 g q12 IV for presumed MRSA and Unasyn 3000 mg IV q6 for presumed gram negatives (with minimal anaerobe coverage)

if clinically decompensates, will consider Zosyn for pseudomonal coverage and Flagyl for anaerobe coverage



ISSUE #2: Diabetes Mellitus


continue with home regimen of metformin 1000 bid and lantus 14 SC

insulin sliding scale for coverage

FSBG AC+HS

Last A1C 8.4 8/1/26



ISSUE #3: HTN


Continue with home regimen of lisinopril 40 mg daily, atenolol 50 mg daily

Monitor and titrate as needed



ISSUE #4: Home safety and cleanliness


Will ask for assistance from social work and case management re: potential need of home safety evaluation

Assess for competency &#8211; re: safety at home



FEN: diabetic diet, replete lytes prn, will bolus 1000 cc NS



PROPHYLAXIS

GI: omeprazole

DVT: Fragmin

BOWEL: Colace, Senna prn



CODE:  unknown



__________________________________

Kenneth Titus, MD MA

PGY-1, Pager #55518





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>