<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2154-11-14


Department of Orthopedic Surgery
42 Wood St                                        OLIVE, XAVIER
Sydney, WV 65157                                      26690002
--------------                                           11/14/54


Michael Ulrey, M.D.
45 Wood St
Sydney, WV  65157

RE:  Xavier Olive

Dear Michael,

Mr. Xavier Olive presents for evaluation, thanks for your
referral.  As you recall he is a 71-year-old gentleman who is
status post angioplasty on the left for high-grade stenotic
lesions of the distal superficial femoral artery and the
popliteal artery on the left.  The patient presents now for
further evaluation of his "claudication symptoms".

The patient states he has bilateral lower extremity symptoms,
there are about equivalent in nature.  He has very minimal low
back pain.  He states it seems to be getting worse and seems to
be associated with some abnormal gait.  He states on a bad day
its about a 9/10 and even on a good day sometimes it can be as
high as 8-9/10.  The episodes are almost daily and are brought on
by things like walking.  He can walk less than one block at which
point he has lateral calf burning and at times notes some slow
shuffling and occasionally falling.  When he is having severe
symptoms he notes his legs to be weak.  He denies any bowel or
bladder abnormalities of late, but has a historic of a chronic
UTI secondary to his benign prostatic hypertrophy.  He has very
little back pain associated with his symptomatology.  He has had
no physical therapy to date and no spinal injections.  He
describes his general health as poor, but when specially asked he
states it is because he his 71 and has a history of hypertension.
 Years ago he stated he was in excellent health.  His weight is
steady at 200 with no significant weight gain or loss.  He
doesn't smoke and drinks socially.  Quit smoking 33 years ago. 
He does not think he will ever be pain free.

Review of Systems:  Reveals that he is a diet controlled diabetic
and he has been for the past couple of years.  He has difficulty
with sleep.  He has a balance problem and also has benign
prostatic hypertrophy leading to chronic urinary tract infection,
for this he takes Cardura.  He has a history of high blood
pressure.  Denies any other cardiovascular abnormality.  No
respiratory malfunction.  He has had surgery for something "in
his colon" he has also had a bypass surgery.  He is on Plavix and
aspirin.

Physical Examination:  Shows that he is solid built, healthy
appearing male.  He is able to toe and heel walk but on the left
side his T band seems to be slightly weak.  Single toe raises
show that the right leg is stronger than the left leg.  He has no
tenderness to his PSIS and he has no Waddell signs.  He has
negative Trendelenburg bilaterally.  Forward flexion allows him
to get to the patella.  Extension is pain free and passive
hyperextension does not reproduce the symptoms.

Motor testing is normal in his lower extremities.  Sensory is
symmetric.  He has negative straight leg raises.  He has no
palpable pulses.  He is hairless in his lower extremities.  He
had no clonus or Babinski and a negative Hoffman's suggesting
that he is not myelopathic despite his "balance abnormality".

He is on multiple meds for his hypertension, for his diabetes,
and for his gastroesophageal reflux.

Personal review of his plain films and a CAT scan indicating
with, show decent residual lumbar lordosis with a stent noted in
his iliac artery on the right.  CT scan shows lumbosacral facet
hypertrophy.

At this point, impression is of spinal stenosis and degenerative
disk disease.  I have asked him to obtain an MRI and return to
see me after that.

Thanks for the referral.





______________________________
Stephen Nichols, M.D.


Dictated By: Stephen Nichols


eScription document:6-0190274 EFFocus



DD: 11/14/54
DT: 11/14/54
DV: 11/14/54



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2155-07-11



July 11, 2155



Name:	Olive, Xavier		

MRN: 26690002



Mr. Olive was seen with Dr. Innis in general neurology clinic on 07/11/55.   Dr. Innis was present for or performed all salient aspects of the history and physical exam and together we discussed with the patient the work-up and treatment plan. 



Return visit.

Mr. Olive is a 71y old RHM, with Idiopathic Parkinson's disease. He was started on Sinemet 25/100mg tid with significant improvement in his balance & gait & rest tremor. However there were still periods of shuffling & stumbling especially going down slope. He also complained of persistant fatigue in his legs. We started him on Amantadine 100mg tid during his last visit. He did not tolerate it well & complained of dizziness especially when he goes out, even with reduced dose of 100mg bid. He has discontinued it since then.

He is tolerating Sinemet well, no hallucinations, on-off phenomenon. He does not notice any wearing off of the effect prior to next dose. No dyskinesias.

No new Neurological symptoms. He still has poor balance but his posture is much improved.

PMHx: 

HTN

Hyperlipidemia

DM type-2

PVD

BPH

H/O colon cancer, s/p partial colectomy

H/O throat surgery in past, does not know the details

Medications at Home:

Sinemet 25/100mg bid.

Simvastatin 10mg QHS

Ranitidine 150mg QHS

Metformin 850mg tid

Lisinopril 2.5mg QD

Gabapentin 100mg bid

Folic acid 1mg QD

Atenolol 25mg QD

Glyburide 2.5mg QD

Bupropion 150mg QD

Ferrous gluconate 325mg TID

Terazosin 4mg QHS

Pyridoxine 50mg QD

Plavix 75mg QD

Allergies: NKDA

Limited physical Exam:

Neuro: 

MS: Alert, oriented, appropriately interactive. Follows all commands. Speech is fluent without paraphasic errors. Voice is hypophonic. Facial expression is flat.

CN II-XII:  Visual fields full to confrontation; PERRLA 3.5 => 3.0; no ptosis; no nystagmus, no hypometric saccades, full EOMI, no restriction of upgaze; sensation on face normal bilaterally, no facial asymmetry; reduced spontaneous blinking of eyes; good smile; good cheek puff; tongue and palate midline; grossly normal hearing; good shoulder shrug and head turn.

Motor:  normal bulk, axial rigidity present. Mild cogwheel rigidity, R>L at rest. No rest tremor. No drift.  Strength 5/5 throughout including: biceps, triceps, brachioradialis, finger flexor and extension, hip, knee and ankle flex and extensions. No bradykinesia.

Sensation:  Decreased to touch, temperature and pin prick bilaterally in feet. Vibration reduced in toes. JP sense normal bilaterally. 

Cerebellar:  Good FNF, rapid alternating movements

Gait/Stance:  Gait is wide based with mild stooped posture, slightly unsteady but no festination noted today. Decreased arm swing noted while walking. Not able to tandem.   Rhomberg negative. Able to rise and sit without assistance.



Assessment and Plan: 71y old RHM, with early idiopathic Parkinson's disease. No evidence of restricted up gaze (PSP), or parkinson-plus syndrome at this time. He had a good response to Sinemet but still has persistent fatigue & periods of festination. Recommend increasing Sinemet to 37.5/150mg tid 7am, 12noon, & 5pm. Wife will give me a call in 2wks to let me know his progress.



Follow up in Neurology clinic in 3mths. Patient & family can contact me in interim with any concerns.



Thank you very much for allowing me to participate in the care of this patient.



Sincerely,



___________________________________

Isabella Edmond, M.D.

Resident in Neurology

Pager #: 98768

CC:

Michael Ulrey MD

24 WOOD ST

SYDNEY, WV 65157



Ximena Keane

46 Marshall Street

Conneaut Lake, WV: 85486





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2157-05-17



			CARDIOLOGY

			

			TRUMBULL MEMORIAL HOSPITAL

			



			Reason for visit:

   Second opinion regarding painful legs with walking at less than 50 yards and also balance disorder.



			Interval History:

   Mr.  Xavier Olive is a 73-year-old gentleman who comes into Trumbull Memorial Vascular Center for a second opinion regarding his lower extremity discomfort and also his progressive difficulty walking and maintaining balance.  His referring physician is Dr.  Ximena Keane, practicing out of Alexandria Clinic.  Mr.  Olive also heard about the TMH VC through TV advertisements.  



He is 73 years old, has history of diabetes starting in 2135, known history of peripheral artery disease with claudication and calf discomfort, for which he has previously seen Dr.  Cain at Alexandria Clinic, and also has been evaluated and treated at the Corcoran District Hospital.  Specifically, he describes having been evaluated by Dr.  Cain and others some three or four years ago, and undergoing at least two procedures, all related to his legs cramping up.  He received prior stenting to his right common iliac artery and his left superficial femoral artery, so far as I can tell.  The stents were placed at Pomeroy Care Center (Big Rapids, AC) and also he had evaluation at the Corcoran District Hospital, and may have had a stenting procedure or revascularization procedure there.  The patient and his wife are somewhat unclear about the dates and locations and times, but he does state that the treatments apparently did not help him at all.  Currently, he has discomfort in both calves when he walks too far or too fast, and this stops him at about 50 yards.  



The issue was complicated by the fact that he has had progressive parkinsonian-type symptoms, walking in a shuffle, tipping forward, and occasionally even falling forward and losing his balance completely.  His legs are rubbery, and he does even realize that he is falling forward when it happens.  It is worse when he is carrying things that weigh anything.  At the same time, his calves do cramp up in a typical fashion consistent with claudication, and he has known peripheral artery disease.  Also feels though his hips sometimes are cramping up.  The patient feels quite disabled by his symptoms, especially as a gentleman who was active and never had physical problems of this nature.  Again, there is some degree of blurring between the parkinsonian symptoms and his claudication, as to which is truly causing his disability.



			Past medical history:

   Diabetes, onset in 2135.  

Parkinsonian-type movement disorder, followed by Dr.  Jeffers and Innis, and for which he was placed on Sinemet, presuming it was due to Parkinson's.  The patient has not improved despite trying the medications.  MRI at AC starting in 2153 has shown apparent central and peripheral atrophy, unchanged.  

Status post vertebrobasilar TIA by report.  

Neuropathy, documented by EMG in 2151 with no spinal stenosis by MRI.  

Cervical spondylosis.  

Tracheal tumor resection in 2128 performed via a suprasternal incision.  

Hypertension.  

Mild renal artery stenosis documented by arteriography in 2153 during one of his peripheral angiograms.



Current Medications:

  lisinopril 2.5 mg QD

 glyburide 2.5 mg QD

 cilostazol 100 mg BID

 terazosin 4 mg QD

 Sinemet 25/100 mg 2 tabs TID

 aspirin 325 mg QD

 pyridoxine 50 mg QD

 atenolol 25 mg QD

 folic acid 1 mg QD

 gabapentin 100 mg BID

 metformin hydrochloride 850 mg TID

 ranitidine HCl 150 mg QHS

 Zocor 10 mg QHS

 Plavix; Dir: Stopped because of ecchymosis and epistaxis -stop



Allergies:

			

No known allergies   



			Family history:

   Noncontributory.  No coronary artery disease or MI.



			Social history:

   He is retried Motor Vehicle Body Repairer.  He used to work at GM.  He lives with his wife, who comes in today with him.  He has three children.  Nondrinker.  He smoked until 30 years ago.



			Review of systems:

   Detailed review of systems was carried out.  It was also reviewed on the patient questionnaire sheet that the patient brought with him.  He does claim to have some dyspnea with exertion as well as intermittent indigestion consistent with GERD.  He has nocturia.  He wears dentures.  No significant weight loss or anorexia.  No visual changes or other neurologic symptoms other than the gait disturbance and neuropathy.  He denies chest discomfort or anything to suggest cardiac ischemia.  Otherwise, review of systems is negative in detail.



Physical examination:

			

-Pulse:   68 and regular.  Afebrile

-BP: 105/55    , obtained by myself.  Equal bilaterally

-General:   Well-developed male in no distress, appears his stated age.  Slightly stooped over, and has a parkinsonian-type affect and appearance

-Skin:   Without rashes

-Heent:   Normal facies, or slightly masked, with normal extraocular motions and reactive pupils

-Neck:   Carotid upstrokes are normal, no bruits.  No JVD

-Chest:   Clear

-Cardiac:   Discloses normal S1 and S2, no S3 or S4, and no murmurs

-Abdomen:   Moderately obese, protuberant, soft, and nontender.  Good bowel sounds, no organomegaly, no enlargement of the aorta.  May be a soft bruit in the midline to deep auscultation

-Extremities:   Femoral pulses are 2+ bilaterally, with soft bruits on both sides.  Below this, no cyanosis or edema (perhaps trace to 1+ edema), and posterior tibial pulses are 1 to 2+.  Dorsalis pedis pulses are not easily palpable.  Good capillary refill

-Neuro:   Gait is disturbed, with slight shuffling and slightly stooped.  His strength is normal, and sensory findings are slightly abnormal with diminished sensation in a stocking-glove distribution.  He does not have any cogwheeling to my examination.  Otherwise, no focal deficits



Procedures:

			

Free text procedures  Exercise ABIs-resting ABI is normal on the right and left at 0.  92 and 1.03, respectively.  The toe brachial index drops to 0.29 on the right side and 0.91 at 1 minute after exercise.  I am not sure what to make of these ABIs since it appears that the actual ankle-brachial indices were not measured following exercise.



			EKG:

    demonstrates normal sinus rhythm or sinus bradycardia at heart rate of 55.  There is normal axis and intervals, with no evidence of prior infraction, and perhaps a slight right ventricular conduction delay.



			Other Data:

   DOB: 11/25/2083.



			Assessment and plan:

   Lower extremity arterial disease (PAD)-the patient clearly has history of PAD with prior interventions on both sides.  Currently, complains of symptoms that sound like claudication, predominantly involving the calves on both sides, right slightly ahead of the left, and I would not be surprised if he has significant focal obstructive disease along the length of his iliac of SFA.  Since his ABIs are well preserved at rest, I suspect he does not have pre-occlusion of the SFA, for example.  On the other hand, he does have diabetes and his ABIs may be falsely elevated.  



His major limitation is due to a combination of the claudication that occurs less than 50 yards and stops him at that point, and the gait disturbance that he has related to his movement disorder, possible Parkinson's disease.  I am not sure that this latter entity has been well enough defined, and I would suggest that we have him see a neurologist here to better ascertain the nature of that disease, and as to whether there is anything better available in the way of treatment.  



1.  As far his peripheral artery disease, it would be extremely helpful to obtain films from AC and/or the CDH, to better define what procedures were actually performed and where stents were placed.  Given that it has been a year or more since his last intervention, it is likely he will need another angiographic study (or MRA/CTA) in order to ascertain the nature of his disease.  



2.  Neurologic disorder-we will refer to a neurologist.  



PLAN: 

1.  Formal exercise ABIs.  

2.  Obtain angiographic studies from AC.  

3.  Followup visit in one month.  

4.  Appointment with Dr.  Ruiz.



Changes to Medications this visit

			

lisinopril 2.5 mg   QD

glyburide 2.5 mg   QD

cilostazol 100 mg   BID

terazosin 4 mg   QD

Sinemet 25/100 mg 2 tabs  TID

aspirin 325 mg   QD

pyridoxine 50 mg   QD

atenolol 25 mg   QD

folic acid 1 mg   QD

gabapentin 100 mg   BID

metformin hydrochloride 850 mg   TID

ranitidine HCl 150 mg   QHS

Zocor 10 mg   QHS

Plavix     Stopped because of ecchymosis and epistaxis - InactivatedCC:

			Outpatient V Chart; Brittany Naylor; Ximena Keane M.D.

			



			Signed electronically by   Jared  Xayasane MD  on  Sep 17, 2157     

		



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2158-06-08




-------------
            Parkinson's Clinic             
Trumbull Memorial Hospital - Corcoran District Hospital    (315) 433-0039 

                                  Office Visit                                  


Chief Complaint:  Increased falling

History of Present Illness:  C/O increased falling. His legs buckling
underneath him. He has occasional dizzyness. Denies angino, or sob. He does not
use a walker. He arrived today in a wheel chair. They both state he leans
forward and the he falls.

Medications:  atenolol 25 mg: 1 tab po qd;  pyridoxine 100 mg: 1 tab po qd; 
Sinemet 25/100: 2 tab po qid, 7:30A, 12, 5, 9P;  Sinemet 25/100: 1.5 tab po
qid;  glyburide 2.5 mg: 1 tab po qd;  Zocor 10 mg: 0.5 tab po qhs;  gabapentin
100 mg: 1 tab po bid;  folic acid 1 mg: 1 tab po qd;  Pletal 100 mg: 1 tab po
bid;  pyridoxine 50 mg: 1 tab po qd;  metformin 850 mg: 1 tab po tid;  ASA 81
mg: 1 tab po qd;  prazosin 4 mg: 1 tab po qd;  Lisinopril 2.5 mg: 1 tab po qd; 
Zantac 150 mg: 1 tab po qhs.

Allergies:   NKDA.

Review of Systems:   The following systems reviews were contributory: endocrine
[pertinent positives:  diabetes mellitus]; cardiovascular [pertinent positives:
 hypertension, occasional light headed ness; pertinent negatives:  chest pain
with exertion, chest pain at rest, dyspnea on exertion, peripheral edema];
gastrointestinal [pertinent positives:  diarrhea] and urinary tract [pertinent
positives:  nocturia, urgency].     The following systems reviews were
noncontributory: general; psychological and musculoskeletal.

General Examination
-------------------------------

6/08/2158 1:31 pm:  In his right arm,  his blood pressure was 100/42 and  his
pulse was 60 per minute  when lying; his blood pressure was 80/40 and  his
pulse was 64 rrr per minute  when sitting.  The orthostatic change was
symptomatic.  He appeared well-nourished and well-groomed.
6/08/2158 1:36 pm:  In his right arm,  his blood pressure was 90/40 when
sitting.

Rating Scales:
UPDRS Subscale III (Motor Examination):  Subscale total score was 22 out of
108.  This subscale was completed while the patient was ON.

Tremor at rest was rated on a 0 to 4 scale (with 0 being absent): 0 in the
face, 0 in the right upper extremity, 0 in the left upper extremity, 0 in the
right lower extremity, 0 in the left lower extremity,.

Action or postural tremor of the hands was rated on a 0 to 4 scale (with 0
being absent): 0 in the right upper extremity, 0 in the left upper extremity,.

Rigidity was rated on a 0 to 4 scale (with 0 being absent): 1 in the right
upper extremity, 1 in the left upper extremity, 1 in the right lower extremity,
1 in the left lower extremity,.

The following movements were rated on a 0 to 4 scale (with 0 being normal): 
    Finger Taps: 1 in the right upper extremity, 1 in the left upper extremity;
    Hand movements: 1 in the right upper extremity, 1 in the left upper
extremity;
    Rapid alternating hand movements: 1 in the right upper extremity, 1 in the
left upper extremity;
    Leg agility: 1 in the right lower extremity, 2 in the left lower extremity.

Each of the following was rated on a 0-4 scale (with 0 being normal):
    Speech:  1 (slight loss of expression, diction and/or volume);
    Facial expression:  1 (minimal hypomimia; could be normal 'pokerface');
    Arising from a chair:  1 (slow or may need more than one attempt);
    Posture:  1 (not quite erect, slightly stooped posture; could be normal for
older person);
    Gait:  2 (walks with difficulty but requires little or no assistance; may
have some festination, short steps, or propulsion);
    Postural stability:  1 (retropulsion, but recovers unaided);
    Body bradykinesia and hypokinesia:  2 (mild degree of slowness & poverty of
movement that is definitely abnormal; alternatively, some reduced amplitude).

Assessment:  
  1.  Parkinson's Disease:  Parkinson with decline in strength and endurance.
It is possible that the added  Sinemet is causing a decrease in his blood
pressure. I made a referral to Mary Darnell PT here at TMH. In addition Dr
Edward Nguyen felt a slight reduction of the Sinemet to 1.5 tab QID may help his
blood pressure with out changing his motor ability. RTC 1 month Dr Edward Nguyen
and 2 months Genevieve Noland, NP


Recommendations:

Medication given:
  Sinemet 25/100: 2 tab po qid.


Medication changes included:
   Stopped:
  pyridoxine 50 mg: 1 tab po qd;

  Sinemet 25/100: 1.5 tab po qid.

   Started:
  6/08/2158 Sinemet 25/100: 1.5 tab po qid.

This patient's history, physical examination, assessment and recommendations
were completed by  Genevieve Noland, NP. 




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>