<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2071-08-08

Reason for Visit	

Mr. Whitehead is here for follow-up of multiple issues.



Problems	  

LOW BACK PAIN	      

he had prolonged discogenic back pain in 1/2070 and could not get appt with NAMG orthopedic/back surgeon and went to Montreal Medical Center.  He underwent L4/5 lamenictomy in 2/2070.  He has persistent right-lower back pain and has seen Dr. Conley.  A myleogram done on 8/5/71 showed degenerative disc disease with moderate spinal stenosis at L4/5.  He will be seeing Dr. Sheehan.  Mr. Whitehead is contemplating surgery as he cannot walk without pain.

Elevated blood sugar	      

BS was 191 in 11/1/69 and was in similar range during his hospitalization in Montreal Medical.  He has been on meds for NIDDM.  He could not tolerate high dose of glucophage and is now seeing endocrine.  His HBA1c was 7.5 in 6/71 on glyburide 5 mg bid and glucophage 500 mg qd.  He has regular optho exam and is on zestoretic.  Little rationale to check for microalbuminuria as he is already on ace-inh.  His lipids are controlled with diet and lipitor.

To see endocrine in 9/71.



hyperlipidemia	      

now on lipitor 40 mg qhs.  He has NIDDM and HTN.  His lipid profile from 4/71 showed a LDL of 103.  LFT were normal.  COntinue med.

HYPERTENSION	      

Now on zestoretic 20/25 qd + atenolol 50 mg qd.  He has significant white coat component.  It is again high at 170/80 in left arm.  His BP reading in hospital for myelogram this week was 130/80.  No change.



h/o PROSTATITIS	      

had recurring prostatitis sx's and saw Dr. Dotson.  Cystoscopy in 1/2070 was normal.  He is on flomax 0.4 mg qd and doing better.  His PSA was 2.9 in 8/69 and 3.2 in 8/70.  To see Dr. Dotson soon.



Neurological symptoms	      

he reports having intolerance to bright lights, tingling in his mid anterior abdomen and chest as well as numbness in his left middle three digits with some neck discomfort.  His MRI of his LS spine done at Montreal Medical in early 2070 evidently showed (by his report) no cord abnormalities.  His sx's sound like left-sided cervical radiculopathy but his visual and abdominal sx's makes me concerned about  systemic demyelinating conditions.  Will check TSH, B12 and have him see Dr. Conley. [08/28/70]



TSH and B12 levels were normal.  His sx's in his eyes and abdomen have essentially resolved.  He still has some cervical radiculopathy syptoms.  He will see Dr. Conley (yet to do so). [01/21/71]



still did not see Dr. Conley.  He now has right neck pain.  His left sided numbness has resolved.  Again referred him to Dr. Conley.  He likely has cervical radiculopathy. [04/09/71]



c-spine MRI ordered by Dr. Conley showed mutliple levels of spondylothis.  





Vital Signs	    

Blood Pressure:	 170/70   

Weight:	 187   Pounds



Physical Exam	  

Chest	

clear

Cor/Cardiac	

s1s2 s4 with s4

Neurological	

He has normal motor strength in his limbs. Normal straight leg raise bilaterally.



Medications	  

MICRONASE (GLYBURIDE)	 5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO BID Start Date: 8/8/71

ATENOLOL	 50MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

ZESTORETIC 20-25 (LISINOPRIL/HYDROCLOROTH...	 20/25 PO QD

Prilosec SA	 20MG PO BIw

LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN)	 40MG PO QHS

GLUCOPHAGE (METFORMIN)	 500MG PO QD  Start Date: 2/19/71

FLOMAX (TAMSULOSIN)	 0.4MG PO QD

ASPIRIN (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)	 81MG PO QD

MVI (MULTIVITAMINS)	 1CAPSULE PO QD



Disposition and Plans	

Follow-up in 12/71.



cc: Dr. Conley





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-04-24

Reason for Visit	

Mr. Whitehead is here for FU of his many issues.





Problems	  

benign prostatic hypertrophy	      

PSA was 2.9 in 8/69 and 3.2 in 8/70 and 3.0 in 2/72.   He has done well on flomax and now sees Dr. Pena.



hyperlipidemia	      

now on lipitor 40 mg qhs.  He has NIDDM and HTN.  His lipid profile from 4/71 showed a LDL of 103.  LFT were normal.  Will check lab  work and continue med.  

Elevated blood sugar	      

BS was 191 in 11/1/69 and was in similar range during his hospitalization in Montreal Medical.  He has been on meds for NIDDM.  He could not tolerate high dose of glucophage and has seen Dr. Lozano in diabetic unit.  His HBA1c was 7.5 in 6/71 and 7.6 in 9/71 on glyburide 5 mg bid and glucophage XR 500 mg qd.   He is on zestoretic.  Little rationale to check for microalbuminuria as he is already on ace-inh.  His lipids are controlled with diet and lipitor.  He has no neuropathic sx's and sees ophtho regularly.  

HYPERTENSION	      

Now on zestoretic 20/25 bid + atenolol 50 mg qd.  He has significant white coat component.  BP is again 145/80 and is lower at home.  Pulse is 70 but it again sped up when he was being examined.



LOW BACK PAIN	      

he had prolonged discogenic back pain in 1/2070 and could not get appt with NAMG orthopedic/back surgeon and went to Montreal Medical Center.  He underwent L4/5 lamenictomy in 2/2070.  He has persistent right-lower back pain and has seen Drs. Conley and Sheehan.  A myleogram done on 8/5/71 showed degenerative disc disease with moderate spinal stenosis at L4/5.  He continues to have chronic low back pain in the right hip and right anterior thigh.  He exercises regularly and has not benefitted from prior epidural injection.  Dr. Sheehan felt that pain may be from some instability vs scar tissue from prior surgery.  Fusion surgery was discussed but Mr. Whitehead is not too keen on it. [12/25/71]



still has back pain but not ready for fusion surgery yet.



Review of Systems	

Otherwise negative.





Vital Signs	    

Pulse:	 70   Regular

Weight:	 189   Pounds

Blood Pressure:	 145/80   Left Arm



Physical Exam	  

Chest	

clear

Cor/Cardiac	

s1s2 s4

Abdomen	

soft and  nontender, no masses or organomegaly, normal bowel sounds

Extremity	

no edema noted, pulses are 1+



Medications	  

MVI (MULTIVITAMINS)	 1CAPSULE PO QD

ASPIRIN (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)	 81MG PO QD

FLOMAX (TAMSULOSIN)	 0.4MG PO QD

LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN)	 40MG PO QHS

ZESTORETIC 20-25 (LISINOPRIL/HYDROCLOROTH...	 20/25 PO QD

GLUCOPHAGE XR (METFORMIN XR)	 500MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Prilosec SA	 20MG PO QD

ATENOLOL	 50MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

MICRONASE (GLYBURIDE)	 5MG 1 Tablet(s) PO BID



Disposition and Plans	

Follow-up in 9/72.  Will contact him with results of lab work.









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2074-03-25

Reason for Visit	

FU of several issues



Problems	  

DVT	      

dx with left calf DVT on 3/20/74 in setting of being sedentary from low back pain.  Had face joint block on 3/09/74.  D-dimer was high and cxr was clear.  No respiratory sx's to suggest pulmonary embolism.  HE is on fragmin bid for 3 more days.  INR was 2.5 on 3/23/74 and he is on 2.5 mg qd.  He will be seeing Internal Medicine on 3/28/74.  Will treat him with coumadin for six months.  He has moderate post-phlebitic pain and is on prn percocets.

Elevated blood sugar	      

BS was 191 in 11/1/69 and was in similar range during his hospitalization in Montreal Medical.  He has been on meds for NIDDM.  His glucophage was stopped as his cr was in the 1.5-1.7 range.   He is now on glyburide 10 mg bid and his sugars are still high with fasting levels in the 180-250 range.  



His HBA1c was 7 in 11/73.  Will transition him to insuline with 25 units NPH sc qhs and he will monitor sugars bid and report back to me.



FU in one month to recheck HBA1c. 

benign prostatic hypertrophy	      

PSA was 2.9 in 8/69 and 3.2 in 8/70 and 3.0 in 2/72.   PSA was checked while in hospital by resident in 3/74 and it was 12.9.



Discussed ramification of this test.  Will favor rechecking his PSA in one month.  Due to recent DVT and his being on coumadin, he would not be amenable to undergo prostate biopsy in the next few weeks.  If PSA remains high, will have him see urology.





Vital Signs	    

Weight:	 183   Pounds

Blood Pressure:	 130/70   Left Arm



Physical Exam	  

Extremity	

minimal swelling in left calf without cords



Medications	  

ASPIRIN (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID)	 81MG PO QD

ATENOLOL	 50MG 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

FLOMAX (TAMSULOSIN)	 0.4MG PO QD

INSULIN NPH HUMAN	 25UNITS SC QHS

LIPITOR (ATORVASTATIN)	 40MG PO QD

MVI (MULTIVITAMINS)	 1CAPSULE PO QD

ZESTORETIC 20-25 (LISINOPRIL/HYDROCLOROTH...	 20/25 PO BID



Disposition and Plans	

FU in one month.  Total visit time was 40 minutes.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-03-18



Freeman Internal Medicine Intern Admission Note


PATIENT:  Whitehead, Aidan D
MRN:  9855218
ADMIT DATE:  3/17/78
ATTENDING:  Bell, Charley
Source: Patient and chart


CC:  Diarrhea
HPI: 1M with DM, HTN, HL, and Parkinson's disease.  In 7/77, he had been treated at NAMG for a left lower lobe PNA with levofloxacin, and developed diarrhea while in the hospital.  After discharge, he continued to have profuse diarrhea, and was treated with IV hydration and metronidazole C. diff infection, first found to be positive on 7/31/77.  Since then he has had multiple episodes of recurrent C. diff.   Most recently, he was admitted to NAMG for treatment of recurrent C. diff in 1/77, with improvement after receiving inpatient vancomycin and flagyl, and discharged to NAMG, where he was for 3 weeks.  He received 21 days of flagyl.  After about two weeks, he noticed a gradual increase in his stool frequency.  Three weeks prior to admission, he began taking 500 mg PO Flagyl q8h, which he had at home.  He felt that his symptoms were improved somewhat on the flagyl.  One week ago, he saw his PCP, where a C. diff stool toxin was negative.   At that point, he stopped the PO flagyl, and shortly afterward his diarrhea again progressively worsened.  Currently he is having 10 BM per day, and he states that they are similar to odor, color, and frequency to his prior C. diff episodes.  He has also had a few days of lower abdominal pain, 2-3/10, with no clear pattern, and noticed a few flecks of blood in his stool 2 days ago on one occasion.   He denies other symptoms including fever/chills, n/v, cp, sob, and dizziness. He reports that when he had taken PO vancomycin in the past, it cost $40 per tablet.


ED:  Afebrile, HR 70s.  Hypertensive to 189/82. He was given 1000 cc NS, 5 mg PO amlodipine, 20 mg PO lisinopril, 500 mg IV flagyl. 


ROS: Otherwise negative in detail. 
PMHx:
Lower back pain
Hypertension
Hyperlipidemia
Elevated blood sugar
Parkinson&#8217;s disease
C. difficile colitis
ALLERGIES: NKDA


MEDICATIONS:


  1. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)   81 MG PO QD
  2. Amlodipine (Norvasc)   5 MG PO QD
  3. Atenolol  100 MG PO QD
  4. Atorvastatin (Lipitor)   20 MG PO QD
  5. Carbidopa/Levodopa 25/100  (Sinemet 25/100 )   1.5 TAB PO TID
  6. Citalopram (Celexa)   20 MG PO QD
  7. Insulin Nph Human  10 UNITS SC QPM BEFORE SUPPER
  8. Insulin Nph Human  5 UNITS SC QAM BEFORE BREAKFAST
  9. Lactobacillus   PO BID
            unit strength:  form: CAPSULE
10. Lisinopril  20 MG PO QD
11. Lorazepam (Ativan)  1 MG PO as directed
            one to two tablets 1-2 hours under tongue prior to MRI and/or injection
12. Omeprazole  20 MG PO QD
            GENERIC OK
13. Tamsulosin (Flomax)   0.4 MG PO QHS


FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory


SOCIAL HISTORY:  Lives with his wife.  Has 2 adult stepchildren, 1 a Web Technician in the area.
Tob: Denies
EtOH: Denies
Drug use: Denies


PHYSICAL EXAM
VITALS:  T 97.9 HR 77 BP 164/70  RR   SpO2 100    
GEN&#8217;L :              Alert, well appearing, NAD.
HEENT:  AT / NC.  EOMI, no nystagmus.  PERRL 6mm -&gt; 4mm bilaterally.  MMM.  2+ carotids without bruits.  No lympadenopathy.
Heart:  RRR, no MRG
LUNG:  CTAB
ABD:  Soft, NT/ND, NABS.  No organomegaly.
EXT: WWP.  2+ L lower extremity edema.  2+ DP PT pulses.
NEURO: A+Ox3.  CN II-XII, speech, language, strength, and sensation intact.
CHEMISTRIES


Chemistry Detail for WHITEHEAD, AIDAN D


Plasma Sodium                    140                       (135-145)      mmol/L
Plasma Potassium                 3.1              L        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L
Plasma Chloride                  102                       (100-108)      mmol/L
Plasma Carbon Dioxide            30.5                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L
Plasma Anion GAP                 8                         (3-15)         mmol/L
Calcium                          8.8                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl
Phosphorus                       2.4              L        (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl
Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L
Plasma Urea Nitrogen             16                        (8-25)         mg/dl
Plasma Creatinine                1.11                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl
eGFR                             &gt;60                                      mL/min/1.73m2
     Abnormal if &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2. If patient is African-American, multiply the
     result by 1.21.
     
Plasma Glucose                   135              H        (70-110)       mg/dl
Total Protein                    7.1                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl
Albumin                          3.8                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl
Globulin                         3.3                       (2.6-4.1)      g/dl
Direct Bilirubin                 0.1                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl
Total Bilirubin                  0.5                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl
Alkaline Phosphatase             94                        (45-115)       U/L
Transaminase-SGPT                19                        (10-55)        U/L
Amylase                          32                        (3-100)        units/L
Transaminase-SGOT                12                        (10-40)        U/L
Lipase                           12               L        (13-60)        U/L


WBC                              10.8                      (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              36.9             L        (41.0-53.0)    %
HGB                              12.9             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl
RBC                              3.96             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm
PLT                              244                       (150-400)      th/cumm
MCV                              93                        (80-100)       fl
MCH                              32.6                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc
MCHC                             35.0                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl
RDW                              14.4                      (11.5-14.5)    %
DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED
Diff Method                      Auto
Poly                             79               H        (40-70)        %
Lymphs                           14               L        (22-44)        %
Monos                            5                         (4-11)         %
EOS                              2                         (0-8)          %
Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %
Absolute Neuts                   8.50             H        (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm
Absolute Lymphs                  1.48                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm
Absolute Monos                   0.54             H        (0.2-0.4)      th/cmm
Absolute EOS                     0.26                      (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm
Absolute Basos                   0.03                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm
Aniso                            None                      (None)
Hypo                             None                      (None)
Macrocytes                       None                      (None)
Microcytes                       None                      (None)


RADIOLOGY:


3/17 KUB.  Study done, radiology read pending.


ECG:  Normal sinus rhythm, rate 84.  Normal axis.  Normal intervals.  No ST segment deviation or T wave inversion. 


ASSESSMENT &amp; PLAN:  81M with recurrent C. diff infections presenting with diarrhea.  Likely he has a recurrent episode of C. diff infection.  


1.  Diarrhea.  
- IV flagyl 500 mg Q8H and PO vancomycin 250 mg Q6H
- stool c. diff toxin
- ID consult re: appropriate management of multiply recurrent C. diff infection
- consider social services consult if ID feels PO vancomycin is the only viable option at this point. 


2. HTN
- HTN improved s/p receiving his home regimen in the ED.
- will replace atenolol with metoprolol while in-patient, up-titrate as needed, starting 37.5mg Q8h


3.  L lower extremity edema.  Patient states he was evaluated at OSH recently and felt to not have a DVT.  Will disuss whether any further workup is neeed with pt&#8217;s PCP in AM.


3.  FEN.  PO diet as tolerated.  RISS / NPH.


4.  PPX.  Lovenox. 






Alexander X. Jenks, MD, PhD
Pager 84261



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>