<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2064-07-26

July 26, 2064





Harry R. Lynn, M.D.

Doraville County Health Center

897 Cider Street

Platteville, HI 79812 



RE:  		Isabelle Y. Quick

ATCH: 		655-75-45



Dear Harry and Yair:



My thanks for your kind referral of the above noted patient with respect to her disabling claudication and of course she is not in a very happy circumstance.  As you know, she is just 52 years of age.  Her cardiovascular risk factors include type 2 diabetes treated with metformin and Glyburide, hypertension, hyperlipidemia and she is a former cigarette smoker but she has not smoked in a year.  She spends a lot of time caring for her partially disabled husband.  She has known and impressive history of peripheral vascular disease.  She has undergone bilateral leg revascularizations.  On the left side initially an iliac stent was tried but in January of 2063 she had a left iliofemoral endarterectomy with angioplasty and in situ above knee left fem-pop bypass graft.  This reconstruction is functioning well, as evidenced by pulse examination and she certainly does not have any major symptoms in the left side.  In April of 2063 she had a right common femoral and external iliac endarterectomy with a right fem-pop bypass graft to the above-knee popliteal artery using transposed greater saphenous veins.  There had previously been a right iliac PTA and stent.  She states that the procedure in the right leg was only transiently of benefit.  By last spring, i.e. a year ago she again had rather limiting claudication.  She says this is now worse over the past several months and she quantifies this as severe calf pain after just a couple of blocks.  Importantly she does not have ischemic rest pain and she has never had tissue loss.  Recently resting ABIs were recorded at 0.46 on the right and 0.8 on the left.  Her continued complaints led to a repeat arteriogram last October documenting a superficial femoral artery occlusion (??? length thereof - she did not bring the films themselves) and a patent albeit small reconstituted above-knee popliteal artery with decent runoff.  Understandably Dr. Adcock was reluctant about recommending further revascularizations.  She has sought an opinion here in this regard.  She has no known coronary artery disease and her general system review is notable for a prior hospitalization in 2061 for severe pancreatitis requiring laparotomy.  On physical examination blood pressure was 140/80.  Pulse was 70 and regular.  Carotid upstroke was normal and there were no major carotid bruits.  She has femoral pulses on both sides and the left fem-pop bypass graft in situ is palpable, as is the left popliteal pulse.  There is no right popliteal nor right foot pulse.  She does have dependent rubor on that right side although there is no tissue breakdown.



This is of course a very unhappy situation.  Further attempts at surgical revascularization in the setting of having both greater saphenous veins harvested and so forth is really not justified for claudication alone since the result can be anticipated to be not very good.  However I am not absolutely ruling this out.  I would suggest the following.  Her risk factor control is decent and she should certainly stay on the Lipitor, aspirin and Plavix.  Since her problem is claudication I would like Yair to institute Pletal at full dosages and give this at least a couple of months before we can say that she has had an adequate trial with question benefit.  She will get the actual arteriogram from the October study to me.  If it seems reasonable and the right superficial femoral artery block is not too long an attempt at percutaneous recanalization could be considered.  I will get back to you after review of the films themselves.  My thanks once again.  With every best wish.



Sincerely,





Daniel W. Iniguez, M.D.



cc:	Yair K. Bennett, M.D., 208 Pheasant Lane, Platteville, HI 79812



DWI/yim





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-09-10

 Date:  9/10/64, 0857 am

Medical Record Number:  6557545, Quick, Isabelle.

Procedure:  The patient is a 52 year old female scheduled for a right femoral popliteal BPG. Surgery is to be performed on 9/17/64, by Dr. Iyer.

Chief Complaint & Present Illness: Patient has history of claudication within past year. She underwent a left ileofemoral  endarterectomy 1/63, and a right  right common femoral and external iliac endarterectomy with right fem-pop 4/63. She denies any relief with any previous procedures. She states she has to stop before walking 1 block due to pain in both legs R>L. Pain resolves with rest. 

Past Medical History: 
1. type 2 diabetes treated with metformin and Glyburide
2. hypertension
3.  hyperlipidemia
4. PVD
5. Chronic pancreatitis

Past Surgical History: 
1. January of 2063 she had a left iliofemoral endarterectomy with angioplasty and in situ above knee left fem-pop bypass graft.
2.  April of 2063 she had a right common femoral and external iliac endarterectomy with a right fem-pop bypass graft to the above-knee popliteal artery using transposed greater saphenous veins
3.  10/09/63, aortogram bilateral lower extremity runoff with a right common runoff
4. Whipple procedure for chronic pancreatitis 2061
Denies problems with general anesthesia

Family History: There is no family history if adverse reactions to general  anesthesia.

Medications: Pre-admission Medication List for QUICK,ISABELLE Y  6557545 (ATCH) 52 F

Last signed by: RICO,HELEN U.,RNC on 09/10/2064 at 09:21

  1. Pioglitazone (Actos)  15 MG PO QAM
  2. Glyburide  1.25 MG PO QAM
  3. Metformin  500 MG PO BID
  4. Clopidogrel (Plavix)  75 MG PO QAM
	dose last taken 09/10/2064
  5. Atorvastatin (Lipitor)  20 MG PO QHS
  6. Atenolol  50 MG PO QAM
  7. Pantoprazole (Protonix)  40 MG PO QAM
  8. Cyproheptadine Hcl  4 MG PO BID
  9. Amitriptyline Hcl  50 MG PO QHS
 10. Therapeutic Multivitamins (Multivitamin Therapeutic)  1 TAB PO QHS
 11. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)  81 MG PO QAM


Allergies: NKDA

Social History:
  Smoking: 1ppd/27 years, quit 2 years ago
  Alcohol use: none
  Substance abuse:none
  Allergen Exposure: (transfusion/pregnancy): none in last 3 months.
  Exercise: walks 20 minutes- 1/2 hour daily
  Occupation: none
  Marital Status: married

Review of Systems:
General: Independent with ADL, well developed, well nourished.

HEENT: History of sinus infections in past.  No history of head injury, glaucoma, cataracts, eye redness, eye/nose/throat pain, earaches, ear infections, nose bleeds, excessive tearing, eye/ear discharge, vision changes (including double vision, spot, specks, or flashing lights), tinnitus, vertigo, motion sickness,  or hearing loss.

Respiratory:  Denies cough sputum, hemoptysis, wheezing, asthma, bronchitis, emphysema, pneumonia,  tuberculosis, COPD, sleep apnea, or pleurisy.

Cardiovascular: History of HTN, hypercholesterolemia. Stress test  9/8/64, shows no evidence for myocardial ischemia, EF 70%.  No history of  rheumatic fever, MI, angina, syncope, palpitations,   edema, dyspnea, chest pain,  orthopnea, or paroxysmal nocturnal dyspnea.

GI: No history of GERD, PUD, bleeding, changes in bowel habits, difficulty swallowing, appetite changes, nausea, vomiting, constipation, diarrhea, abdominal pain, food  intolerance, excessive belching or gas.

Hepatobiliary: History of chronic pancreatitis s/p Whipple. Has taken protonix since surgery. No history of jaundice, hepatitis, or colic.

GU: No history  of CRF, hematuria, obstruction, colic, stones, UTI, polyuria, nocturia, decreased caliber or force of urinary stream, hesitancy, incontinence, or frequency of urination.  

Musculoskeletal:  No history of arthritis, muscle pain, joint pain, stiffness, gout, or limitations with ROM.

Neuro:History of right inner leg numbness.  No history of seizures, stroke,  TIAs, migraine, fainting, weakness, paralysis, tingling, tremors, or other involuntary movements.

Peripheral Vascular: History of bilateral claudication R>L.  No history of DVT, varicosities, cramps, or ulcers.

Endocrine: History of type II diabetes (non insulin dependent) diagnosed 2 years ago. Checks BS regularly usually 150 -160 in am. No history of thyroid problems, heat or cold intolerance, excessive sweating,  excessive thirst    

Heme/Onc:  History of easy bruising. No history of  bleeding, anemia, lymphadenopathy, chemotherapy or radiation.

Psychiatric:  No history of anxiety, panic attacks, depression, or psychosis.  

Skin:  No history of rash, abnormal pigmentation, pruritis, lumps, or sores.   

Physical Exam:

     SaO2: 100
     Resp: 16
     Temp:96.4
     Ht: 65in
     Wt: 132.6
     BP: 140/82
     AP: 80
    
     General:  Well developed, thin
     
     HEENT:  Normocephalic, cranium intact without depressions. no icterus, thyroid non-palpable, neck veins flat, carotids palpable without bruits, no swelling, lumps, masses, tenderness, or visible pulsations. Movement symmetrical with full  range of motion. Frontal and maxillary  sinuses non-tender.

     Airway:  Mallampatti Class I

     Teeth:  missing lower molars

     Chest:  Breath sounds  clear.  No abnormal retraction  or impairment of lower interspaces during inspiration.  Symmetrical, even respiratory movement.

     Heart: Regular rhythm, normal rate, no murmurs, rubs or gallops, S1=S2.

     Abdomen:  Soft, non-tender, with scars, no distention, normal bowel sounds, no organomegaly or palpable masses.  Contour round, symmetrical,  without  lesions, striae, or dilated veins.  No visible peristalsis or pulsations.

     GU/Rectal:  No CVA tenderness or hernias. LMP - 10 years ago, postmenopausal

     Lymphatics:  No lymphadenopathy

     Peripheral Vascular:  No edema, varicosities. Spider veins
       Carotids- 2+
       Radials- 2+
       Femorals- 2+
       Anterior tibial- not palpable
       Dorsalis pedis- not palpable

    Neuro:         
      CNII:  Visual Acuity:  Able to read newspaper and see distances with glasses.  Visual fields full to confrontation.
      CN III, IV, and VI, : EOMs intact, parallel, no ptosis.  PERRLA&A.
      CN V & VII: Intact. Temporal and masseter muscle contractions equal  in symmetry and strength.  Equal sensation to sharp stimulus to forehead, cheek, and jaws.
      CNVIII: Intact. No loss of hearing to either ear via whisper test.
      CN IX, X:  Intact.  Voice without hoarseness or nasal quality.  Uvula midline.
      CN XI:  Intact. Equal strength and contraction to trapezii and sternomastoid muscle.
      CN XII:  Intact.  Tongue movement symmetrical without deviations or protrusions.  No atrophy or fasciculations as tongue lies on floor of mouth.
      Mental Status:  Oriented x 3.  Appearance neat and clean.  Pt pleasant and cooperative for exam.  Able to answer questions appropriately and clearly. Able to articulate own thoughts and questions logically and coherently.
      Coordination:  Gait - slow, steady
      Strength and Tone: Tone and strength intact to upper and lower extremities.
      Sensory: Intact.
      Reflexes: not tested
  Extremities: No clubbing  or cyanosis.
  Musculoskeletal:  Normal range of motion.
  Skin: Warm and dry to touch. Turgor intact.  Color consistent.  No lesions, rashes, or edema.

Assessment:  ASA physical status: III. Patient is a 52 year old female scheduled for a right femoral popliteal BPG. Patient has history of PVD, HTN type II diabetes, hyperlipidemia, chronic pancreatitis s/p Whipple, and no problems with general anesthesia. Have enclosed stress test  from Hospital Lafayette, Platteville, Hi. Anesthesia consent form and tentative plans reviewed and explained. Patient will sign anesthesia consent form day of surgery.


Plan:  Proposed anesthetic: general, epidural
          Monitors: standard, arterial line
          Pain Management:  IVPCA/epidural
          Autologous Blood:  none
          Premedication: none 
          Usual Medications: Pre-admission Medication List for QUICK,ISABELLE Y  6557545 (ATCH) 52 F

Last signed by: RICO,HELEN U.,RNC on 09/10/2064 at 09:21

  1. Pioglitazone (Actos)  15 MG PO QAM
  2. Glyburide  1.25 MG PO QAM
  3. Metformin  500 MG PO BID
  4. Clopidogrel (Plavix)  75 MG PO QAM
	dose last taken 09/10/2064
  5. Atorvastatin (Lipitor)  20 MG PO QHS
  6. Atenolol  50 MG PO QAM
  7. Pantoprazole (Protonix)  40 MG PO QAM
  8. Cyproheptadine Hcl  4 MG PO BID
  9. Amitriptyline Hcl  50 MG PO QHS
 10. Therapeutic Multivitamins (Multivitamin Therapeutic)  1 TAB PO QHS
 11. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)  81 MG PO QAM
          Medications to be held on day of surgery: <>
          Diabetic Medications: <>
          NSAIDS: Avoid for three days prior to surgery
          Aspirin:  Avoid for one week prior to surgery.
          NPO: <>

Ancillary Studies: <>




__________________________________________________________________
Helen Rico, MSN, APRN-BC, FNP




___________________________________________________________________




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2065-08-02



 



















Vascular Surgery Admission Note



Patient Name:  Quick, Isabelle

MRN:  6557545

Date and Time: 8/02/65 2:40PM

Attending: Dr. Iyer

Fellow: Dr. Wade

Junior Resident: Dr. Joyce



cc: thrombosed R fem-pop BPG; increasing rest pain in R leg



HPI:  The patient is a 53 year old woman with a past medical history of diabetes, HTN, and PVD s/p L fem-pop BPG with in-situ vein 2063, R fem to AK pop BPG with GSV 2063, R fem-BK pop BPG with propatent graft 9/17/64, and multiple attempts at angiographic intervention who presents with worsening rest pain in the R leg X 1 month.  



Immediately following her 2nd R fem-pop BPG in 9/2064, she felt well and without significant LE pain.  Over the past month, however, the patient reports that she has had progressive pain in her R foot and leg, which wakes her up from sleep almost every night.  She can walk less than one block without disabling claudication which improves with rest.  She also has noticed discoloration of her R foot, along with numbness and paresthesias, which have been progressive over the same time period.  



She denies all symptoms other than RLE pain and claudication as described.  Specifically, she denies chest pain, shortness of breath, dizziness, headache, and fevers/chills.  She reports that her left leg is occasionally painful, although it has been tolerable in comparison to her R leg.  She has been taking aspirin and plavix regularly, but has not taken coumadin for 2 days (last dose 7/31/65).  



She last underwent arterial LENIs on 7/17/65, which demonstrated critical ischemia in her R leg and a thrombosed R fem-pop BPG (see below for official report).  She is admitted for elective revascularization of her R leg.  



PMH:  

DM II

HTN

PVD

Hyperlipidemia

Chronic Pancreatitis



PSH: 

9/20/64: angio/PTA L proximal fem-pop bpg and L SFA

9/17/64: R CFA endarterectomy; R fem-BK pop BPG w/ propatent graft

10/2063, angio w/ BLE runoff

4/2063: R CFA and EIA endarterectomy; R fem-pop BPG to AK pop using transposed greater saphenous veins

1/2063: L iliofemoral endarterectomy with PTA &amp; in situ vein AK L fem-pop bpg

2061: Whipple procedure for chronic pancreatitis



Meds: 

  1. Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin)  325 MG PO 

  2. Atenolol  50 MG PO QD

  3. Clopidogrel (Plavix)  75 MG PO QD

  4. Cyproheptadine Hcl  4 MG PO BID

  5. Glipizide  2.5 MG PO QD

  6. Metformin  500 MG PO TID

  7. Multivitamins  1 TAB PO QD

  8. Pantoprazole (Protonix)  40 MG PO QD

  9. Pioglitazone (Actos)  30 MG PO QD


10. Simvastatin  20 MG PO QD


11. Warfarin Sodium (Coumadin)  5 MG PO QD



ALL:  NKDA



Social: 

Previous smoker, quit approximately 3 years ago

Denies EtOH



ROS: as above; otherwise negative with exception of presenting complaints



PE: 

VS: T 98.2 
HR 80  BP 129/65  RR 18  96%  RA

NAD, comfortable-appearing middle-aged woman, NAD

Neck: no bruits appreciated

CV: RRR, no m/r/g

Pulm: CTA bilaterally, no wheezes or crackles

Abd: soft, non tender, non distended; R vertical paramedian scar, well-healed

Ext: 

LLE warm, with well healed femoral and L knee incisions, normal color and sensation

R foot cool, with small amount of discoloration present distal to mid-metatarsals; sensation grossly intact although subjectively less than L foot

Pulses: 

     Rad Fem   Pop   DP                                    PT

R     2+            1+        NP       weak Doppler signal     no doppler signal          

L     2+ 2+        NP       strong Doppler signal    + Doppler signal



PVRs demonstrate pulsatile signals in LLE; waveforms are flat in RLE



EKG: normal sinus rhythm, no ischemic changes



Labs: 

Plasma Sodium                    139                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.9              H        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  101                       (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            28.7                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 9                         (3-15)         mmol/L

Phosphorus                       3.7                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.6                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             9                         (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                0.94                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             &gt;60                                      mL/min/1.73m2

Plasma Glucose                   289              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



WBC                              8.1                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              39.3                      (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              13.8                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              4.31                      (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              281                       (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              91                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              31.9                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             35.0                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              15.6             H        (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               15.8             H        (10.3-13.2)    sec

PT-INR                           1.4

APTT                             28.3                      (22.1-34.0)    sec



UA-Color                         Yellow                    (YELLOW)

UA-Turbidity                     Clear                     (CLEAR)

UA-Glucose                       2+                        (NEG)

UA-Bili                          NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Ketones                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Specific Gravity              1.005                     (1.001-1.035)

UA-Occult Blood                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-pH                            5.0                       (5.0-9.0)

UA-Albumin                       NEGATIVE                 
(NEG)

UA-Urobilinogen                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Nitrite                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-WBC Screen                    NEGATIVE                  (NEG)



Imaging: 

CXR 8/02: clear lungs



Arterial LENI (7/17/65):

1. Critical peripheral arterial disease in the right leg at rest.

2. Disease is located in the aorto-iliac, femoral and popliteal segments on the right side.

3. Mild peripheral arterial disease in the left leg at rest.

4. Disease is located in the aorto-iliac and tibial/peroneal segments on the left side.

5. There has been a significant drop in the ankle/brachial index in the right  leg since the last exam, from 0.77 to 0.26.

6. Occlusion of the right femoral to popliteal PTFE bypass graft.



Assessment:  

The patient is a 53 year old woman with a past medical history of diabetes, HTN, and PVD s/p L fem-pop BPG with in-situ vein 2063, R fem to AK pop BPG with GSV 2063, R fem-BK pop BPG with propatent graft 9/17/64, and multiple attempts at angiographic intervention who presents with worsening rest pain in the R leg X 1 month.  



Given her progressive pain, worsening PVRs, and thrombosed BPG, she will go to the OR 8/03 for fem-pop thrombectomy, possible fem-fem bypass graft, and angiogram with possible angioplasty/stent.



Plan: 

-Admit to Vascular Surgery, attending Dr. Iyer

-Labs, EKG, CXR

-Hold Coumadin, continue aspirin/plavix, begin heparin drip at 500 Units/hr, with sliding scale and target PTT 40-60

-Hold heparin drip on call to OR

-NPO p midnight, IV fluids

-Consent obtained and placed in chart



Case discussed with Dr. David Wade, Vascular Fellow











Francis D. Link

ATCH Surgery

Pager 40232 




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>