<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2062-09-18

Tammy Umphrey

PDI Unit No: 094-22-07



CLEVELAND PUBLIC INSTITUTE



Internal Medicine





Date: September 18, 2062



MEDICATIONS: Glynase 3 mg q.a.m., Glucophage 500 mg q.p.m., Ultram 50 mg b.i.d., Synthroid ? dose q.d., Premarin 0.625 mg q.d., Monopril 40 mg q.d., Dyazide 1 q.d., Neurontin 300 mg q.i.d., glucosamine chondroitin, vitamin E 400 IU q.d., Citracal 2 q.d., Centrum Silver 1 q.d. 



(1)	Diabetes mellitus: Went on cruise.  Ate frequently but watched portions.  Apparently patient checks blood sugars between 3:00 and 3:00 and when she has shakiness.  She was under the impression that after lunch she had to fast for three hours prior to checking sugar, at which point notes low blood sugars in the 50's to 70's with shakiness, for which she takes a handful of raisins.  Generally eats breakfast at 8:30, lunch 12:00 or 12:30, supper at 5:30.  Snacks in the evening, always apple and yogurt.  Most recently, additionally popcorn and saltine crackers, occasional pretzels.  After takes raisins, shakiness of hypoglycemic symptoms resolve.  While on cruise, patient found that she could actually walk more than she thought she could.  Since she has been home, has not been walking routinely.

(2)	HTN: No chest pain, shortness of breath or palpitations.  

(3)	Back pain/lower extremity pain.  States taking glucosamine chondroitin.  Over the last two or three months, feels that it is helping with decreased pain.  Also has been seen at physical therapy again.  Feels that this is helping.



PE:	Weight down 2 pounds!.  Blood pressure, right arm: 126/68.  Chest is clear.  Cardiac: Regular rhythm at 66, no murmur or gallop.  



A/P:	(1)	Diabetes mellitus: Somewhat better control with mildly elevated morning sugars.  Have asked patient to decrease popcorn and/or crackers at h.s.  Have advised patient to take small handful of raisins prior to onset of hypoglycemic symptoms advised around 2:00 to 2:30 p.m.  Have encouraged patient to continue to walk daily.  Continue current treatment.

(2)	Back pain/lower extremity pain: Some improvement with PT and increased med.  Continue for now.

(3)	HTN: At goal.  Return to clinic at the beginning of November to Dr. Ullom to resume care.

Kathleen L Kuhn, RNC, ANP

KL/utz/orton







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2063-12-13




NAME:     Umphrey, Tammy 
MRN:       0942207

The patient is here as a walk-in.  Her spouse is present.

Patient says she is status post a fall this past Monday at home.  Says that she seems
to have lost her balance while opening a door at home.  Denies prodromal
symptoms including shortness of breath, dizziness, or palpitations.  There was no
loss of consciousness.  Patient was seen in the emergency room that day for trauma
to the head.  Had a negative CT of her head and had an x-ray of her pelvis, as she
complained of some hip pain.  Both studies were negative.  Patient was then sent
home with Roxicet.  Patient was seen in the walk-in clinic at CPI yesterday, after
noticing a swollen tongue and some difficulty swallowing.  Patient was immediately
told to stop both her Roxicet and Monopril and was treated for angioedema with
Zantac and Claritin.  Today patient has no further throat tightness or tongue
swelling.  She is, however, uncomfortable continuing the Effexor for unclear
reasons and wants to stop it.

Patient is also complaining of severe low back pain, which she says has persisted
since her fall on Monday.  Did not have an x-ray of the area.  Says it is very painful
to sit.  Roxicet was not helping.  She is off her Ultram as well.

PHYSICAL EXAM:  WD/overweight female in NAD.  Vital signs as per LMR,
WNL.  Weight 213 pounds. 

Lungs - clear bilateral breath sounds.  Cor - RRR, S1, S2, without murmur or S3
noted.  Back - slightly bent gait.  Tenderness over lower sacrum.  No asymmetry or
obvious deformity.  

X-ray of sacrum 12/13/63 - could not see fracture as per my reading.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  

(1)  Angioedema.  Agree that most likely culprits are Roxicet since it was started
     only two days ago, and ACE inhibitors which have been associated with
     angioedema.  Currently on Lopressor and Dyazide, patient's blood pressure
     is WNL.  So will follow for now.

(2)  Low back pain.  Reviewed the possibility of a coccygeal fracture for which
     treatment would not be any different than pain management and a donut
     pillow.  Patient was given a prescription for the pillow.  She was told to look
     out for signs of nerve compression and to go to the ER if she experienced
     any perianal numbness or incontinence.  Will notify patient by phone if x-ray
     shows a fracture. 

(3)  Depression.  Did not feel I was able to speak freely in front of the patient's
     spouse.  Had been put on the Effexor by Dr. Zeman.  Advised patient to let
     her psychiatrist know that we are tapering her off of the Effexor.  Will take
     25 mg q.o.d. for the next week.  

(4)  Pain control.  Will switch from Vicodin to Vicodin ES 1 q. 6 as needed. 
     Knows to go to ER if experiences any symptoms consistent with angioedema.

Return to clinic in approximately one month.



Susan Ullom, M.D.

SU/utz/rankin
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2064-08-28

Patient Name: UMPHREY, FRANKIE;  MRN: 0942207
Dictated on: 08/28/2064 by WHITNEY EASTERLING, M.D. 

 
CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Falling and low back pain.  
 
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 66 year old, right-handed female whose past medical history is significant for status post laminectomy at L3 to L5 in January of 2061.  The patient was in her usual state of health with some residual weakness from the stenosis and occasional buckling of her knees without loss of consciousness until 12/01 when she fell backwards.  There was no obvious leg buckling.  She said she just came off balance without loss of consciousness or dizziness or preceding lightheadedness.  Since then she has had several falls always when she is moving.   
MEDICATIONS:  Her medications have included in the past Motrin 800 t.i.d. without significant effect on her low back pain.  Ultram q.i.d. was beneficial.  Neurontin 300 q.i.d. which was also beneficial without side effect and chondroitin sulfate which she feels has been very helpful without side effect.   
REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She has bilateral dysesthesias, left sciatica to her ankle.  She has had weight loss without fevers, chills or night sweat.  She has had no retinopathy and she has a history of reflux and otherwise her cardiovascular, pulmonary, GI/GU and musculoskeletal review of systems are unremarkable.   
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Spinal stenosis with a laminectomy at L3, 4 and 5 in January of 2061.  She has had left knee arthroscopy.  She had mild spinal stenosis at T12 to L1, severe at L3/4 and 4/5 with bilateral foraminal disease.  She has had a ten year history of diabetes.  She has hypertension and hypothyroidism.   
MEDICATIONS:  Synthroid, Premarin, glynase, glucophage, metoprolol and Effexor.  
 
ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.  
 
SOCIAL HISTORY:  She is married.  No history of tobacco or alcohol.  
 
FAMILY HISTORY:  Positive for coronary artery disease, breast cancer and diabetes.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  She is a well-appearing, well-nourished, 66 year old female.  Her mental state examination is normal.  Cranial nerves II through XII are intact.  Motor strength is significant for full strength in the upper extremities as well as the lower extremities.  Sensation is intact to all modalities with bilateral lower extremity dysesthesia reported subjectively.  DTR's are symmetric with downgoing toes bilaterally.  Coordination is intact with no axial or appendicular ataxia.   
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  This is a 66 year old right-handed female with history of spinal stenosis status post decompression who has a history of falls.  We will obtain an MRI of her lumbosacral to evaluate that area for any recurrent pathology or new changes.  For her radicular pain will increase her Neurontin 400 q.i.d.  We would like to obtain EMG with nerve conduction studies of the lower extremities to evaluate possible need for reoperation.  The patient will return to clinic after these studies.  The patient was seen and evaluated and management was discussed with the attending.  
 
 
_______________________________ 
Whitney Easterling, M.D.  
 
 
 
DD:08/28/2064 
DT:08/29/2064 
DT:2617      :6415
 




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2066-08-27

      Team A Intern Admit Note

Patient Name: Tammy Umphrey

MR#  0942207

Date of Admission:  8/26/66

Attending: Yoel Pollard

PCP:  Susan Ullom



CC/ID:  70 yo woman with significant disability following cerebral aneurysm rupture 1/ 66, admitted with likely UTI and question of altered mental status



HPI:  (As summarized from ED admit note and computer notes, pt is not able to give history and family is not present.)  Ms. Umphrey is somewhat cognitively and expressively impaired following rupture of a cerebral aneurysm 1/ 66; she was required sub-occipital craniotomy, clot evacuation, and placement for a VP shunt.  She was transferred to Kingsley County Clinic 2/66, and was d/c'd 5/31/66. Discharge summary indicates that her baseline at that time included being able to follow 1 step commands part of the time and some attempts at communication.  She gets nutrition and medication through a G-tube at this point, and has had an indwelling foley catheter.

	Computer notes suggest that prior to August 5, the indwelling foley catheter had been removed. However, the patient's constant incontinence and difficulty keeping a decubitus ulcer dry, the notes suggest that the foley was replaced 8/5/66.  8/09/66 Ms. Umphrey was taken to the emergency room; the symptoms she was having at that time are not clear. U/A was suggestive of a UTI, and she was treated with a 3-day course of levofloxacin. There is no record of her foley catheter being changed at that time, and urine cultures were not sent.  Telephone notes from 8/23 suggest that Ms. Umphrey had yeast infection and foley blockage;  8/25 the VNA checked a U/A at home; results were consistent with a UTI.  Her husband reports that she has also been more somnolent and    less herself    over the last few days. She was sent to the PDI ED for further evaluation.

	In the ED, repeat U/A was consistent with UTI; urine culture grew abundant staph aureus. She was given a dose of levofloxacin 500mg and transferred to the floor.



PMH: (Per chart- pt unable to provide history)

1.    S/P  aneurysm rupture, suboccipital craniotomy for microsurgical trapping and   clipping

of distal PICA aneurysm, and evacuation of  4th ventricular clot.

2.	S/P  right VP shunt placement.

3.	?decubitus ulcer

3.    History of  hypothyroidism.

4.    Type II diabetes mellitus.

5.    HTN

6.    Gastritis

7.    OA in hips bilaterally



Medications:

Glyburide 2.5 mg qd

Prozac 30mg qd

Prevacid 30mg qd

Synthroid 137 mg qd

Cozaar 25mg qd

Ritalin 20mg 8am and 1pm

Lipitor 10mg qhs

MVI

ASA 81mg qd

Colace 100mg tid



Allergies:  finosopril, percocet, erythromycin



SH:  	Lives with husband, who sounds like he is primary caregiver. Has VNA come into home to help with care.

	Tob:	unknown

	EtOH:  	unknown

	Illicits: unknown



FH:	unknown



Exam:  	VS:  T=  98.6 HR= 80 BP= 129/75 RR= 20	SaO2= 94% on room air

General:  No acute distress. Sleepy, but easily arousable.

HEENT: PER 3 to 2 bilaterally. Slight crusting over eyelids bilaterally. Anicteric sclera, no conjunctival injection. EOMI.  Continuous purposeful tongue movements. Dry mucous membranes, but pt breathes solely through mouth.

Skin:	Telangiectasias over face and chin.

Neck:  	Supple.  Neck plethoric; difficult to assess JVD. Carotids 2+ bilaterally, no bruits.  No thyromegaly, no cervical adenopathy.

Chest: 	upper airway sounds, otherwise CTA bilat anteriorly.

CVS:  	Difficult to distinguish over upper airway sounds.

Abd:  	Obese. Soft, non-distended. Does not appear to be tender.

Extr:  	no clubbing or edema bilaterally.

Neuro: Sleeping but arousable, follows simple commands, but not able to answer questions. Good hand squeeze bilaterally. DTRs difficult to elicit in arms, 2+ in patellae bilaterally.



DATA

Chemistry:	



Plasma Sodium                    126              L        (135-145)        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.0                       (3.4-4.8)        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  89               L        (100-108)        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            27.1                      (23.0-31.9)      mmol/L

Calcium                          10.1                      (8.5-10.5)       mg/dl

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             14                        (8-25)           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                0.6                       (0.6-1.5)        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose                   101                       (70-110)         mg/dl



Heme:	

WBC                              11.5             H        (4.5-11.0)       th/cmm

HCT                              38.2                      (36.0-46.0)      %

HGB                              13.5                      (12.0-16.0)      gm/dl

RBC                              4.53                      (4.00-5.20)      mil/cmm

PLT                              474              H        (150-350)        th/cumm

MCV                              84                        (80-100)         fl

MCH                              29.9                      (26.0-34.0)      pg/rbc

MCHC                             35.4                      (31.0-37.0)      g/dl

RDW                              15.8             H        (11.5-14.5)      %

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED

Diff Method

     Automated with manual review

Poly                             81               H        (40-70)          %

Lymphs                           11               L        (22-44)          %

Monos                            5                         (4-11)           %

EOS                              3                         (0-8)            %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)            %



Urinalysis:  



UA-Color                         Yellow                    (YELLOW)

UA-Turbidity                     SLIGHT                    (CLEAR)

UA-Specific Gravity              1.010                     (1.005-1.035)

UA-pH                            7.5                       (5.0-8.5)

UA-WBC Screen                    3+                        (NEG)

UA-Nitrite                       POSITIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Albumin                       Trace                     (NEG)

UA-Glucose                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Ketones                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Urobilinogen                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Bili                          NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Occult Blood                  Trace                     (NEG)

UA-SED-WBC                       20-50                                      /hpf

UA-SED-RBC                       0-2                                        /hpf

UA-SED-Bacteria                  Many                                       /hpf

UA-SED-Bladder Cells             Few                                        /hpf

UA-SED-Amorphous Crystals        Many                                       /hpf



Microbiology:





CXR:	The findings are consistent with pulmonary venous hypertension with possible early interstitial edema.



Head CT:  1. No significant change compared to prior CT Brain-04/18/2066.

	No change in ventricle size.   No acute infarct; although, this is

	better assessed with MR with diffusion.

	2.  Patchy low attenuation areas in the centrum semiovale

	bilaterally which are more prominent now and most likely are due

	to chronic microangiopathic changes in this agroup.



EKG:	Normal sinus rhythm, normal axis, normal intervals. Flattened T-waves, but not changed from prior exam. No evidence of acute ischemia.



Impression:  70 yo woman with compromised baseline neurologic function, admitted with complicated UTI and possible change in mental status.



Mental status changes: given likely undertreated UTI 8/09/66, pt likely has recurrent complicated UTI and may have some mental status alterations from this source. Important to rule out VP-shunt complication as cause of mental status chage, but CT appears unchanged from 4/66. Hyponatremia may also be contributing somewhat  to mental status changes.

-will treat UTI and pursue possibility of urosepsis with blood cultures

-will check TSH and am cortisol which could also contribute to mental status changes, particularly given pts history of hypothyroidism

UTI

-likely UTI- tx

-will send blood cultures to assess for sepsis from urinary source

-unclear if staph aureus is true urinary pathogen, but will treat with vancomycin until sensitivities come back, then treat with appropriate antibiotic

-treat with levoquin for complicated UTI while awaiting final microbiology data

-change foley now

-resend u/a and culture after 1-2 days of antibiotics

Hyponatremia- may be contributing to any change in mental status

-volume status very difficult to assess- if hypovolemic, likely hypovolemic hyponatremia. If euvolemic, likely SIADH, which could be caused by neurologic process, pain, or infection

-given difficulty assessing volume status, will send urine for sodium and osm. If low sodium high osm, likely hypovolemic. If higher sodium, more likely SIADH.

DM

-will switch patient to ISS for now to assess in-hospital insulin requirements

Hypothyroidism- continue levothyroxine at home dose, checking TSH

GI/FEN- ranitidine BID, glucerna tube feeds per KCC discharge summary

HTN-continue home medications

wound care consult requested for report of decubitus ulcer





_________________________________

Wendy Randolph MD

#61504





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2067-02-12

 



teaM B Intern Admit Note 



Pt:Umphrey,Tammy

MR#:	0942207

Date of Admission: 2/11/67



Attending: PCP Dr. Baird (Cleveland Public Institute)

Source: Chart and Pt.'s husband - Pt is non-verbal



HPI : 70yo F PMH of DM, CHF, bullous pemphigoid and HTN, s/p intracranial aneurysm rupture 1/66 , s/p VP shunt placement. Pt. is minimally responsive at baseline, cared for at home by her husband with the assistence of VNA. She is s/p suprapubic catheter placement by IR on 2/4/2067. She was discharged from PDI on 2/09/2067 after an admission for occlusion of her superpublic catheter. She represents to the ED today after her husband, who is the primary care giver noted on the morning of admit that the catheter was not draining, but the pt. was incont. Of urine. He attempted to flush the catheter and was unable to. VNA was called and also attempted to flush the catheter. The VNA nurse noted that it was possible to instill water, but not possible to draw any back. VNA contacted the pts. PCP and IR, who placed the catheter on her previous admit , and the pt. was brought to the ED. 





PMH:   

1. s/p IC aneurysm rupture 1/66

2. Bullous pemphigoid -biopsy proven 2/67

3. DM2

4. HTN

5. gastritis

6. UTI

7. s/p G tube placement

8. SIADH

9. Aspiration PNA - To complete course of Cefpodoxime/Ceftriaxonew 2/16





Meds:  

Asa (CHILDRENS) 81MG PO QD 

Mvi ELIXIR (MULTIVITAMIN SOLUTION) 5 ML PO QD 

Colace (DOCUSATE SODIUM) 100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO TID 

Synthroid (LEVOTHYROXINE SODIUM) 137MCG TABLET PO QD 

Fluoxetine HCL 20MG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s) PO QD 

Prevacid (LANSOPRAZOLE) 30MG SUSPDR REC JTUBE QD 

Cozaar (LOSARTAN) 25 MG (25MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Ritalin (METHYLPHENIDATE HCL) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Ascorbic ACID 1000 MG (500MG/5ML SYRUP take 10 ML) PO BID 

Glyburide 2.5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Cefpodoxime 200 mg bid x 4 more days





Allergies: 

Fosinopril Sodium - Angiodema, tongue swelling, 

PERCOCET - Angiodema, 

Erythromycins - SOB

levaquin - Rash 



  



SH:  	Pt. cared for at home by husband with VNA. Minimally responsive at baseline. 

	 

	



ROS:  Bullous lesion , worst along left flank. 



Exam:  	

	VS: BP 118/74 P 80 T 97.0 RR 18 98% RA  

              GEN: awake, responds to voice.

HEENT: PERRLA, supple, no LAD

Lungs:  CTAB - anterior

Cor:  	RRR, no mumurs, rubs, gallops

Abd:   	Soft non-tender. BS +

Extr:  	 Scattered bullae on b/l lower extremities. NO decbus. PPP.

              Neuro:  . Opens eyes to voice, some rigidity upper and lower extremities. 

              GU:  Superpubic tube in place, site clean with min. erythema, no discharge,

              Scant drainage in bag. Foley in place draining clear urine. 



Labs:  



Hematology Detail for UMPHREY, TAMMY U



   PDI  RANDOM         12-Feb-2067 00:27  Accession# 8859J84563



Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units



UA-Color                         Yellow                    (YELLOW)

UA-Turbidity                     Clear                     (CLEAR)

UA-Glucose                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Bili                          NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Ketones                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Specific Gravity              1.020                     (1.001-1.035)

UA-Occult Blood                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-pH                            5.5                       (5.0-9.0)

UA-Albumin                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Urobilinogen                  NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-Nitrite                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

UA-WBC Screen                    2+                        (NEG)

UA-SED-RBC                       0-2                       (0-2)          /hpf

UA-SED-WBC                       20-50                     (0-2)          /hpf

UA-SED-Bacteria                  Few                       (NEG)          /hpf

Hyaline Cast                     5-10                      (0-5)          /lpf

Squamous Cells                   Few                       (NEG)          /hpf





             	          



	 







_____________________________________________________________________________________



A/P:  70 year old woman s/p IC aneurysm rupture, now with minimally responsive state, presents with occluded superpublic cathere. 



1)	GU - Foley placed in ED. Will send UA/Culture. Contact IR for revision of tube given 2nd admission this month for occlusion.

2)	ID - completing course of cefpodoxime for aspiration pna

3)	F/E/N - Nocturnal tube feeds, as per home program

4)	HTN Cozaar, as per home regimen

5)	ENDO - RISS, cont. glyburide. 

6)	Prophy - Nexium, fragmin

        









_______________________________

G. George Vetter, MD 

Pager # 05967      



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>