<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2067-08-15


Neuro
30 Caitlyn Circle                                      HEATH, HANNAH
Prestonsburg, MS 54151                                      91156456
535-022-8716                                           08/15/67


CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Stroke.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 72-year-old right-handed
woman with a history of hypertension, diabetes, and
hypercholesterolemia who was admitted to the Neurology Service on
06/18/2067 with right-arm weakness and difficulty speaking.  She
presented to the Emergency Room 5.5 hours after last seeming
normal.  Her initial NI stroke scale was 11.  She was admitted to
the Neurology Service for a stroke workup.  Her imaging studies
showed a left MCA infarct involving the left corona radiata, head
of the caudate basal ganglia, and an MI cutoff on the CTA and MRA
in addition to a left ICA occlusion.  She was taken to angiogram
for interventional neuroradiology.  She had an angiogram. 
Radiology felt they were unable to access the
cause and no intervention was attempted and the patient was
admitted to the Neuro ICU for blood pressure monitoring and
hypertensive therapy.  She remained stable anti-coagulated on
heparin.  During the hospital stay, she spontaneously converted
to rapid ventricular rate atrial fibrillation, which was felt to
be the likely source of her stroke and as such was planned to
remain anti-coagulated.  She was discharged to rehab and
subsequently went home from rehab on 08/04/2067.  At home, she
had been noted to have elevations in blood pressure but has been
feeling O.K.  VNA sees her once a week.  At rehab, for unclear
reasons, her warfarin was discontinued and in speaking to the
discharging physician from the Tracy Medical Clinic, this was
done for a question of vaginal bleeding although the patient is
unaware of any such problems.  She continues to get PT and
occupational therapy twice per week and complains that her memory
remains poor.  According to the family member and her daughter
who are here interpreting for her at Clinic today, she continues
to have right-sided weakness, although significantly improved and
decreased verbal output although her daughter seemed to be able
to communicate well with her.  Since her discharge, she has not
had any new episodes of numbness, weakness, headaches, or visual
changes.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  She denies any fevers, chills, weight loss,
chest pain, shortness of breath, palpitations, leg cramps,
claudication, dyspnea on exertion, cough, wheezing, hemoptysis,
heartburn, abdominal pain, hematemesis, nausea, vomiting,
diarrhea, melena, dysuria, changes in bowel or bladder habits,
rashes, arthralgias, myalgias, polyuria, polydypsia, breathing,
or bleeding problems.  Review of neurological systems as above.  

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Hypertension, diabetes, and elevated
cholesterol.

MEDICATIONS:  Metoprolol, Zoloft, Zocor, and Captopril.

ALLERGIES:  She has no known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  The patient lives in Castle Rock with her son. 
No history of tobacco or alcohol.

FAMILY HISTORY:  A sister had a stroke.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her blood pressure was 150/80, her heart
rate was 70, respiratory rate of 12.  General:  Pleasant woman in
no acute distress.  HEENT:  Atraumatic, normocephalic, sclera
anicteric, and oropharynx is clear.  There is no thyromegaly. 
Neck:  Supple, no bruits, with 2+ carotids.  Heart:  Regular rate
and rhythm.  Lungs:  Clear to auscultation.  Abdomen:  Has good
bowel sounds, soft, nontender, no hepatosplenomegaly. 
Extremities:  No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  Skin:  No rashes
or ulcers.  Neurological exam (conducted via her daughter and the
interpreter):  She is alert and oriented.  She is attentive.  She
is non-fluent with really minimal verbal output.  She has
decreased naming and decreased comprehension.  She does not have
any neglect or apraxia.  Registration is 3/4.  Short-term memory
is 0/4 in 5 minutes.  Pupils are 3 and reactive to 2 millimeters.
 Fundi are normal.  Extraocular movements are intact with
nystagmus.  Visual fields are full to confrontation.  She has a
right facial droop.  Facial sensation is intact.  Hearing is
normal.  Motor exam:  There is increased muscle tone on the right
arm and leg.  She has strength on the left is normal.  On the
right, her strength is at least 4/5 in all muscle groups on the
left on the neck, except for about 3/5 in the distal arm.  She
reports decreased pinprick and temperature on the right arm. 
There is no ataxia on the left.  Gait is slow, walks with a cane,
and so conducts the right leg.  Her reflexes are brisker on the
right at about 3 and she has a right plantar extensor response.  

IMAGING DATA:  Initial head CT on 06/18/2067 did not show any
acute stroke or hemorrhage.  On the CT, there was a question of a
left MI cutoff.  CT angiogram also showed a distal left ICA
stenosis with minimal distal interflow.  MRI of the brain showed
a left MCA infarction involving the left corona radiata, head of
the caudate basal ganglia.  She has had mild to moderate chronic
small vessel ischemic changes on her MRI.  Echo showed a normal
EF of 55% without any clot, no PFO.  

IMPRESSION:  This is a 73-year-old woman with significant
vascular risk factors, including paroxysmal atrial fibrillation
with a left ICA MCA clot resulting in a left MCA territory
infarct.  On exam, she has residual aphasia involving both
comprehension and fluency; and a moderate right hemiparesis.  It
is unclear to me why the warfarin was discontinued but given her
stroke and the documentation of paroxysmal atrial fibrillation
during her hospital stay, I think that she would benefit from
anti-coagulation therapy.  I have asked her to get a follow up
PCP evaluation at the OCH to determine if indeed there are
any contraindications to anti-coagulation.  If there are no such
contraindications, she should restart on warfarin.  In addition,
her blood pressure is still not well controlled and I would ask
her to increase her Captopril to 12.5 mg t.i.d. and to maintain a
blood pressure diary.  

RECOMMENDATIONS:
1.  Continue anti-hypertensive and increase Captopril to 12.5 mg
t.i.d.
2.  Blood pressure diary for next clinic appointment.
3.  Continue risk factor modification with the management of
blood pressure, diabetes, and hypercholesterol as she is doing.
4.  PCP evaluation for question of bleeding problem during rehab
stay and resumption of warfarin if there are no contraindications
per the PCP.
5.  Continue physical therapy and occupation therapy for gait
training and language rehab.
6.  Return to clinic in 6 months or sooner if there are any new
problems.

More than 50% of this clinic visit was spent on patient education
and counseling.





______________________________
Jordan Namari Akers, MD, PHD


Dictated By: Jordan Namari Akers


eScription document:7-1410500 VSSten Tel



DD: 09/16/67
DT: 09/16/67
DV: 09/16/67



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2069-05-27

May 27, 2069



Chad Norwood, MD





Re: Hannah Heath

OCH #: 91156456





Dear Dr. Norwood,

 

I had the pleasure of seeing your patient, Hannah Heath, for consultation in the Vascular dept at the OCH.  As you know she is a 72 year-old woman with prior stroke. I will review his medical history for our records.



HPI: This is a 72-year-old right-handed woman with a history of hypertension, diabetes, and hypercholesterolemia and PAF with a prior stroke (2067) who subsequently was admitted to the OCH again for SDH with supratherapeutic INR in 2068. She has a prolonged hospital course as well as rehab stay and now returns having made significant recovery.  She is here with her family who is translating.  She ambulates with walker, but does well over short distances without it.  She communicates well with eth family and is able to feed and dress herself.  She has an aid for bathing three ties per week. She has not needed the PEG tube in the past 6 months and is eager to have it removed. She has not had any new episodes of weakness, numbness, visual or language changes.



ROS: 

Denies fevers, chills, chest pain, SOB, palpitations, leg cramps, claudication, DOE, cough, wheezing, hemoptysis, heartburn, abdominal pain, hematemesis, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, melena, dysuria, changes in bowl or bladder habits, rashes, arthralgia or myalgias, polyuria, polydipsia, bruising or bleeding problems.  Review of neurological system as above.



PMH: 

Hypertension 

Diabetes

Elevated cholesterol.

Stroke 

SDH



MEDS:

Lipitor 10mg qd

Protonix 40mg qd

Diltiazem 60mg qd

Metoprolol 50mg qd



ALL: 

NKDA



SHX: 

Married and lives with her husband. She has a very supportive family. 



FHX: 

Sister with seizures.



PHYSICAL EXAM:

BP: 120/60 		HR:70		RR: 14

GEN: Pleasant woman in NAD.

HEENT. AT/NC.  Sclera anicteric.  OP is clear.  There is no thyromegaly. 

NECK: Supple. No LAD.  Carotids are 2+ without bruits. 

HEART: RRR, no m/r/g

LUNGS: CTA

ABD: +BS. Soft.  PEG site inspected.  Slightly red margin. No significant drainage at this time. No odor.

EXT: No c/c/e

SKIN: No rashes or ulcers. 

NEURO: Cognitive testing limited secondary to language barrier. Alert and oriented.  Interacting well in Spanish with  her family members. No neglect or apraxias. Pupils  3->2mm.  Fundi are normal. EOMI without nystagmus. Right field cut.  Right facial. Tongue and palate are midline. Facial sensation is intact. Hearing is normal.  On motor exam there is normal muscle bulk, but increased tone right more than left. She has a mild right HP. There is a RPD. On sensory exam, pp/temp/vib are symmetric.  There is distal gradient loss of sensation.  There is no loss of cortical sensation.  There is mild ataxia with FNF and HTS and RAM on the right. Gait is normal based and uses a walker. Reflexes are symmetric. Plantar responses are extensor.



DATA:

MRI 2068: old right MCA stroke

CT 2068: SDH



ASSESSMENT/ RECOMMENDATIONS:

72 year-old woman with vascular risk factors including atrial fibrillation and prior stroke  with a subsequent SDH with super elevated INR who now returns for follow-up.  She has had a significant recovery. Our goal should now be secondary stroke prevention and risk factor modification.  Given that her bleed was a SDH and in the setting of elevated INR, it is worth considering restarting warfarin,  until then, she should at least be on ASA and I have communicated this with them. She should continue with her BP and cholesterol treatment as well. She is eager to remove the PEG and I will refer her to Dr Queen for this. RTC as needed. Call with questions.







More than 50% of this visit was spent on patient education and counseling.

Thank you for allowing me to participate in the care of your patient.  I will continue to follow along with you.







Sincerely,





Jordan N. Akers, M.D., Ph.D.

Department of Neurology 

Stroke Division

Orange City Hospital

Prestonsburg, MS 54151



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2070-08-28

 CC: 

follow-up



HPI: 

75-year-old woman with a history of hypertension, diabetes, and hypercholesterolemia and PAF with a prior stroke (2067) who subsequently was admitted to the OCH again for SDH with supratherapeutic INR in 2068. She has a prolonged hospital course as well as rehab stay and now returns having made significant recovery.  Her PEG was pulled-out in 06/69.  She is here with her husband who is translating from columbian.  



I saw her about 1 month a go with hiperpigmentation of the skin, which I felt was melasma, and treated her with hydroquinone TP, sun blocking cream and avoidance of sun exposure.  Both she and her husband say tha her hiperpigmentation has decreased significantly.   



At present she has no symptoms and says she feels well.  She ambulates with a cane, and she is planning a 6-month trip to Columbia next October with her husband.  



She denies any other symptoms: constipation, polydypsia, polyuria, excessive fatigue, weakness 

Denies fevers, chills, CP, SOB, n/v. GI/GU complaints.



PMH: 

Hypertension 

Diabetes

Elevated cholesterol.

Stroke 

SDH



MEDS



Medications (updated 8/28/70)

LISINOPRIL 10 MG (30MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  

ATORVASTATIN 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  

DILTIAZEM 60 MG (60MG TABLET take 1) PO QID  

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO BID  

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  





ALL: 

NKDA



SHX: 

Originally from Columbia. Married and lives with her husband. She has a very supportive family. 



FHX: 

Sister with seizures.



PHYSICAL EXAM:

BP: 155/75 		HR:75		

GEN: Pleasant woman in NAD. Amiling, in a wheelchair. Interactve, appropriate reponses.

HEENT. AT/NC.  Sclera anicteric.  OP is clear.  There is no thyromegaly. 

NECK: Supple. No LAD.  Carotids are 2+ without bruits. 

HEART: RRR, no m/r/g

LUNGS: CTA

SKIN: Hyperpigmented skin in face, symmetric distribution, affecting more densely more cephalad areas of her face. The only area which is spaired is the nasolabial region.  





ASSESSMENT/ RECOMMENDATIONS:

No evidence of acute illness.  



Other problems:

1) HTN: on lisinopril 10 mg po qd, and diltiazem.  Her BP today is slihtly elevated at 150/75.  I will increase her lisinorpil dose. to 30 mg po qd.  Her las BMP was unremarkable.  

2) DM: last A1C was 7.1 in 07/70.  She controlls her DM with diet. Urine microabuminuria, UA are pending.

3) Lipids: will re-check. On lipitor 10 mg po qd.

5) F/u with me after they return from Columbia







_____________________________________________

David Timothy Howard Baldwin, M.D.



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



Discussed with Dr. Timothy Howard Baldwin. Agree with assessment and plan as above.





_____________________________________________

Caleb N. Womack, M.D.,M.P.H. CC: 

follow-up



HPI: 

75-year-old woman with a history of hypertension, diabetes, and hypercholesterolemia and PAF with a prior stroke (2067) who subsequently was admitted to the OCH again for SDH with supratherapeutic INR in 2068. She has a prolonged hospital course as well as rehab stay and now returns having made significant recovery.  Her PEG was pulled-out in 06/69.  She is here with her husband who is translating from Columbian.  



I saw her about 1 month a go with hiperpigmentation of the skin, which I felt was melasma, and treated her with hydroquinone TP, sun blocking cream and avoidance of sun exposure.  Both she and her husband say tha her hiperpigmentation has decreased significantly.   



At present she has no symptoms and says she feels well.  She ambulates with a cane, and she is planning a 6-month trip to Columbia next October with her husband.  



She denies any other symptoms: constipation, polydypsia, polyuria, excessive fatigue, weakness 

Denies fevers, chills, CP, SOB, n/v. GI/GU complaints.



PMH: 

Hypertension 

Diabetes

Elevated cholesterol.

Stroke 

SDH



MEDS



Medications (updated 8/28/70)

LISINOPRIL 10 MG (30MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  

ATORVASTATIN 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  

DILTIAZEM 60 MG (60MG TABLET take 1) PO QID  

Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO BID  

Lasix (FUROSEMIDE) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QD  





ALL: 

NKDA



SHX: 

Originally from Columbia. Married and lives with her husband. She has a very supportive family. 



FHX: 

Sister with seizures.



PHYSICAL EXAM:

BP: 155/75 		HR:75		

GEN: Pleasant woman in NAD. Amiling, in a wheelchair. Interactve, appropriate reponses.

HEENT. AT/NC.  Sclera anicteric.  OP is clear.  There is no thyromegaly. 

NECK: Supple. No LAD.  Carotids are 2+ without bruits. 

HEART: RRR, no m/r/g

LUNGS: CTA

SKIN: Hyperpigmented skin in face, symmetric distribution, affecting more densely more cephalad areas of her face. The only area which is spaired is the nasolabial region.  





ASSESSMENT/ RECOMMENDATIONS:

No evidence of acute illness.  



Other problems:

1) HTN: on lisinopril 10 mg po qd, and diltiazem.  Her BP today is slihtly elevated at 150/75.  I will increase her lisinorpil dose. to 30 mg po qd.  Her las BMP was unremarkable.  

2) DM: last A1C was 7.1 in 07/70.  She controlls her DM with diet. Urine microabuminuria, UA are pending.

3) Lipids: will re-check. On lipitor 10 mg po qd.

5) F/u with me after they return from Columbian







_____________________________________________

David Timothy Howard Baldwin, M.D.



========================== Preceptor's Note ==========================



Discussed with Dr. Timothy Howard Baldwin. Agree with assessment and plan as above.





_____________________________________________

Caleb N. Womack, M.D.,M.P.H.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-03-01

EDVISIT^91156456^HEATH, HANNAH^03/01/72^YEAGER, CHRISTOPHER

I saw this patient with Dr. Rosalia West.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient. 

Please see the resident's note for further details.

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Altered mental status.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 76-year-old female

with history of prior strokes, hypertension, diabetes, and

paroxysmal atrial fibrillation, who presents with altered mental

status.  As per report, the patient has not been acting like

herself and not communicating or speaking like herself.  The

patient was in her usual state of health until a few days ago

where she started to develop a cough as well as some chills.  The

patient's family members state that the patient has not been out

of bed and has been unwilling to eat.  The patient's family

members state that the patient is not acting like her usual self.

 The patient's family members deny noting the patient complaining

of any nausea, vomiting, chest pain or shortness of breath.  The

patient was actually taken to clinic yesterday because the

patient was starting to speak less.  The patient was seen clinic

and was thought to be depressed.  The patient has a known history

of a facial droop.  The patient was incontinent of urine today.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  The patient's vital signs reveal the

following:  Temperature was 102.8, heart rate 110-160 beats per

minute, respiratory rate 20, blood pressure is 144/110, and

oxygen saturation was 95% on room air.  The patient's oxygen

saturation was interpreted as borderline low.  General:  No acute

distress, multiple family members at bedside.  HEENT:  The

patient's head was normocephalic and atraumatic, no scalp

hematomas.  Pupils were equal, round, and reactive to light. 

Mucous membranes were somewhat dry, right facial droop noted, no

drooling.  Neck:  Supple, no JVD, no carotid bruits appreciated. 

There was no meningismus.  Respiratory:  Poor cooperation with

exam.  Fair aeration, no focal rhonchi, rales, or wheezes, no

increased work of breathing or use of accessory muscles was

noted.  Cardiovascular:  Irregularly irregular, tachycardic,

unable to appreciate any gross murmurs, rubs, or gallops.  GI: 

Abdomen:  Soft, no rebound or guarding, prior well-healed prior

G-tube scar noted.  Rectal exam deferred.  GU exam:  The patient

was incontinent of urine.  Skin:  Warm and dry.  No rash or

lesions were noted.  Back:  The patient did not have any

costovertebral angle tenderness.  There is no midline thoracic,

lumbar, or sacral spine tenderness to palpation.  Extremities: 

Warm and well perfused, no clubbing, cyanosis or asymmetrical

lower extremity edema was noted.  There were no palpable cords. 

Neuro:  The patient was alert, the patient was a verbal.  The

patient grossly moved all 4 extremities with fair strength.  The

patient responded to touch appropriately.  The patient was unable

to cooperate with cranial nerve examination.

INITIAL IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  The patient is a 76-year-old female

with history of prior stroke, hypertension, diabetes, and

paroxysmal atrial fibrillation, who presents with altered mental

status and urinary incontinence.  Differential diagnosis at this

time includes infectious versus a metabolic abnormality.  The

patient has no new deficits on neuro exam as per the family and

as per review of prior notes.  Repeat stroke is certainly on the

differential, however, I have a lower suspicion then for a

metabolic or infectious etiology.  The patient will need to have

a large workup including laboratory studies, urine studies, Foley

catheter, portable chest x-ray, and repeat noncontrast head CT

scan.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  Upon arrival to the Emergency

Department, the patient had history and physical exam performed. 

The patient was noted to be in atrial fibrillation with rapid

ventricular response.  The patient's 12-lead EKG revealed a rate

of 166 beats per minute, atrial fibrillation with rapid

ventricular response, stable T-wave inversions noted over the

lateral leads as well as over the precordial leads.  No definite

ST segment abnormalities were noted.  The patient then had a

portable chest x-ray and as per report, the patient's portable

chest x-ray did not reveal any acute cardiopulmonary process or

findings.  The patient did have a noncontrast head CT scan and

the patient's noncontrast head CT scan was notable for some

right-sided edema.  The patient will have this followed up with

an MRI of the brain.  The patient's laboratory studies were

notable for sodium of 131 and potassium of 5.2.  The patient's

lactic acid was 1.7.  The patient's white blood cell count was

not elevated.  The patient was not anemic.  The patient's

urinalysis was consistent with infection.  The patient's first

set of cardiac markers were negative.  The patient's coagulation

studies were normal.  The patient was treated with ceftriaxone

for her urinary tract infection.  The patient could possibly have

urosepsis given her fever and tachycardia.  Urine sepsis is my

leading diagnosis at this time.  The patient's right-sided edema

is certainly concerning, however, I do not feel that the patient

will need to be admitted to Neurology at this time.  The patient

will be admitted to medicine for presumed urosepsis.  The patient

will need to be admitted to a monitor bed.  The patient's blood

pressure is normal, and as such, I do not feel that the patient

needs an intensive care unit bed.  In terms the patient's atrial

fibrillation with rapid ventricular response, the patient was

given metoprolol IV.  The patient was not given any oral

medications secondary to her possible stroke.  The patient was

given rectal Tylenol as well as rectal Kayexalate for her

elevated potassium at 5.2.

PRIMARY DIAGNOSES:

1.  Urosepsis.

2.  Atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response.

3.  Hyponatremia.

4.  Hyperkalemia.

DISPOSITION:  The patient was admitted to the Medicine and to a

monitor bed.

CONDITION AT THE TIME OF DISPOSITION:  Stable, but guarded.

______________________________

YEAGER, CHRISTOPHER M.D.

D: 03/01/72

T: 03/01/72

Dictated By: YEAGER, CHRISTOPHER

eScription document:4-2135677 IFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="not met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="not met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>