<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2092-08-16

EDVISIT^06129040^MACK, ROSE^08/16/92^GRAHAM, ANGELA

This patient's visit was shared with PA, Quiring.  I also

personally interviewed and examined this patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  This is a 50-year-old female with

past medical history of type 1 diabetes, peripheral vascular

disease, and hypothyroidism who presents for evaluation of an

infected left heel ulcer.  The patient is status post bypass

grafting in her lower extremities and skin grafting of a

nonhealing ulcer on her right heel.  Since that time, she has

developed a chronic nonhealing ulcer on the left heel, which has

been followed closely by VNA.  Today, she was seen by her VNA who

was very concerned about redness and swelling of her left foot

with redness that extended underneath the plantar surface of the

foot and over the dorsal surface and concern for infection of

this ulcer.  The patient has minimal sensation in the left foot. 

She states sometimes she can feel a pressure sensation.  She does

have some pain when she tries to weightbear, has not noted any

fevers, has noted some chills and states that her fingerstick

earlier today was elevated.  She denies any abdominal pain,

nausea, or vomiting.  She does note that her foot does appear to

be somewhat slightly more swollen but has not noticed redness up

until today.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Positive for hypothyroidism, type 1

diabetes, and peripheral vascular disease with a nonhealing

diabetic foot ulcers.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  She is status post femoral bypass

grafting, thyroidectomy, skin grafting for nonhealing wounds, and

right foot debridement in the past.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  She smoked in the past, does not drink.  She

lives with family, is followed by a VNA, and is not working.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Reviewed and is also positive for diabetes.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  All other systems reviewed and otherwise

negative except per the HPI.

MEDICATIONS:  Insulin.

ALLERGIES:  She has an allergy to codeine, aspirin, erythromycin,

oxycodone, and sulfa.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her temperature is 98.6, her pulse 105,

respirations 16, blood pressure 117/70, and O2 saturations are

100% on room air.  The patient is awake, alert, frail, and thin

female.  She is in no respiratory distress.  Her head examination

is normocephalic and atraumatic.  Her conjunctivae are slightly

pale.  She has moist mucous membranes.  The airway is patent. 

Her neck is supple with full range of motion without any pain. 

The trachea is midline.  Her lungs are clear to auscultation

bilaterally with equal breath sounds.  No respiratory distress,

no accessory muscle use, and no chest wall tenderness.  Her

cardiac examination is tachycardic and regular at about 100 with

a 3/6 systolic murmur.  Her abdomen is nondistended, soft, and

nontender.  No guarding and no peritoneal signs.  Her skin is

remarkable for healing superficial ulcers on the right heel.  On

the left heel, she has a superficial ulcer with a dark eschar,

which is approximately 4 x 4 cm in diameter.  There is no

purulent discharge around the area; however, the skin of the left

foot is fairly violaceous and warm on the plantar surface of the

foot surrounding the ulcer extending up the lateral aspect of the

foot to the anterior aspect of the left ankle was demarcated in

the Emergency Department.  There is no other break in the skin

visualized.  Her back is nontender with full range of motion. 

Extremities are remarkable for lower extremity atrophy.  She does

have 1+ edema of both feet.  She has minimal sensation on

palpation of her feet with no obvious tenderness on palpation

over her left foot.  Her pulses are trace.  She is alert and

oriented x3, has a depressed affect.  See the PA note for

remainder of the details of the physical examination.

EMERGENCY DEPARTMENT COURSE:  The patient had IV access

initiated.  Laboratory studies were sent including blood

cultures.  She was started on IV antibiotics, vancomycin, and

gentamicin and was consulted to Vascular Surgery.  Her feet

remained elevated.  She had a plain x-ray performed of her foot,

which showed no obvious evidence of osteomyelitis and no

subcutaneous gas.  Her laboratory studies are remarkable for

hyperglycemia and she was started on IV fluids.

DISPOSITION:  She is admitted to Surgery.

DIAGNOSIS:  Left foot, nonhealing ulcer with left foot

cellulitis, and peripheral vascular disease.

See the note for details.

______________________________

GRAHAM, ANGELA M.D.

D: 08/16/92

T: 08/16/92

Dictated By: GRAHAM, ANGELA

eScription document:3-3296461 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-10-26

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.GCC Team A Infectious Disease Consultation


Patient: Mack, Rose C (06129040, 63I)
ID Fellow: Amanda Qualls
ID Attending: Craig Faulkner
Referring Physician: Dr. Kevin Katz
Date of Consult: 10/26/2092


Reason for Consult: DM, chronic R and L. foot ulcerations; L. foot ulceration with surrounding erythema, pain


HPI: 50F w/longstanding type I DM with retinopathy, nephropathy, autonomic and peripheral neuropathy, recent development of L. heel and forefoot ulcers, here with a few days of pain, erythema, and swelling around her L. forefoot ulcer. She has an extremely complicated history of R and now L. foot infections and ulcerations, in setting of here severe neuropathy and DM. She originally sustained a R. 5th metatarsal fracture in 2083, with poor union, and subsequent fracture of her 2nd &#8211; 4th metatarsals. She developed a chronic ulcerated callus over her R. lateral metatarsal heads, with underlying osteomyelitis&#8212;this did not improve despite multiple courses of antibiotics. She underwent I+D of her R. foot ulceration in 12/89, OR cultures grew P. aeruginosa. In 3/90, she underwent debridement of her chronic R. lateral plantar ulceration and skin grafting. In 6/90, she underwent deep debridement of her ongoing 5th metatarsal osteomyelitis, along with excision of her 5th metatarsal&#8212;bone cultures grew MSSA. She did well until 2/92, when she underwent R. ankle revision for an equinovarus deformity of her R. hindfoot (calcaneal osteotomy, lateral translation, dorsiflexion first metatarsal osteotomy, and Achilles lengthening). She subsequently developed a R. heel ulceration, and in 4/92, underwent debridement of this ulceration, removal of a screw, and placement of a vacuum sponge. Her wound continued to heal poorly, and she underwent R. SFA to posterior tibial bypass grafting. In 7/92, she underwent debridement of her R. heel wound and placement of a full thickness skin graft, which has taken well; she feels that her R. heel has been healing nicely. During her long hospitalization in 4/92, she started developing L. heel and L. forefoot ulcerations. She attributes the heel ulcerations to chronic pressure from her position in bed, and the forefoot ulcerations to the boots that were used to relieve her heel pressure, which apparently abraded her forefoot chronically. These ulcerations continued to worsen over the next few months, and she presented with cellulitis of this area in 8/92. She received vancomycin, levofloxacin, flagyl initially, then augmentin, with persistent poor healing of her wounds. On 9/10, she underwent operative debridement of her L. plantar heel ulcer&#8212;she was found to have extensive necrotic yellow-brown tissue underlying her L. heel eschar, which was extensively debrided; she received a course of linezolid postoperatively. She had an angiogram on 9/12, which showed no significant flow limiting lesions in her LLE, and good flow through her prior R. SFA to posterior tibial bypas graft. She feels that her wounds have been healing fairly well recently; she feels that her R. heel is almost completely healed, and that her L. heel ulcer is smaller than it was previously. Her L. forefoot ulcer is also more shallow than it was in the past. Over the past 2-3 days, she developed fairly acute swelling, erythema, and pain around her forefoot ulcer, with erythema spreading to the dorsal surface of her foot. She was seen in vascular surgery clinic, and was admitted for antibiotics and further debridement. She has a chronic &#8216;fast heartbeat,&#8217; denies any systemic symptoms (no fevers, chills, sweats, notable weight changes), headaches, sinus symptoms, sore throat, cough, shortness of breath, chest pain, nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, diarrhea, blood in her bowel movements, dysuria, frequency, LE edema, rashes, myalgias, or new arthralgias. She feels that her foot erythema has improved significantly overnight with vancomycin.


PMH:

poorly controlled type I DM since age 12&#8212;complicated by diabetic retinopathy s/p bilateral vitrectomies for retinal hemorrhage, nephropathy, peripheral neuropathy, autonomic nephropathy (gastroparesis)&#8212;on an insulin pump
chronic foot ulcerations, initially R, now L, requiring numerous antibiotic courses and operative interventions:

2083: R. 5th metatarsal fracture in 2083, poor union, subsequent fracture of the remainder of her R. metarsals
chronic ulcerated callus over R. lateral metatarsal heads, with underlying osteomyelitis, no improvement despite multiple courses of antibiotics
12/89: I+D of R. foot ulceration&#8212;cultures grew P. aeruginosa
3/90: debridement of chronic R. lateral plantar ulceration and skin grafting
6/90: deep debridement of her 5th metatarsal osteomyelitis, excision of her 5th metatarsal&#8212;cultures grew MSSA
2/92: calcaneal osteotomy, lateral translation, dorsiflexion first metatarsal osteotomy, and Achilles lengthening for equinovarus deformity of her R. hindfoot
4/92: subsequent development of R. heel ulceration, s/p debridement of her ulceration, removal of a screw, vacuum sponge placement
4/92: R. SFA to posterior tibial bypass grafting
7/92: debridement of her R. heel wound and full thickness skin graft (12 x 5cm)
9/92: development of L. heel and forefoot ulcerations at rehabilitation, with debridement of her L. plantar heel ulcer on 9/10&#8212;found to have extensive necrotic yellow-brown tissue underlying her eschar
PICC-associated RUE DVT 7/92, on coumadin
s/p L. ankle fracture in 2083
R. foot RSD s/p multiple R. lumbar sympathetic blocks
s/p R. carpal tunnel surgery
hypothyroidism
iron deficiency anemia
depression&#8212;inpatient admission 2090 with suicidal ideations
s/p subtotal thyroidectomy 2073
s/p breast lumpectomy 2078&#8212;has missed her follow-up mammogram appointments due to her foot issues
2088 colonoscopy with &#8216;precancerous polyp&#8217;&#8212;needs repeat evaluation


Home Medications:

insulin pump
Acetaminophen650 MG PO Q6H prn Pain,Headache
Calcium Carbonate 1250 Mg (500 Mg Elem Ca)   1 TAB PO TID
Clonazepam0.5 MG PO BID
Clonazepam0.25 MG PO QD prn Insomnia,Anxiety
Clotrimazole 1% Cream   TOPICAL TP BID prn Itching
Desipramine Hcl175 MG PO HS
Docusate Sodium (Colace)100 MG PO BID
Folic Acid1 MG PO QD
Haloperidol    1 MG PO QHS
Hydromorphone Hcl (Dilaudid)4 MG PO Q4H prn
Levothyroxine Sodium250 MCG PO QD
Omeprazole40 MG PO QD
Sennosides Liquid2 TSP PO QHS
Therapeutic Multivitamins (Multivitamin Therapeutic)1 TAB PO QD
Trazodone200 MG PO QHS
Warfarin Sodium5 MG PO QPM


Inpatient Medications:
Antibiotics:
-vancomycin 1g IV bid (10/25-)
Immunosuppressants: none
Others: home medications, SC heparin, novolog sliding scale q6hrs


Allergies:
&#183;         ASA&#224;asthma
&#183;         erythromycin&#224;severe nausea, syncope
&#183;         sulfa&#224;rash, nausea
&#183;         IV contrast&#224;nausea, has tolerated LE angiogram recently without problems


SocHx:
-was walking with a cane; more recently, has been using a wheelchair; still non-weight bearing on her L. foot, but has been working with physical therapy
-lives in Girard with her parents, sister
-Tob: smoked 30 years, rolled her own cigarettes; quit 8 years ago
-EtOH: none recently
-IVDU: no IVDU; used marijuana in the past


FamHx: sister&#8212;gestational DM


ROS: negative in detail except as described above in HPI.


Exam: Tm 99.2Tc 97.4   HR 96-122BP 120-136/50-72RR 16O2 sat 99-100% RA
Gen: thin, pale, chronically ill appearing woman in NAD
HEENT: clear oropharynx without thrush, ulcerations; few cracked teeth, no significant cervical/supraclavicular lymphadenopathy, few L. axillary nodes
Pulm: lungs clear
CV: tachycardic, regular, II/VI SEM
Abd: soft, NT, +normal BS, no HSM
Extr: warm, no edema, 1+ PT pulses bilaterally; R. heel ulcer/skin graft site healing well, minimal drainage; L. heel ulcer fairly shallow, 2cm in diameter, 3cm L. forefoot ulcer with necrotic material at base, some drainage, minimal surrounding erythema
Skin: no rashes, no nail changes


Labs: (10/26)
WBC                              4.35                      (4-10)         K/uL
 LYMP %                          16.2             *        (18-41)        %
 MONO %                          5.8                       (2.5-8.5)      %
 NEUT %                          77.8             *        (48-76)        %
 EOS %                           0                         (0-5)          %
 BASO %                          0.2                       (0-1.5)        %
HCT                              32.3             *        (36-48)        %
PLT                              452              *        (150-450)      K/uL
PTT                              54.3             *        (23.8-36.6)    sec
PT(INR)                          2.1              *        (0.9-1.1)
GLUCOSE                          265              *#       (54-118)       mg/dL
UREA N                           20                        (9-25)         mg/dL
CREATININE                       1.36             *        (0.7-1.3)      mg/dL
ALT/GPT                          11                        (7-52)         U/L
AST/GOT                          9                         (9-30)         U/L
ALK PHOS                         113                       (36-118)       U/L
TOT BILI                         0.3                       (0.2-1.2)      mg/dL
ALBUMIN                          3.6              *#       (3.7-5.4)      g/dL
UA (10/25): sg 1.013, 1+ glucose, (-) LE, (-) nitr


Microbiology:
&#183;         9/10: L. foot debridement cx: 4+ CoNS (ox/PCN/lev-R), 4+ Corynebacterium spp
&#183;         8/14: R. groin wound cx: many MRSA
&#183;         7/92: R. foot skin graft cx: 3+ CoNS, 3+ diphtheroids
&#183;         4/92: R. heel biopsy cx: few S. simulans (ox/PCN-R, vanc/tet/rif/bactr-S). few S. epidermidis (PCN/lev-R, ox-S), few diphtheroids
&#183;         6/90: rare MSSA (PCN-R, erythro-I, otherwise sensitive)
&#183;         12/89: R. foot debridement cx: many P. aeruginosa (S to all tested agents)
&#183;         12/89: R. foot wound culture: rare MSSA, rare alpha-hemolytic streptococci, many bacteroides gracilis, many peptostreptococcus prevotii, few fusobacterium nucleatum, moderate anaerobic GNRs


Radiology:
&#183;         10/25: PA/lateral CXR: no acute cardiopulmonary process
&#183;         9/12: BLE angiogram: distal aorta and iliac vessels without stenosis, R CFA and PFA widely patent, proximal 1-2cm SFA with mild-moderate stenosis, without flow limitation; remainder of SFA above bypass without obvious stenosis, R mid-SFA to mid-PT bypass widely patent, PT outflow vessel good quality, other tibial vessels quite atretic; LLE: L. CFA and PFA widely patent, L. SFA with mild eccentric proximal stenosis, L. popliteal with mild-moderate non-flow limiting stenosis, two vessel PT and peroneal runoff good quality
&#183;         8/16/92: L. foot films: diffuse bone demineralization, no fracture or dislocation; dorsal talar osteophyte, nonspecific punctate calcification in plantar aspect of calcaneus, no evidence of osteomyelitis, soft tissue swelling in plantar aspect of foot
      
Impression/Recommendations: 50F w/longstanding type I DM with severe peripheral neuropathy, recent development of L. heel and forefoot ulcers, here with cellulitis surrounding her L. forefoot ulcer, improving on vancomycin. Awaiting debridement today, need to determine depth of her infection and whether it extends to bone:


&#183;         Continue vancomycin 1g IV bid for now. Her renal function is impaired from her DM&#8212;would check a vancomycin trough prior to her next dose.
&#183;         Please send biopsy of bone underlying her L. forefoot ulcer for gram stain, aerobic culture, and anaerobic culture from OR today.
&#183;         Needs to be on MRSA contact precautions&#8212;grew abundant MRSA from her R. groin wound last month.
&#183;         Has missed her follow-up mammogram appointments and colonoscopy appointments for follow-up of an abnormal lumpectomy finding and a &#8216;precancerous polyp&#8217; because of her recent foot issues. Unable to stand for mammography because of her foot issues&#8212;will discuss optimal imaging of her L. breast with breast radiology, will hopefully be able to obtain this study during this hospitalization.


Discussed with Dr. Craig Faulkner, ID Attending. Recommendations discussed with Dr. Zane Querry of primary team. Thank you for this interesting consult&#8212;we will continue to follow with you.
____________________________________
Amanda Qualls, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2092-12-26


Diabetes CONSULT REPORT



CC    
Asked by Dr. Katz to see the patient for assistance with management of hyperglycemia.


HPI   
This is a 50 year old male patient with a history of type 1 diabetes diagnosed 40 years ago at an age of 10. Pt was initially treated with insulin and has been requiring insulin since diagnosis. Pt was started on an insulin pump in 2079. Current basal rates are 0.6 units from 12am-6am, 0.7 units from 6am to 6:30pm and then 0.6 units at 6:30pm again. Pt uses a carb ratio of 10:1. Pt cannot recall her correction factor as it is programmed into her pump. Monitors her blood glucoses at least 4 times per day and reports variable glucoses for 70-&gt;200. Reports hypoglycemic episodes 1-2 times per week and she is usually symptomatic with glucoses of 70. Reports that she was admitted to the hospital about one month ago with DKA. States that she had flu-like symptoms and severe vomiting and was admitted ot Ames Pathology Center for treatment. Had never had DKA before. Pt reports complications associated with diabetes. Reports retinopathy and has had several laster surgeries. Reports nephropathy as well as an episode of renal failure related to a hospitalization this summer. Reports peripheral neuropathy as well as peripheral vascular disease, including non-healing ulcers that have lead to right TMA. 


Patient is admitted for stenosis of right bypass graft stenosis and is going to the cath lab for angiogram shortly. Currently receiving D5W with 150 meq of Bicarb at 125 ccs/hr for renal protection. 
BG today (with IV fluid infusing): 230 (4am), 271 (9am), and 195 (11am - prior to leaving for cath) 
BG 12/25: 152 (1pm), 196 (6pm), 172 (8pm)
Pt is using her insulin pump. 
 
Allergies
Erythromycins - rash 
Sulfa - rash
Aspirin - rash




Medications             
Diabetes medications at home included: Insulin pump, see HPI
Diabetes medications now include: Insulin pump


Problems
Anemia 
Anxiety 
Deep venous thrombosis 
Depression 
Hypothyroidism 
Palpitations 
Right TMA
Let ankle fracture
                        
FHX
No history of hormonal disorders in any family members 
                  
SHX and Habits
Non-smoker
 
ROS 
Patient is post-operative. 


Physical Examination
General:  Patient is in no apparent distress.  
Vitals: BP 110/60, HR 99, Temp 
HENT: Inspection reveals no abnormalities. 
Eyes:  Conjunctivae, sclera and lids are normal. No icterus. 
Respiratory:  Assessment of respiratory effort reveals even respirations without use of accessory muscles
Skin: No skin rash, warm and dry skin.  No acanthosis nigricans.
Neurological Examination: Alert and oriented to person, place, time, and situation. Grossly nonfocal exam.
Psychiatric: Mood and affect appropriate to situation.
Extremity exam: No pedal edema, right foot with bandage.


Lab Results
12/25/2092 NA 136,  K 4.5,  CL 107,  CO2 22 (*),  BUN 52 (*),  CRE 2.11 (*),  EGFR 25,  GLU 212 (*)12/02/2092 HGBA1C 9.0 (H)12/25/2092 WBC 6.55,  RBC 4.34 (#),  HGB 10.5 (*#),  HCT 33.5 (*#),  MCV 77.2 (*#),  MCH 24.2 (*),  MCHC 31.4 (*),  PLT 302 (#) 
Assessment 
T1DM - Uncontrolled. Pt appears alert, oriented and confident to use her insulin pump in the hospital. Pt is able to verbalize her insulin doses and states that she would prefer to continue with pump use. Suspect that IV fluids are contributing to hyperglycemia, therefore reluctant to change insulin doses since IV fluids will likely stop later today. While in procedure, will need to monitor blood glucoses more closely, but anticipate that pump can continue as programmed. 


Recommendations
1. Continue with insulin pump. Instructed pt that she must:
       a. report all pre-meal bolus doses to the RN so that it can be documented on the 
       flow sheet.
       b. have blood glucoses checked as ordered using the hospital approved glucose meter. 
       c. alert RN if she feel uncomfortable using insulin pump. RN should page HO and/or diabetes dept 
       immediately for orders for SC insulin. 
       d. agree to discontinue insulin pump and start SC insulin if deemed necessary by house staff. 
Pt agrees to all of the above. 
 
2. Monitor blood glucoses at least before all meals and at bedtime. Please also check blood glucoses with any symptoms of hypoglycemia or at pt's request. Be sure to record these values on the daily flow sheet. 
 
3. For procedure today, I spoke with Kathryn Kincaid and asked that blood glucoses be monitored hourly while in cath lab unless BG is less than 140. If BG less than 140, monitor blood glucoses every 30 minutes. Treat BG less than 80 with 1/2 amp D50 and continue to monitor as described above. Do not remove insulin pump. Page 5-8112 with any concerns during the procedure. 
 
Diabetes dept will continue to monitor. Please page 5-8112 with any questions or concerns. Thank you.
 
 
________________________
Faye Easley, NP
       
             







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2094-03-19



 
Infectious Disease Consult Note 


Pt: Rose Mack
MR#: 06129040

Consult Date: 3/19/94



CC/RFC: 
Pt is a 52 year old w/ chronic R heel wound, now w/ wound infection. Consultation was requested by Dr. Katz for recommendations regarding antibiotic management.



HPI:  Pt has longstanding DM and PVD complicated by severe R foot ulceration. She underwent R femoral to posterior tibial bypass graft in 5/92 and skin grafting in 7/92. R heel wound subsequently improved but pt developed L plantar ulceration requiring debridement 10/92. Cultures grew MSSA. Pt was subsequently treated w/ extended course of doxycycline, rifampin through 2/93. She subsequently did well until developing R heel ulcer while undergoing psychiatric hospitalization in mid 2/94. She was initially hospitalized at Altadena Hospital, where she underwent debridement of wound and treatment w/ extended course of penicillin VK and probenicid. Wound failed to improve. Pt was rehospitalized on 3/18 at GCCfor further management. She underwent incision and debridement on 3/18. Intraoperative evaluation revealed ulcer wound tracking to bone. Intraoperative gram stain revealed GPCs in pairs. Intraoperative cultures are pending. Pt was subsequently treated w/ vancomycin, levofloxacin and metronidazole. 




On interview, pt reports feeling generally well. No F/C/NS. Appetite normal. Had  previously noted creeping erythema up R leg, now resolved.



PMH (from EMR)

DM type 1: c/b PVD, neuropathy, nephropathy

PVD: s/p right mid superficial femoral artery to mid posterior tibial bypass graft with reversed ipsilateral greater saphenous vein

CKD

Hx femoral neck fracture: in situ screw fixation

Anemia 

Anxiety/Depression 

Deep venous thrombosis 

Hypothyroidism: s/p subtotal thyroidectomy 74

S/p R carpal tunnel surgery



Meds on Consultation

 
Plavix

Lopressor

Simvastatin

Lantus

Levoxyl

Abilify

Cogentin

Nortriptyline

Trazadone

Probenecid

Neurontin



All

Erythromycins cause rash  

Sulfa causes rash

Aspirin causes rash



SHx

Pt lives at home w/ her parents



FHx 
NC



ROS

Ten point review of systems negative except as noted in HPI. 



Exam
Pt is a tired appearing middle aged woman, lying comfortably in bed

VS: 
T- 96.4, HR- 84, BP- 153/72, RR- 18, Sat- 100% on 2L     

HEENT: 
MMM, w/o exudates

Chest: 
CTAB; no crackles, no wheezes

CV: 
RRR; normal S1S2, no m/r/g appreciated

Abd:  NABS; soft, non-tender, non-distended; no organomegaly

Extr:  R heel w/ 2 x 2cm wound vac dressing in place, no surrounding erythema; L foot without erythem or ulceration

Neuro:  MS nl, motor and sensory normal

Skin:  scattered patchy erythematous rash across trunk and upper extremities



Labs
Chemistry:                                                          

BUN:   19

Cr:    1.3



Tbili: 0.2

ALT:   20

AST:   22

AP:    290



Heme:    

WBC:  
4.7              

HCT:  
33.2

Plt:   290



Impression
52F w/ DM, PVD and hx of R heel ulceration s/p skin grafting in 5/92 and L midfoot MSSA infection in 9/92, now w/ relapse of R heel ulceration. Intraoperative cultures show involvement of bone. Clinical picture is concerning for osteomyelitis. Possible culprit organisms include drug resistant Staphylococcus aureus, which should be treated empirically while awaiting cultures. Pt will likely require an extended course of IV therapy for treatment of osteomyelitis.



Recommendations

 



Follow up intraoperative cultures

Continue vancomycin 1g IV Q24H; check trough prior to fourth dose.

Discontinue levofloxacin, metronidazole.









_______________________________

Victor Reid, M.D.   (pager # 81625)



Case discussed with infectious disease attending, Dr. Amber Akins.




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>