<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2082-01-28

             				

 Critical care 					 





PULMONARY FELLOW ADMIT NOTE





Reason for Admission: focal neurologic deficits



HPI: 48 yo man with CF, HTN, GERD, spinal stenosis, DM, CF arthropathy, h/o crypto meningitis and h/o left UE paresthesias who presented to Sheffield Care Center 1/26 with complaints of sudden-onset right hand paresthesias, followed by left sided weakness and left sided visual deficits. Also with frontal-occipital headache during this time. He presented to the Sheffield Center ED, and shortly after he was seen his left sided weakness resolved, although his visual field deficits and right hand paresthesia as well as his headache had remained. He denies F/C/N/V. No neck stiffness. 



He had a noncontrast head CT which was negative for any acute process per radiology read.  He had an LP with 2 WBC, 2 RBC, glucose 98, protein 84, appeared clear. Gram stain with no orgs, rare polys.  ESR 44, crypto ag pending.  He was transferred to HSH because Sheffield Center does not have an MRI machine.



He says that his pulmonary status has been stable, and produces a moderate amount of yellow sputum. He does not do chest PT at home. He has a h/o mild sinusitis, but he says that it hasn't been bothering him lately. He has been having normal bowel movements with no difficulties with constipation.



PMH: 

CF

HTN

GERD

Gout

Spinal stenosis (2062)

CF induced DM

CF arthropathy

Crypto meningitis 2062

Nephrotic syndrome

Bilateral cataracts

 

Current Meds: 

Lasix 20 bid

Advair 250/50 bid

ASA 81 qd

Albuterol prn

Pancreacarb 8 tabs with meals, 3-5 w/snacks

Colchicine 0.5mg qd

Cozaar 50qd

Zestril 40mg qd

Accolate 20mg bid

Prandin 2-4 mg tid qac

Vit E and D

Celebrex 100mg qd

Vit K 5mg 3x/wk

Protoniz 40mg qd

Azithro 500 3x/wk

Probenecid 250mg bid



Allergies: NKDA



Family History: mother died of Hodgkins dz at 33. Father with CVA, HTN, sister with CF



Social History: 

Occupation/exposures: shoe repairer

Smoking: no tobacco, +occasional marijuana. Occasional alcohol.

 

Physical Exam:

Vitals:  T 97.9, HR 78, BP 118/68, RR 20, 99% RA

Gen:  comfortable in NAD

HEENT/neck:  OP clear, PERRL, EOMI, no nuchal rigidity

Lungs/chest:  diminished breath sounds bilaterally, no crackles or wheezes

Heart:  RRR no murmurs

Abd:  soft nt/nd +BS

Extr:  no edema

Neuro: +left unilateral left-sided hemianopsia. OTW CN II-XII intact. 5/5 strength throughout, normal sensation, normal cerebellar exam, normal gait.  +paresthesias in right hand in a glove distribution.



Lab: pending



Imaging: pending



Impression: 48 yo man with CF, CF-induced DM, and HTN, who presented to an outside hospital with focal neuro changes of unclear etiology, but concerning for a CVA.  



Recommendations: 

1.	Neuro: Would get a brain MRI/MRA to further evaluate.  After the MRI is done, would get a neurology consult in the morning.  Continue ASA, BP control in the meantime.  Patient may need a repeat LP depending on neuro consult recs.

2.	Pulm: CF appears stable. Would continue his outpatient Advair, albuterol, azithro.

3.	GI: continue enzymes, vitamins. High calorie, high protein CF diet.

4.	Endo: monitor blood glucose.









 

______________________

Quiana Titus, M.D.

Critical care Fellow

Pager: 33911



Lung Transplant Attending Note:



I have seen and examined the patient with Dr. Titus and I agree with her evaluation and plan as outlined above.  Mr. Aguilar is a 48 yo man with h/o CF with mild pulmonary disease, who presented to an OSH on 1/26 with sudden onset of right upper ext paresthesias, followed by a loss of left visual field, diplopia, and left sided weakness.  The patient denies incontinence but had some gait instability related to weakness.  The patient was evaluated at the OSH with non-contrast head CT and L/P which were significant only for elevated CSF protein.  Currently symptoms have resolved other than persistent occipital headache which began with the onset of the other symptoms, as well as unilateral hemianopsia in the left eye evident on exam.  Exam also notable for disdiadochokinesis, otherwise neurologic exam non-focal.  Lung exam notable for diminished BS but no wheezes or crackles.  DDX for above includes ischemic process, though symptoms appear to be multi-focal, vs. mononeuritis multiplex related to inflammatory process.  Less likely is mass lesion leading to above symptoms, or meningeal process.  We plan to obtain CNS MRI, neuro consult.  Will await MRI findings prior to pursuing further serologic work-up.  Continue maintenance medications for CF.



_______________________

Debra F. Mullen, MD

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2082-09-29

I have personally reviewed the history, examined the patient, and reviewed and edited the note and I agree with the assessment and plan developed under my personal supervision as documented by previosu PA note from Ursula Bowers, PA-C. Please see additional comments below.

Vicente Aguilar is a 49 y/o male with cystic fibrosis, moderate to severe lung disease, colonized with mucoid-type Pseudomonas aeruginosa pancreatic insufficiency, CF related DM, HTN, renal insufficiency with proteinuria, recent h/o CVA, gout, cataracts who is currently experiencing a subacute exacerbation of his pulmonary disease requiring hospitalization to initiate IV antibiotics. His symptoms include long-standing fatigue, increased cough and sputum production, some SOB with mild chest tightness and wheezing. His FEV1 significantly decreased during recent clicni visit. He also reports some sinus headaches, but denies sinus pain or tenderness.  He denies hemoptysis, fever/chills, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea or constipation.  Please see details regarding recent MRI/MRA results on PA note above, as well as medications, and other pertinent historical data reviewed independently. 

VSS: afebrile, oxygen saturation 
Gen: alert, NAD
HEENT: sclera clear, persistent visual defects right upper quadrant visual field, neck supple
CV: regular
Lungs: essentially clear with good aeration, no wheezes wuth few scattered ronchi. 
Abdomen: soft, NT, ND, no masses
Ext: warm, clubbing
Neuro: normal gait, oriented x 3.

Assessment/Plan: Vicente Aguilar is a 49 y/o male with cystic fibrosism noderate to severe lung disease with past medical history as noted above who is currently experiencing a subacute exacerbation of his pulmonary disease requiring hospitalization to initiate IV antibiotics

1. PULM/ID: We will start treatment with tobramycin 700 mg IV q am, as well as  Ceftazidime 2 g IV q 8 hours based on culture results. We will continue maintenance pulmonary medications including bronchodilators, mucolytics and steroids. We will discuss hypertonic saline therapy and trial its use if agreeable. We will send a new sputum sample for culture. Chest x-ray after PICC placement. Will review routine admission labs.

2. CVS: monitor blood pressure assess need for other protective medications. Will continue antihypertensives, ACEi and ARB if creatinine stable. We will review findings from recent MRI/MRA. Check lipid profile if not done, on Zocor. 

3. FEN/GI: High calorie, high protein CF diet. 

4. Renal: check electrolytes, as well as UA with random protein and creatinine. His creatinine was elevated to 1.6, now 1.5 and was 1.1-1.4 at baseline. He described an incident last week with nausea and vomiting that likely led to above result while taking colchicine, celebrex, and other meds. This is probabyl on its way to improvement. We did not hold ACEi and ARB at this time, but will repeat Cr tonight. He will drink fluids during the day priro to PICC by IR. He does not have a nephrologist adn will need to find him one. He did have a renal biopsy in teh late 60s adn thus will look for results, but renal disease likely multigfactorial. We will tobra levels bvery close adn started at low dose for his size. Will likely check renal US while here.

5. Endo: continue insulin regimen. He will check blood sugars more frequently and folow HgA1c. He did state that he occasionally gets blood sugars in the 40s when he wakes up, but usually nto when he is sedentary, ie. admitted to hospital. IF BS normal here, he will check them very closely at home as well and make adjustments as necesary. We will also need toset him up with Endocrinologist. 

6. Access: PICC line to be placed in IR

7. Dispo: 14 day of inpatient IV antibiotics

8. Neuro: He was last seen by Neurologist on 8/30 and was discharged from routine follow-up. He will continue anti-hypertensive meds and ASA. He contineu sot have visual deficit in R upper quadrant.




_____________________________________________
Quinton Israel,D.O.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-12-07


Pulmonary Service Admission Note
Vicente Aguilar #98179909
December 7, 2084


HPI  51 y/o male with cystic fibrosis, pancreatic insufficency and CRI who was last admitted for cleanout in 1/2084 now presenting after being seen by Dr Mann as outpatient on long island with newly increased creatinine above baseline and to initiate cleanout. He notes he has been doing fairly well this last year. He was seen for a physical by his primary care physician Dr Haas on November 13th at which time he reports she told him he was doing well. Dr Mann followed up with her on his lab studies and results and called Mr Aguilar on friday alerting him to the change in his renal function. It was decided that he be admitted for renal work-up as well as initiating cleanout as he does his cleanouts yearly. He notes he has felt generally well with no increased cough or sputum, chest pain or tightness. He notes he has 'danced around' some cold symptoms earlier in the summer but has had none since. He denies any fevers or chills and notes he only gets sweats if he has a low blood sugar. He denies any N/V, diarrhea or constipation and has stable appetite. He notes stable weight of 185-186 lbs. He notes he has had erratic control of his blood sugar as he does at times 'forget' to give himself insulin. He does monitoe his BS four times per day. He denies any dysuria, hematuria or urgency. he does note frequency has increased over the year, he now urinates every few hours. He denies any sore throat or sinus pain, does have occasional mild congestion. 


Reviwe of systems: he has a flu shot, denies sick contacts. notes his prostate exam at his PCP office was reported to be normal. denies reflux symptoms, does have feeling of pills "sticking' when he swallows them occasionally. 


PMH:
Cystic Fibrosis
Pancreatic insufficiency
CF related Diabetes Mellitus
Hypertension
Nephrotic syndrome (baseline creatinine 1.1), chart dx at CHB of GN, unclear source of dx
Gout
Cataracts


Allergies: NKDA


Medications:  
Aspirin 81 mg po daily
Colchicine 0.6 mg po daily
Probenecid 250 mg po bid
Azithromycin 500 mg po q thu/sat/Monday
simvastatin 20 mg po qhs
Cozaar 50 mg po BID
Accolate 20 mg po bid
Albuterol inh prn
Plaretase 8000 6 tabs po qac/ snacks (what his pharmacy switched him to as pancrecarb not available)
Protonix 40 mg po daily
Lantus 12 u qhs
Humalog scale ac


FH/SH: lives on long island with partner of 4 years, she is a Notary. Works in shoe repair. Denies tobacco, usually drinks daily galss of grand marnier. notes prior daily marajuana smoking, now 3-4 times per month recently.


PHYSICAL EXAM (in CDIC): 
Vitals: see nursing flowsheet
GEN:NAD. Pleaseant male. Nad.
HEENT: PERRL, op moist, with no exudates, no sinus pain or tendernes, no LAN
LUNGS: clear to auscultation bilaterally, no wheezes or rhonchi
HEART:S1S2 reg, no m/g/r, rrr
ABDOMEN:soft. NT/ND, active BS, no HSM
EXT: trace digital clubbing b/l, trace b/l ankle edema
NEURO:alert and oriented x 3, no focal deficits



DATA (from CHB):
-reported BUN/Cre from PCP office- 68/2.1
-no other updated data


Assessment/Plan:  Mr Aguilar is a 51 M with cystic fibrosis and hx of CRI who presents now with significant worsening of his renal function seen on outpatient labs as well as it having been nearly one year since prior cleanout. He is being admitted for initiation of cleanout and evaluation of renal dysfunction. He will be admitted to pulmonary PA service.


1) Pulm/ID: Based on his past sputum culture studies from CHB and his renal function we will start him on Ceftaz at renal dose of 2g q24h and cipro 250 q12h. Have used aminoglycosides in the past but given his renal function will avoid these at this time. Will get a f/u CXR to compare to his study done last year to assess for any change. Will consult RT for Chest PT TID and discuss restarting hypertonic saline/pulmozyme. Will continue other pulmonary inhalers. 



2)FEN/GI: Will maintain on high calorie, high protein CF diet and continue current regimen of vitamins and enzymes. Will get 
Nutrition consult as patient has not been seen in quite some time. Will monitor bowels, currently stable.


3) CV: history of HTN, will continue home cozaar and lisinopril for now but may consider alternative choices given renal dysfunction if needed. Will monitor vital signs.


4) ENDO: CF related DM: will continue lantus and SSI and check FSBS AC/HS. Will send HgA1c given his report of erratic control at home.


5) Rheum: Gouty arthritis has been stable, will contiue probenecid and celebrex 



6) Renal: Recent BUN/creatinine as reported from his PCP is significantly elevated from his prior levels earlier this year. Patient has not been followed regularly by nephrology in the past. Unclear the exact nature of his renal dysfunction and the etiology of its worsening of late. Will send for renal ultrasound and send urine lytes, protein, creatinine and eosinophils to begin work-up and will consider renal consult.  Will start gentle IVF hydration overnight.


7)Access: PICC line in IR today


8)PPX: sc heparin , PPI


9)Dispo: TBD


______________________________________
Francine Morales, PA-C
68626





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2085-08-29


Pulmonary Service Admission Note


HPI: 52 yo male with Cystic Fibrosis, CKD, CF related Arthritis  presents with c/o increased cough, sputum production, SOB and fatigue for several weeks. He also has had a 15 lb weight loss over the past 2 months. His po intake has been decreased.  He denies fever, chills, night sweats, chest tightness, hemoptysis or blood streaking.  
 


PMH:
Cystic Fibrosis
Pancreatic insufficiency
CKD
CF related Diabetes Mellitus
Hypertension
Nephrotic syndrome (baseline creatinine 1.1), chart dx at CHB of GN, unclear source of dx
Gout
Cataracts


Allergies: NKDA


Medications:  
Accolate 20 MG PO BID 
Allopurinol 300 MG daily
Aspirin 81 MG PO QD 
Azithromycin 500 MG po Q Thursday/Saturday/Monday
Colchicine 0.6 MG  PO Q thu/sat/monday 
HCTZ 25 mg daily
Humalog SS q AC (approx 20 units)
Lantus 15 UNITS SC QHS 
Lopressor  50 MG  PO BID 
Pancrecarb MS 8 (PANCRELIPASE 8,000 UNITS (PANCRECARB MS 8)) 8 TABS PO QAC and snacks 
Probenecid 250 MG  PO QD 
Prednisone 15 MG daily
Protonix 40 mg PO QD 
Simvastatin 20 MG po q hs
Symbicort 80/4.5 2 PUFF INH BID 
Pulmozyme 2.5 mg nebulized bid
Hypertonic Saline 4mL inhaled bid


FH/SH: lives on long island with partner of 5 years, she is a Notary. Works in shoe repair. Denies tobacco, usually drinks daily glass of grand marnier. notes prior daily marajuana smoking, now 3-4 times per month recently.



Review of systems:  Denies sick contacts.  denies reflux symptoms. states urine output regular, but had several day period of constipation and abdominal that he was able to resolve with prune juice and Activia yogurt.  


PHYSICAL EXAM (in CDIC): 
Vitals: see nursing flowsheet
GEN:NAD. Pleaseant male. Nad.
HEENT: PERRL, op moist, with no exudates, no sinus pain or tendernes, no LAN
LUNGS: clear to auscultation bilaterally, no wheezes or rhonchi
HEART:S1S2 reg, no m/g/r, rrr
ABDOMEN:soft. NT/ND, active BS, no HSM
EXT: trace digital clubbing b/l, trace b/l ankle edema
NEURO:alert and oriented x 3, no focal deficits


 
DATA (from CHB):
PFT&#8217;s 
2/01/85 : 65/43/14
12/12/84: 78/46/14
2/4/2084: 90/56/18
1/26/84: 85/53/14
10/6/82: 45/50/20
8/13/82: 48/33/14


Sputum cultures:
2/01/85 : PsA (pan sensitive), PsA (pan sensitive), PsA (pan sensitive)
12/8/84: MRSA (S: linezolid, synercid, tetra, tigecycline, vanco), PsA #1pan sensitive, PsA #2 (S: cipro, zosyn, tobra), PsA#3 (S: amik, azt, ceft, cipro, gent, zosyn, tobra)
1/26/84
PsA: (S: ceftaz, cipro, zosyn, tobra)
PsA: (pan sensitive)
PsA: (pan sensitive) 


 
Assessment/Plan:  Mr Aguilar is a 51 M with cystic fibrosis and CKD presenting with subacute CF exacerbation for IV antiobiotic cleanout. He will be admitted to pulmonary PA service.


1) Pulm/ID: Start Ceftaz 2 g IV q 12 , Cipro 500 mg po q 12, Vanco 1 g IV q 24
Sputum cx to CHB, Chest xray, PT c/s for treadmill, Chest PT BID, hypertonic saline, pulmozyme



2)FEN/GI: Will maintain on high calorie, high protein CF diet and continue current regimen of vitamins and enzymes. Will get 
Nutrition consult as inpatient has not been seen in quite some time. Will monitor bowels, currently stable.


3) CV: History of HTN, will continue home cozaar and lisinopril for now but may consider alternative choices given renal dysfunction if needed. Will monitor vital signs.


4) ENDO: CF related DM: will continue lantus and SSI and check FSBS AC/HS. Will send HgA1c given his report of erratic control at home.


5) Rheum: Gouty arthritis has been stable, will contiue probenecid. Obtain uric acid level.Wean prednisone. 



6) Renal: Followed by Dr Esparza -no current issues, last bun/cr: 82/1.77, BP maintained on hctz/lopressor.


7)Access: PICC line in IR today


8)PPX: sc heparin , PPI


9)Dispo: TBD


______________________________________
Ursula Bowers, PA-C 34680






Pulmonary Attending
I have seen and examined Mr. Aguilar with PA Bowers with whose note I agree. Admission for "clean-out" for CF. Increased dyspnea and sputum and decrease in spirometry. No hemoptysis. Plan as reviewed with team is to start  Ceftazidime 2 g IV q 12 , Cipro 500 mg po q 12, Vancomycin  1 g IV q 24. Sputum cx will be sent to  CHB. We will initiate chest PT BID, hypertonic saline, pulmozyme. Encourage ambulation. He is on prednisone at 15 mg given hx of arthritis. No alterations in dose at present for pulmonary status. IR picc pending. Laboratory studies and chest x ray pending and will be reviewed personally once available. Disposition pending. Full code.
 
 
Rachel G. Richardson, MD 










****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>