<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2087-12-05







Beckley Appalachian Regional Hospital

040 Townsend West              MOSS, DEREK

Espanola, WI  85976                    59624156

895-239-5445, 302-843-7619                     12/05/2087





History of the Present Illness/Chief Complaint:  The patient is a 77-year-old man who is here with his son and daughter today, acutely ill with multiple acute medical problems.



Medications:  Per the list entered on the computer today, a total of 28 medications and accessories.



Allergies:  None.



Past Medical History

	Surgeries

       1.  Hip surgery.

       2.  Cholecystectomy.

       3.  Lumbar laminectomy.

       4.  Left leg surgery.

       5.  Bilateral cataract extraction.

       6.  Prostate biopsy 2086, Gleason grade 6/10.

       7.  Left skin cancer removal.



	Medical Problems

       1.  Septic arthritis of the left shoulder.

       2.  Dislocated left shoulder.

       3.  CHF with dilated cardiomyopathy.

       4.  Atrial fibrillation.

       5.  Insulin-dependent diabetes.

       6.  Parkinson's disease.

       7.  GI bleed.

       8.  Diffuse arthritis.

       9.  Prostatic cancer.

       10.  Prostatic obstruction.

       11.  Microcytic anemia.



Family History

	Family history was reviewed and is notable for:

	CVD:  Positive.



Social History

Living arrangements:  He has recently moved from Ouagadougou.  He is living with his son and daughter-in-law in Harrisburg.  He has mostly been in the hospital over the last several months.

Work:  He is a retired vocational instructor.  He had been with the city of Cadiz for 32 years.

	Smoking:  None.

	ETOH:  None.

	Exercise:  None.

	Diet:  Minimal, poor appetite.

	Domestic Violence:  None.

	

Health Maintenance

	Seat belts:  Always.

Colonoscopy:  Has had but there are no records (may have been indadequate exam).  Endoscopy in 2087 showed gastritis.

	

	Immunization

		Td:  Up-to-date.

	











Review of Systems

       ROS reviewed in detail.

General: Good mood.  No F/S/C.  Depressed with chronic illness, extremely fatigued.

       Skin:  Multiple ecchymoses, extremely dry skin.

       HEENT: no sore throat; no change in vision or blurring;

       No change in hearing, ear pain, or  tinnitus

Cardiovascular:  History of substernal chest pain, on longacting nitroglycerin, dyspnea on exertion, sleeps with the bed propped up and one pillow, chronic ankle edema, chronic AF.

       Respiratory:  Dyspnea on exertion.

GI:  Loose bowel movements multiple times a day.  Over the last week he has been having bright red blood.  He has had melena in the past, most recently grape jelly like clots of blood.  He has had anorexia.  No abdominal pain, no vomiting.

Extrem:  Left shoulder pain, history of significant infection in the left shoulder, torn rotator cuff so that he is essentially unable to use the left arm.

       Endocrine: no polyuria or polydipsia; one episode of sig hypoglycemia

       Neurologic: no HA, visual change, seizure, or acute neurologic sxs

       Psychiatric: depression; acutely ill

       Hematologic:  Significant bruising and bleeding.

       GU:  Urinary hesitancy, prostatic obstruction, prostatic cancer.



Physical Examination

General/constitutional:  Pleasant, alert, oriented, in acute distress, weak, has difficulty moving; nl affect

Vital signs:  Ht 67 inches Wt (lbs) 154 BMI

	BP 128/68 Heart rate 84, irregularly irregular RR12 and comfortable  w/out accessory muscles         Temp 96.3.

Skin:  Dry skin, sallow pale, multiple ecchymoses, significant ulcer on the left shoulder in the subdeltoid bursa area with pus in the center and erythema surrounding it.

Lymph nodes: no cervical, supraclavicular, axillary, inguinal lymphadenopathy

Neck: supple; carotid upstroke good w/out bruit; no thyromegaly or tenderness

HEENT: pharynx with nl mucosa w/out exudates; good dental care; conjunctivae noninjected; no scleralicterus; PERRLA; EOMI w/out nystagmus; pupils pinpoint, discs not visualized; hearing significantly reduced; TM nl; sinuses non-tender

Chest: w/out chest wall tenderness; clear P&A w/out rales, rhonchi, or wheeze

Cardiac:  In AF, rate of 80, palpable, PMI laterally displaced, soft S2, S4, 2/6 apical systolic murmur radiating to the left sternal border and to the axilla.

Breast:  No gynecomastia.

Abdomen: nl BS, no hepatomegaly/splenomegaly or mass; no tenderness/G/R;

           abd aorta w/out bruit or palpable enlargement

Extremities:  1+ pretibial edema.  No motion of the left shoulder ulcer as noted above.

Neurologic: A&O; nl affect; nl speech; weakened left arm;

	reflexes symmetric; plantars flexor

Rectal: Copious amounts of blood in the rectal exam, loose sphincter, no prostatic mass.





Laboratory data and Old record reviewed extensive records.





Impression: Acutely ill gentleman w/

GI Bleed

CHF

Hz L shoulder infection; currently w/ infected ulcer and limited ROM due to rotator tear

DM out of control

Multiple problems as above.  Long discussion with the family regarding previous care.  Acute problem today is massive GI bleed without clear etiology.  History of heart failure with significant weakness, shortness of breath, recent chest pain, nonhealing ulcer on his left shoulder, all requiring emergency hospitalization, and he will be sent to the BARH ER at once.  Long discussion with the family about this and his other chronic problems including diabetes and episodes of hypoglycemia.













Plan

Health Maintenance

Diet and exercise counseling

Further evaluation 

Medications

FU





______________________________

Ursula Yawn, MD











eScription document:7-3720969 HFFocus







DD: 12/05/87

DT: 12/05/87

DV: 12/05/87



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-01-20



 

Infectious Disease Consultation





Patient Name: Moss, Derek

MR: 89659991

Reason for consult: assistance with management of possible persistent L shoulder septic arthritis in patient pre-op for planned hip replacement 

Source: patient, MR

Counsult requested by: Dr. Everett Pace

Date of consult: 1/20

Location: 4E-66

__________________________________________________________________



HPI: Mr. Moss is a 77 yo M with PmHx significant for DMII, CHF (EF 20-25%), afib, Parkinson's, prostate cancer s/p XRT c/b proctitis and GIB, multiple hip replacements, s/p multiple knee surgeries who, recently treated for S. aureus L shoulder septic arthritis (10/87) who presented 1/19 s/p fall.  



Mr. Moss has experienced multiple falls recently, and was ultimately diagnosed with Parkinsons last September.  Following the diagnosis, he was discharged to Bellaire City Hospital, where he continued to experience falls.  After one episode, he was forcibly picked up, and began to have L shoulder pain thereafter.  He also noted a cut over the L elbow on transfer to the NH that was slow to heal.   After several weeks of worsening shoulder pain, erythema, and warmth, he was re-hospitalized at Ouagadougou, where he underwent L shoulder aspiration.  MRI 10/87 demonstrated complete rupture of the rotator cuff, with associated large joint effusion.  Of note, he denied fevers, chills, or NS.

L shoulder aspiration 10/10/87 demonstrated purulent fluid, with 2,800,000 WBC (97%PMN). Gram stain demonstrated GPC in clusters.  He subsequently underwent L shoulder I&D 10/12, with removal of 300cc of frankly purulent fluid.  He was started on cefazolin.  Culture results returned a pan-sensitive Staphylococcus aureus isolate (including to ampicillin, cefazolin, clindamycin, penicillin, rifampin).  Blood cultures were negative.  He was taken back to the OR 10/16 for arthroscopy, with extensive debridement.  Interop findings included demonstration of significant fibrinous tissue, with no normal-appearing cartiledge present.  A penrose was placed into a large cavity down the subdeltoid rescess, and a second in the subacromial space.  He was transitioned to ampicillin 2g q6 hours x 2 weeks, and then given amoxicillin (either 1g BID or 500mg TID, unsure which) x 2 weeks.  



Repeat R shoulder MRI obtained 12/12/87, which was reviewed with staff radiologist, and demonstrated again complete tear of the supra/infraspinatus/teres minor/ subscapularis/ biceps tendons, with also persistent large joint effusion, extensive synovitis, and full thickness cartiledge loss of glenoid and humeral head.  Also noted was possible AVN of medial portion of the humeral head. Overall, was difficult to tell from MRI whether findings represented prior vs active disease.  



Mr. Moss was seen in the ID clinic 1/18, at which time he complained of a several week h/o progressively worsening L shoulder discomfort with activity.  He did not experience shoulder pain at rest, and had not recently noted erythema.  No drainage.  Appetite was near baseline, though he had experienced fatigue.  Blood glucoses had been well controlled.  His daughter in law brought in extensive data on his home vital signs, which revealed absence of fever except for a single isolated temp of 103, with stable pulse/BP, and overall well controlled blood sugars.    



Date 		ESR	CRP

12/6/87	88 	23

12/19/87	96	28

1/18/88	67	9.4



Unfortunately,  Mr. Moss sustained a mechanical fall 1/19.  Following the fall, he had significantly increased hip pain.  Hip/pelvis films notable for femoral component with lucency measuring more than 2mm superolaterally and along the stem. Orthopedic team felt that loosening of hardware would require another hip revision.  



ROS: as per HPI.  Denied having R hip pain prior to his fall.  No cough, sore throat, chest discomfort, abdominal pain, dysuria, diarrhea.  Extensive ROS otherwise negative.



PmHx: 

h/o L shoulder septic joint s/p I/D in  10/87 c/b hemorrhage as per HPI CHF (EF 20-25%)

s/p 5 hip surgeries, s/p bilateral hip replacements.  S/p R THA with revision x 2, last 2081 (Kent), s/p l THA with revision x 1.

Afib, maintained on coumadin

DMII, diagnosed ~20 years ago.  Unsure of last A1c

CRI (baseline Cr ~1.6-1.7) 

HTN

Parkinson's  disease,

prostate ca s/p radiation c/b radiation proctitis, 

LGIB, thought secondary to radiation proctitis.  Was to have a colonoscopy this week.  Admitted with GIB 12/87.

s/p multiple knee surgeries

GERD

melanoma s/p excision

s/p cholecystectomy.  



Meds on admission:

Protonix, isosorbide, MVI, lasix, hydralazine, sucralfate, flomax, FeSo4, senna, avodart, sinemet, coumadin, quinine, lantus/novolog.



Current medications:

Iron, quinine, isosorbide, lasix, hydral, insulin, sinemet,flomax, avodart, nexium, requip, sucralfate



All/adverse rxn: NKDA



Social history: widowed, lives with family, who are very involved in his care.  No tobacco, EtOH, or IVDU.  Retired.  



FHx: Noncontributory



P.E. 

VS: 97.4 76 118/97 18 98%RA

Gen: found lying flat in bed, in no acute distress

Skin: no rashes.  Multiple areas of ecchymoses, with some skin breakdown, on extremities bilaterally (he attributes this to multiple falls)

HEENT: anicteric, conjunctiva uninjected.  No sinus tenderness.  No nasal d/c.  No sores/lesions in oral cavity.  No thrush

Neck: supple, no JVD, no LAD.  

Cor: irregular rhythm, nl S1 S2, II/VI SEM at RUSB

Chest: clear to auscultation and percussion

Abd: soft, NT/ND, +BS x4, no hepatomegaly, no spleen tip palpable.  

Extr: acyanotic, nonedematous.  

Back: no midline or CVA tenderness

Shoulder: L shoulder non-erythematous, not significantly tender to palpation, though does have pain with active motion.  No exudate.  Can forward flex past 90, abduct to 45.

Hip: minimal tenderness to palpation of R hip (though just given pain meds);  unable to flex or abduct hip (was able to on Wednesday in clinic).  

Neuro: MS: awake, alert, oriented to person, place, time.  CN II-XII intact.  Motor exam limited by shoulder pain, though strength exam non-focal when adjusted for injuries.  Mildly shuffling gait noted on Wednesday in clinic,not tested today.  Resting tremor, pill rolling.  

Lines: no erythema.



Laboratory Data:

SODIUM                           134              *        (136-142)      mmol/L

POTASSIUM                        4.1                       (3.5-5.0)      mmol/L

CHLORIDE                         95               *        (98-108)       mmol/L

TOTAL CO2                        27                        (23-32)        mmol/L

GLUCOSE                          100                       (54-118)       mg/dL

UREA N                           99               *        (9-25)         mg/dL

CREATININE                       2.5              *        (0.7-1.3)      mg/dL



WBC                              8.66                      (4-10)         K/uL

HCT                              34.1             *        (40-54)        %

PLT                              252                       (150-450)      K/uL

POLY                             87               *        (48-76)        %

BAND                             4                *        (0-3)          %



PT                               17.9             *        (11.8-14.6)    sec

PTT                              33.2                      (23.8-36.6)    sec

PT(INR)                          1.5              *        (0.9-1.1)





Micro Data: 

None recently



Shoulder aspirate as per HPI (S aureus, pan sensitive)



Imaging:

Pelvis/Hip (right) films:  Bilateral total hip arthroplasties without any acute fracture or dislocation.  The acetabular component demonstrates vertical inclination with evidence of polyethylene wear. The femoral component demonstrates lucency measuring more than 2mm superolaterally and along the stem consistent with granulomatous disease. There is no subsidence or loosening based on Grauer's classification.



AP chest film: no acute pulmonary process, probable cardiomegaly.



Assessment: 77 yo M with DMII, CHF (EF 20-25%), afib, Parkinson's, prostate cancer s/p XRT c/b proctitis and GIB, multiple hip replacements, recently treated for S. aureus L shoulder septic arthritis (10/87 - 11/87) who presented 1/19 s/p fall.  With regards to his shoulder, it is difficult to know whether his infection was cured by the 4-week abx course.  Though his shoulder does not appear to be grossly infected on exam, 2 months after completion of his course, it is too early to determine sterilization of the shoulder on a clinical basis.  The MRI is difficult to interpret, and may well reflect prior inflammatory changes.  He did have persistently elevated inflammatory markers (though confounded by multiple comorbidities).  Given the possibility that he had cleared the infection, our plan as of the clinic visit Wednesday had been to observe him clinically, off abx, for signs of recurrent infection.  However, given his fall and the possibility of new hardware placement, would now favor a more aggressive workup of his shoulder.  As such, would recommend shoulder aspiration off antibiotics.  



The source for the L shoulder staph infection was never elucidated, and blood cultures were negative.  However, such septic arthritis often results from hematogenous seeding, and there is a small change that his R hip may also have become infected.  This could help to explain the prosthesis loosening.  Alternatively, he may have had hardware mechanical failure in setting of falls, or less likely involvement by his prostatic ca (?read of granulomatous disease around the prosthesis).  



Recommendations:

-hold antibiotics, including pre-operative prophylactic antibiotics to allow optimal culture data

-Aspirate shoulder.  Send fluid for cell counts, Gram stain, aerobic/anaerobic/fungal cultures

-if do not see contraindication to proceeding with planned hip replacement

-would obtain hip biopsies in the OR, again off abx, to assess for possible hip infection

-likewise, would send OR hip specimen to pathology to assess for infection vs. neoplastic involvement

-check CK, given elevated Cr following fall, and possible rhabdo



Thank you for this interesting consultation.  We will continue to follow with you.

___________

Yair Gillespie 

Pager #52719

Infectious disease fellow 









****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2088-09-04




Beckley Appalachian Regional Hospital
315 Townsend West              MOSS, DEREK
Espanola, WI  85976                    89659991
895-239-5445                     09/04/2088


REASON FOR VISIT:  Follow up with Mr. Derek Moss who is here with his son and daughter-in-law with multiple problems and for preop check of electrolytes.  Mr. Moss is 78 years old.

MEDICAL PROBLEM LIST:
1.  Diabetes mellitus type 2, insulin dependent.
2.  Left shoulder pain.  Scheduled for surgical care tomorrow.
3.  GI bleeding, ongoing.
4.  Parkinson's disease.
5.  Fatigue.
6.  BCE.

MEDICATIONS:  Medication list updated on the LMR.  Major change is furosemide now 60 mg b.i.d. instead of 80.

INTERIM HISTORY:
1.  Hyperkalemia occurred on higher dose of Lasix.  Apparently this has been a problem in the past.  He also bumped his creatinine to 2.3.  Potassium rechecked today and is now down to 5.1, stable creatinine.
2.  Diabetes.  Blood sugars running in the 80s in the morning, higher later in the day on 16 units of Lantus sliding scale to cover other meals.  Uses regular insulin about twice a day.
3.  GI bleeding ongoing by Mr. Moss's report, still having clots of blood, no abdominal pain, has not had GI follow up recently, is off Coumadin prior to shoulder repair.
3.  Skin lesions, one on his left leg, one on his right medial leg and a lump on his back noticed by his daughter when she was giving him a therapeutic massage.
4.  Left shoulder pain.  Scheduled for surgery in the a.m.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is brighter, cheerier, acutely oriented.  No acute pain.  Vital Signs:  Blood pressure 126/57, pulse 66 and regular, respirations 12 and unlabored, weight 161.  Skin shows seborrheic keratoses, actinic keratoses on the right leg, papule with eschar on the left leg, a subcutaneous nodule on the right upper back.  Chest is clear P&A.  Cardiac exam regular rate and rhythm, normal S1, S2, II/IV apical systolic murmur radiating to the left sternal border.  No gallop.  Extremities, trace edema.  Decreased ROM R shoulder.  Abdomen soft.  Neurologic, alert and oriented.

IMPRESSION AND PLAN:  Hyperkalemia resolving.  Discussed importance of careful fluid balance, low-protein diet given azotemia, renal follow up, follow up with GI for GI bleeding, blood transfusions are available.  Continue lower dose of Lasix.  Skin lesions include seborrheic dermatitis, seborrheic keratoses, possible lipoma, although lump on his back is firm and may need a biopsy once he has recovered from shoulder surgery.  Long consultation with him and his daughter regarding home care after surgery.


______________________________
Ursula Yawn, MD





eScription document:7-9274121 EMSSten Tel



DD: 09/04/88
DT: 09/05/88
DV: 09/04/88



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2089-03-11

EDVISIT^89659991^MOSS, DEREK^03/11/89^GODFREY, XAVIER GEORGE

I saw this patient with the resident, Dr. Louvinia Duvall.  Please

see her note for further details.  I confirm that I have

interviewed and examined the patient, reviewed the resident's

documentation on the patient's chart, and discussed the

evaluation, plan of care, and disposition with the patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a 78-year-old male

with a history of diabetes, hypertension, atrial fibrillation,

congestive heart failure, prostate cancer, chronic renal

insufficiency, and Parkinson disease previously hospitalized 2

weeks prior for right lower extremity cellulitis, which he had a

PICC line placed, and was discharged to home on vancomycin. 

Since that time, he has had progressively increase in his

creatinines despite decreasing doses of vancomycin.  He was

concerned and requested that the patient to come in for a

possible acute renal failure secondary to the antibiotic.  There

is also concern that cellulitis had worsened, as the patient was

experiencing increasing weakness.  He is denying currently any

fevers, chills, or constitutional symptoms.  His baseline

shortness of breath has been going on for months.  No GI

complaints.  He has had a mild headache, but no visual changes,

no focal motor or sensory loss.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: The systems reviewed and found to be negative.

MEDICATIONS:  He has a long list of medications Please see the

chart.

ALLERGIES:  Morphine.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Reviewed and found to be noncontributory.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Reviewed and found to be noncontributory.

PAST SURGICAL HISTORY:  Cholecystectomy and bilateral total hip

replacement.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  He is awake, alert, nontoxic appearing,

and in no acute distress.  Vital signs reviewed and found to be

within normal limits.  Afebrile at 95.6.  HEENT exam is

unremarkable.  Mucosal membranes are moist.  Neck is supple. 

Lungs are clear bilaterally.  Heart is regular rate and rhythm,

no murmurs or gallops.  Abdomen:  Soft, nondistended, and

nontender with normoactive bowel sounds.  Skin is warm and dry. 

Extremity exam:  He has right lower extremity cellulitis with 2

small ulcerations and serosanguineous drainage is minimal.  No

evidence of pus.  It is about where it was at the start based on

the initial skin markings.

LABORATORY DATA:  Hematocrit of 32.  However, his BUN has been

150 and creatinine of 3.  This has significantly increased from

his baseline of 1.8-2 he has had in the past.  Vancomycin level

was sent.

DIAGNOSIS:  Cellulitis with acute renal insufficiency most likely

secondary to vancomycin.  This was discussed with his primary

care provider.

DISPOSITION:  He is admitted to the Medicine Service.

______________________________

GODFREY, XAVIER GEORGE MD

D: 03/17/89

T: 03/17/89

Dictated By: GODFREY, XAVIER GEORGE

eScription document:7-3638497 BFFocus

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2090-02-18

                                                       Patient Name: MOSS,DEREK P [ 89659991(QMC) ] 

                                                         Date of Visit: 02/18/2090





Problems

      Parkinsons disease

      Diabetes mellitus type 2

      Congestive heart failure

      Atrial fibrillation

      Pacemaker

      Gastroesophageal reflux disease

      Hyperlipidemia

      Chronic renal dysfunction

      H/O basal cell carcinoma

      H/O prostate cancer



Chief Complaint

Comes in for his 2 month follow up visit



History of Present Illness

79 year old male comes in with his son for a follow up.

He reports right LE swelling and redness increasing over the last 1 week.  Patient and his son also noted right big toe swelling and ulceration yesterday.  They stated that the did not look at bilateral feet for the last 4-5 days.  The patient reports pain in the right foot as well.  He has no h/o fevers.  The patient has a VNA nurse that was dicontinued by the family 1 week ago.





Past Medical History

Parkinson's disease

Diabetes mellitus type 2

Atrial fibrillation

Hyperlipidemia

Pacemaker

CHF (Ischemic cardiomyopathy with an EF of 25-30%)

Moderate AS/ moderate MR 

CKD

GERD

OA s/p bilateral hip replacements

Prostate Cancer diagnosed in 2084 s/p XRT in 2085 with h/o radiation proctitis

Basal cell carcinoma excision

 

Past Surgical History

Lumbar laminectomy in the 2060s

Left septic shoulder s/p placement of a prosthetic shoulder placement in 2087

Bilateral THR s/p RH revision 2/88

H/o bilateral knee surgeries x 4 (2 surgeries on each side)

Cholecystectomy for gall stones in 2084





Social History

Widowed in 2081

Smoking-None

Alcohol-None

Illicit drug use-None

Occupation-Was a vocational instructor

Health care proxy-Yes, son (West)





Allergies

      DUTASTERIDE    - cough, 

      Morphine    - Mental Status Change



Medications

      ASA   81 MG PO QD 

      Ferrous Sulfate   325 MG (325(65)MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

      FUROSEMIDE   80 MG (80MG TABLET take 1) PO BID x 30 days

      Hydralazine Hcl   10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO TID 

      Imdur Er (ISOSORBIDE Mononitrate (SR))   120 MG (120MG TAB.SR 24H take 1) PO QD x 90 days, pt needs increase in dose for afterload reduction for severe MR. Substitution permitted.

      Insulin Regular Human   6 UNITS SC as directed based on BG , at meals pending BG levels

      Lantus (INSULIN Glargine)   16 UNITS SC QHS , Lantus #3 vials 3rf

      LISINOPRIL   2.5 MG PO QD 

      MULTIVITAMINS   1 TAB PO QD 

      Nitroquick 0.3mg (NITROGLYCERIN 1/200 (0.3 Mg))   1 TAB SL as directed PRN emergency 

      Procrit (EPOETIN Alfa)   6000 UNITS SC Q OTHER WEEK , Dose reduced per order Dr. Dunlap

      Protonix (PANTOPRAZOLE)   40 MG PO QD 

      Requip (ROPINIROLE)   2 MG (1MG TABLET take 2) PO TID 

      Silver Sulfadiazine 1%   1 APPLICATION TOP BID PRN  , cream

      Toprol Xl (METOPROLOL Succinate Extended Release)   12.5 MG (25MG TAB.SR 24H take 0.5) PO QHS 

      Warfarin Sodium   5 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 2) PO QPM 

      Zocor (SIMVASTATIN)   20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 



Vital Signs

      BLOOD PRESSURE   115/55 

      PULSE   70 

      TEMPERATURE   96.3 F

      WEIGHT   152 lb



Physical Exam

      General Appearance

Alert, sitting, comfortably on the examination table, oriented, in no acute distress

      HEENT

PERRL/EOMI, Nose-no congestion, Throat-clear, no lesions

      Neck

Supple

      Cor/Cardiac

S1 S2 +, irregularly irregular rhythm, no murmurs

      Chest

Clear to auscultation bilaterally, no wheezing

      Abdomen

Soft, no organomegaly, BS +

      Extremity

No cyanosis, clubbing, or edema.

Sleeves on all 4 extremities covering dressings.

Improvement in the forearm abrasions.

Right big toe with a 1.5 x 1.5 cm ulcer with granulation tissue and surrounding erythema.  Abscess collection visible at the lateral toe.

Erythema, swelling, and warmth noted in the right LE up to the middler of the lower leg.



      Neurological

No resting tremor, CNs II-XII intact, increased tone all extremities, walks with a walker, has bradykinesia

      Nodes/Lymphatic

No lymphadenopathy



Assessment and Plan

Right foot diabetic ulcer and right LE cellulitis:

-Advised to go to the QMC ER as soon as possible to start IV antibiotics.

-Patient will needs debridement and incision and drainage of his right big toe ulcer and abscess.

-Expect message left with the charge nurse at QMC.

 

RTC after discharge from the hospital.



______________________________

Frank T. Xuan, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>