<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2081-03-22

Chief Complaint of:  Nephrolithiasis



2/28/81 cysto, left stent, ESWL,meatal dilatation



History of Present Illness:  50 yo male here for removal of his stent.   He denies fevers, nausea, chest pain, shortness of breadth (at baseline), and vomiting.  Voiding symptoms:  hesitancy, intermittency, nocturia x1 3/week, no frequency, and intermittent urgency.  Reports erectile dysfunction-difficulty maintaining erections.

                     

Past Medical History:  NIDDM, neurofibromatosis, Hodgkins disease-chemo and XRT (bleomycin, adriamycin, vincristine, DTIC)



Past Surgical History:  left axillary biopsy, pectus excavatum, neck surgery



Medications: metformin, urocit K, ibuprofen PRN



Allergies: he reports an allergy to contrast in the past but did well with his last CT scan.



Social History:

Single

Does not smoke

No alcohol use

Retired from dc comics



Family Hx: 

No history of stones

Mother - died of sarcoma

Father -died of an MI

Sister with ITP



Review of Systems: 

No interval change



Genitourinary Review of Systems

No Kidney stones in the past

No Urinary tract infections

No Sexually transmitted diseases		



Physical Examination:

General Examination:

Vital Signs:

Morbid obesity

BP 154/82

cor RRR

lung CTAB

abd soft 

No CVAT

LE no calf tenderness



cystoscopy

Patient was placed in the supine  position and prepped and draped in the standard sterile fashion.  Lidocaine jelly was inserted into the meatus for local anaesthesia.  A flexible cystoscope was inserted into the meatus.  The urethra was without lesions.  The lateral lobes of the prostate coapted at the midline.  The stent was identified and using alligator forceps the distal portion was grasped.  It was removed intact.  The patient tolerated the procedure and was discharged from the clinic after receiving ciprofloxacin.



Laboratory Values:

An independent review of a urinalysis shows:

                          No WBC's

                          +  RBC's

                          No Glucose

                          No Protein

                          Nitrite Negative

                          pH  7.0



Abdomen Single                 22-Mar-2081 

REPORT:

	History: As above.

	Comparison:Noncontrast CT abdomen and pelvis 3/14/81.

	Findings:

	There is a left ureteral stent.  Tiny residual stones seen on

	prior CT are not identified on this KUB.The bowel gas pattern is

	nonobstructive.      The bones are unremarkable in appearance. The

	visualized lung bases are unremarkable.

IMPRESSION:

	LEFT URETERAL STENT.  NO ABNORMAL CALCIFICATIONS IDENTIFIED.

		

	

Impression:  50 yo male treated for a 1.1 cm symptomatic left renal stone.   His post-operative KUB does not show any calcifications.  The stent was removed intact without difficulty.   He is to have a follow up CT in June with and without contrast for further evaluation of a renal lesion seen on a previous CT scan.  He did have a post-operative CT that showed a subcapsular hematoma for which his blood pressure will be followed.   That study also showed the stone which is no longer visualized on todays KUB.  The imaging in June will again assess his stone burden.

        

Plan:   

1  CT abd/pelvis I-/I+ in June



Follow Up:  in June



Patricia Barajas, MD

Urology- Gila Regional Hospital





Please note: This email may contain confidential patient information which is legally protected by patient-physician privilege.  If you are not the intended recipient, you are hereby notified that any disclosure, copying, or distribution of this information is strictly prohibited by law.  If you have received this communication in error, please notify us by telephone at once and destroy any electronic or paper copies.  We apologize for any inconvenience.





cc:







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-04-28




















Medicine &#8211; Mediquik 6 Intern Admission Note



PATIENT: Gillespie, Patrick

MRN: 2571454

ADMIT DATE: Tuesday 4/28/84

PCP: Dr. Yakov Xie

ATTENDING: Ward (Dr. Wiggins / Dr. Stone)

CONTACT: sister Snow 241-904-0696

SOURCE: patient and records



CC/ID: cough



HPI

Mr Gillespie is a 53 yo man with a history of NIDDM and hypertension who presented to House Of Calvary Hospital today with a chief complaint of cough for the last 5 days.  He was in his usual state of health prior to that.  Cough has been dry; also notes shortness of breath with exertion and diaphoresis.  He notes intermittent palpitations and mild lightheadedness during the last few days.  He has had pneumonia several times in the past.  He denies fever, chills, SOB at rest, orthopnea, PND, chest pain, wheezing, hemoptysis, and sick contacts.   He reports compliance with his medications and no recent change in diet.  At Calvary, CXR was interpreted as bilateral pneumonia L&gt;R.  EKG revealed atrial fibrillation, of which he had no known history.  He was referred to the GRH ED for further evaluation.



In the ED he was afebrile, HR 130s-140s (atrial fibrillation)  SBP 140s  O2 sat 99-100%.  On exam he had fine bibasilar crackles.  He was given levofloxacin 750 mg po, dalteparin 5000 units, diltiazem 10 mg iv and 30 mg po with lowering of HR to 90s, and NS 500 cc.  He was admitted to Medicine &#8211; Mediquik 77 for further management.



REVIEW OF SYSTEMS

General &#8211; +sweats, no weight loss/gain, no fever, no chills, no change in appetite

HEENT &#8211; no neck swelling, no neck stiffness, no hoarseness, no hearing loss

Pulmonary &#8211; per HPI, no hemoptysis, no wheezing

Cardiac &#8211; +palpitations, no chest pain/pressure, no PND

Gastrointestinal &#8211; no N/V, no diarrhea, no constipation, no BRBPR, no melena, no abd pain

Genitourinary &#8211; no hematuria, no dysuria, no polyuria, no nocturia

Extremity &#8211; no leg swelling

Musculoskeletal &#8211; no back pain, no neck pain, no leg pain, no arm pain, no joint pain 

Hematologic &#8211; no bruising, no bleeding

Neuro &#8211; no seizures, no headache, no weakness, no numbness/tingling

Skin &#8211; no new concerning rashes or lesions

Exposures &#8211; no sick contacts, no recent travel



PAST MEDICAL HISTORY

NIDDM &#8211; A1c 6.4 last month

Hypertension

Hyperlipidemia

Nephrolithiasis

Neurofibromatosis

Pectus excavatum

Hodgkin&#8217;s disease &#8211; diagnosed in 2070; s/p XRT, chemo (bleomycin, adriamycin, vincristine, DTIC), and surgical 

Resection; oncologist Dr. Bass at MAC

Pneumonia &#8211; multiple times in past



PAST SURGICAL HISTORY

Left axillary biopsy

L neck/shoulder surgery (to remove Hodgkin&#8217;s tumor)

Surgery for pectus excavatum



RECENT DIAGNOSTIC STUDIES

Adeno-MIBI 2082: negative for ischemia, maybe a small inferior wall scar, LV fxn at lower limit of normal

Chest CT 3/25/84: Homogeneous soft tissue mass in the right apical paraspinal region that is slightly fusiform in morphology (2.6 x 2.6 cm x 4 cm) with imaging features suggestive of a neurogenic tumor (ganglioneuroma, neurofibroma, schwannoma). No evidence of associated osseous change or extension into the neural foramina.



MEDICATIONS ON ADMISSION

ASA 81 mg daily

Metformin 1000 mg bid

Lisinopril 10 mg daily

Simvastatin &#8211; not sure of dose

Flovent 2 puffs bid (started 1 month ago for cough)



ALLERGIES/ADVERSE REACTIONS

IV contrast &#8211; SOB, nausea



FAMILY HISTORY

Mother &#8211; DM, died of sarcoma, Father - died of an MI, Sister with ITP, Brother and Sister have neurofibromatosis



SOCIAL HISTORY

Native of Edgefield.  Lives in Edgefield with his brother.  On disability.  Volunteers - animal rescue.  No current or previous tobacco.  Rare EtOH.  No illicits.



PHYSICAL EXAMINATION

Vitals  97.7  92  141/69  18  98% 3L

General &#8211; obese, breathing comfortably

HEENT &#8211; sclerae anicteric, MMM

Neck &#8211; supple, no LAD

Pulmonary &#8211; good air movement, no crackles or wheezes, decreased breath sounds at L base

Cardiac &#8211; irreg irreg rhythm, no m/g/r, nl LV heave; pectus excavatum

Abdomen &#8211; +BS, obese, soft, nontender, nondistended

Extremity &#8211; warm, 2+ DP pulses bilaterally, trace bilateral lower extremity edema, no foot ulcers

Neuro &#8211; CNs 2-12 grossly intact, normal sensation to light touch, 5/5 strength bilaterally

Skin &#8211; multiple 5mm elevated round vesicular lesions on face, chest, and back



LABS

143 / 4.3 / 100 / 32.4 / 17 / 1.07 / 117     8.9 / 3.6 / 1.7

LFTs wnl

12.8 &gt; 39.8 &lt; 405   83% polys

INR 1.2



MICROBIOLOGY

Blood culture pending (sent)



RADIOLOGICAL STUDIES

CXR &#8211; no acute abnormalities, severe pectus excavatum and rib deformities noted, unchanged from the prior studies



EKG

Atrial fibrillation, L axis deviation, narrow QRS, QTc 438, incomplete RBBB, no concerning ST segment or T wave changes



ASSESSMENT AND PLAN

53 yo man with NIDDM and HTN presents with 5 days of cough and mild SOB, CXR reveals possible pneumonia, also noted to have new atrial fibrillation.



###ATRIAL FIBRILLATION &#8211; per patient, no history of a fib.  May have been triggered by pneumonia.  No chest pain to suggest recent MI.  No sign of PE.  Hemodynamically stable.  CHADS2 score 2, so warfarin is indicated for anticoagulation.  Unclear when this rhythm started, so will hold off on cardioversion.

- Rate control with po diltiazem

- Warfarin for anticoagulation; follow INR

- Check TTE, TSH



###PNEUMONIA &#8211; afebrile, but has elevated WBC count; also symptomatic cough and SOB, and history of pneumonia several times.  Will treat for community-acquired pneumonia.

- Levofloxacin 750 mg daily; plan for 10 day course (4/28-5/7)

- Check sputum and blood cultures



###DIABETES MELLITUS &#8211; RISS, FSG; hold metformin



###HYPERTENSION &#8211; will switch lisinopril to captopril 12.5 mg tid; also getting diltiazem as above



###DYSLIPIDEMIA &#8211; simvastatin 20 mg daily (does not know home dose)



###PROPHYLAXIS:  GI: none   DVT: dalteparin   BOWEL: Colace/Senna prn



FEN: Cardiac, ADA 1800 calorie



DISPO: to home once HR controlled



CODE: Full (confirmed &#8211; does not want prolonged intubation)







___________________________________

Marion Costa, MD

Internal Medicine PGY-1

Pager 67531 






****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-06-09


Medicine Attending Admit Note


June 9, 2084 
1340 h


I interviewed and examined the patient on rounds this morning with Dr. Lilly and with Team E and we reviewed the relevant data and discussed the case in detail.  I agree with the findings and recommendations in Dr. Lilly's note, with any small exceptions or points of emphasis noted below.  Please refer to it for details of HPI, PMH, medications and allergies, family and social history, laboratory and other data, and ROS.  I would only add/emphasize the following:



Mr. Gillespie is a 53 year-old man with medical history that includes: 

h/p Hodgkin&#8217;s lymphoma, 2070-2071, treated with local resection, bleomycin, adriamycin, and other agents, XRT to a wide chest field 
Atrial fibrillation - diagnosed in 3/84; on warfarin, metoprolol 
Pectus excavatum &#8211; repair failed as a child 
Pneumonia several times in the past 
Central obesity &#8211; weighs about 315#, down from a high of 360# 
Type II diabetes mellitus, last A1C 6.4, on metformin only, 1000 mg BID 
Hypertension, on lisinopril 10 mg, Toprol XL 
Elevated lipids - on statin 
Neurofibromatosis (Soft tissue mass in right apex noted on 3/84 CT may be neurogenic tumor.) 
Kidney stones 
Patent foramen ovale


He presents with dyspnea, orthopnea, and palpitations as described by Dr. Lilly, and was found to be in atrial fibrillation/flutter with rapid ventricular response.  He has improved with heart rate control.  


Exam
VS - as noted
General - pleasant obese white man with severe pectus deformity.  Breathing with abdominal muscles tensed on expiration.  
CV - heart with regular rhythm, normal S1, prominent S2, and no murmurs, rubs, or gallops
Lungs - clear
Abdomen - obese
Extremities - minimal edema


Data  - reviewed in detail and are as in Dr. Lilly's note.  Bicarb 31, BNP 2050, WBC 15, INR 3.1.




Impression:  Poorly tolerated atrial fibrillation/flutter with RVR, needing better rate control.  Given the severe pectus deformity as well as his history of lung-toxic chemotherapy drugs and XRT, he may have some restrictive lung disease that would limit his cardiopulmonary reserve.  I would not be surprised if he additionally has obstructive lung disease, given the "belly breathing" and the wheezing he had last admission.  


Recommendations:  

Increase metoprolol dose.  May need Toprol XL 100 BID.  Best to maximize utility of BB prior to adding other agents.

Filter all IVs (PFO)
PFTs and Pulmonology consult as an outpatient
Balance of plan per Dr. Lilly.






Peter Wiggins, MD, PhD
pager 32089







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2084-06-15



PATIENT: Patrick Gillespie
MRN: 2571454
ADMIT DATE: 6/13/84
TRANSFER DATE: 6/15/84
ATTN: Wright




Reason for admission/transfer: aflutter starting on sotalol


HPI
Please see admission note for full details.


In brief, this is a 54 y/o M hx neurofibromatosis, Hodgkin's lymphoma s/p chemo/XRT in the 70s, DMII (A1c 6.5 in 03/84), HTN, obesity and new diagnosis of Afib, recently discharged from the Mediquik 2 days prior to readmission 6/13 where he was being treated for AF w/ RVR.  His toprol was increased from 100mg dily to 100mg BID at that time. Prior w/u w/ fairly nl TTE and nl TSH. Now returned for his third admission with AF w/ RVR, rates into the 140s. He is considerably symptomatic with the AF w/ palpitations, lightheadedness, dyspnea, and diaphoresis. HD stable. He has been on increasing doses of Toprol without effect given this is his third admission. 


MEDICAL HISTORY
NIDDM 
HTN
HL
Neurofibromatosis
Pectus excavatum
H/o Hodgkin's disease - diagnosed in 2070; s/p XRT, chemo (bleomycin, adriamycin, vincristine, DTIC), and surgical resection; oncologist Dr. Bass at MAC


ALLERGIES: IV contrast


For social history/ family history/ meds on admission please see admission note. 


HOSPITAL COURSE: 


PAF/ Flutter: In the Ed, he had been given IV lopressor 5mg  w/ 25mg PO lopressor w/o improvement and then was given 10mg IV dilt which brought HR down to 90s. He was also given 0.5mg digoxin for possible dig load. Given he was failing on Toprol 100mg BID his medications were switched to diltiazem 60mg q6hr to see if a different drug class might help. Cardiology/ EP was consulted for the possibility of ablation given this was his third admission and he is so symptomatic. EP decided to start the patient on sotalol 80-mg BID with the plan to increase sotalol to 120mg BID on 6/15 if Qtc remains stable ( &lt;500 msec). He is planned to received 5 doses of sotalol prior to dispo and if he remained in aflutter through 6/15 is to get DCCV on 6/16. He received his first and only dose in the pm 6/14. Overnight he was bradycardic into the 40s while sleeping. He had a 3.5 second pause however on telemetry. His heart rates have ranged from 45-60 in AFlutter. BPs 90s systolic. Per EP, as pt asleep, will con't sotalol. He is on coumadin for anticoagulation. INR goal 2-3. EP(Dr. Moody= fellow) and cards (PRM wright) are following. 


PUMP: echo 04/84 which demonstrated an elongated LA sLVH, EF 61%, tr TR, RSVP 41, RV nl. On ACEI. 


PULM: CXR in ED with pulm edema. Given 20mg PO lasix x1 for gentle diuresis. On 1 L O2 as of am 6/15 and lasix 10mg Iv x 1 again this am 6/15. Felt to be related to his AF. He does have a h/o repeated PNAs. On xopenex, flovent. 


FEN: Mild hyperK in the ED to 5.3. Received 30g kayexelate. Normalized. NPO at midnight 6/15 for possibel DCCV if still planned by E. 


Isabella Glenn Mathews, MD MSc,
Pager 43771



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>