<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2071-05-31

Walk-in clinic                                Xian, Imogene

                                              81376761

                                              5-31-71

 

 

HPI: Ms. Xian is a 74-year-old female who presented to clinic this 

evening for follow up of her diabetes. Patient was last seen in clinic in 

11-70 after which time she left for Ghana for the past six months. She 

returned this past Friday but has since run out of insulin. She states 

that she has been feeling well and has not had any problems but does not 

know the amount of insulin that she has been taking. It has been 

administered to her by a friend in Ghana. Our records show that when 

she left Ghana she was on a 70/30 of Humulin, 20 units per day and 

also 600mg of Rezulin and 20mg q.d. of Lipitor.

 

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS: Review of systems is positive for insulin dependent 

diabetes mellitus but other than that Ms. Xian is a fairly healthy woman. 

 

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION: On physical exam this evening her pulse is 80. Blood 

pressure was 152/80 in her left arm. Blood sugar was 262. It should be 

noted that she has not had any insulin since Sunday. Her weight was 116 1/2 

which reflects a 1/2 lb. weight loss since 11-70. Tonight her heart had a 

regular rate and rhythm at 80. Her neck veins were flat. Her lungs were 

clear to auscultation bilaterally and there was no evidence of peripheral 

edema. 

 

ASSESSMENT: Insulin dependent diabetes mellitus. 

 

PLAN: LFTs, A1C, basic panel this evening. Glucotrol 10mg dispense No. 60 

with 1 refill b.i.d. A VNA referral for medication management and patient 

was instructed to return to the clinic on Saturday 6-05 for repeat blood 

sugar and also to bring her glucometer at that time so that it could be 

calibrated correctly. 

 

 

________________________________

Grace Vann, R.N.P.                                                  

 

DG:WA:1749                                                              

DD:5-31-71                                                               

DT:6-1-71                                                               

DV:5-31-71                                                               





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2072-07-30




SCHLESWIG COUNTY CLINIC
Walk-in clinic
24 Weld St
Grandview, NE  13472

Xian, Imogene
64187177
07/30/72

CHIEF COMPLAINT:  Ms. Xian is a 75-year-old female who presented 
to the walk-in clinic this evening as a walk-in with a chief 
complaint of bilateral foot pain especially in the toe area, and 
she says that this has been going on for approximately two 
months.

ALLERGIES:  She denies any known drug allergies.

MEDICATIONS:  At present, she is taking Glucophage 500 mg one 
p.o. q.a.m, two p.o. q.p.m., Avandia 2 mg one p.o. q.a.m., Plavix 
75 mg one p.o. q.d., glipizide 5 mg two p.o. q.a.m., and two p.o. 
q.p.m., and Lipitor 20 mg q.d.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  The patient states that she has had constant 
pain in her toes and at times with a feeling of tingling.  
Otherwise, she states she has been feeling well.  She denies any 
chest pain or heart palpitation.  She denies any shortness of 
breath.  She denies any nausea, vomiting or diarrhea.  She denies 
any frequency, dysuria or thirst.  She has a history of non-
insulin-dependent diabetes at this time.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Her temperature was 98.5 degrees p.o., her 
pulse was 80, her blood pressure was 118/60 in her right arm.  
Her weight was 117 pounds, which reflects a one-pound weight loss 
since her last visit.  Her blood sugar, which was random, was 
159, her last meal being at 12 noon.  Her son, who accompanied 
her states that it is questionable whether she is taking her 
medications as instructed and voiced an interest in having his 
mother take insulin, which she has taken in the past.  Her heart 
had a regular rate and rhythm at 80.  There was no evidence of 
any peripheral edema.  Examination of her toes revealed presence 
of some tinea interdigitally.

ASSESSMENT:
1.  Non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, moderate control.
2.  Tinea pedis.

PLAN:  Medication refills were given for Glucotrol 5 mg dispensed 
No. 120 with two refills, two p.o. q.a.m., two p.o. q.p.m., 
Glucophage 500 mg No. 90 one p.o. q.a.m., two p.o. q.p.m., and 
Avandia 2 mg No. 30 with two refills one p.o. q.a.m., and a new 
prescription for Lotrimin AF 1% cream dispensed 12 g with one 
refill, apply to the affected area b.i.d. for up to four weeks.




Xian, Imogene
64187177
07/30/72
Page 2

The patient has an appointment scheduled with her primary care 
provider Dr. Paul Shaw for 8/16/72, and was advised to 
keep that appointment.



Grace Vann, N.P.

GV:arreola:06:278:08;37-60093.doc;DD:07/30/72;DT:08/01/72;DV:07/30/72;





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2073-05-29


Internal Medicine
97 Weld St                                        Xian, Imogene
Grandview, NE 13472                                      81376761
(552) 598-5590                                           05/29/73


HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  Ms. Xian is 75 years of age. 
She has adult-onset diabetes, which in the past has required
treatment with insulin.  She has been managed with oral
hypoglycemics because of her reticence to using injections. 
She also has a history of CVA.

I last saw her in August of last year.  She was seen by Ms.
Vann, our nurse practitioner in early May.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Glipizide 5 mg two in the morning and
two in the evening, Plavix 75 mg one p.o. q.d., and Avandia
2 mg one p.o. q.a.m.  According to Ms. Vann's note of Apr
29, 2073, she is also supposed to be taking metformin 500 mg
one in the morning and two with the evening meal as was
prescribed back in 2072.  The patient and her son today are
not sure that she is taking this medication.  In fact, they
believe that she is not.  There has been moderate polyuria
and polydipsia.  Control of diabetes has been erratic. 
Hemoglobin A1c has been elevated.  On Apr 29, 2073, blood
glucose was 274, BUN was 25, creatinine 1.0, electrolytes
within normal limits as was calcium.  Cholesterol was 315. 
Hemoglobin A1c 10.6.  The patient has not experienced chest
pain, palpitations but she is moderately short of breath
when climbing stairs.  There has been no orthopnea and no
PND.  She denies dysuria and urgency and has not experienced
near syncope.  She denies nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, and
constipation.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  On physical examination today, she
appears well.  Blood pressure 122/66.  The heart rate is 90
and regular, weight 113 pounds, approximately five pounds
less than last year.  Random blood glucose was 224.

The patient suffered a minor CVA back in September 2071. 
She denies any recurrence of motor deficits or symptoms
suggestive of TIA.  The patient has a past history of
hyperthyroidism that was treated with iodine 131.  She has
not been hypothyroid since then.  In fact, the last TSH
level was 0.05 in August of last year, just prior to her
departure to Ghana.  She denies heat intolerance as well
as palpitations.

On physical examination, she is a small lady in no acute
distress.  The neck veins are flat.  The extraocular
movements are full.  There are no symptoms of
hyperthyroidism.  The chest is clear to auscultation.  The
heart sounds are regular.  There are no rubs or gallops. 
The lower extremities are free of edema and now her toes are
free of fungi but the nails are overgrown and require
attention.

ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:  A 76 year old woman with a past
history of hyperthyroidism, which was treated with I-131
with good results who, last year before she left the
country, had a subnormal TSH.  She does not have obvious
symptoms of hyperthyroidism but today I have obtained a
repeat TSH as well as T3 and T4.

Diabetes continues to be a problem.  Glycemic control
continues to be difficult to achieve.  Today, I have
reinstated metformin at 500 mg p.o. q.d.  The son is going
to check on the medications to make certain that indeed she
is not taking this medicine at this point.  The other
medications were continued.  It is indeed possible that she
will need insulin in the near future.  I plan close followup
and will see her again in six weeks' time.  If she is
hyperthyroid, this may also explain the difficulty in
achieving glycemic control.  Against this is the high
cholesterol.  She used to be on Lipitor, which was
discontinued during her trip to Ghana.  I have
reinstated the Lipitor today 20 mg p.o. q.d.  I have also
added a small dose of enalapril 2.5 mg p.o. q.d. to protect
her kidneys even though she is not hypertensive.


______________________________
Kevin Shamar-Trevino, M.D.


eScription document:0-389401 NFFocus

DD: 05/29/73
DT: 05/30/73
DV: 05/29/73



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2080-06-15


Walk-in visit because of  
Pt of Dr Shamar 
Seen in the EW bo  HA , work up negative. Basicallty the diagnosis was anxiety. It seems she's very lonely here,  lives with son who works long hours.   In the EW  it was recommended she antecipates her trip to Ghana because she  feels much better there.   Sent for fup with pcp . 
Symtpoms all resolved . Son needs a letter to  antecipate her airplane ticket 
She ahs no new complaints. 


Problems
TOXIC NODULAR GOITER 
ARTHRITIS 
CVA : In year 2071.
Hyperthyroidism : I-131 5 years ago.
Insulin dependent diabetic 
Hyperlipidemia 
Hypertension 
h/o urosepsis 
 
Medications
Actos (PIOGLITAZONE) 15 MG (15MG TABLET Take 1) PO q.d. #90 Tablet(s)
Calcium + D (600 MG ELEM CA) (CALCIUM CARBONATE 1500 MG (600 MG ELEM CA)/ VIT D 200 IU) 1 TAB PO BID #3 Month(s) Supply
Enteric COATED ASPIRIN (ASPIRIN ENTERIC COATED) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Insulin NPH HUMAN 17 UNITS SC as directed , 15 units in the morning and 5 units at night #3 Month(s) Supply
Lancets ONE UNIT (Take 1) PO bid x 90 days #180 units
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Lisinopril 10 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD x 90 days #90 Tablet(s)
Lopressor (METOPROLOL TARTRATE) 25 MG (25MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #3 Month(s) Supply
Micronase 5 MG PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Motrin (IBUPROFEN) 400 MG (400MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #30 Tablet(s)
Onetocuh Ultra Soft Lancets ONE TOP As directed , Use as directed #1 Box(es)
Onetouch Test Strips ONE TOP as directed , Use as directed #1 Box(es)
Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD #90 Tablet(s)


Social history:   smoking ( - )


ROS: 
Constitutional: Feels well.  Energy: good. Wt: stable       
ENT: no hearing loss, no ear pain, no nasal discharge   
Skin: no rashes, itching  
CV:  no chest pain,  no SOB, PND, DOE, no edema  
Respir: no cough, no wheezing   
GI: no nausea, no vomiting, no abdominal pain, heart burn, nl BM  
GU: no dysuria, no frequency, no urgency. 


PE:    Appears     well.  Legally blind. 
Vital Signs
BP 151/68, P 88, Wt 140 lb
FINGER BLOOD GLUCOSE 90 
O2 sat 99         
HEENT: NCAT, EOMI
Neck: no  cervical adenopathy 
Lungs:  clear bilaterally
Heart:  regular, normal S1 and S2.
Abd: Soft, non-tender. 
Extr: no edema. 


ASSESMENT AND PLAN: labs reviwed
DM : check A!C today
HTn :    increase lisinopril to 20 mg, check chem 
HL;  check  cho profile on lipitor. 
Anxxiety: letter to  antecipate  her  trip 







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-09-06


09/06/81


Follow up after long absence. Pt was seen last week by Dr.Anderson and prior to that she was at Chesterfield ED and prior to that her son reports that she had been in Ghanna. I suspect she has been under someone else's care since I never prescribed Glyburide, Actos and Insulin. The last  time I saw her in January I discontinued  Metformin because of GI intolerance and her regimen was Insulin only. She did not keep subsequent appointments.


She was seen at Chesterfield ED because of pyelonephritis/UTI treated with ceftriaxone and discharged on Nitrofurantoin. She has now completed the treatment. She feels better although there is still mild dysuria, denies chills and fever. course


Problems
TOXIC NODULAR GOITER 
ARTHRITIS 
CVA : In year 2071.
Hyperthyroidism : I-131 5 years ago.
Insulin dependent diabetic 
Hyperlipidemia 
Hypertension 
h/o urosepsis 


Medications
Actos (PIOGLITAZONE) 15 MG (15MG TABLET Take 1) PO q.d. #30 Tablet(s)
Calcium + D (600 Mg Elem Ca) (CALCIUM Carbonate 1500 Mg (600 Mg Elem Ca)/ Vit D 200 Iu) 1 TAB PO BID #3 Month(s) Supply
Clotrimazole 1% Cream 1 APPLICATION TOP BID, Apply between toes left foot #15 GM TUBE
Enteric Coated Aspirin (ASPIRIN Enteric Coated) 81 MG (81MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Insulin Nph Human 17 UNITS SC as directed, 15 units in the morning and 5 units at night #3 Month(s) Supply
Lancets ONE UNIT (Take 1) PO bid x 90 days #180 units
Levofloxacin 500 MG (500MG TABLET Take 1) PO Q48H #3 Tablet(s)
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD #90 Tablet(s)
Lisinopril 20 MG (20MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD x 90 days #90 Tablet(s)
Lopressor (METOPROLOL Tartrate) 25 MG (25MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #3 Month(s) Supply
Micronase 5 MG PO QD #30 Tablet(s)
Motrin (IBUPROFEN) 400 MG (400MG TABLET Take 1) PO BID #30 Tablet(s)
One Touch Glucometer 1 (Take 1) PO bid #1 Unit
Onetocuh Ultra Soft Lancets ONE TOP As directed, Use as directed #1 Box(es)
Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD #90 Tablet(s)


Soc Hx: Smoking (-) 


ROS: all other systems were reviewed and are negative.


PE: Appears elderly but in no distress.. Comes accompanied by son. 
Lungs: clear bilaterally
Heart: regular, normal S1 and S2.
Abd: Soft, non-tender, no CVA tenderness




ASSESMENT AND PLAN: 
UTI: Reculture now post Rx
DM:   she did not tolerate  Metformin. I have DC Actos and kept her on Glyburide and current dose of insulin. Instructed son to call if hypoglycemic or if Sx of UTI reccur. Plan to see her in one week and will then DC Glyburide. Son denies taking her to another MD. I will obtain a second urine culture and sensitivities
.


Kevin P. Shamar MD








****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>