<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2129-08-20

						July 06, 2129









Robert Trejo, M.D.

17 Unicorn Way

Suite 353

Chickasha, NC 75156



						RE:  Tyler Pearson

					                    WMC#727-19-02



Dear Doctor Trejo:



I had the pleasure of seeing our mutual patient, Mr. Tyler Pearson, in follow up evaluation in our vascular surgery clinic here today.  As you will remember he recently underwent right carotid endarterectomy with Dacron patch angioplasty after treatment of a severe underlying pneumonia.  He returns today reporting that he is doing well from a neurologic standpoint.  He has had no focal, motor, sensory deficits, and no amaurosis fugax.  A follow up duplex examination performed in our vascular laboratory reveals mild right ICA disease after his carotid endarterectomy with moderate left ICA stenosis which should be followed over time.  



Assessment and plan:  Overall, I am extremely pleased with Mr. Pearson's outcome given his high risk pulmonary status.  It would be prudent to see him again in follow up evaluation in six months' time with a repeat carotid duplex examination.  I would be happy to assist in the management of this or any of your other patients as you deem necessary in the future.  Thank you again for allowing me to assist in his care.  If I can be of any further assistance, please feel free to contact either myself or one of my partners directly.



						Sincerely,







						Steven E. Land, M.D.



SEL:kerns





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2132-05-27

Date 5/27/32
Time 4am
Team E Admission Note

Patient: Pearson, Tyler 
Medical Record Number: 727 19 02
Room: J8845I
Date of Admission: 5/26/32
PCP: Yale Triplett (Turner Clinic)
Attending Physician: Arias/Wesley
Admitting Intern: Jaquan Mahoney
Code Status: FULL CODE

Source: Patient, Medical Record

ID/CC:
87yoM h/o COPD, DM2, CVA p/w SOB, cough.

History of Present Illness:  
Patient w/ severe COPD (PFT not available).  Reports coughing x 3wks, productive of light, white sputum.  Has had intermittent, fluctuating symptoms of cough/DOE since then.  10d prior, seen at VGH ED and was discharged w/ prednisone (7d course).  He reports that his symptoms never improved on prednisone.  At baseline, he is able to walk 40-50y flat ground and several flights of stairs; limited by dyspnea.  Now, has dyspnea at rest and cannot climb 1 flight of stairs.  Saw his PCPs NP on the day of admission and was referred to WMC.  Denies clear precipitant, denies sick contacts, h/o seasonal allergies. 

In the ED, VS: T 98.1 HR 100-114 BP95/55-172/79 RR24-36 O2sat 96%4L.  He was noted to be visibly dyspneic, wheezes on exam w/ an irregular heartbeat.  He was transferred to trauma for close observation of respiratory status, although he did not require PPV or ABG.  BNP 136, cardiac markers neg x 1.  WBC returned at 17.5.  AP CXR was indeterminate for clear PNA.  Patient was started on albuterol/atrovent nebs, solumedrol 125mg, ceftriaxone/azithromycin for possible PNA.  

Review of Systems:
Chest pressure sensation,    muscle tightness   , L sided, intermittent lasting only minutes, nonradiating, non-exertional, nonpleuritic, non-positional.  
Patient denies the following symptoms.
CONSTITUTIONAL: f/c/r/sweats, anorexia/weight-loss 
HEENT: h/a/ear pain/sore throat/rhinorrhea
PULM:cough/SOB/DOE
CV: chest pain/palpitations/LH   dness/LOC/PND/LE swelling
ABD:abd px/n/v/constipation/diarrhea/melena/BPR/ bloating
GU: dysuria/frequency/urgency
SKIN: rash, bruising, mucosal bleeding
NEURO: unilateral weakness/paresthesia/dysphasia/dysphagia/visual change.

Past Medical/Surgical History:
COPD
	PFTs not in CAS
	Home O2: 2L at baseline (used continuously)
	No history of intubation
Cerebrovascular Disease
	R ICA stenosis 
		S/p R CEA for symptoms
	L ICA stenosis
		F/b Steven Land
Avoiding CEA given severe pulmonary disease
		On ASA, suggesting addition of plavix (not currently on)
DM2
BPH
PTSD
Lung CA
	S/p L lobectomy.


Allergies:
Tetracycline - unknown
Bactrim - unknown

Medications (on PCP note as of 5/3/32):
Tylenol prn
Albuterol inh qid prn
Albuterol neb qid
ECASA 325 qd
Ca + D 250/125 bid
Advair 250/50 bid
Lasix 10mg qd
Neurontin 300mg tid
Guaifenesin 300mg tid
Atrovent inhaler 2 puff qid
Loratidine 10 qd
Losartan 50 qd
Zantac 150 bid
Senna prn
Simvastatin 20 qd
Travoprost 0.004% OS qhs

Social History:
Lives in North Wilkesboro w/ wife.  Son lives first floor of same house.  Wife and family split responsibilities for his care-taking.  Has VNA.  Former civil engineer, supervisor, consultant.  + asbestos exposure.
TOB:3-4ppd x 40y.  stopped 40y prior
ETOH: social
ILLICITS: none

Family History:
Denies colon/prostate CA, DM, CVD.

Physical Examination:
GEN: 	appropriate, mildly dyspneic, worse with standing up
VS: 
T
98.1
P
111
BP
183/90
RR
28
O2SAT
94%4L
	
HEENT: 	MMM, JVP base of neck.  Conjunctiva clear.
PULM: 	partially broken sentences; mildly-moderately dyspneic.  incr expiratory:inspiratory ratio. Quiet BS bilaterally. Wheezing scattered.
CV: 	no bruits auscultated. Tachy, regular, S1 and S2 normal, no murmurs
ABD: 	soft, NT/ND/NM/NHSM. BS active
EXT: 	no c/c/e, DPs 2+ 
NEURO:   
MS 	A&Ox3
SKIN:		no rash, good skin turgor

Data: 
NA        	          	          	          	139       	          
K         	          	          	          	3.6       	          
CL        	          	          	          	101       	          
CO2       	          	          	          	33.9(H)   	          
BUN       	          	          	          	22        	          
CRE       	          	          	          	1.2       	          
GLU       	          	          	          	131(H)    	          

CA        	          	          	          	          	8.7       
PHOS      	          	          	          	          	2.7       
MG        	          	          	          	          	1.6       

TBILI     	          	          	          	          	0.4       
DBILI     	          	          	          	          	0.1       

TP        	          	          	          	          	8.0       
ALB       	          	          	          	          	3.3       
GLOB      	          	          	          	          	4.7(H)    
AMY       	          	          	          	          	72        
LIPS      	          	          	          	          	2.1       
ALT/SGPT  	          	          	          	          	25        
AST/SGOT  	          	          	          	          	21        
ALKP      	          	          	          	          	67        

NT-BNP    	          	          	          	          	136(T)    
CK        	30(L)     	          	          	          	          
CK-MB     	2.9       	Negative  	          	          	          
CKMBRI    	see detail	          	          	          	          
TROP-I    	          	Negative  	          	          	          
TROP-T    	<0.01     	          	          	          	          

WBC       	          	          	17.5(H)   	          	          
RBC       	          	          	5.31      	          	          
HGB       	          	          	14.8      	          	          
HCT       	          	          	47.1      	          	          
MCV       	          	          	89        	          	          
MCH       	          	          	27.9      	          	          
MCHC      	          	          	31.4      	          	          
PLT       	          	          	332       	          	          
RDW       	          	          	15.8(H)   	          	          
DIFFR     	          	          	Received  	          	          
METHOD    	          	          	Auto      	          	          
%NEUT     	          	          	83(H)     	          	          
%LYMPH    	          	          	12(L)     	          	          
%MONO     	          	          	4         	          	          
%EOS      	          	          	1         	          	          
%BASO     	          	          	0         	          	          
ANEUT     	          	          	14.77(H)  	          	          
ALYMP     	          	          	2.02      	          	          
AMONS     	          	          	0.64(H)   	          	          
AEOSN     	          	          	0.08(L)   	          	          
ABASOP    	          	          	0.03      	          	          
ANISO     	          	          	None      	          	          
HYPO      	          	          	None      	          	          
MACRO     	          	          	None      	          	          
MICRO     	          	          	None      	          	          

PT        	          	          	13.6(T)   	          	          
PT-INR    	          	          	1.1       	          	          
PTT       	          	          	25.3      	          	          


EKG tachycardia, at least two atrial foci. RBBB.
CXR L lower lung opacity. Poor film.

Impression/Plan: 
87yoM h/o COPD, vascular disease p/w SOB, cough.  Likely COPD flare.  High WBC may be steroids, but CXR too poor to rule out PNA.  Otherwise, no clear precipitant.  Failed steroids as outpatient (dosing unclear).  Given level of dyspnea, will treat w/ solumedrol for now, and transition to prednisone when improvement/trajectory is clear.  Patient may need a longer taper than over 10d.

SOB: COPD flare +/- PNA.
	-repeat CXR in AM.
-solumedrol 125mg q6 for now.  Transition to prednisone 1mg/kg when clinically stable.  Follow trend, decide on length of taper at later date.
-advair, spiriva.  Standing albuterol nebs q4 for now.  Space nebs when improvement demonstrated.
-keep O2 sats 88-92%
CHEST PRESSURE: follow for now.  Would deserve stress.  Unless  has more activity/symptoms while here, would defer to be done as outpatient.  Does have significant risk factors.
	-ROMI by markers.
	-telemetry.
	-ASA, ARB, statin.
	-start low dose beta-blocker to see if he tolerates.
HTN: likely exacerbated by steroids.  Will be moving target in setting of changing steroid dose.
	-c/w home ARB.
	-start lopressor 25 tid for now.
	-hydralazine 25mg q6h for immediate decrease in BP now.  Taper off when able.
DM2: no meds from home
	-RISS, FS qid.
	-check A1c.
FEN: no added salt, low cholesterol/fat, no conc sweets
PROPHY: fragmin, zantac.
CODE: full code (confirmed w/ patient)
DISPO: PT eval.


             			                                        
Jaquan Mahoney, MD
Pager: #84464




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2132-06-14


Internal Medicine Intern Admission Note

Name: Tyler Pearson
MR#: 7271902
Date of admission: 14 June 2132
Admitting Intern: Noah Rosario
Admitting Junior: Raymond Pack
Attending: Frank Ash

Chief Complaint: shortness of breath

History of Present Illness: Mr. Pearson is a an 87 year old gentleman with COPD on home oxygen, CVA, DM, and history of lung cancer s/p resection without chemotherapy who presented to the ED with acute shortness of breath.  Of note, he was hospitalized from May 26 until May 29 for a COPD flare, and was discharged home at that time on a prednisone taper, which he completed about one week ago.  He was in his usual state of good health and had even spent the past weekend with family in Connecticut camping.  But on the evening of June 13 he began to feel short of breath, without cough or chest pain, and the dyspnea was made worse with exertion.  Not made worse with lying down.  He also had a fever to 103, without mental status changes.  EMS was called and in the field he was noted to be breathing at a rate in the 40s; he was given a dose of IV lasix and he put out 600cc of urine.  He was then brought to the WMC ED where he continued to display labored breathing, breathing in the 40s, afebrile, tachycardic to 147bpm.  An ABG on BIPAP showed 7.35/53/100.  His blood pressure dropped from systolic 130s to 70/50, and so he was subsequently intubated, and a central and arterial lines placed.  He was given approximately 2L of NS with resultant CVP of 11.  He was also started on dopamine, which was eventually transitioned to norepinephrine.  He was given vancomycin, levaquin, and flagyl, as well as a dose of solumedrol.  He was then transferred to the Internal Medicine.

Review of Systems: per HPI; no changes in mental status; no cough, chest pain, palpitations; no N/V/C/D; no BRBPR or melena; no sick contacts.

Past Medical History
COPD on home O2 2LNC at all times, never been intubated
Cerebrovascular disease: s/p R CEA, and with L ICA on aspirin
DM2
Lung cancer: s/p L partial resection
BPH
PTSD

Medications on Admission
Albuterol and atrovent nebulizers prn
Advair 250/50 2puffs bid
ASA 325mg po qd
Calcium and vitamin D 250mg po bid
Lasix 10mg po qd
Neurontin 300mg po tid
Guaifenasin 10mL tid
Zantac 150mg po bid
Senna 2tabs bid
Zocor 20mg po qhs
Losartan 100mg po qd
Toprol XL 100mg po qd
Loratidine 10mg po qd

Allergies: bactrim and tetracycline, reactions unknown

Social History: retired Civil Engineer, positive asbestos exposure; quit smoking 30 years ago; no EtOH or illicits

Family History: denies any known family history of lung disease, COPD, CAD, or cancer

Physical Exam
Gen: NAD, appears comfortable
VS: T96.1 bp118/60 without pressors P93 CVP 6-9 O2sat 97% on mechanical ventilation
HEENT: R eye not reactive to light; L eye 3  2mm with light; EOMI
Neck: supple, JVP flat
Pulm: ronchi bilaterally without wheezing or crackles
Cor: regular, nls1s2, no mumurs
Abd: soft, NTND, +BS, no HSM
Ext: trace lower edema bilaterally; warm, DP 2+ B
Neuro: no focal findings, pt appropriate; CN 2-12 intact, tongue midlines, strength 5/5 all extremities, toes downgoing

Labs

Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            
06/14/2132                       4.3                                          
06/14/2132        138            4.1            101            29.1           
Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            
06/14/2132                                      132 (H)        
06/14/2132        30 (H)         1.6 (H)        123 (H)        

Date/Time         CA             PHOS           MG             TBILI          
06/14/2132        9.4            4.1            1.4            0.9            
Date/Time         DBILI          TP             ALB            GLOB           
06/14/2132        0.0            6.7            3.4            3.3            
Date/Time         LACT           
06/14/2132        1.2            

Date/Time         TEMP           FIO2           bPO2           bPCO2          
06/14/2132        37.0           1.00           100 (H)        53 (H)         
Date/Time         bPH            
06/14/2132        7.35           

Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          
06/14/2132        16             22             54             0.9            
Date/Time         NT-BNP         CK-MB          TROP-I         
06/14/2132                       NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       
06/14/2132        325                                          

Date/Time         PT             PT-INR         PTT            
06/14/2132        12.8           1.0            26.8           

Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            
06/14/2132        22.9 (H)       4.89           14.1           42.9           
Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            
06/14/2132        88             28.9           32.9           190            
Date/Time         DIFFR          METHOD         %NEUT          %LYMPH         
06/14/2132        RECEIVED       Auto           82 (H)         15 (L)         

Date/Time         UA-GLUC        UA-KET         UA-SPGR        UA-BLD         
06/14/2132        NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       1.015          NEGATIVE       

Date/Time         UA-PH          UA-PROT        UA-NIT         UA-WBC         
06/14/2132        5.0            NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       NEGATIVE       

06/14/2132 07:10 CXR
     Right upper lobe and right middle lobe opacity, new since
     5/27/2132, suspicious for pneumonia.
     Lines and tubes as described above, without evidence of
     pneumothorax following left IJ placement.

EKG: sinus tachycardia at 134bpm; right ventricular hypertrophy; 0.5mm ST depression V6

Assessment and Plan

Mr. Pearson is a pleasant 87 year old gentleman with a history of COPD, never intubated, who presented with one day of dyspnea.  He had a fever to 103, and presented with hypotension and respiratory distress requiring intubation.  He has an elevated wbc and an increased creatinine to 1.6; his chest x-ray is consistent with a RUL and RML pneumonia, and he has a low bnp negative for cardiac stretching.  His presentation is consistent with sepsis secondary to pneumonia.

Sepsis: continue EGDT, with goal MAP>65 and goal CVP of 8-12
a. IVF with NS for goal CVP 8-12
b. pressors as needed (vasopressin +/- levophed) for goal MAP>65 (currently off pressors)
c. monitor urine output
d. measure central venous oxygen saturation
e. antibiotics for pneumonia: would treat with vancomycin and cefepime, check vancomycin trough tomorrow am
f.  f/u all culture data
g. continue advair 250/50
h. no need for steroids currently, and will not check cort-stim in setting of having received solumedrol in ED
i.  hold antihypertensives (losartan 100mg qd and toprol 100mg qd) in setting of hypotension

ARF: creatinine up to 1.6 from baseline of 1.1, likely pre-renal etiology in setting of sepsis; will give trial hydration

Ppx: ranitidine and heparin

 
_______________________________
Noah G. Rosario
Pager 81251
PGY-1




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2134-10-28


















 




Team IV Attending Admission Note

PT Name:  Pearson, Tyler

MR# 7271902

Date of Admission: 10/28/34 at 1930



CC:         shortness of breath



HPI:        Mr. Pearson is a 89 year old male with past medical history of COPD, s/p CVA, AODM, BPH, CRI who presented to WMC complaining about shortness of breath.  The patient was admitted to the Ross Medical Center with pneumonia on three occasions in the last 6 weeks.  He was discharged home and completed the most recent course of antibiotics today.  He has noted increasing shortness of breath, wheezing, decreased exercise tolerance prompting him to seek medical attention.  The patient denied fever, productive cough, nausea, vomiting, diaphoresis, chest pain.



ROS: all systems are negative in detail except as noted above  



PMH:



COPD on home O2 2LNC at all times

Cerebrovascular disease: s/p R CEA 6/2129

L ICA stenosis, followed medically with serial ultrasound, on aspirin

DM2

Lung cancer: s/p L partial resection 2106&#8217;s

BPH

PTSD

Artificial R eye (s/p trauma 2069)

CRI (baseline 1.1 &#8211; 1.3)



Medications (from discharge notes):



Acetylsalicylic Acid (Aspirin )  PO 325 MG QD 

Fluticasone Propionate/salmeterol 250/50 (Advair Diskus 250/50 )  INH 1 PUFF BID 

Simvastatin (Zocor ) PO 40 MG QD

Losartan PO 100 MG QD

Ipratropium Nebulizer (Atrovent Nebulizer )  NEB 0.5 MG QID 

Calcium Carbonate/vitd (250mg Ca++/125u Vitd)  PO 250 MG TID

Gabapentin (Neurontin )  PO 300 MG TID

Albuterol Nebulizer  NEB 2.5 MG Q4H prn

Metoprolol PO 12.5 MG BID

Furosemide (Lasix ) PO 10 MG QD

Loratadine PO 10 MG QD

MVI

Brimonidine one gtt OS BID

Tamsulosin 0.4 mg QHS

Prednisone 40 mg QD



Allergies:  Bactrim/Tetracycline



FH: noncontributory

SH:         
retired Civil Engineer; 

(-) ETOH 
(-) illicit drugs (+) tobacco &#8211; stopped 30 years ago; 30 pack year history



Exam:  VS:           T=99  HR=112       BP= 139/57            RR=28; 96% after neb in ER               

General:  well nourished/well developed male in no acute distress

HEENT: NC/AT

Neck:  Supple; JVP flat

Chest: diffuse expiratory wheezes

CVS:      distant heart sounds (difficult to appreciate over breath sounds)

Abd:      soft, nontender, nondistended, normoactive BS

Extr:   no C/C/E

Neuro: nonfocal

Skin: no rashes



DATA:



Chemistry:



Plasma Sodium                    135                       (135-145)      mmol/L

Plasma Potassium                 4.5                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Plasma Chloride                  96               L        (100-108)      mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide            31.5                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

Plasma Anion GAP                 8                         (3-15)         mmol/L

Calcium                          9.6                       (8.5-10.5)     mg/dl

Phosphorus                       3.0                       (2.6-4.5)      mg/dl

Magnesium                        1.8                       (1.4-2.0)      meq/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen             15                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine                1.38                      (0.60-1.50)    mg/dl

eGFR                             51                                       mL/min/1.73m2

     Abnormal if &lt;60 mL/min/1.73m2. If patient is African-American, multiply the

     result by 1.21.

     

Plasma Glucose                   124              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



Creatine Kinase Isoenzymes       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

Troponin-I                       NEGATIVE                  (NEG)

NT-proBNP                        398                       (0-1800)       pg/ml



Hematology:



WBC                              14.4             H        (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              36.9             L        (41.0-53.0)    %

HGB                              12.7             L        (13.5-17.5)    gm/dl

RBC                              4.07             L        (4.50-5.90)    mil/cmm

PLT                              354                       (150-400)      th/cumm

MCV                              91                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              31.3                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             34.5                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              13.7                      (11.5-14.5)    %

PT                               14.7             H        (10.3-13.2)    sec

PT-INR                           1.3

DIFFERENTIAL REQUEST             RECEIVED

Diff Method                      Auto

Poly                             81               H        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           11               L        (22-44)        %

Monos                            5                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              3                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            0                         (0-3)          %

Absolute Neuts                   11.75            H        (1.8-7.7)      th/cmm

Absolute Lymphs                  1.60                      (1.0-4.8)      th/cmm

Absolute Monos                   0.70                      (0.2-1.2)      th/mm3

Absolute EOS                     0.36             H        (0.1-0.3)      th/cmm

Absolute Basos                   0.01                      (0.0-0.3)      th/cmm

Aniso                            None                      (None)

Hypo                             None                      (None)

Macrocytes                       None                      (None)

Microcytes                       None                      (None)



Chest x-ray: diffuse interstitial opacities likely representing interstitial fibrosis; no definite focal consolidation

EKG: sinus tach at 111; nl axis; RBBB; 


___________________________________________



Impression: 89 year old male with past medical history of COPD on home O2, HTN, AODM, hyperlipidemia, remote CVA, CRI admitted with COPD exacerbation after recent admission to Ross Hospital with pneumonia.





Plan: 




1.  COPD exacerbation  -- Patient appears comfortable after nebulizer treatments in the ER.  He has completed his course of oral antibiotics and remains on oral Prednisone.  Will continue oral Prednisone and continue aggressive nebulizer treatments.  He may require higher dose of oral steroids and subsequent taper.  His chest x-ray does NOT demonstrate a focal area of consolidation at this time.



2.  HTN &#8211; continue Lasix, Losartan, and Lasix



3.  diabetes &#8211; Patient reportedly does NOT require medication for management.   Will check BS BID now that he is on oral Prednisone



4. Glaucoma 
&#8211; continue Brimonidine BID







______________________

Gennaro B. Norwood, MD

Medical Team 4 

Team 4 Beeper #07736




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="not met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>