<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2111-09-26

CC:  Ear pain, cough

HPI:  49 y.o. female c/o cough with clear mucus, left ear pain and nasal congestion for the past week.  She denies any chest pain, shortness of breath, fever, chills or sweat.  No sore throat.  She does smoke about one pack/day for 25 years and does not want to quit.  She also notes problems with bending her right thumb without h/o trauma, pain, parathesias or numbness.  Symptoms present for past 3 months.


Allergies
NKA   

Health Maint
Cholesterol 03/10/01 222   
Mammogram 11/02/97 see report in Results   
Pap Smear 09/28/99 see report in Results   
HbA1c 08/22/2106 10.70   

Procedures
Hysterectomy   


Flowsheets
BLOOD PRESSURE 110/70  
WEIGHT 206 lb 

HENT:  PERRLA, oral w/out lesions, neck supple, nasal turbinates mildly enlarged with no sinus tenderness.  No lymphadenopathy and TMs clear.
LUNGS:  CTA
EXT:  Inability to bend right thumb without tenderness, warmth or swelling.

A/P:  1.  Allergies with cough.  Claritin and robitussin for cough and given smoking history will check chest xray.
2.  Right thumb stiffness.  Check xray and referral to orthopedics.
3.  Health maint.  Pt. declined physical and on reviewing chart noted to have diabetes.  Recommend f/u for physical and assessment of diabetes.



_____________________________________________
Grace C. Valerie-Yun, M.D.





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2112-01-17

 CC:  Follow-up labs/MRI

HPI:  49 y.o. female with h/o diabetes who had meds resumed on last visit.  She is unable to check her blood sugar due to unable to afford strips and insurance will not pay for them.  She was started on pravachol for hyperlipidemia and lisinopril for microalbuminuira on last visit without side effect to meds.  She had an MRI of hips which shows mild DJD and arterial noninvasives showing mild disease on the right and moderate on the left.  Mammogram was negative.  She continues to smoke but is done to one pack/day from two pack/day.  She denies any chest pain, shortness of breath or palpitations.  She has difficulty walking long distances due to claudication.

Problems
Peripheral vascular disease   
Diabetes mellitus type 2   
Hyperlipidemia   
Claudication   

Medications
Claritin (LORATADINE) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 30 days 
Glipizide Xl (GLIPIZIDE Xl) 10 MG (10MG TAB OSM 24 take 1) PO QD x 30 days 
IBUPROFEN 800 MG (800MG TABLET take 1) PO TID PRN pain x 30 days, Take with food or milk. 
LISINOPRIL 2.5 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD x 30 days 
METFORMIN 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO BID x 30 days 
Pravastatin (PRAVASTATIN) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS x 30 days 
Tylenol #3 (ACETAMINOPHEN W/codeine 30mg) 1 TAB PO Q6H x 21 days, Do not drive, drink alcohol with this medication. 

Allergies
NKA   

Family/social History
Coronary Artery Disease  Relative: Brother; Comments: H/o 4V CABG 
Bone Cancer Relative: Father; Age of Onset: 53; Living: No  
Uterine Cancer Relative: Mother; Age of Onset: 46; Living: No  
Diabetes Mellitus Type 2 Relative: Brother;Relative: Sister;Relative: Grandfather, maternal; 

Health Maint
Smoking status 01/17/2112  Current smoker  Last Counsel date: 01/17/2112, No Of Cigarettes Smoked per Day: 10-19 CIG/DAY (1/2-1 ppd), Readiness to Change: Ready to quit now 
Mammogram 01/11/2112 see report in Results    
Pap Smear 09/28/99 see report in Results    
Pneumovax 12/26/2111     

Flowsheets
BLOOD PRESSURE 110/72  
PULSE 78  
WEIGHT 207 lb 
AGE 49y7.7m  

EXAM:  Deferred.

A/P:  1.  PVD.  Start walking program, d/c tobacco, cholesterol, diabetes and hypertension control.  Start Pletal.  Will also evaluate for CAD given multiple risk factors.  Check EKG and schedule nonexercise stress test. 
2.  Diabetes.  Continue current meds and check labs at f/u visit in 2 months.  Referral for eye exam.
3.  Hyperlipidemia.  Continue on Pravachol and check last at next visit.
4.  Tobacco use.  Pt advised to d/c tobacco.  She wants to try on her own and if no success will consider supplemental therapies.




_____________________________________________
Grace C. Valerie-Yun, M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2112-09-30

SECTIONS OF THIS NOTE WERE CREATED WITH A 'COPY AND PASTE' ACTION.  THESE SECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE COPIED COMPLETELY.  PLEASE USE CAUTION WHEN RENDERING CLINICAL JUDGMENT BASED ON THE INFORMATION IN THIS NOTE.
Vascular surgery consult note


Date: 09/30/2112                                     Time: 10pm
Patient:Adair, Helen                       MR#: 6842267 
CC: Right foot infection


HPI: 50 y/o F diabetic female who noticed redness of the right 4th and 5th toes about a week ago.She was seen and given cipro.Her infection progressed.She now presents with worsening infection, pain, but no fever.Of note, ROS is positive for symptoms of claudication.


PMH/PSH:
Diabetes mellitus type 2 
Hyperlipidemia Claudication 
Peripheral vascular disease


MEDS:
Cilostazol (CILOSTAZOL) 100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO BID
Glipizide Xl (GLIPIZIDE Xl) 10 MG (10MG TAB OSM 24 take 1) PO QD
LISINOPRIL 2.5 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD
METFORMIN 500 MG (500MG TABLET take 1) PO BID x 30 days 
Pravastatin (PRAVASTATIN) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS x 30 days 
Tramadol (TRAMADOL) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO Q6H PRN x 30 days


ALLERGY: nkda


EXAM:
Temp= 98 HR= 104 BP= 129/80 RR= 16 Sat= 97%RA
NAD, AAOx3
Ext Right 5th toe appears necrotic, 4th toe ulcerated laterally where the 4th and 5th toe rub together
R forefoot is erythematous and warm, +edema.
Pulse      Fem         DP           PT
Right      1+            D             -
Left         1+            D             -


LABS:
Chemistry Detail for ADAIR, HELEN V


   NVHBLOOD          30-Sep-2112 20:54Accession# 2693D15325


Test Description                 Result           Flags    Ref. Range       Units


Plasma Sodium                    134              L        (135-145)      mmol/L
Plasma Potassium                 3.7                       (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L
Plasma Chloride                  101                       (100-108)      mmol/L
Plasma Carbon Dioxide            26.5                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L
Plasma Urea Nitrogen             19                        (8-25)         mg/dl
Plasma Creatinine                1.2                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl
Plasma Glucose                   155              H        (70-110)       mg/dl


WBC                              12.7             H        (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm
HCT                              34.5             L        (36.0-46.0)    %
HGB                              12.0                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl
RBC                              4.03                      (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm
PLT                              350                       (150-350)      th/cumm


Superstat PT                     12.9                      (10.3-13.2)    sec
Superstat PT-INR                 1.1
Superstat APTT                   28.8                      (22.1-34.0)    sec


MRA: recently performed but not read.By my read, looks as though iliacs and CFAs are OK, but there is left and right SFA lesions.The popliteal artery reconstitutes bilaterally.Distally, one vessel run off (DP).Please


A/P: Diabetic foot infection.PVD.
*Agree with admit to medicine for IV antibiotics
*Vascular surgery service / Dr. Salgado&#8217;s service will follow with you
*She is likely a candidate for revascularization.Will review MRA and provide further recommendations
*Further recommendations for toe in the AM.
*Will follow with you, please call Vascular Millen service with questions.
*Discussed with Dr. Kennedy


____________________________________________________
Vance U. Arias, MD, Resident in Surgery, Pager 51363




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2113-04-07





Vascular Surgery
Millen Service Admission Note


Name: Adair, Helen
MRN: 684-22-67
Date: 4/07/13


Attending: Dr. Salgado
Fellow:  Dr. Cross  
Junior:  Dr. Chandler  


History of Present Illness:  50 yo F with NIDDM, active smoking, hypercholesterolemia, and severe PVD (s/p PTCA and multiple toe amputations for diabetic foot), now presents with worsening wet gangrene.  She first noted drainage from her left great toe five days prior to admission.  This was accompanied by toe swelling, fevers to 100.5 and chills, but she denies pain in her L great toe.  Almost simultaneous with the drainage from her L great toe, she also noted increasing pain from the lateral aspect of the plantar surface of her left forefoot, especially when walking.  She denies any trauma to her left foot.  She reports that the ulcer on her right lateral foot is stable, and she has been dressing it with Panafil ointment as prescribed by Dr. Salgado.  She denies any rest pain, and reports that her prior claudication is almost fully resolved following her R SFA angioplasty last year.  She presented today to Dr. Salgado&#8217;s clinic for routine follow-up, when wet gangrene of her L great toe was detected on clinical exam.  Furthermore, she underwent repeat A-LENIs that demonstrated a major decline in the ABI of her R leg, suggestive of worsening peripheral vascular disease.  She is now admitted for parenteral antibiotics and amputation of the L great toe and debridement of the R forefoot ulcer.


Past Medical History:
(1) Diabetes mellitus type 2 (A1Cs &#8211; 7.70% in 3/2113, 7.60% in 2112, 10.10% in 2111, 10.70% in 2106, 9.80% in 2104)
(2) Hypercholesterolemia
(3) Smoking (50 pack years, currently &#189; pack per day, recently started Chantix)
(4) PVD with claudication and lower extremity ulcers:  arterial vascular study - right ABI 0.34 (down from 0.69) and left ABI 0.81, disease diffusely in R leg
(5) Uterine cancer


Past Surgical History:
2097: TAH-BSO
10/03/12: Balloon angioplasty of right superficial femoral artery and
right peroneal artery
10/05/12: Thrombin injection for left common femoral artery
10/30/12:  R 5th toe amputation
1/24/13: L 4th toe amputation, foot debridement


Social History:
Works as waitress at Hardee's and cashier at Barnes Noble.
No kids, closest to sister Trudy
Tobacco - 50 pack year, currently 1/2 pack per day, had recently quit for 4 weeks but restarted due to &#8220;stress&#8221;.  Tried to start Chantix, but insurance does not cover.
No EtOH
No drugs


Family history:  Brother CAD; father died of bone cancer; mother died of uterine cancer; brother, sister, grandfather on maternal side all w/ DM.


Medications at home:
Ferrous Sulfate 325 MG (325(65)MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 
Glipizide Xl (GLIPIZIDE Xl) 10 MG (10MG TAB OSM 24 take 1) PO QD 
LISINOPRIL 2.5 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
METFORMIN 850 MG (850MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 
Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG (75MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Pravastatin (PRAVASTATIN) 20 MG (20MG TABLET take 1) PO QHS 
Tramadol (TRAMADOL) 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO Q6H PRN


Allergies: NKDA


Physical Examination:
Vital Signs            T: 97.7    P: 82   BP: 126/67       RR: 20     Sat: 98%
General:  Comfortable, in bed, no acute distress
HEENT:  Normocephalic, atraumatic, PERRLA, no lymphadenopathy, anicteric sclera, moist mucous membranes.
Neck:  supple, no thyromegaly, no jugular venous distension, normal carotid upstrokes bilaterally, no carotid bruits.
Pulm:  Clear to auscultation bilaterally
Cardiac:  Regular rate and rhythm; no murmurs, rubs or gallops.
Abdomen:  Soft, mildly overweight, non-distended, non-tender, no palpable pulsatile masses, no organomegaly, no abdominal bruit, no costovertebral tenderness
Extremities:  R foot cool, L foot warm.  s/p R 5th toe and L 4th toe amputation.  No venous stasis dermatitis or bronzing, no pedal edema.  5/5 plantar/dorsiflexion bilaterally.  Sensation to light touch intact in both feet.  Deep ulcer with fibrinous exudate at base on lateral aspect of R forefoot (at 5th toe amputation site), no visible bone, no periulcer cellulitis. L foot with wet gangrene involving primarily plantar surface and nailbed of L great toe, visible sinus extending deeper on medial aspect of L nailbed, cellulitis and edema extending throughout toe.  Plantar surface of L foot with superficial ulcer of (~3x1cm) overlying 5th toe metatarsal head, no expressible drainage or fluctuance.  Extensive scale and sclerotic nails noted on forefeet bilaterally.  
Pulses:
            Radial      Femoral     Popliteal   Dorsalis    Post Tib
Right       ++          ++                      doppler     non-doppler
Left        ++          +                       doppler     doppler


Diagnostic Testing:

ResultsDate/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            04/07/2113        137            4.3            100            27.3           Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            04/07/2113        34 (H)         1.60 (H)       141 (H)        Date/Time         MG             04/07/2113        1.5            Date/Time         WBC            HCT            PLT            04/07/2113        16.2 (H)       33.7 (L)       550 (H)        Date/Time         PT             PT-INR         PTT            04/07/2113        15.3 (H)       1.4            35.0 (H)       CardiologyReport Number:  YLU102821                              Report Status: PreliminaryType:  Vascular StudyDate:  04/07/2113 08:00Ordering Provider:  SALGADO, BRUCE,   *** PRELIMINARY ***                                                            VASCULAR LABORATORY                                                      NIOBRARA VALLEY HOSPITAL                         ADAIR, HELEN                           DOB:    25 May 20626842267                                 Age:    50     Sex: F07 Apr 2113                             RefMD:  SALGADO, BRUCE                 TEST TYPE: Peripheral Arterial TestingHISTORYDiabetes: Yes  Hypertension: No  Tobacco: Yes  Hyperlipidemia: YesREASON FOR STUDYExtremity gangreneBP(Arm) R:125 L:119Right LegSegmentals:    AbnormalPVR:           AbnormalToe press.:    0.00Ankle/Brachial: 0.34 Site of occlusive disease:-aorto-iliac, femoral, popliteal and tibial/peroneal segments and the digitsLeft LegSegmentals:    AbnormalPVR:           AbnormalToe press.:    35.00Ankle/Brachial: 0.81Site of occlusive disease:-aorto-iliac, femoral, popliteal and tibial/peroneal segments and the digitsSYMPTOMSFINDINGSRIGHT:  The ankle/brachial index (ABI) is .34.  Prior ankle/brachial index (ABI) was .69.  Pulse volume recordings (PVR) and segmental limb pressures suggest inflow aorto-iliac/common femoral/profunda femoris/or proximal superficial femoral artery disease, and popliteal artery/tibial vessel  at rest.  The toe/brachial index is 0.LEFT:  The patient is s/p a left superficial femoral artery pta and stent since last exam.  The ankle/brachial index (ABI) is .81.  Prior ankle/brachial  index (ABI) was .55.  Pulse volume recordings (PVR) and segmental limb pressures suggest mild inflow aorto-iliac/common femoral/profunda femoris/or proximal superficial femoral artery disease, and popliteal/tibial vessel disease at rest.  The toe/brachial index is .28 (taken from 2nd toe).IMPRESSION1. Severe peripheral arterial disease in the right leg.2. Disease is located in the aorto-iliac, femoral, popliteal and tibial/peroneal segments and the digits on the right side.3. Mild peripheral arterial disease in the left leg.4. Disease is located in the aorto-iliac, femoral, popliteal and tibial/peroneal segments and the digits on the left side.5. There has been a significant drop in the ankle/brachial index in the right leg since the last exam, from 0.69 to 0.34.

Assessment and Recommendations: 50 yo F diabetic with active smoking and peripheral vascular disease, now with wet gangrene of L great toe.
1)       Consented and added to schedule for L great toe amputation and R forefoot ulcer debridement.
2)       NPO past midnight
3)       Hold all oral hypoglycemics, start insulin sliding scale.
4)       Prevalon boots
5)       Bedrest


_____________________________ 
Owen Franklin, MD
NVH PGY-2 Surgery Resident
Pager:  x76221



****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="not met" />
<CREATININE met="met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>