<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2081-02-10

GI Fellow Consult Note 



Pt: Frantz, Nicole

MRN: 236-07-19

Date of note: 2/10/81 at 12:20pm

Reason for consult: nausea and epigastric pain

Referring MD: Dr. 

ID/CC:  52yoF with DM s/p recent cholecystectomy for nausea here with recurrent nausea/vomiting

HPI:   Pt with DM presenting with 6 weeks of N/V, beginning on 12/26/80 when she had green emesis, then abdominal pain.  Was seen in ED at OSH and sent home.  She continued to vomit, went to another hospital where she stayed for a week, and had a cholecystectomy.  She felt better at home for 4 days after discharge, but had recurrent vomiting, back to ED, admitted again and discharged after a week-long stay.  She now comes to PSH after four episodes of emesis yesterday.

	Pt reports intermittent periumbilical pain, which worsens right before a bout of emesis, then dies down after the emesis.  Pain does not radiate; pt not able to characterize frequency, duration, or quality of the pain.  No obvious relationship between pain and PO intake.

	In between episodes of vomiting, she feels increased amount of secretions in her mouth that she has to spit out.  Denies any dysphagia or odynophagia.  No melena or hematochezia.  Had had constipation, which resolved with laxatives, more recently having 2 BMs/day.

	She does not recall the workup at OSH but thinks she may have had EGD and colonoscopy already, which she reports did not show any abnormality.



ROS:  no fever or night sweats.  No odynophagia or dysphagia.  No rash.  No CP, SOB, LE edema.  Appetite was good and no weight changes before 12/26/80; since then, she is afraid to eat and has lost weight and feels    weak   



PMH			

DM

HTN

S/p cholecystectomy on 1/04/81

No TB or exposure to TB



Meds currently

Zestril

Reglan

Ativan

Colace

ASA



ALL:   Percocet    GI upset.



SHx:	 lives alone  

ETOH:  none

Tobacco:  never

Drugs:  never



FHx:  	 no GI malignancy or IBD



PE	afeb	193/1-9		94		18		98% on RA

General:	middle-aged woman, thin, in some distress in the midst of vomiting green liquid

Skin:	no jaundice; no rash

HEENT:	benign OP

Chest:  	CTA bilaterally anteriorly

Cardiac:  	RRR, nl S1 & S2

Abd:		soft, obese, not distended, mild diffuse tenderness without guarding or rebound, liver edge not palpable, good BS

Rectal:		deferred; pt in midst of vomiting; ED resident did rectal exam yesterday showing nl anal sphincter tone and scant gu- stool

Extremities:	no peripheral edema

Neuro:	awake and alert and appropriate



Labs:

10-Feb-2081 03:24  

Sodium (Stat Lab)                134              L        (135-145)      mmol/L

Potassium (Stat Lab)             3.3              L        (3.4-4.8)      mmol/L

Chloride (Stat Lab)              105                       (100-108)      mmol/L

CO2 (Stat Lab)                   26.6                      (23.0-31.9)    mmol/L

BUN (Stat Lab)                   16                        (8-25)         mg/dl

Creatinine (Stat Lab)            0.9                       (0.6-1.5)      mg/dl

Glucose (Stat Lab)               274              H        (70-110)       mg/dl



09-Feb-2081 21:21  

Total Protein                    7.9                       (6.0-8.3)      g/dl

Albumin                          3.7                       (3.3-5.0)      g/dl

Globulin                         4.2              H        (2.6-4.1)      g/dl

Direct Bilirubin                 0.1                       (0-0.4)        mg/dl

Total Bilirubin                  0.4                       (0.0-1.0)      mg/dl

Alkaline Phosphatase             78                        (30-100)       U/L

Transaminase-SGPT                12                        (7-30)         U/L

Amylase                          103              H        (3-100)        units/L

Lipase                           7.8              H        (1.3-6.0)      U/dl

Transaminase-SGOT                15                        (9-32)         U/L



09-Feb-2081 21:08  

WBC                              5.9                       (4.5-11.0)     th/cmm

HCT                              41.3                      (36.0-46.0)    %

HGB                              14.3                      (12.0-16.0)    gm/dl

RBC                              5.00                      (4.00-5.20)    mil/cmm

PLT                              300                       (150-350)      th/cumm

MCV                              83                        (80-100)       fl

MCH                              28.6                      (26.0-34.0)    pg/rbc

MCHC                             34.6                      (31.0-37.0)    g/dl

RDW                              12.8                      (11.5-14.5)    %



Poly                             56                        (40-70)        %

Lymphs                           38                        (22-44)        %

Monos                            4                         (4-11)         %

EOS                              1                         (0-8)          %

Basos                            1                         (0-3)          %



Abd CT:  The liver, spleen, pancreas, adrenal glands and kidneys

	are unremarkable on this unenhanced CT.

	There is diverticulosis of the sigmoid colon without CT evidence

	of diverticulitis.  There is no evidence of bowel obstruction.

	There is a segment of terminal ileum demonstrates thickened wall.

	No significant surrounding inflammatory change.  There is

	questionable thickening of the gastric and proximal duodenal wall

	which may possibly be due to under distention.  There is no

	evidence of free air.

	There is no retroperitoneal, mesenteric or inguinal

	lymphadenopathy. 

A/P:     52yoF with DM with six weeks of recurrent green emesis and periumbilical pain without abdominal distention or KUB or CT signs of obstruction.  Question of TI thickening and gastric thickening (but may appear that way only due to underdistention).  As per pt, she has had EGD and colonoscopy at OSH already.  Would suggest obtaining records from Fairview-Southdale Hospital first before decision regarding repeat w/u here.  Workup may entail gastric emptying scan to assess for gastroparesis, EGD and colonoscopy to evaluate for malignancy or IBD, brain imaging to r/o CNS process.  Can continue to try Reglan 10mg up to QID.



Will staff with Dr. Otis Aguilera later today.



					_______

Regina Dorsey, M.D.

      



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-06-10



Attending Admission Note



HPI

52 year old woman with DM and h/o gastroparesis who presented with nausea and vomiting.  She was last admitted one week ago with N/V and treated for gastroparesis.  Her diabetes has been poorly controlled with her last hemoglobin A1c over 12 in April of 2081.  She has had recurrent episodes of nausea and vomiting.  During this past year in January, she was admitted to Missouri Baptist Hospital.  She had a negative EGD, and HIDA scan showed low ejection fraction to cholecystokinase.  She underwent a laparoscopic cholecystectomy.  She was admitted again a few weeks later to Missouri Baptist and had a gastric emptying study, which was consistent with gastroparesis.  In February, she was seen in the Philadelphia State Hospital Emergency Room with nausea and vomiting and had a KUB, which showed significant stool.  She presented again on 02/11/2081 and had an abdominal CT that showed thickening of the terminal ileum and possible thickening of the gastric and possible duodenal wall.  GI was consulted and the colonoscopy done on 02/14/2081 was normal, but did not visualize the terminal ileum.  A small-bowel follow-through on 02/16/2081 was normal.  She was discharged on a regimen of Reglan and erythromycin.  Since February, she has been seen multiple times in the outpatient clinic as well as medical walk-in.  She reports being complaint with her regimen of erythromycin 250 mg four times a day and Reglan 10 mg twice a day.  She was also recently started on Glucophage titrating up to 1000 mg b.i.d. as she had difficulty with multiple short per day regimen of insulin administration.  



She was admitted from 5/31-6/2 and treated with IV Zofran and enemas.  GI saw the pt and recommended increasing reglan to TID and adding colace and miralax.  She also had a head CT to r/o mass lesion causing the nausea, and this was negative.  At the time of d/c, her nausea had decreased.  She states that the N/V did not improve much since that admission, and she has not been able to eat much.  She has pain throughout her abdomen.  She denies f/c, diarrhea, constipation, dysuria, hematemesis, or melena.



Problems

Diabetes mellitus : since 2060's, poorly controlled

Hypertension 

Gastroparesis : N/V due to diabetes

Retinopathy : due to AODM, s/p first laser treatment 3/81, sees Ophtho in Stanwood

S/P cholecystectomy 

S/P TAH/BSO : menopause at age 86, had some hot flashes which are slowing improving. 



Medications

Metformin 1000 MG (500MG TABLET take 2) PO BID 

Erythrocin ETHYL SUCCINATE SUSP (ERYTHROMYCIN) 250MG TABLET PO QID 

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325 MG (325MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Lisinopril 40MG TABLET PO QAM 

Reglan (METOCLOPRAMIDE HCL) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO TID 

Lantus (INSULIN GLARGINE) 40 U SC QHS

Atenolol 50 mg po QD

Colace 2 tablets QHS 

Miralax 17 gm QOD

Zofran 8 mg po BID prn nausea



Allergies

PERCOCET - GI upset, 



Social History	

Lives alone; work- biological technician; no smoking; Etoh- none.



Family History	

Brother with DM.



Review of Systems	

No dizziness, F/C, cough, SOB, CP, dysuria, joint pain.



Physical Exam	

BP: 162/78     T: 98.6   P: 84    RR: 18

GENERAL: 	Appears sleepy in her bed.

SKIN:		NL turgor, no abnormal lesions

CHEST:	            Clear lungs, NL frame

COR:		NL S1S2, no murmur, rubs, or gallops.

ABD:		Hypoactive BS; diffuse tenderness but no guarding or rebound; no HSM.

EXT:		No edema, clubbing, or cyanosis

NEURO:	            NL MS



Assessment and Plan	

1.  Nausea/vomiting:  Most likely secondary to her gastroparesis.  Her amylase and lipase are also elevated, raising the question of pancreatitis as well.  Will check abd-pelvic CT.  NPO with IVF.  Continue Reglan and erythromycin.  GI has been consulted for further recommendations.  Morphine prn abdominal pain.

2.  DM: Continue glucophage.  Adjust insulin depending on BS. 

3.  HTN:  Continue lisinopril and atenolol. 





_____________________________________________

Mildred D. Yunker, M.D.







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-08-09

Here for f/u, was again hospitalized with N/V. Seen by both GI and Endocrine. D/c on regimen of NPH insulin 30u with Reg sliding scale before breakfast and NPH 20u (per d/c instructions, should be 22u) with Regular sliding scale before dinner.  Thinks she had some low blood sugar reactions in the hospital, but hasn't had any since. Brings in BS record with BS in 200's mostly especially during daytime. Nausea controlled, wary of another episode starting. Began Zelnorm 6mg which she is only taking QD.



Problems

Diabetes mellitus : since 2060's, poorly controlled

Hypertension 

Gastroparesis : N/V due to diabetes

Retinopathy : due to AODM, s/p first laser treatment 3/81, sees Ophtho in Stanwood

S/P cholecystectomy 

S/P TAH/BSO : menopause at age 86, had some hot flashes which are slowing improving. 





Medications

Lexapro (ESCITALOPRAM) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Colace (DOCUSATE SODIUM) 100 MG (100MG TABLET take 1) PO BID 

Hydrochlorothiazide 25 MG (25MG TABLET take 1) PO QAM , for high blood pressure

Ativan (LORAZEPAM) 1 MG (1MG TABLET take 1) PO Q8H 

Lisinopril 40MG TABLET PO QAM 

Miralax (POLYETHYLENE GLYCOL ) 17 GM PO QD , Each 17 GM dose to be dissolved in 8 oz of water

Zofran (CHEMO N/V) (ONDANSETRON HCL (CHEMO N/V)) 8 MG (8MG TABLET take 1) PO BID PRN 

Insulin REGULAR HUMAN SC , Follow sliding scale

Norvasc (AMLODIPINE) 5 MG (5MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Zelnorm (TEGASEROD) 6 MG (6MG TABLET take 1) PO QD

Insulin NPH HUMAN 100 U/ML VIAL ML SC QAM & QHS as directed , Take 30u in AM and at bedtime

Atenolol 50 MG (50MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325 MG (325MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 

Reglan (METOCLOPRAMIDE HCL) 10 MG (10MG TABLET take 1) PO QID , Take with each meal and at bedtime.

Nexium (ESOMEPRAZOLE) 20 MG (20MG CAPSULE DR take 1) PO q AM , Take 15-30 min before first meal of the day. 



Vital Signs

BP 143/75, P 69, Temp 98.2 F

Repeat BP136/72

Abd:soft, mild diffuse tenderness without rebound

Affect:still flat



A/P:1.AODM-given elevated BS in AM, will increase NPH at night to 30u. F/u with me in one month, also has Endocrine f/u 9/20 schedulued. Continue sliding scale insulin. Reviewed that key to improving gastroparesis will be sustained BS control.

2.Diabetic gastroparesis-increase Zelnorm to BID, with Reglan QID, Ativan before meals and prn Zofran (using about once a day).

3.HTN-reasonable control, will continue meds for now.

4.Depression-continuing on Lexapro 10mg qD



Over 1/2 of 45 min visit spent in counselling. Pt to bring in disability paperwork; will remain off work until her f/u appt.



  



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2081-09-30

 



Endocrinology Fellow Consult Note



Date: 	09-30-2081

Name:	Nicole Frantz

MRN:	236-07-19

	

Requesting Service:	Medicine

Reason for consultation:   Diabetes, gastroparesis

	

HPI:  52-yo woman with poorly-controlled DM diagnosed 2061 and h/o gastroparesis, retinopathy, nephropathy, peripheral neuropathy, and  with multiple visits and three recent admissions for n/v/gastroparesis: May 1-3and June 7-21, July 22. Her GI symptoms began in December, 2080. Delayed gastric emptying by nuclear medicine study, with 9% emptying at 60 minutes and 29% emptying at 90 minutes. 



Originally, she had been on oral medication and has been on insulin since 2076, initially on NPH bid and then switched to Lantus.  After her admission June 2081, she was placed back on NPH from what had been lantus 40 U qhs + metformin 1000 bid. HbA1C was 12.2, 4/2081, more recently it has been 10.2 in 7/2081 and 10.1 on 9/14/2081. 



On her last visit to see me in diabetes counseling approximately 10 days ago, gastroparesis was under good control without nausea or vomiting. Glycemic control, however, was poor, and it was clear to me that she was not properly administering a sliding scale, and this was too complex for her. Accordingly, and in response to severe hyperglycemia and a hemoglobin A1c above 10, we changed her reigimen to NPH 70/30 50Units BID. 

Her known diabetic complications include retinopathy with prior photocoagulopathy, nephropathy with microalbuminuria, neuropathy with intermittent numbness and tingling at night in feet, and no known macrovascular disease. Gastroparesis may be the consequence of poor glycemic control or frank autonomic neuropathy, but is often multifactorial. 

She was re-admitted to the PSH on 09/30/2081 after having 2 days of nausea, vomiting, and anorexia. She was unable tolerate any oral hydration in the ED, and was admitted for management. 

On ROSystems and history, she reports that she had been taking her new 70/30 insulin, 50 units BID. Sugars had been running 200s, all the time 200s, no better or worse. Nausea per her report began suddenly on Friday evening 09/27 and got gradually worse. Currently nausea has abated, but abdominal pain persists.

Written only for insulin sliding scale. Glucose 500+ on admission with anion gap of 20 that closed rapidly with hydration.  



PMH: 

1)	DM (from 2061a)

2)	gastroparesis 

3)	retinopathy (s/p laser Rx 03/81)

4)	nephropathy

5)	HTN

6)	s/p cholecystectomy

7)	s/p TAH/BSO

ALL: Percocet

MEDS: 

1)	Insulin 70/30 NPH/Regular 50U BID

2)	ASA 325 QD

3)	Lisinopril 40 mg qam

4)	Atenolol 50 mg QD 

5)	Reglan 10 mg bid-qid

6)	Lexapro 10mg QD

7)	Colace 100mg bid

8)	Miralax 17g QD

9)	Nexium 40 mg QD

10)	Ativan 0.5-1mg tid

11)	Zofran 8mg bid

12)	Hydrochlorothiazide

13)	Norvasc 5 QD

14)	Zelnorm

15)	Metformin 500 QD titrating up to 1000 BID (started on last visit, she has not taken it yet.

SH: Lives alone in Coshocton, from Herzegovina, sister in town. Works as biologies at Yale

	

FH: Mother car accident, father fine at age 78, brother DM at age 40.   



HAB:  

Tobacco:  none

EtOH:  none

RD:  none



Physical Exam:  	VS:T 99.1 P 99-108  BP 180/82	O2 100%RA	FINGERSTICKS: 287 noon, 343 5pm

General: Ill appearing, uncomfortable

HEENT:  MM sl dry, hirsute with acne

Neck:  	Supple, JVP about 4cm, thyroid normal. 

Chest: 	Clear anteriorly

CVS:  	Hyperdynamic precordium with 3/6 systolic ejection murmur. 

Abd:  	Soft, non-tender, pain out of proportion to exam. 

Extr:  	 Warm, no edema

Neuro:  Deferred



DATA:  

          	09/14/81  	07/22/81  	04/19/81  	02/12/81  	02/11/81  

HGBA1C    	10.20(H)  	10.10(H)  	12.20(H)  	          	11.70(H)  

MEAN-GLU  	254       	251       	321       	          	304       





          	09/14/81  	04/19/81  

UCREAT    	2.34      	0.88      	          	          	          

MALB      	162.6(H)  	77.9(H)   	          	          	          

MALB/CRE  	694.9(H)  	885.2(H)  	          	          	          



          	06/10/81  

CHOL      	224(T)    	          	          	          	          

TRIG      	149       	          	          	          	          

HDL       	101(H)    	          	          	          	          

LDL       	93(T)     	          	          	          	          

CHOL/HDL  	2.2(T)  



          	09/30/81  	09/30/81  	09/30/81  	09/30/81  

          	08:30     	04:32     	01:59     	01:49     

NA        	138       	          	136       	          	          

K         	3.8       	3.4(L)    	5.7(H)    	          	          

CL        	105       	          	91(L)     	          	          

CO2       	23.4      	          	25.3      	          	          

BUN       	22        	          	24        	          	          

CRE       	1.0       	          	1.3       	          	          

GLU       	359(H)    	373(H)    	527(H)    	          	          

CA        	          	          	10.0      	          	          

PHOS      	          	          	5.4(H)    	          	          

MG        	          	          	1.7       	          	          



ABG:

TEMP      	          	37.0      	          	          	          

FIO2      	          	ROOM AIR  	          	          	          

aPO2      	          	111(H)    	          	          	          

aPCO2     	          	35        	          	          	          

aPH       	          	7.44      	          	          	          

HC03      	          	23(L)     	          	          	          





UA:

UA-COLOR  	          	          	          	Yellow    	          

UA-APP    	          	          	          	Clear     	          

UA-GLUC   	          	          	          	3+        	          

UA-KET    	          	          	          	3+        	          

UA-SPGR   	          	          	          	1.036(H)  	          

UA-BLD    	          	          	          	2+        	          

UA-PH     	          	          	          	5.0       	          

UA-ALB    	          	          	          	3+        	          

	          





Impression   52F with poorly controlled type II DM and known neuropathy, nephropathy, retinopathy and gastroparesis, repeated admission for nausea, vomiting, poor nutrition. Found to be profoundly hyperglycemic on admission with BG of 526 with anion gap of 20. Rapidly closed anion gap to 10 with hydration alone.  Abdominal pain can be multifactorial. I don't doubt that this is most likely hyperglycemia with associated gut dysmotility, but differential includes small bowel angina (pain is definitely out of proportion to exam and seems colicky), hepatobiliary disease. With normal anion gap, I doubt that this is ischemic disease of the gut, but small bowel angina is still a possibility. 

Recommendations: 

1)	 Gastroparesis may be in part due to poor glycemic control, we need to achieve better glycemic control to help with gastric motility. 

a.	Would not hold long acting insulin. Start NPH 30U BID,    dose if NPO

b.	While NPO, have D5 running in IVF once fingerstick drops below 200, especially once NPH started. If she needs IVF at a higher rate, you might run D5NS at 50cc/hour along with NS or    NS at whatever rate is needed.

c.	Continue sliding scale insulin Q6H when NPO, QAC and QHS when eating, but change parameters to tighten coverage as follows:

i.	Fingerstick <150, 0 units; 151-200 4 units; 201-250 6 units; 251-300 8 units; 301-350 10 units, >350 12 units. 

d.	Start mealtime insulin (clearly hold while NPO) of 10U regular pre-breakfast and pre-dinner. Hold if NPO or PO intake poor. She will need rapid uptitration from this point once eating. 

e.	No metformin for now given GI upset. 

2)	Agree with other therapies for gastroparesis as she had been on as an outpatient, including ativan, reglan, zofran PRN, zelnorm, miralax, colace. 

3)	For crude r/o of poor circulation to gut you could send a lactate level and check stool guaiac. Colonoscopy and endoscopic exams were normal earlier this year, but this does not exclude small bowel angina. Study of choice would be MR angiography or CT angiography of abdominal vessels. I do not think this is warranted at this point, but ischemic small bowel should remain on the differential.  

4)	With hyperdynamic precordium and tachycardia, would check TSH, though this is almost certainly due to hypovolemia and compensatory response. 

Thank you for the consult.  

We will follow with you.  Please call with any questions.

Will staff in AM. 	









	______________________

	Mark Kenney, MD, PhD

	Pager # 12036





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2083-02-26

 
Attending Admission Note

HPI:  54 year old woman with h/o DM, HTN, and depression who is transferred to PSH from Missouri Baptist Hospital after being admitted from 2/15-2/20/83 and then readmitted on 2/22 with abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting.  She has a h/o several admisions to the hospital for abdominal pain attributed to diabetic gastroparesis.  She has had an extensive GI work-up in the past including multiple abdominal CT scans, gastric emptying study, colonoscopy, upper endoscopy, and small bowel follow through.  All studies were negative except for the gastric emptying study.  She has been treated with multiple medications, including Reglan, Ativan, Compazine, and Zelnorm without much effect.  She is currently taking Neurontin and Cymbalta to treat neuropathic pain, and her PCP started her on MS Contin in December since nothing else seemed to be helping.  The pt states that the MS Contin helped during the month of December, but then it did not seem to be working as well.  The pt is distraught over her symptoms because the pain is severe and frequent.  She has been unable to return to work for 2 years because of the pain, and she would like to be able to do so.  The pain is not necessarily related to eating.  Yesterday, she felt well and was able to eat.  Today, she was doing fine until she had to drink the gastrografin, and then it escalated to an 8/10.  She received some IV morphine, and now it is down to 4/10.
	At Missouri Baptist Hospital, her MS Contin was held, but when her BP went up, she was restarted on it.  They also started clonidine BID for her uncontrolled HTN.  It appears that a AFP level was drawn and was elevated at 11.1.  However, it is written multiple times in the transfer materials that she had an elevated CEA level of 11.1.

Problems
Diabetes mellitus : since 2060's, poorly controlled
Hypertension 
Gastroparesis : N/V due to diabetes
Retinopathy : due to AODM, s/p first laser treatment 3/81, found to have swelling of the optic discs in 8/82 and evaluated at PCH
S/P cholecystectomy 
S/P TAH/BSO : menopause at age 46 

Medications (on transfer)
Heparin 5000 u SQ BID
Reglan 10 mg IV Q 6 hours
Hydrochlorothiazide 25 MG (25MG TABLET take 1) PO QAM , for high blood pressure
Insulin 70/30 HUMAN 70-30 U/ML VIAL SC as directed , 25u SQ before breakfast and 15u before dinner.
Nexium 40 mg po QD
Lisinopril 20MG TABLET PO QAM 

Medications (as an outpatient)
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 325 MG (325MG TABLET take 1) PO QD 
Cymbalta (DULOXETINE) 60MG CAPSULE DR PO QAM x 30 days
Hydrochlorothiazide 25 MG (25MG TABLET take 1) PO QAM , for high blood pressure
Insulin 70/30 HUMAN 70-30 U/ML VIAL SC as directed , 60u SQ before breakfast and 40u before dinner.
Lipitor (ATORVASTATIN) 10MG TABLET PO QHS 
Lisinopril 40MG TABLET PO QAM 
Ms CONTIN (MORPHINE CONTROLLED RELEASE) 15MG TABLET SA PO Q12H 
Neurontin (GABAPENTIN) 300 MG (300MG CAPSULE take 1) PO TID 
Potassium CHLORIDE SLOW REL. (KCL SLOW RELEASE) 40 MEQ (10MEQ CAPSULE SA take 4) PO QD 

Allergies
PERCOCET - GI upset, 

Social History	
Works as bio technician at Yale but has not worked x 2 years due to abdominal pain; Born in Herzegovina, but in Canada x yrs. Sister in area is local support; no smoking or Etoh. 

Family History	
Mother-died in car accident. Father-alive in Herzegovina, in good health. 

Review of Systems	
Negative unless noted in HPI.

Physical Exam	
BP: 229/103--> 195/95          Tmax: 99.5         P: 72        RR: 18      Pulse ox=98% RA
GENERAL: 	Tearful when talking about her pain; appears comfortable.
SKIN:		NL turgor, no abnormal lesions
NECK:	            No thyromegally, no nodes
CHEST:	            Clear lungs, NL frame
COR:		NL S1S2, no murmur, rubs, or gallops.
BACK:	            No spinal tenderness.
ABD:		NL BS; soft, tender over umbilical region and LLQ; no guarding or rebound; NO HSM
RECTAL:	            Guaiac neg., no masses.
EXT:		No edema, clubbing, or cyanosis
NEURO:	            NL MS, NL gait

Results
Date/Time         NA             K              CL             CO2            
02/25/2083        138            3.4            102            28.4           

Date/Time         BUN            CRE            GLU            
02/25/2083        10             1.1            169 (H)        

Date/Time         CA             MG             TBILI          DBILI          
02/25/2083        8.3 (L)        1.1 (L)        0.2            0.1            

Date/Time         TP             ALB            GLOB           LACT           
03/04/2007                                                     0.9            
02/25/2083        5.8 (L)        2.7 (L)        3.1                           

Date/Time         AMY            LIPS           
02/25/2083        98             2.3            

Date/Time         ALT/SGPT       AST/SGOT       ALKP           TBILI          
02/25/2083        9              11             67             0.2            

Date/Time         DBILI          
02/25/2083        0.1            

Date/Time         WBC            RBC            HGB            HCT            
02/25/2083        5.3            3.73 (L)       11.0 (L)       30.3 (L)       

Date/Time         MCV            MCH            MCHC           PLT            
02/25/2083        81             29.5           36.3           235            

Date/Time         RDW            
02/25/2083        13.0           

Date/Time         DIFFR          METHOD         %NEUT          %LYMPH         
02/25/2083        RECEIVED       Auto           57             36             

Date/Time         %MONO          %EOS           %BASO          
02/25/2083        5              2              0              

Results
Endoscopy

Report Number:  28618552                              Report Status: Final
Type:  Upper Endoscopy
Date:  06/16/2081

Gastrointestinal Endoscopy Unit
Patient Name: Nicole Frantz
Gender: F
Patient ID:   2360719
Exam Date:    6/16/2081 02:50 PM
Procedure:       Upper GI endoscopy
Indications:     Epigastric abdominal distress/pain

Findings:        The esophagus was normal. The stomach was
                 normal. The examined duodenum was normal.
Impression:      - Normal esophagus.
                 - Normal stomach.
                 - Normal examined duodenum.
Recommendation:  medical management of gastroparesis


Report Number:  67659198                              Report Status: Final
Type:  Colonoscopy
Date:  02/14/2081

Gastrointestinal Endoscopy Unit
Patient Name: Nicole Frantz
Gender: F
Patient ID:   2360719
Exam Date:    2/14/2081 10:00 AM
Procedure:       Colonoscopy

Findings:        The colon (entire examined portion) was normal.
                 Unabel to successfully enter into the terminal
                 ileum.
Impression:      - The colon is normal.
Recommendation:  SBFT to visualize TI.

Radiology

Exam Number:  2873517                        Report Status:  Final
Type:  AbdCT + PelCT +
Date/Time:  08/09/2082 22:38
Exam Code:  GMKUN+
Ordering Provider:  UGALDE, JAZZLYNN

HISTORY:  
     S/S ABD PAIN, NAUSEA/VOM, PLS ASSESS FOR OBSTRUCTION

REPORT:
     This study was reviewed by Dr. Yee and Dr. Janssen.
     HISTORY: As provided in the header.
     COMPARISON: 10/31/2081
     TECHNIQUE:
     Contiguous axial CT scans of both the abdomen and pelvis were
     performed from the lung bases to the proximal femora to assess for
     obstruction.
     Imaging was continued into the pelvis because a charge can affect
     both cavities.
     Abdominal and pelvic images were obtained following administration
     of both oral and intravenous contrast.
     FINDINGS:
     LUNG BASES. Linear densities in the lung bases likely represents
     atelectasis.
     HEPATOBILIARY.
     Liver. The liver is normal in appearance without evidence of
     biliary ductal dilatation or focal lesion.
     Gallbladder and Bile Ducts. Patient status post cholecystectomy.
     Pancreas. Normal in appearance.
     BOWEL. There is no evidence of the obstruction or bowel wall
     thickening.  A moderate amount of stool seen in the colon and
     rectum.
     GENITOURINARY:
     Kidneys. Normal in appearance without evidence of renal calculus
     or hydronephrosis.
     Ureters and bladder. Normal in appearance.
     Adrenal glands. Normal in appearance.
     Pelvic organs. Vascular calcifications are noted the pelvis.
     PERITONEUM:No evidence of fluid collection, free air or peritoneal
     mass lesions.
     RETROPERITONEUM:
     Lymph nodes. There are a few small bilateral inguinal lymph nodes
     present without bulk.
     Vessels.  Unremarkable.
     BONES AND SOFT TISSUES. Partial sacralization of L5.
     IMPRESSION.
     No evidence of obstruction.
     
    
Exam Number:  3436658                        Report Status:  Final
Type:  Gastric Emptyng
Date/Time:  06/22/2081 12:42
Exam Code:  224
Ordering Provider:  FARLEY, ERIC

HISTORY:  
     GASTROPERISIS, NAUSEA AND VOMITING

REPORT:
     A gastric emptying study was performed using eggs labeled with 17
     MBq technetium 99m sulfur colloid.  There was no evidence of
     gastroesophageal reflux over 60 minutes of observation.  Gastric
     emptying was reduced, showing only 9% emptying at 60 minutes and
     29% emptying at 90 minutes.
     Impression
     Reduced gastric emptying with 29% emptying of a solid meal at 90
     minutes after ingestion.
     
     
Exam Number:  2048395                        Report Status:  Final
Type:  SmallBowel only
Date/Time:  02/16/2081 13:40
Exam Code:  204QY
Ordering Provider:  SHEEHAN, XIMENA

HISTORY:  
     iddm, htn, n/v and abdominal pain x 6 weeks, negative coloscopy, but
could not enter terminal ileum
assess for mass, TI thickening

REPORT:
     Image interpretation reviewed by Dr. Narvaez.
     TECHNIQUE:
     A single contrast small bowel series.
     FINDINGS:
     On small bowel follow through, the small bowel loops are normal in
     caliber and distribution. Spot compression views of the terminal
     ileum are normal. The transit time was normal.
     

IMPRESSION
     NORMAL SMALL BOWEL SERIES.
     
Assessment and Plan	
54 yo woman with DM, HTN, and depression who has had severe chronic abdominal pain x 2 years.  Extensive GI w/u has been negative except for gastric emptying study.
1.  GI: Pain is responsive to morphine.  Will continue MS contin and treat with IV morphine prn for breakthrough pain.  Gastroparesis has been a working diagnosis since all other testing has been negative.  She has other complications of DM which does put her at increased risk for autonomic dysfunction of the GI tract.  Other diagnoses to consider are bowel ischemia, although colonoscopy and CT scans in the past have not shown any changes in the bowel consistent with this diagnosis.  We will order CTA of the abdomen to rule this out.  She did have a negative anti-endomysial Ab in 2081, but I think it would be worth checking both anti-endomysial Ab and anti-gliadin Ab to r/u celiac sprue again.  We will send both an AFP and CEA levels to f/u on the unclear laboratory abnormality from Missouri Baptist Hospital.
2.  HTN:  BP is very elevated today, and this may in part be due to stopping the clonidine (which may have been given to help with GI motility).  Will continue her on her 40 mg dose of Lisinopril and 25 mg of HCTZ.  In addition, we will treat her with hydralazine until we can get the BP down.
3.  DM:  Will  treat with Insulin NPH 25 u Q am, 20 u Q pm and with sliding scale regular insulin.  Will monitor BS.
4.  Pain management:  Will continue Cymbalta and Neurontin along the the MS Contin and prn IV morphine.



_____________________________________________
Mildred D. Yunker, M.D.




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="not met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>