<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2104-11-10

                     SLHC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

DO,TANYA V   639-25-21-7                    VISIT DATE: 11/10/04

The resident's history, physical examination, and evaluation were 

reviewed by me; and I concur.  In addition, I personally 

interviewed and examined this patient.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 76-year-old female with 

a history of type 2 diabetes on Glucophage with a history of 

neuropathy who presents complaining of right foot pain, swelling, 

and redness.  The patient had a callus shaved off the plantar 

aspect of her foot approximately three weeks ago.  She noticed some 

aching pain in the area of her foot over the last several days and 

then in the last 24 to 48 hours has developed swelling and redness 

of her foot with inability to ambulate secondary to severe pain.  

She has had loss of appetite, but she denies any fever or 

generalized malaise.  She denies any leg swelling.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  Positive for arthritis, type 2 diabetes, a 

history of vasculitis, history of diabetic neuropathy, and history 

of cataracts.  Her surgical history is positive for right total hip 

replacement, bilateral knee replacements, laminectomy in the back 

with fusion with rods, and a history of a colostomy with reversal.  

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  She has smoked in the past.  

She does not drink.  She is a retired Paralegal, lives alone.  She 

has a family history of diabetes.  Please see resident note for the 

remainder of the details of the patient's history including a long 

list of medications.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  VITAL SIGNS:  Temperature 99.0, pulse 94, 

respirations 18, blood pressure 137/50.  Oxygen saturation is 92% 

on room air.  The patient is an awake, alert, well-developed 

female, pleasant, talkative, in no acute distress.  EXTREMITIES: 

Her examination is most remarkable for the right lower extremity 

which shows edema and redness over the dorsum of her right foot.  

This extends down over the metatarsophalangeal joints and down 

underneath the plantar aspect of her foot over the heads of the 

metatarsals and the bases of the toes.  On the plantar aspect of 

the foot below the third toe, there is an area of skin change which 

is very tender.  There is a blanching yellow appearance that is 

very firm.  It is not fluctuant.  There is no drainage.  It appears 

to be the area where the callus was shaved.  The remainder of the 

foot is slightly firm, erythematous, and tender.  Her pulses are 

1+.  She has good capillary refill, and light touch is intact.  Her 

calf is soft and nontender.  Please see the resident note for the 

remainder of the details of the physical examination.  Evaluation 

of this patient in the Emergency Department included laboratory 

studies.  This is a diabetic patient with foot cellulitis secondary 

to a wound on the plantar aspect of her foot.  Of note, she also is 

exposed to pool water as she swims daily.  

LABORATORY EVALUATION:  She had laboratory studies performed which 

show a white blood cell count of 14,000; hematocrit 31.5; platelets 

348.  Her electrolytes including glucose are pending at the time of 

this dictation.

THERAPY RENDERED/COURSE IN ED:  IV access was obtained, and the 

patient was treated with IV antibiotics of Levaquin and 

Clindamycin.  

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Right foot cellulitis.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  Her primary care 

physician, Dr. Keane, who saw her prior to her arrival in the 

Emergency Department was contacted.  The patient is being admitted 

to the General Medical Service.  Please see the resident note for 

the remainder of the details of the patient's visit.

___________________________________                    VK603/23033 

LISA NOYES, M.D.  LN95                              D:11/10/04 

                                                       T:11/10/04 

Dictated by:  LISA NOYES, M.D.  LN95 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2106-05-02

                     SLHC EMERGENCY DEPT VISIT

 

DO,TANYA V   639-25-21-7                    VISIT DATE: 05/02/06

This patient was interviewed and examined by myself, Dr. Martinez, 

as well as Dr. Xanders, on May 02, 2106.  Please see note for full 

details, reviewed in full.

PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  Leg swelling and pain.

HISTORY OF PRESENTING COMPLAINT:  This is a 78-year-old female who 

is on chronic prednisone for rheumatoid arthritis, who comes in 

with left leg swelling and pain going on for two days, and she was 

sent in for evaluation.  There has been no change in range of 

motion.  She has been able to ambulate, but with difficulty and 

limping.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  She does have a history of Staphylococcus 

aureus infection of the right side.  She also has 

non-insulin-dependent diabetes, vasculitis and neuropathy.  She is 

status post multiple joint operations.

SOCIAL HISTORY AND FAMILY HISTORY:  No tobacco or ETOH.  She lives 

alone.  Family history is noncontributory.   Please see the 

resident's note for the rest of the details.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL:  Awake, alert, very pleasant female 

in no apparent distress.  VITAL SIGNS:  Her temperature is 98.  Her 

normal temperature is about 96.5.  She is not tachycardic.  

EXTREMITIES:  Her exam is notable for some shininess to the skin, 

some redness and some swelling.  Distally neurovascularly intact.  

Full range of motion of her knee and ankle above and below the area 

at her baseline.  She does have a total knee replacement on that 

side.

FINAL DIAGNOSIS:  Cellulitis.

DISPOSITION (including condition upon discharge):  We are concerned 

that she may have a DVT.  We are going to admit her to our 

observation unit to give her antibiotics.  We will discuss her case 

with Dr. Keane, her primary care physician, and likely discharge 

her in the morning with improvement as long as she does not have a 

DVT.  If she has a DVT we will add on subcutaneous enoxaparin to 

her medical regimen.  The patient is currently in satisfactory 

condition.

___________________________________                    DJ241/84357 

BEVERLY B. MARTINEZ, M.D.     BM88                      D:05/02/06 

                                                       T:05/03/06 

Dictated by:  BEVERLY B. MARTINEZ, M.D.     BM88 

 ******** Not reviewed by Attending Physician ********





****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2106-10-07





OFFICE NOTE
SAINT LUKE'S-ROOSEVELT HOSPITAL CENTER
799 SARGENT AVENUE
KAUFMAN, MO  85156


Tanya Do
MRN: 63925217
October 07, 2106


CHIEF COMPLAINT.  Follow-up with regard to multiple medical problems.

SUBJECTIVE.  She begins with a very long reprise of her complaints about her 
hospitalization at Sawtelle Veterans Hospital earlier this fall.

She then follows with a long discussion of the difficulties in securing 
diabetic supplies.  Her home blood glucoses have been variable, reportedly 
due to poorly functioning glucose meter.

The Neurology Consultant has added lisinopril and Plavix to her regimen.

Had what appears to have been an injection of epidural steroids for treatment 
of symptoms referable to spinal stenosis per Dr. Jaeger, to good effect.  Her 
back pain has now begun to recrudesce, and she is considering another such 
injection.

There are multiple other somatic complaints -- neck pain; recurring nocturnal 
sweating; dry cough; runny nose; other.

MEDICATIONS.  Baby aspirin; supplements of calcium and vitamin D; Fosamax 
70 mg once weekly; prednisone 5 mg b.i.d.; folic acid 1 mg per day; 
methotrexate 15 mg per week; Celebrex 200 mg b.i.d.; Glucophage 500 mg 2 PO 
b.i.d.; Zebeta 2.5 mg per day; lisinopril 20 mg per day; Plavix 75 mg per 
day; Lipitor 10 mg t.i.w.

PMH.  Reviewed.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS.  Other systems reviewed and are negative.

OBJECTIVE.  General appearance.  In no distress.  Vital signs.  Blood 
pressure 128/60 left arm sit.  Pulse 64 and regular.  Respiratory rate 12.  
Chest.  Clear.  Cardiovascular.  No murmurs.  Abdomen.  No mass, tenderness, 
or organomegaly.  Bowel sounds normal.

LABORATORY DATA.  Imaging studies reviewed; a PA and lateral chest x-ray, 
obtained on April 13, showed only bibasilar atelectasis.

Hemoglobin A1C was 6.5.

IMPRESSION.  

1.	Chronic rheumatoid arthritis:  apparently unchanged.
3.	DM:  ? current status.  Last time's hemoglobin A1C was slightly 
elevated.
6.	Psychosocial stresses.
29.	? TIA:  Now on lisinopril and Plavix per Neurology.


Tanya Do
MRN: 63925217
October 07, 2106
Page 2


__.	Spinal stenosis:  Reportedly good symptomatic response to epidural 
steroids.
__.	Hypercholesterolemia:  Now on low-dose Lipitor:  ? current status.
(a)	Nasal congestion, other:  ? etiology.

PLAN.  

Diagnostic.  CBC, hepatic function profile.  BUN and creatinine.  Hemoglobin 
A1C.  Lipid profile, CPK.

Therapeutic.  All medications refilled.  Continue current regimen.  Activity 
as tolerated.  Flu shot.  Return visit later in the year.



________________________________
Harold G. Keane, M.D.

DD: 10/07/06
DT: 10/11/06
DV: 10/07/06
/talbert






****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2107-08-03




Team 3A Intern Admission Note

Name:	Do, Tanya
MRN:  6051778
Date of Admission: 8/03/07

PCP: Dr. Orelia Burns
Admitting Physician: Dr. Orelia Burns

Chief Complaint:  
	79 year old woman with DM-2 (7 years), HTN, on chronic immunosuppression for RA, presents with left lower leg erythema and swelling. 
History Obtained From:  
Patient, chart review

History of Present Illness:  
	This is a 79 year old woman with a long-standing history of RA on chronic immunosuppression (prednisone and now on methotrexate), DM-2 (HbA1c 5.5), previous history of leg surgeries with ?vasculitis, and prior history of cellulitis, who presents with a 1 week history erythema and swelling on right lower leg (anterior).  Ms. Do has had two prior hospitalizations for cellulitis/osteomyelitis. In 2104, she developed osteomyelitis following a fall, requiring surgery for debridment (right leg).  In 2106, she was also admitted to Seymour Hospital with cellulitis of right leg and required a 2-week course of IV antibiotics.  At this presentation, she has been in her usual state of health (ET 25 feet, limited by pain in legs, no dyspnea, no chest pain) until last Tuesday when she presented to her podiatrist for a corn removal (right foot). The podiatrist made an observation that she had some erythema on the dorsal part of the foot. She was not experiencing any pain.  Over this past week, she noted that the erythema and some swelling had extended, now to include the anterior portion of the lower shin.  She presented to EFHC for a follow-up appointment, and was treated with Keflex po.  Her cellulitis failed to improve and she presented to her PCP for evaluation on the day of admission, and was directly admitted to OGH.
	She denies any new fevers or chills (patient is having almost daily night sweats, which have been partially relieved with standing Tylenol intake. These night sweats, along with the weight loss and anorexia are in the process of being worked up at this time). She has had no cough, nasal discharge, headaches, diarrhea, or dysuria/burning. No recent trauma to the leg.

Past Medical History:

Diabetes 
	On oral hypoglycemics, no history of insulin use
	Checks own FSG tid
	HbA1c - 5.5% (3/07)
	Yearly eye exams, frequent podiatrist visits
Hypertension - on two agents, no known history of CAD
Rheumatoid arthritis
	40+ year history
	Has been on chronic steroids - 25 years
	Methotrexate - several years
Osteomyelitis - 2104 (left foot)
	Fallowing a fall and injury
Vasculitis on legs with ulcers 
Leg cellulites - 2106
Right renal mass 
	See on CT scan during a work-up for anorexia, weight loss, and night sweats
	To be biopsied by IR
Chronic anemia - approximately monthly Aranesp injections - being evaluated at EFHC
Osteoporosis
	Multiple fractures
Spinal stenosis - s/p rod fixation/fusion
TIA - 2106, no residual deficits
Hyperlipidemia
Secondary adrenal insufficiency - due to chronic steroid use
Viral meningitis - 2106
Cataracts - bilateral surgeries


Surgeries:
Back fusion - 2098, 2099
Left knee replacement - 2082
Right knee replacement - 2081
Right hip replacement - 2070
Sigmoid resection secondary to obstruction - 2103
Reversal of colostomy - 2103
Cataract surgeries

Medications: 
1.	Methotrexate 15 mg qweek
2.	Prednisone 5 mg bid
3.	Glucophage 1000 mg bid
4.	Folic acid 1 mg qam
5.	Zabeta 1.25 mg qd
6.	Fosamax 70 mg qweek
7.	Celebrex 200 mg bid
8.	Aspirin 81 mg qd
9.	Tylenol 1000 mg bid
10.	Calcium 500 mg bid
11.	MVI 1 qd
12.	Lipitor 10 mg qod
13.	Lisinopril 10 mg qd
14.	Plavix 75 mg qd
Allergies: 
	Codeine, morphine - nausea
	
Family History: 
Father - died when patient was 13 months old
Mother - diabetes
No know family history of malignancies or autoimmune disorders
Social history:
Divorced, lives alone, no children. Used to work as a paralegal for 42 years. Retired. 
    Tobacco: 50 pack-year history (stopped 20 years ago)
    Alcohol: none

Review of System: 
General: Night sweats, weight loss - 1.5 years.  Loosing approximately 0.5-1 lbs per week.
Skin: Multiple bruises, easy bruising
HEENT: No headaches, trauma, , diplopia, photophobia, eye pain or discharge;  hearing loss  (? Worsened after meningitis) deficits; no epistaxis, rhinorrhea, sinus pain; no dental problems, mouth sores, pain or hoarsness, no history of thrush
Neck: No pain, limitation of motion, masses
Resp: No pleuritic pain, wheezing, cough, hemoptysis
CV: No chest pain, palpitations, DOE, orthopnea, PND, claudications
GI: Decreased appetite during the past several months.  No food intolerance,  dysphagia, abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, hematemesis, hematochezia, diarrhea, constipation, hemorrhoid
GU: No dysuria, urgency, burning, frequency, polyuria, nocturia, hesitancy, incontinence, hematuria
Heme: Easy bleeding, bruising
MSK: See HPI
Neuro: No vertigo, tremors, memory deficits, seizures, paralysis, weakness, incoordination, aphasia 

Physical Exam:
VS: BP=142/ 67; HR=77 ; RR=20 ; SaO2=95% RA ; Tmax=100.7; Weight=100.6 
General: In no apparent acute distress, well-nourishes, well-groomed, appears of younger than stated age
Skin: Soft, warm, moist, multiple bruises on extremities
HEENT: NCAT, PERRL, EOMI; sclera anicteric, no conjuntival injections, no nasal erythema or discharge; moist mucous membranes, no oropharyngeal lesions, no thrush
Neck: Supple, full range of motion, no thyromegaly, JVP 5-6 cm
Lymph glands: No cervical, supraclavicular, inguinal LAD
Spine: No spinal tenderness, normal curvutre. Scars consistent with prior surgeries. No CVA tenderness.
Chest: No dullness to precussion, good air entry bilaterally, clear to auscultation without wheezes, rales, ronchi
Cor: Non-displaced PMI, no precordial thrills or heaves; regular rhythm, normal rate, normal S1, S2, ? S4, no murmurs
Abdomen:  Scars consistent with a prior surgery, minimally distended, BS normal throughout; soft, non-tender to palpation and precussion, no rebound tenderness or guarding, no organomegaly or masses palpated
Ext: Trace edema at ankles right >left; no clubbing or cyanosis; bruise (palpable on right distal shin), erythema and slightly increased temperature on leftight anterior shin (8x5 cm).  No tenderness to palpation, no tenderness to palpation of calves bilaterally. Scars from prior surgery on the right.  Upper extremities - left in brace; ulnar deviation bilaterally, increased MCPs and PIPs, + rheumatoid nodules
Pulses: 2+ radial, dorsalis pedis, posterior tibialis bilaterally 
Neuro: Awake, alert, very talkative. CN - PERRLA, EOMI, symmetric face with intact sensation, no horizontal or vertical nystagmus.  Normal tone, 5/5 strength throughout upper and lower extremities; 2+ brachial, radial, patellar, ankle reflexes; downward plantar reflexes bilaterally; bilaterally equal and intact sensation to light touch, cold, vibration; intact proprioception bilaterally.  Normal-based gait.
Labs:
Recent labs pending
Radiology: 
CT Scan:  MILD SPLENOMEGALY WITH MULTIPLE DISCRETE SPLENIC LESIONS AND CALCIFIED FOCI.  DIFFERENTIAL DIAGNOSIS INCLUDES GRANULOMAS/SARCOIDOSIS.  ISOLATED LYMPHOMA IS ALSO A CONSIDERATION.  ON IMAGING IT IS DIFFICULT TO DIFFERENTIATE THESE PATHOLOGIES. 
	TWO DISCRETE LESIONS IN THE POSTERIOR CORTEX OF RIGHT KIDNEY ARE SUSPICIOUS FOR SOLID RENAL MASS OR HYPERDENSE CYST.
Assessment/Plan: 
	This is a 79 year old woman with past medical history of DM-2, chronic immunosuppresion (steroid use), RA, HTN, h/o leg ulcers, cellulitis and osteomyelitis, who presents with a 1 week history of left lower extremity swelling and erythema, without other symptomatic complaints, that has been resistant to po treatment
1.	Cellulitis - this woman is predisposed to cellulitis for a number of reasons, including chronic immunosuppression, diabetes, and prior surgeries to the area that have altered the anatomy and blood supply and lymphatic drainage.  Other potential causes include osteo or DVT. At this point, there is little to suspect osteo in this patient.
a.	Blood cultures
b.	Given her multiple problems, requires broad spectrum coverage - Zosyn 2.25 g IV q6 h (CrCl 45)
c.	Elevate the leg
d.	Warm compresses to increased circulation
e.	Mark the extent of cellulitis and monitor progression with therapy
f.	If cellulitis does not improve - will get imaging to evaluate for underlying infection. Will also get LENIS to rule out a DVT.
2.	Weight loss, anorexia, night sweats, now with R kidney mass - the differential for potential causes is very broad. She apparently had a negative PPD last year.  Extensive work-up to date was only notable for kidney cysts and mass
a.	Will attempt to schedule IR-guided biopsy
b.	Will stop ASA, plavix and celebrex in anticipation of the biopsy
c.	Continue to monitor fever curve
3.	Diabetes - patient is taking in normal diet, however in the setting of infection, will  put of home meds and do RISS/FSG
4.	HTN - continue Lisinopril
5.	RA - continue Prednisone and Methotrexate 
a.	Blood cultures (in the setting of patient's infection)
b.	Monitor fever curve and other vitals signs carefully
6.	Adrenal insufficiency - given patient's long term history of steroid use, she will need stress doses if becomes more acutely ill
7.	Prophylaxis - Nexium 20 qd; Fragmin 2500 U sc qd
8.	Code - DNI but wants chest compressions "for a while".  Healthcare proxy (Theresa  Kraft  270 Ridge Road/street, Little Elm, Mo 86277, tel 019-793-7578)


-------------------------------
Denise Overman, MD
Pager 13831




****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2109-09-08

Patient Name: DO, TANYA V.;  MRN: 6051778
Dictated on: 09/08/2109 by TIBOR OQUINN, M.D. 

 
Ms. Tanya V. Do is an 81-year-old right-handed white woman with seropositive, nodular, erosive rheumatoid arthritis that was diagnosed in 2060, type II noninsulin-dependent diabetes mellitus, vascular insufficiency in her legs, peripheral neuropathy, hearing loss in her left ear, right total hip arthroplasty surgery in 2070, right total knee arthroplasty surgery in 2081, left total knee arthroplasty surgery in 2082, a lumbar fusion performed in 2098 and again in 2099, a sigmoid colonic resection in 2103, cellulitis and osteomyelitis involving her right foot in October 2104, a cataract extracted from her right eye in 2102, a cataract extracted from her left eye in 2103, a transient ischemic attack in June 2106, and cellulitis involving her legs in 2107.  She returns to see me in rheumatologic follow-up at Rheumatology, this morning.  
 
Ms. Do has continued to take prednisone 5 mg by mouth twice daily, Celebrex 200 mg by mouth twice daily, and methotrexate 17.5 mg by mouth weekly, with good control of her joint pain, swelling, and stiffness.    
 
She continues to have difficulty grasping objects with her right hand, dropping objects that are held in that hand.  She also experiences numbness in her right ring and little fingers.  She wears a neutral resting splint on her right wrist for symptoms that she ascribes to right carpal tunnel syndrome.  She has opted not to undergo surgical treatment of her right ulnar neuropathy, after consultation with Dr. Kyron M. Castaneda of the hand surgery service at OGH.  
 
She has experienced inadequate treatment of her pain on Darvocet-N 100 two tablets taken by mouth once daily.   

She has continued to tolerate methotrexate therapy without symptoms of significant toxicity.  She has not experienced skin rashes, fevers, chills, sores in her nose or mouth, hair loss, cough, shortness of breath, nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea.   

She has continued to tolerate prednisone therapy without adverse symptoms other than for fragility of her skin and easy bruisability.  
 
She experienced improvement in her lower back discomfort following an epidural corticosteroid injection to her lower back on Jun 02, 2109.  She is scheduled to receive another epidural corticosteroid injection to her lower back on September 09, 2109.   

She has some difficulty dressing herself, getting in and out of bed, lifting a full cup or glass to her mouth, washing and drying her entire body, bending down to pick up clothing from the floor, and turning regular faucets on and off.  She has much difficulty walking outdoors on flat ground and getting in and out of an automobile.  She is unable to walk two miles or participate in sports or games to her liking. (MDHAQ = 1.8)  She has much difficulty getting a good night's sleep and she has some difficulty dealing with feelings of anxiety and depression.   

She is stiff throughout the day and experiences severe pain and severe fatigue.  

Medications

Tylenol (ACETAMINOPHEN) 500MG TABLET take 2 Tablet(s) PO BID 
Folic ACID 1MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Asa (ACETYLSALICYLIC ACID) 81MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Mvi (MULTIVITAMINS) 1 CAPSULE PO QD 
Cod LIVER OIL 1 TBSP PO BID 
Calcium + D (500 ELEM. CA) (CALCIUM CARBONATE 1250 MG (500MG ELEM CA)/ VIT D 125 IU) 1 TAB PO BID 
Aranesp (DARBEPOETIN ALFA) 200 MCG SC EVERY OTHER WEEK 
Methotrexate (RHEUM.) 17.5 MG (2.5MG TABLET take 7) PO QWEEK 
Prednisone 5MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO BID 
Glucophage (METFORMIN) 500MG TABLET take 2 Tablet(s) PO BID 
Zebeta (BISOPROLOL FUMARATE) 5MG TABLET take 0.5 PO QD 
Fosamax (ALENDRONATE) 70MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QWEEK 
Celebrex (CELECOXIB) 200MG CAPSULE take 1 Capsule(s) PO BID 
Plavix (CLOPIDOGREL) 75 MG PO QD 
Lisinopril 10MG TABLET take 1 Tablet(s) PO QD 
Carafate SUSPENSION (SUCRALFATE SUSPENSION) 1 GM (1G/10ML ORAL SUSP take 10 ML) PO QID 
Restoril (TEMAZEPAM) 15MG CAPSULE take 1-2 PO QHS PRN INSOMNIA 
 
ALLERGIES:  Codeine has caused gastrointestinal upset.  Morphine has caused nausea and projectile vomiting.  
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  Vital Signs  BP 148/60, P 64, RR 16, Temp 98.7 F, Wt 144 lb  Ms. Do was a very pleasant, cushingoid-appearing white woman in some distress due to pain.  Her skin was notable for ecchymoses on her extremities.  There was a healed skin graft on her left lower leg.  Well-healed scars were present over the lateral aspect of her right hip and over the anterior aspect of each knee.  There were no skin rashes.  Subcutaneous nodules, consistent with rheumatoid nodules, were present over the extensor surfaces of both elbows.  Her lungs were clear to auscultation.  Her cardiac examination revealed normal first and second heart sounds without murmurs or extra sounds.  Her musculoskeletal examination was notable for pain upon abduction and external rotation of her left shoulder.  There was ulnar deviation of the fingers of her right hand.  There was a boutonniere deformity of her left ring finger.  Bilateral hallux valgus deformities and cock-up toe deformities were present on both feet.  There was full painless motion of all small and large joints in both arms and legs without evidence of joint inflammation or of other significant joint deformity.  Her neurologic examination was notable for decreased sensation to light touch in the distribution of her right ulnar nerve, but was otherwise normal.  Her neurologic examination was normal with normal mental status, normal function of cranial nerves II through XII, normal muscle strength and tone in both arms and legs, intact sensation to light touch throughout, normal coordination, and symmetric deep tendon reflexes with downgoing plantar reflexes bilaterally. 
 
LABORATORY DATA:  I reviewed the laboratory data in the LMR with Ms. Do.  Studies performed at OGH on Jun 04, 2109, revealed ESR 19 mm/hr, CRP 10.6 mg/L, a benign urinalysis, ANA 1:80 with a speckled pattern of immunofluorescence, rheumatoid factor 165 IU/mL, and IgG anti-CCP antibodies 129 units.  

IMPRESSION:  
 
1.  Nodular, erosive rheumatoid arthritis since 2060, without evidence of synovitis on prednisone 5 mg p.o. b.i.d., Celebrex 200 mg p.o. b.i.d., and methotrexate 17.5 mg p.o. weekly.  She continues to be most limited by her right hand dysfunction and right ulnar neuropathy, but has opted to treat this conservatively.  
 
2.  Low back pain, treated with epidural corticosteroid injection on Jun 02, 2109.  
 
3.  Type II noninsulin-dependent diabetes mellitus.

4.  Vascular insufficiency in her legs.

5.  Peripheral neuropathy.

6.  Hearing loss in her left ear.

7.  Right total hip arthroplasty surgery in 2070.

8.  Right total knee arthroplasty surgery in 2081.

10. Left total knee arthroplasty surgery in 2082.

11. Lumbar fusion performed in 2098 and again in 2099.

12. Sigmoid colonic resection in 2103.

13. Cellulitis and osteomyelitis involving her right foot in October 2104.

14. Cataract extracted from her right eye in 2102.

15. Cataract extracted from her left eye in 2103.

16. Transient ischemic attack in June 2106.

17. Cellulitis involving her legs in 2107.  

RECOMMENDATIONS:  I discussed my impressions with Ms. Do.  I suggested that she increase her frequency of Darvocet-N 100 dosing to 2 tablets taken by mouth every 6 hours, as needed for pain control.  She will withhold a Tylenol dose, when she takes Darvocet N-100.  She will continue taking her other medications at their present doses.  
 
Laboratory studies will be performed today to assess her CBC, WBC differential count, plasma creatinine, ALT, AST, serum albumin, ESR, and CRP.  
 
Ms. Do will return to see me on December 11, 2109, at 9:40 a.m., so that I may assess her response to continued treatment and make any necessary changes in therapy. 


_____________________________________________
Tibor Oquinn, M.D.

cc:  

Orelia D. Burns, M.D.  
Kyron M. Castaneda, M.D.  
Scott N. Jaeger, M.D.  
 
Ms. Tanya V. Do 
74 Weymouth Dr 
Chongging, MO  82179 
 
DD:09/08/2109 
DT:09/08/2109 
HY:323054    :7774




****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>