<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<PatientMatching>
<TEXT><![CDATA[

Record date: 2076-06-19

Physical exam - Male



Patient is a 45 yo  M who presents for yearly physical exam.  He has been lost to f/u x > 1 year and was recently hospitalized for R foot ulcer/heel.



Active medical issues include:

Diabetes mellitus : dxed dec 2074 when admitted with foot ulcer. On metformin. 4/75: BG at home 160-170 6/76: BG at home 120-200. Taking glyburide 5 mg qd instead of metformin bec afraid of renal failure. To see diabetes ctr doc in July



Smoking : 12 cig/day x 30 years 

6/76: still smoking, thinking about quitting



Lower extremity ulcer : Right leg. Admitted to RSC 12/2074 - rxed with dicloxacillin 

6/76: admitted to RSC 2 weeks ago with R foot ulcer, rxed with abx, wound care. Followed by surgical clinic - f/u 2 weeks. Wet dry dressings. Pain meds as needed



neuropathy :  6/76: neuropathy bilateral. No longer on ultram - on neurontin



Other issues: impotence.  Asking for viagra.  No chest pain, not on nitrates.

ROS otherwise negative



Current medications:Medications

Neurontin (GABAPENTIN) 100MG, 1 Capsule(s) PO TID : for diabetic neuropahty and pain from heel ulcer

GLYBURIDE 5MG, 1 Tablet(s) PO QD

Percocet 5 Mg/325 Mg (OXYCODONE 5 Mg/acet... 1 TAB PO Q4-6H PRN prn foot ulcer pain : Take as directed 



Allergies

Codeine - GI upset 



Social History:

Single.  Divorced.  He has 1 child - he does not have custody.  He worked up until Dec 2074 - editor at DRS Technologies and burned himself on both legs - developed ulcer.  No workman's comp case pending.  Working again as editor.  Lives in an apartment with his girlfriend.



Smoke 12 cig/day x 30 years.  NO etoh.  Rec marijuana.  No ivda.  Does not wear seat belts.  Walks regularly.



Family history:  Mother has diabetes - on dialysis.  Father also has diabetes. He has 2 brothers - one has diabetes.  Negative for early CAD, stroke, htn, hyperlipidemia, bleeding/clotting disorders, breast CA, colon CA, skin CA.  FH otherwise negative.



PE:

Vital signs

bp 126/70  Wt 130 lbs



Gen: NAD.  A&Ox4.

Affect: normal

HEENT: PERRLA. EOMs intact.  Oropharynx clear

Neck: supple, no adenopathy, no thyromegaly or thyroid nodules.  NO carotid bruits

Lungs: CTAB.  No crackles or wheezes

Cardiac:  RRR.  No m/g/r

Abdomen: soft, ND, NT, nl BS.  No masses or hsm

Ext: no edema.  Pulses 2+ bilaterally.

Back: no flank tenderness, no spinal tenderness

Skin:  R heel ulcer noted - granulation tissue present, healing well.

Neuro DTRS 2+ bilat, strength 5/5 bilat, gait nl.  MOnofilament diminished bilaterally feet



A/P:



Diabetes mellitus : dxed dec 2074 when admitted with foot ulcer. On metformin. 4/75: BG at home 160-170 6/76: BG at home 120-200. Taking glyburide 5 mg qd instead of metformin bec afraid of renal failure. HbA1c pending, microalb pending. Reviewd foot care. Needs eye exam at some point. To see diabetes ctr doc in July



Smoking : 12 cig/day x 30 years

 6/76: still smoking, thinking about quitting - counseled.



Lower extremity ulcer : Right leg. Admitted to RSC 12/2074 - rxed with dicloxacillin 6/76: admitted to RSC 2 weeks ago with R foot ulcer, rxed with abx, wound care. Followed by surgical clinic - f/u 2 weeks. Wet dry dressings. Pain meds as needed



neuropathy : 4/75: started 5 days ago (Fri) - seen in er - sent home. Has signif pain and swelling posteriorly in lower thigh on R - worse since ER eval. To RSC ER again for eval - needs CT thigh/knee and r/o dvt eval. Gave ultram for pain 

6/76: resolved and now with neuropathy bilateral. No longer on ultram , cont neurontin.



Impotence: gave sample of viagra today - 1 50 mg 6 pack, counseled useage.



Health maintenance

Cholesterol 06/19/2076 Done/scheduled 

Complete Physical Exam 06/19/2076 

Home glucose monitoring 06/19/2076 

Hypoglycemia Assessment/Counseling 06/19/2076 

Microalbumin 06/19/2076 pending 

Podiatry exam 06/19/2076 + neuropathy and dec sensation 

Smoking status 06/19/2076 Current smoker 

UA-Protein 04/06/2075 Trace 

HBA1C 06/09/2076 CANCELLED Test request exceeds frequency limits. Cancelled per laboratory policy.Check prior result.

Hct (Hematocrit) 06/11/2076 45.0 

Hgb (Hemoglobin) 06/11/2076 15.9 



f/u 3 mos







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-07-21

Attending Admit Note

Joel Goldberg

MR#  0370149



PCP:  Quentina Thornton , MD

Health Center: Arroyo Grande

CODE:  FULL



Date of admit:  7/20/76





Chief Complaint:  Right foot pain



History of Present Illness:  

46 yo man with hx of DM neuropathy who presented to the ED with right foot pain. He noted "blood blister on right 4th toe 1 wk ago and was seen in ED. He was sent home on neurontin. Last night, right 4th toe was black, with redness on 5th toe as well, with extension to dorsum of foot. No hx of trauma to foot. 



ED course: 

Seen by surgical consult in ED. Recommended Unasyn and arterial LENI's. Localized wound care with silvadene. 



Past Medical History:  

Diabetes - neuropathy, HgB A1c 8.8% on 7/7. Dx 12/74

Nephropathy - trace protein in urine

MGUS

Tobacco abuse

Right heel ulcer - recent hospitalization 6/4 - 6/12 for ulcer with eschar



Allergies:  

Codeine - GI upset



Medications:  

neurontin 100 mg tid

glyburide 5 mg qd

zestril 2.5 mg qd

viagra

percocet



Family History:  





Social History:  

+ tobacco use



Review of Systems:  

No F/C/S, NO CP, No SOB. 



Physical Examination



Vital Signs:  T:98.3  BP:114/73  HR:100  RR:16  96%onRA  



General Appearance:  laying in bed in NAD

HEENT:  mmm, PERRLA, oropharynx clear

Skin:  warm, dry

Neck:  no LAD, no bruits, no thyromegaly

Lungs:  CTA, no w/r/c

Heart:  RRR, +S1/S2, no m/r/g

Abdomen:  soft,  NT/ND, +BS, 

Extremities:  +2 pulses throughout, no edema, right dorsum of foot erythematous, right 4th toe black, right 5th toe erythema

Neuro:  decreased sensation to light touch on both feet, otherwise nonfocal

Psych/Mental Status:  A&O x3, 

Rectal exam:  deferred



Diagnostic Testing:

Plasma Sodium          138                       135-145        mmol/L

Plasma Potassium       4.8                       3.4-4.8        mmol/L

Plasma Chloride        100                       100-108        mmol/L

Plasma Carbon Dioxide  29.8                      23.0-31.9      mmol/L

Plasma Urea Nitrogen   12                        8-25           mg/dl

Plasma Creatinine      0.8                       0.6-1.5        mg/dl

Plasma Glucose         168        H              70-110         mg/dl



WBC                    10.0                      4.5-11.0       th/cmm

HCT                    39.1       L              41.0-53.0      %

HGB                    13.8                      13.5-17.5      gm/dl

PLT                    194                       150-350        th/cumm

MCV                    86                        80-100         fl

RDW                    13.0                      11.5-14.5      %



Poly                   70                        40-70          %

Lymphs                 20         L              22-44          %

Monos                  8                         4-11           %



Blood cultures x 3 neg todate

Wound cx pending

    



Impression:  46 yo male with Diabetic neuropathy and gangrenous 4th right toe with cellulitis. 



Plan:  

1. Foot Ulceration: Surg following. Wound care and unasyn as previous. Arterial leni's pending. 



2. CV: Agree with starting ASA. Stress testing, if indicated, can be performed as outpatient. Agree with starting lipitor 10 mg qd.



3. DM: agree with restarting Zestril for diabetic nephropathy. Would increase dose of glyburide to 5 mg bid. Follow sugars. 



4. ID: Blood cx, wound cx. Unasyn. Adjust abx if necessary. Broad coverage appropriate at this time. 



5. Dispo: agree with SW consult. 



6. Tobacco abuse: agree with urgency of smoking cessation. Thanks to Dr. Rodriquez for discussing with patient. Will discuss wellbutrin with patient. 





_________________________________

Richard Goins, M.D.

Arroyo Grande RSC 

Pager 66553







****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2076-09-21

                                                       Patient Name: GOLDBERG,JOEL [ MRN: 0370149RSC ]

                                                         Date of Visit: 09/21/2076


Chief Complaint:  46yr man with diabetes and peripheral vascular disease with recurrent cellulitis of R foot



History of Present Illness:  Pt known to General surgery service from recent R 4th digit amp for non-resolving wet gangrene.  history of critical distal right superficial femoral artery stenosis treated with a stent in July. He initially presented with ischemia of the fourth and fifth toes on his right foot. Post stenting, the fifth toe eventually recovered; however, the fourth toe became gangrenous.  Now presents with new 5th digit ulcer



Past Medical History: 

Diabetes, HTN, peripheral neuropathy, nephropathy



Past Surgical History: 

Right superficial femoral artery angioplasty and stent placement on 7/20/76.

R 5th digit amp, 9/3/76



Medications: 

Lipitor 10qd

Glyburide 5bid

Neurontin 300tid

Plavix 75qd

Zestril 2.5qd

MS Contin 30bid

Atenolol 12.5bid

Nicotine patch 21mg



Allergies: Codeine->GI



Social History: Homeless

Habits: Tob: 1/2 ppd



Review of Systems:  

No fevers, chills, night sweats

No chest pain, diaphoresis

No DOE, orthopnea



Vital Signs: 

Temp: 98.7    BP: 138/83    HR: 110    RR: 18    SpO2: 99



Physical Exam:  

General Appearance 

Thin, chronically ill-appearing, NAD

Neck 

Supple, no nodes, no JVD

Chest 

CTA bilaterally

Cardiac 

RR S1 S2, no murmurs

Abdomen 

soft, ND, NT, no rebound, no guarding

Extremity 

2+ radials, 2+ carotids

RLE: 1+ DP, PT, 2+ fem, sensation intact to tips of all remaining toes. 4th toe stump closure intact with sutures in place, no d/c no erythema. 4th toe with erythema and swelling to the MTP, no crepitance, mildly tender, no lymphangitis, 1cm ulcer with serous discharge

LLE: tr DP, dopplerable PT, 2+ fem, sensation decreased to just above knee

Neurological 

AAOx3, speech fluent, CN's 2-12 intact

Full strength all 4 ext

Sensation as above



Laboratory Data: WBC 6.9, Hct 34



Assessment and Plan:  46yr man with severe diabetic vascular disease, recurrent RLE cellulitis

--Admit to Surgery

--Unasyn, blood cultures sent and pending

--Wound care nurse consult

--Wet to dry to R toe ulcer

--No need for amp at this time, consider repeat arterial LENIs if no improvement





______________________________                              

Vu C. Mccarty, M.D.



****************************************************************************************************
Record date: 2078-09-07

       



RYBURY HOSPITAL INTERN ADMISSION NOTE





Name: Goldberg, Joel

MR #: 0370149	

Date of admission: 9/6/2078

Resident: Lange/Bailey

Attending: Schmidt MD

PCP: Odom, Kacie MD



CC:    L foot pain   

 

HPI: The patient is a 48 yo gentleman with a hx of DM2, peripheral neuropathy and PVD with multiple admissions for LE cellulitis in the setting of gangrenous toes in the past 5 years, last one in July. He now presents with acute on chronic LLE sweeling that began this morning after he got up walked around his home for about 2-3 hrs and then suddenly felt an acute pain shooting up his leg, with a severity of 10/10, he knew right away this was similar to the pain he had felt before on prior admissions for cellulitis so he called 911. On arrival to the ED his temp was 98.1, 112, 145/79, 20, 99%RA and was started on antibiotic treatment with Unasyn for cellulitis.      



ROS:  Per HPI. No F/C/NS.  No CP/Palps.  No Orthopnea. No SOB/cough/hemoptysis/wheezing/sore throat/.  No hematochezia/melena. No delta MS/LOC. No slurring of speech, unilateral weakness. No dysuria.  No chills or fevers, no lightheadedness.



PMH:   

1.	DM2 diagnosed in 2075, says peripheral neuropathy was diagnosed around the same time, denies any retinopathy or nephropathy.

2.	Peripheral vascular disease with the following surgeries performed:

	Right 5th toe amputation 2/2 osteomyelitis 12/14/76

Right 4th toe amputation 2/2 wet gangrene 9/03/76

Angioplasty and stenting of the distal LEFT superficial femoral artery 11/6/76

Angioplasty and stenting of the distal RIGHT superficial femoral artery 7/20/76

I&D of right thigh abscess 4/75



Medications on admission (confirmed with patient):

1.	Glyburide 2.5mg BID

2.	Glucopahge 500mg QD

3.	Zestril 2.5mg QD

4.	Percocet PRN



ALL:  Codeine upsets his stomach

SH: Lives in Arroyo Grande apartment with friend, works occasionally as a copy editor but unemployed right now, has smoked 1/2ppd for 35 years, no ETOH, no drugs. Adequate diet.

FH: Many family members with DM.    



Physical Exam:  

V:  98.5, 149/84, 98, 18, 99%RA

Gen:  NAD, conversant

HEENT: PERRL, EOMI.    

Neck:  Supple, no thyromegaly, no carotid bruits, JVP 

Nodes: No cervical or supraclavicular LAN

Cor: RRR S1, S2 nl.  No m/r/g.  No S3, S4

Chest: CTAB  

Abdomen: +BS Soft, NT, ND.  No HSM, No CVA tenderness. 

Ext: LLE with dorsal and medial erythema, extending from L 5th toe that has eschar on its side and is mildly tender, no secretions. L toe also tender. Pulse on LLE + and RLE ++.

Skin: No other rashes

Neuro: AO X 3. CN II-XII intact. Decreased sensation from LT up to knee on R and 4cm above ankle on Left..



Labs and Studies:

	RSC       

          	09/06/78  

          	10:17     



NA        	137       	          	          	          	          

K         	4.5(T)    	          	          	          	          

CL        	106       	          	          	          	          

CO2       	28.4      	          	          	          	          

BUN       	25        	          	          	          	          

CRE       	0.9       	          	          	          	          

GLU       	266(H)    	          	          	          	          

CA        	9.5       	          	          	          	          

PHOS      	3.1       	          	          	          	          

MG        	1.7       	          	          	          	          

	

CBC

WBC       	12.7(H)   	          	          	          	          

RBC       	4.13(L)   	          	          	          	          

HGB       	13.0(L)   	          	          	          	          

HCT       	37.1(L)   	          	          	          	          

MCV       	90        	          	          	          	          

MCH       	31.5      	          	          	          	          

MCHC      	35.0      	          	          	          	          

PLT       	165       	          	          	          	          

RDW       	13.3      	          	          	          	          

DIFFR     	Received  	          	          	          	          

METHOD    	Auto      	          	          	          	          

%NEUT     	79(H)     	          	          	          	          

%LYMPH    	17(L)     	          	          	          	          

%MONO     	3(L)      	          	          	          	          

%EOS      	1         	          	          	          	          

%BASO     	0         	          	          	          	          

ANEUT     	10.02(H)  	          	          	          	          

ALYMP     	2.13      	          	          	          	          

AMONS     	0.44(H)   	          	          	          	          

AEOSN     	0.11      	          	          	          	          

ABASOP    	0.03      	          	          	          	          

ANISO     	None      	          	          	          	          

HYPO      	None      	          	          	          	          

MACRO     	None      	          	          	          	          

MICRO     	None      	          	          	          	          



PT        	11.9      	          	          	          	          

PTT       	25.0      	          	          	          	          



LENIS: Negative for DVT, did not assess arteries.

FOOT ANKLE XR: There is a lytic lesion in the distal lateral aspect of the proximal phalanx of the fifth toe. This can be consitent with an area of infection/osteomyelitis.



Microbiology 

21-Jul-2076 09:41  

  Specimen Type:     WOUND

  Specimen Comment: ULCER  4TH 5TH TOE



  Wound Culture - Final    Reported: 24-Jul-76 15:05

    Moderate PROTEUS VULGARIS

      RAPID METHOD

      Antibiotic                      Interpretation

      ----------------------------------------------

      Amikacin                        Susceptible   

      Ampicillin                      Resistant     

      Aztreonam                       Susceptible   

      Cefazolin                       Resistant     

      Cefepime                        Susceptible   

      Cefpodoxime                     Susceptible   

      Ceftriaxone                     Susceptible   

      Gentamicin                      Susceptible   

      Levofloxacin                    Susceptible   

      Piperacillin                    Susceptible   

      Trimethoprim/Sulfamethoxazole   Susceptible   



    

    

A/P: 48M with a hx of DM2, PVD and multiple admissions in the past for LE cellulitis in the setting of gangrene. 

1.	ID: Patient is now presenting with appears to be another episode of cellulitis but now probably coming from his L 5th Toe lesion. Surgery has debrided the wound, sending wound cultures as well as blood cultures. Acute OM would not be visible on XR changes and clinical picture is more consistent with acute than Chronic OM. Will consider further work up for OM if symptoms do not respond to treatment. Levo and flagyl were added to unasyn in accord to previous culture data.

2.	PVD: Will need arterial LENIS to assess for vascular patency and flow. Continuing ACEI, and adding ASA and lipitor, will order lipid profile and smoking cessation consult.

3.	DM2: Very poor control last admission, eventhough patient now says he takes medications and checks it up to QID. Will order HgbA1C and glucose monitoring.



_______________________________________________________________________

Name Ian Jurado MD                               

Pager # 14558

PGY-1











****************************************************************************************************
]]></TEXT>
<TAGS>
<ABDOMINAL met="not met" />
<ADVANCED-CAD met="not met" />
<ALCOHOL-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ASP-FOR-MI met="met" />
<CREATININE met="not met" />
<DIETSUPP-2MOS met="not met" />
<DRUG-ABUSE met="not met" />
<ENGLISH met="met" />
<HBA1C met="met" />
<KETO-1YR met="not met" />
<MAJOR-DIABETES met="met" />
<MAKES-DECISIONS met="met" />
<MI-6MOS met="not met" />
</TAGS>
</PatientMatching>